Unholy things,
give us that crown.
B-bwow!
Shwa-zaah!
Nova, that was amazing.
Aw, I just cast the
spell you showed me.
Moon Demon King.
Too late, Casper.
I'm going to an
undisclosed third location.
Thwarted again.
I could summon a
sun-ship to give chase.
Hmm. I think we should
check the launch pad
for clues about
where he's headed.
Yeah, that sounds smart, too.
What do you think we should do?
"Fire once for Casper's idea.
Fire twice for Nova's idea."
Ugh, every time we get close,
the crown gets further away.
This book cheats.
"Simon," I know you're
really into this story,
but if you're not enjoying
yourself, you can just stop.
That's the great
thing about books.
No.
Yoo-hoo!
Bloo-bloo-bloo.
Gimme that thingus, dingus.
You? Get outta
here, Choose Goose.
Silly boy.
The geese are long gone.
Now is the era of...
Pawn Swan.
Get outta here!
Goldang geese!
What's got into you?
We love Pawn Swan.
Look, I know
this is hard to understand,
but I have to decode the
secrets of this book.
I have to.
I have to stop the Scarab.
Crossovers.
Crud. Oh, no, he's hot.
He ruined our house. Aah!
Hey, man.
I'm sorry we put you
in a bunch of jars,
uh, but we're back
in our world now
so it's all good, right?
Ow!
All the worlds you've visited,
all the people you've infected.
Your little trip must
have shown you the truth.
It would be better for everyone
if you were just gone.
'Scuse.
Get zapped.
My crystal.
Get eggy. Whoo!
Hand it over.
Za'Baby. Scarab,
all I was doing
was playing games on my work PC,
and you put me in
a flippin' egg?
Keep laying. Cluck, cluck!
Get out of my way.
Oh-ho-ho! Well, if it isn't
Mr. Entomb His Coworker
Because She Was Stealing
Office Supplies.
Scarab, you dweeb.
This is for the egg.
Enough, you cosmic delinquents.
Hello. I'm Perry, the
living island of insight,
may you direct me to
the nearest ocean?
Or inland sea?
Terry.
We're in luck.
These rockets have a
pre-programmed route
to the cosmic gate.
Oh, no, but the Moon Demon
King is so far ahead,
we'll never catch up.
Up-up-up. Now that we
have the destination,
I've figured out a shortcut.
Oh, Casper, I should have known.
Get up, Fi.
Ugh.
Crys-tal.
Oye. Huh?
Ants.
Hey.
Slick.
If I can't extract
this place whole...
I'll rip it out piece by piece.
Tree.
Our post office.
That was our oldest building.
Back up, everybody.
I've seen movies.
Ooh, I think I
stretched too big.
Go, Cake!
Love you, Fi.
"The Cosmic Gate."
Well, this is it.
"Casper and Nova arrive
at the cosmic gate.
On the other side
lies the magic crown."
Yes.
But the gate's closing.
Uh...
Nova.
Wait.
We can't both make it.
But you can climb
through, Casper.
Go. Aw, geez.
"Casper reaches
into his cloak."
What do we do?
"Fire once, Nova will hold
the gate open long enough
for Casper to grab the crown,
but she'll be crushed.
Or Casper drinks a potion
that'll give him the
strength to force the gate,
but it will also cause him
to forget Nova forever."
Forever?
Yeah, these options
are real downers.
But, hey, the
crown's right there.
Beth, I don't want either
of those things to happen.
I like Nova.
There should be more choices.
Well, maybe there would be
if you hadn't picked
Casper's options every time.
What? I did? Uh, that's...
That doesn't sound right.
There was the time I... Hmm.
If we had gone on
Nova's tablet quest
or ordered the baos that Nova
wanted from the food wizard,
it could have led down a
completely different path.
But they were both after
the same thing, the crown.
Weren't they?
I guess you're a kid. You
don't get this stuff yet.
Nova was basically
obsessed with Casper.
Wait. I thought...
I thought they were in love.
They were, but it wasn't
exactly on equal footing.
I guess that's not
Casper's fault per se.
No, but he could have
been more thoughtful.
He could've noticed
that she was sacrificing
over and over.
He could've...
Nyah! Get it off me!
Hey, Beth, I was a
prisoner in my own head.
Roar!
Oh, my God. Cake's so cool.
Yeah, but I'm worried she's
overextending herself.
Yay.
My breadbasket.
Oh, no, Cake.
Cake. Cake.
Ugh. Sorry, Fionna.
You did great.
You're in
eight, right?
Oh, no, Ellis P. Was in there.
What?
I'm not magic. I
don't have a sword.
I can't do anything.
Hm.
Uh, you more of a
butter-tart guy?
I'll stop him...
with music.
Your song about tumbleweeds?
No, a new, heartfelt song
inspired by our love.
I think it's wor...
No.
Please.
I take it back.
I want this world!
Oh, Betty.
Is that what it was like?
I stood by and allowed you
to sacrifice yourself for me.
Even though part of me
should've known better.
Like that day at the bus stop.
Betty!
Petrikov.
I could've made the
effort to support you,
the way you always supported me.
Maybe I never would
have found the crown.
I, uh... I-I found your note.
Yeah?
Who knows what life
would have been like.
You should be more
careful with...
You know what?
The Enchiridion can wait.
Let's go check out
some petroglyphs.
Really? You'd do that for me?
Oh, Petrikov.
But wait.
This isn't how it happened.
No, we made our choices.
We could've made better ones,
but I don't have any regrets.
You were a wonderful experience.
You were...
everything.
Where are you going?!
Was that conversation
all in my head?
I think...
I only offered to
become Ice King
because I felt my
life didn't matter.
But I'm really no
less worthy of life
than Fionna or Cake.
Huh?
Simon. Fionna.
What happened? Are you okay?
I'm okay.
I accidentally got
the ritual to work.
I'm with GOLBetty.
Hey, that's great.
Did you talk?
Aah! Mostly I talked.
Listen, the Scarab is here...
Oh, no. Hang on.
I'll put on the crown.
Maybe you can fight
better with magic.
Don't.
Don't change anything.
This is the world we
want to fight for.
The Scarab is
kinda invincible...
Fionna, let's go.
But we won't give up.
But, Fionna, what if...
If we die, we'll die together.
As ourselves.
It's not fair that your
world is in my stupid head.
Hey, if it wasn't,
we wouldn't have met
the Simon Petrikov.
Don't worry, Simon.
What happened
to my bus? I gotta go.
Fionna...
I swear it was
right here. Aah!
I didn't ask for
this responsibility.
It's too much.
GOLBetty.
It's too mu...
Fionna-world?
Fionna's world.
Come on, Cake. Please get up.
Just give me five minutes.
I'm not sure we
have five minutes.
Simon, please don't
make it harder.
I have something for you.
Fionna.
What are you talking about?
Is that...? Yes.
Your world.
What do I do with...
You'll do fine.
That's our world?
So now what?
Do we eat it?
Our universe was inside one
dude for years and years.
But it wouldn't be right
for us to have it, either.
Of course not.
Hmm.
Pbht!
I wish...
Que linda. Aah!
I don't totally understand
what's happening.
Come to mama.
Thank you.
Whoa.
Uh...
Oh, no.
One of these has to lead to Ooo.
Come on. Come on.
Ugh, gonna have to ice
these knucks for a week.
Okay, let's see.
Is Fionna-world still there?
Wait, what?
They're legit now?
How did that happen?
Aah!
It's gonna hurt.
Oh, glob.
Huh?
Ha! You can't repo an
authorized universe.
No. No. Come on.
This isn't possible.
Unless... this universe
has been canonized.
Boss?
Okay, but... ugh,
it's not fair.
I did everything right.
Yay! We won!
Come on, bring it in.
No, listen. Listen.
I... Boss, please.
Fine.
Hey, Mr. Scarab?
No hard feelings, okay?
No hard feelings?
I'm gonna tear down
Prismo's precious sandcastle
with my bare hands!
Oh, crap. That
guy's just not cool.
There's gotta be
something I can do.
Hey, Scrabby, stop
wrecking my town
just 'cause you got
beef with Prismo.
If anything, you
should be mad at us.
Ma'am.
Alright, baby. Yay, baby!
Hey. Some pink laser
came to visit us all.
Said you needed back-up.
Aw, thanks, y'all.
Hey, friend.
Sorry I bailed on you before.
Never again.
Aah! Don't hurt me!
- Aah!
Squirrel, throw the strawbs.
Oh. Right.
Huh? Eat 'em.
I meant like one or two.
Oh, my God!
Cake! What?
This is my top fantasy.
Lemme try this again.
Yaaa!
Blegh.
Hey, Cake, little help?
Time to get hammered!
Oh, yeah.
Ptwuh.
You think you've
won something? Ha
You were living in
this fake bubble
where nothing happens.
But now you get all
the bad stuff, too.
Your world to screw up.
That just sounds like
we're real to me.
Nyeh, nyeh.
Egg you.
Jay.
Heads up!
Guess what. I'm a copycat.
Aah!
It's over.
What do we do now?
Hmm.
Oh, I got you something to eat.
No more mice.
Mnh-mnh.
Eyyy.
Fionna. Would it be okay
if we just stayed here?
Oh, angels, stay forever.
Ugh, yes. Thank you.
You have functioning toilets.
Yeah.
Yeah, we do.
♪ There's nothing left to say ♪
♪ If my experience
counts for anything ♪
♪ I've got a weekend to waste ♪
♪ And I've got
nothing to gain ♪
♪ Let's just zone
out on the couch ♪
♪ Get lost in symbols
and fractals ♪
♪ That come from the world ♪
♪ We've got good
front-row seats ♪
♪ And the show's
just getting good ♪
♪ All around the world ♪
♪ You feel the sound
and shape of time ♪
♪ I'll find a comfy
little place ♪
♪ For you and I ♪
♪ All throughout my life ♪
♪ You cast a light
that's shifting blue ♪
♪ I know I'll fight
against the stream ♪
All in all, I think
Orbo let you off easy.
It probably helped that I
put in a good word for you.
Maybe you can even grant a
wish in a couple hundred years.
But you gotta pay
your dues first.
Only people who never
pay their dues say that.
Hey, Scarab, why
don't you take five?
I'll show you how to use my
character-creation program.
So I like to start
with an overall theme.
How about true heroes?
No.
Put in "dark medieval
mystery drama."
Wow, okay.
I'm feeling like this whole
experience with Fionna and Cake
helped me realize that
my life is worthwhile.
I'm worried I'll forget that.
This will be a cycle of
learning and forgetting
and relearning and
forgetting again.
This
is juicy stuff.
Keep going.
I'm thinking of moving.
Ah, just a normal world.
♪ All around the world ♪
♪ You feel the sound
and shape of time ♪
♪ I'll find a comfy
little place ♪
♪ For you and I ♪
♪ All throughout my life ♪
♪ You cast a light
that's shifting blue ♪
♪ I know I'll fight
against the stream ♪
♪ It's me and you ♪