Where...
Hey, girl.
Ellis P?
Look at me. I'm even
more beautiful now.
Chase me, Stanley.
Wait. Where's Cake?
Fionna!
Cake!
It worked.
Simon did it.
Let's go to our house.
Yeah. We can throw a party.
Yah!
I feel snacky.
People eat cake
at parties, right?
Let's get one from BB's.
Ooh.
Gary? Are you here?
We're throwing a party.
Gary?
Fionna.
You're back.
Try my new pastry.
Huh?
It's you!
Marshall?
Our building.
No, no. Don't
do it, Stanley.
My spaghetti!
Wait! I'm too
pretty to get eat!
Aah!
Okay, we're safe now.
I'll put in a video game.
You go make us margaritas
I've always wanted
to try one of those.
Are you happy, Fionna?
All this for you.
Fionna.
Fionna, wake up.
You alright?
It's... It's... normal.
Yeah, I know.
I had the worst dream.
When Simon put on the crown,
it all went wrong.
Gary became a scary gum
blob, and Marshall Lee was
a hideous monster that burst into flames.
Hideous monster that burst into flames.
Yeah. Did you see
Simon in the freezer?
Simon in the freezer!
What if it was an omen?
It was just a nightmare.
I can't wait for
this dump to change.
Look at that. It
even has lip sync.
Can I help you?
We didn't know this
rink had a mascot.
Ooh. My butt is an icicle.
Whoa.
Hey, get off the ice.
No skates, no entry.
Yeah, yeah. I'm going.
Whoa-oa.
Pbht!
This place is gonna
be magic soon,
I can feel it.
There.
That squirrel is reading.
Magic.
False alarm.
Marshall and Gary?
Fionna.
Cool threads. You
been thrifting?
What... What... What is this?
Fionna, where have you been?
You just disappeared.
Okay, this is gonna
blow your mind,
but our whole world is
inside this guy Simon's head,
and everything we know is
about to turn crazy magical.
Any second now.
Simon, what's the hold up?
The crown.
Where am I?
Scared of the darkness that
lay before your eyes...
You.
Hey! Lich!
What did you do
to my spell, huh?
Great embodiment of chaos,
hear me.
For ages untold I
studied your ways,
devoting my existence to you.
I strove to be your vassal
on the physical plane,
to build mountains of
bodies in your honor,
to extinguish all life,
and in my universe,
this I achieved.
But it gave me no satisfaction.
In succeeding, I
lost all purpose.
I know what you mean. Why?
Why must this be?
Hear me, Golb.
GOLB?
Betty, are you in there?
Even a little?
I finally get to you
when I'm not even trying.
I've... I've wanted to
see you again for so long.
No, no, no.
Answer me.
What more could I have done?
What do you want from me now?
What?
Betty, I really
tried to fix you.
I searched for years for
a way to undo this...
but I failed.
Living among the humans in Ooo,
I felt completely out
of place and time.
My life had been
drained of all meaning.
You gave me a second chance,
and I've wasted it.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry, Betty.
When I first did the ritual,
I just wanted to come
here and tell you that
but then something
else happened.
I met two people who really
needed my help, Fionna and Cake.
You would have liked them.
They'll use a second chance
better than I ever did.
You of all people should
understand why I must do this.
I finally have a purpose now.
By the order
of Gibbon, find them!
This way.
Halt!
Ugh!
Shoot. Hey, Beth,
launch me.
Ye-e-e-e-ah!
Oof!
Come on, Beth.
On it.
Yeah.
Keep it coming.
Look out!
- Vandals!
- You wont get away with this!
Gibbon doesn't forgive!
Huh?
Ugh!
Yeah, that was great.
Good technique on those
little stink lines, Shermy.
Step four of the revolution...
check.
Ha! Nyah! Nyah!
Take that, Gibbon!
And that!
Oh! You got me!
Tell my kids... I resent them.
Quit wiggling
around, you nugget,
or you're walkin'.
If I'm going to the library,
you're going to
have to carry me.
I finally have a purpose now.
You just got real weird there.
Shermy? Wha?! Aah!
Your legs aren't
broken. You can walk.
What just happened?
I'm in another weird
version of Ooo.
Bread balls! Language.
Betty, why did you send me here?
And in this body?
Why, why, why?
Shermy...
are you going through puberty?
This is going to
sound farfetched,
but I'm not Shermy.
My name is Simon Petrikov.
I'm from another world far
different than your own.
Okay, "Simon."
You're not getting out
of going to the library
by acting weird.
Library? That's
great, actually.
I could really use
a library right now.
Are you making fun of me?
No, no, no. I
love the library.
Okay. I like this new you.
Fionna and Cake are still
waiting for their magic world.
I'll find myself another crown.
You can zap me to whatever
alternate universe you want,
but I have free will.
Do you hear me,
Betty? Do you...
Hear me, Betty?
Do you hear me, Betty?
I keep
stepping on my tail.
Ugh, this will take
some getting used to.
Stay out of this.
Ooh, sparkly.
What's the matter, Simon?
Spell malfunction?
I'm a professional,
and professionals
don't hold grudges.
Aah!
So you're not a robot?
You're a magic cat?
Yes, I always was.
I'm just back to
my original form.
And pretty soon,
you will be, too.
But if everything's
gonna change,
will we still be together?
Uh... maybe?
In the world we all came from,
Gary was a candy prince,
and you were a cool vampire.
- Sick.
- Vampire?
Well, we did see a world
where versions of y'all
tried to kill each other,
so there's that option.
Fionna and I got into a
big fight in that place.
Hey, hey, don't worry.
We smoothed it over.
Honestly, I don't know if
you'll even remember each other.
Or if anyone will remember
this version of our world.
But I don't want
to forget anything.
Marshall and I just met.
Yeah.
Oh, I told you it shouldn't
be up to us to decide.
Pbht!
Maybe we can make requests.
That Simon guy's thoughts
affect our world, right?
Yeah, like, if Simon
knows Marshall and I
are supposed to be
together, it could work out?
And I'd still date you
if you were a vampire.
It's worth a shot.
Simon can do anything.
Just gotta find a portal.
B.R.B.
Blue sparkles.
There.
Portal.
Can you hear me, Simon?
Big damn bugs.
The Scarab.
Just
leave us alone.
So is this part
of the fun magic?
Whoa!
Two scoops in five cones?
I'll see what I can do.
Aah!
Danger.
Oh, no.
Simon, what's going on?
Have there been any significant
ice events in this world?
Not recently.
Who has the magic crown now?
What crown?
It's gold and pointy,
set with red gems...
Shh. We have to be quiet now.
Where's the books?
Shh.
Uh...
What are you waiting for?
Whoa.
Come on. One of these has to be
about ice magic or the crown.
Psst. Just
throw some down.
Preferably something
about high technology,
transcendental meditation,
or trashy romance.
Yes.
Uh, Simon, we should go.
Just a minute.
Don't you hear it?
Euripides.
Sherm... Simon.
Aah!
Pagelings.
Return your books.
Aah.
I need that book.
- Show us your card.
- Return your books!
This is not working out.
Ugh, that's so annoying.
Ugh, keep them apart.
Gimme that.
Aah! Hunter.
I love all plants and animals,
but not these things.
Got it.
Hey, Scarabs.
Huh? Huh?
I got your dumb crystal.
Come and get it.
I can feel their
little, tiny feet.
Ugh.
I shoulda kept up the
medicine-ball routines.
Come on, Prismo.
He-hey! Who needs a gym?
Gotta help
Fionna and Ca-a-a-ke.
I need a bath.
So if this Scarab reforms,
he's going to destroy
our entire reality?
Mm-hmm.
And we can't kill him
because he's immortal?
A Godlike being outdone by
a humble cheese-ball barrel.
So, do we just
keep them in jars,
like forever?
Will they still try to kill
us when the world resets?
I don't know.
I don't even know what's
going on with Simon
or why the Scarab got in.
Mm, Simon must still be alive,
or else we'd be blinked
out of existence.
Hmph. What'd you
bugs do to Simon?
Abominations!
Ugh!
Just call him.
Huh?
I gave him my phone.
You know, to play "Worm"
when he was all alone.
That's my phone.
Can I borrow this?
Oh, wait, the pass
code is... Shh. I know.
Huh?
It's ringing.
Beth, Beth.
Beth, where's the
book? I wanna see...
The book! I need
to see the book.
We're almost to the
ol' reading spot.
Which one's got
you so worked up?
Ah.
"Ancient Artifacts"
written by...
I can't read the author's name.
What luck... this
world's Simon Petrikov
wrote a history
of the crown, too.
The invisible forces
of the universe
must have wanted
me to find this.
That's not how you...
I
know how to read.
I have degrees.
Ugh!
Chill.
Why do you want to
read this one so badly?
The fate of my friends depends
on me finding a magic crown,
and that is the best chance
I have of locating it.
They're waiting.
They're waiting for
their magical...
Oh.
Okay, Simon.
Let's save your friends, then.
Ah.
"Ready for adventure?"
This looks like one of those
choose-your-own-choice deals.
Oh, like the ancient
game books of my world.
"Fire once for yes.
Fire twice for no."
"This is the story about
two best friends...
Casper and Nova.
They are both great explorers.
We meet them on
their great quest
to document and preserve
important talismans.
They journey through
the Gobblebad Caverns
and lodge near a sunken city
in the seaside town of Scandia.
There they hear a rumor
about a magic crown."
The crown.
"A crown guarded by
a deadly fire tiger
who lives atop the
volcanic mountain of Yag."
"Yog?" "Yag."
"Casper wants to go for it.
Nova is really excited
to search for artifacts
in the nearby ancient sea ruins,
but she would be cool with
going with Casper's plan, too.
Which thing should they explore?
Fire once for Casper's quest.
Fire twice for Nova's."
We have to go for the crown.
I don't know. The sea
ruins could be fun, too.
Finding the crown is a literal
matter of life and death
for a whole world
of living souls!
I'm digging the
commitment to this bit.
Casper, then.
"Casper is bitten, and the
crown has already been stolen
by moon demons." Dang it.
Maybe we can go back and
try the sea-ruins route.
Good idea.
"Casper is bitten, and the
crown has already been stolen."
No do-overs with
this book, I guess.
Where are the games
on this thing?
Hmm.
Eh, I'm watching TV.
Leave a
message. Blehh.
Ugh,
either the phone isn't working
or Simon is too hurt to answer.
What would the barflies from
"Cheers' do in this situation?
"Cheers" is filmed before
a live studio audience.
Somebody left the door open.
Hey, I'm walkin here.
I'm gonna go back
through the portal.
The blue sparkles again?
Hey, I saw a glowing
opening with blue sparkles,
out there in the park.
I'll take you there.
Let's go, Cake.
We'll look, too. Really?
We can cover more ground if we
look for portals everywhere.
I could even call my...
mom, if we have to.
Oh, my gob! What are you doing
to these beautiful creatures?!
Be free, my babies!
Be free!
Freedom! Ah-ha-ha-ha!
I saved you!
Does everybody know
where they're headed?