♪ Mm-mmm ♪
♪ Coming up for oxygen ♪
♪ The world's the same ♪
♪ But something's changing ♪
♪ You see it on the street again ♪
♪ Lighting up ♪
♪ The strangest faces ♪
♪ And it feels like that ♪
♪ Sweeter than the best you've ever had ♪
♪ And oh, it takes me back ♪
♪ To being 16
Dancing like you're under attack ♪
♪ I don't really care
If it nearly kills me ♪
♪ I'd give you the world
If you asked me to ♪
♪ I could break a glass
Just to watch it shatter ♪
♪ I'd do anything just to feel with you ♪
♪ I don't really care
If it nearly kills me ♪
♪ I'd give you the world
If you want me to ♪
♪ I can feel it in my fists
It's time to shatter ♪
♪ I'd do anything just to feel with ♪
♪ With you ♪
♪ I'd do anything… ♪
-Nick.
-
-Hi.
♪ I'd do anything just to feel… ♪
Where are we going?
♪ Ooh ooh-ooh ooh-ooh
-♪ Ooh-ooh ooh-ooh ♪
-♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh ooh-ooh ooh-ooh ♪
Guess what?
What?
-I came out to my mum last night.
-Oh my God.
-How did it go?
-Really well.
She was completely fine with it.
Want a "well done" kiss?
Yeah.
Kissing at school is a terrible idea.
-I've never--
-I saw you.
One of the first things
I ever said to you…
-You're not gonna get distracted.
-Yes, I will.
-Hi.
-Hey.
- Argh, just let me win, Charlie!
- Yes!
I can't do this anymore!
I'm sorry!
-That was uncalled for.
-I was here first.
-Um, really?
-Yeah.
-We're in my room.
-I was here…
Oh no. This is war!
Come on!
What?
No, stop tickling me. Stop it!
Hi.
-Hi.
Go on then.
Cheers, love.
You're making me feel
really single right now.
I have a boyfriend!
Yes, we're all fully aware!
And he's amazing.
-I mean…
-Tao!
Yeah, he's okay.
And he wants to come out.
To some of his friends at least.
Um… I thought
he wasn't speaking to the rugby lads
after the fight with Harry.
He's not,
but I'm gonna help him.
Okay.
Well, as long as you're both fine with it,
and you're looking out for each other,
I'm sure it'll be fine.
Tao Xu!
Are you giving Charlie
relationship advice?
-Ah!  Rude!
-
I know about relationships.
I watch a lot of romance movies, so…
Mm.
Uh…
Excuse me.
-You're excused.
-No!
-
-Excuse me. Uh… N… No.
-You have it.
-No.
-You won. Fair and square.
-No. Take it.
No.
Tao!
Get it! Get it!
Hey, Nick!
Here comes Captain Dipstick.
Nicholas!
Imogen.
Are you okay?
I have something very important
to show you.
Okay.
I named him Brooklyn because
that's where I want to live someday,
and I want him to meet Nellie
so they can be best friends!
He's absolutely adorable.
We're still friends, aren't we?
I promise I don't fancy you anymore.
Yeah. I still wanna be friends.
Okay, good.
-Also, I fancy someone else now.
-Really?
Who?
Okay, fine, don't tell me.
We've been friends since Year 7, but…
If anything actually happens,
I promise I'll tell you.
And if you have any romantic developments,
I want to hear all about them.
Oh my God,
I forgot to show you this one. Look.
I got Brooklyn to roll over.
Happy Monday, Truham Grammar,
or perhaps not so happy for our Year 11s
as I regret to inform you that two weeks
of GCSE study hall starts today.
Exam season is nigh.
-Quiet!
-
For those of you who don't know me,
my name is Mr. Farouk.
I normally teach science,
but for the next couple of weeks,
I'll be supervising
your independent GCSE revision.
My rules are simple.
No chatting,
no phones, no annoying questions.
Break my rules, and you go
straight to isolation for the day.
Nicholas Nelson.
Why don't I let you off with a warning
as I hadn't finished listing my rules?
If I catch you with that phone again,
I'll be confiscating it.
Do you understand?
Yes, sir.
Good.
A'ight, I think
we're gonna get on just fine.
- Yusef.
-Yes, sir.
- Jim.
-Here.
- Maximilian.
- Stuart.
-Here, sir.
- Addison.
- William.
-Here, sir.
Nicholas.
- Todd.
-Here, sir.
- Leah.
-Here.
- Warren.
-Here, sir.
Charlie.
Here, sir.
- Toby.
-Here, sir.
- Paul.
Dennis.
Are you just gonna ignore me
for two weeks then?
-I didn't even do anything to you.
-Don't talk to me.
I said sorry to Charlie for what happened.
-Don't talk about him.
-Wow.
You know,
if you're trying to keep it quiet,
you should probably
stop acting so gay for him.
I seem to remember
saying something about no chatting.
-
-Come in!
I want to rejoin the rugby team.
You know you don't have to do this
if you don't want to.
I want to.
Otherwise we'll barely see each other
this term.
-And I've missed rugby.
-
-Have you now?
-Yeah.
I love running around and falling over.
Oh, well, you are very good
at the falling over part.
I'm good at the running part,
too, actually.
What, running away from the ball?
-Okay, well, if you don't want me here…
-Oh, no, no, no, no. Come on.
I need you.
Oi! Are you coming back to rugby?
-Yeah.
-Yes, lad.
Come on then.
- Go on then, pass it.
- Touch warm-up!
You all right, Nick?
What? Are you still in a mood with us?
Let's go, lads.
You've all been playing like girls lately.
-
-Harry, cross! Cross!
Wide! Nice and wide!
Charlie, pass the ball!
Let's go. Let's go.
And again! And again!
- Nick!
Nick, you're meant
to pass the ball!
- Come on.
- You had an overlap.
- I was open!
-Why aren't you guys playing like a team?
-Set up.
- Pass the ball!
-Can we set up?
-Leave it, Otis. Leave it.
Leave it. Come on.
-Let's go again!
- We don't want another St. John's.
Elle, listen, you deserve
to have the perfect romance.
Exactly.
Like us.
But Tao is literally
the worst person to have a crush on.
Sometimes I think he might like me back,
but other times it's…
It's probably just Tao being weird.
But maybe being weird
is how he expresses his romantic feelings.
Personally, I can relate to that.
What if you tried
actually flirting with him?
-Just to see what happens.
- Yeah, flirt with him.
You're quiet today.
-What's up?
-Nothing. Everything's normal.
Normal? Okay.
My mum's been moaning at me
to get a haircut.
Your hair's cute long.
But it'd look cute short too.
-
-You should do what you want.
That's my mum.
I'll see you tomorrow.
- …starting lineup on Sunday.
- If no one passes, we won't win.
I got you a present.
What? Why?
Because… we've been going out
for two months.
As in, it's our two-month anniversary?
It sounds silly when you say it like that.
-No, no, it doesn't.
-And now I'm embarrassed.
No! Look. Um…
I… I did not get you a present.
It's okay. I didn't want it
to become a thing, so…
It could be a thing.
And how did you know
this is my favorite chocolate bar?
Uh…
You mentioned it ages ago, so…
Thank you.
-
And that's why
we shouldn't kiss at school.
Oh, but kissing's so fun.
But you getting outed
because we get caught kissing is not.
I… I want to tell people.
You know, like Imogen. I just…
It's hard to find the right time.
You don't have to tell everyone,
or anyone, if you don't want to.
-You're making me wanna kiss you again.
-I'm being serious.
So am I.
Hey.
If we're out by the time
we're on the Paris trip, we can, uh…
kiss on the Eiffel Tower.
No more kissing at school.
It's too risky.
-Are you staying to hang out with us?
-I will be going upstairs.
Mum and Dad
hardly ever go away at weekends.
-You can invite some of your friends over.
-I treasure my alone time.
Why exactly did you purchase
the entire Tesco snack aisle?
It's a sleepover.
We need snacks.
And everything about tonight
needs to be perfect.
Are you getting graded for it?
I'm helping Nick come out
to one of his oldest friends.
Hi.
- I made cupcakes.
- Wow. Well done. Proud of you.
It's very unlike me.
We have a snack table
you can put them on.
-You know, like, toffee popcorn.
-Toffee popcorn is the best popcorn.
♪ 40 days and 40 nights… ♪
-Yes.
-No.
-Yes!
-If you were a worm? That's weird.
- No, it's not!
-These are my favorite.
-Is it?
-Like, ever.
Tao, I bet your mum's bao buns
are the best.
♪ Waited for you… ♪
The height. Okay, ready?
I swear. Tao!
- Okay. Again.
- Tao.
♪ You were out of my league ♪
♪ All the things I believed ♪
♪ You were just the right kind ♪
♪ Yeah, you were more than just a dream ♪
I swear, I'm gonna move into your house
just so I can get your mum
to make me these every day.
-Oh my God, me too.
-Same.
Well, we only have one spare room, so…
So… we can share your room.
♪ From time to time, I pinch… ♪
-Uh…  My mum wouldn't let me.
- Darcy's mum's the same.
She hates having people over.
Yeah, but your mum
lets us have sleepovers, so…
Yeah. Speaking about sleepovers,
do you wanna come to mine?
Of course I do.
- Movie?
- Movie.
A classic, or…
- Oh!
-Who's that?
- Did someone deliver something?
- Did we invite someone else?
♪ All the things I believed… ♪
Hi.
- Hi!
- Imogen!
Come in, come in.
Let me show you where to put your bags.
- Charlie will give you a tour.
- Yeah, um… Yeah, a tour.
We've got loads of snacks in there. Um…
I'm so excited!
Does she, uh, know about you guys?
Not yet. I'm… gonna tell her today.
It'll be fine.
-She's an ally.
-
Darcy!
I'm gonna move in. I'm moving in!
Your friend group is so nice.
How did you get to know everyone?
Uh…
Well, um…
I guess it was Charlie first. Um…
'Cause me and Charlie, we're, like…
You know, we're in the same form, and… um…
Yeah.
Cute!
Guys, we're ordering pizza!
Oh my God, I am so ready for pizza!
I want ham and mushroom.
It's okay.
I don't know
why it's so hard to just… say it.
It's all bad.
No, it's not.
None of your art is ever bad.
Well, my coursework needs to be amazing
if I'm gonna use it
to get into art college.
-What about all this floral stuff?
-Boring. It doesn't mean anything.
You just need to get inspired.
I could be your model.
Hmm?
-Draw me like one of your French girls!
-Is this supposed to be inspiring?
Please, Jack! Jack!
I'm swimming!
Mm?
Okay, fine. Sit up.
Wait. Tilt your head a bit to your left.
That's your right.
No, not like that. Look at me.
Uh…
Sorry.
I'll…
go order our pizzas.
Do you want Hawaiian?
Oh. Yeah. Thanks.
♪ Pressure to party, gonna stay in ♪
♪ Nothing good can come
From me drinking… ♪
Come on.
♪ I would run, shoes off
Straight back to you ♪
♪ I know where you live, I used to… ♪
Isaac, come dance with me.
-No, I'm good.
-Agh, give me your book!
Tara, I don't like dancing.
Imogen?
-Come on!
- Go on, Imogen.
-Okay.
- Yes!
♪ Meeting a stranger, touching his face ♪
♪ I don't want anyone to ever take… ♪
Nick, come and dance.
Uh… No. No.
Come on!
Come on.
Whoo!
Come on!
♪ With my isolation… ♪
-
- Oh my God, finally! Pizza!
♪ In my room, but I'll open up the door… ♪
You need to tell her!
♪ And try to love again soon ♪
Hey.
-Pizza's here.
-Mm.
So, um… you and Elle
have been doing work, like, all afternoon.
Elle's trying to get
into this prestigious art college.
She'll definitely get in,
but she's still worried about it.
Do you think it's gonna be weird for you?
-If you're apart next year?
-What do you mean?
We're not dating.
-Oh, no, I--
-She's my friend.
She's my best friend, and there's… We're…
It's none of your business.
This is a kitchen,
not a poetry recital.
I will, after you tell me
what béarnaise sauce is.
Again,
why didn't you ask me this
before you started making it?
-Charlie, can I use your bathroom?
-Yeah, sure.
Um… I'll show you where it is.
I'm not supposed
to be approachable.
You've got a lot of people
relying on you and looking up to you.
It wouldn't hurt you to be…
- Yes!
- Tell her.
Go on!
That's the, uh… That's the bathroom there.
Oh. Cool, thanks.
Imogen, um…
I… I kind of have something
that I… I wanna tell you.
Well, it's…
It's kind of hard to--
Is it about you and Charlie?
Oh my God.
I should've let you say it.
It's just… it is kinda obvious.
And, like, it totally makes sense.
Like, the whole date thing
and the sports-day thing.
You didn't like me because you're gay.
Uh…
Well, I… I'm bisexual actually.
-Oh.
-Yeah.
I'm sorry.
I don't actually know how to react.
This is… This is good.
Okay, well, now you know about Charlie,
you have to tell me about your crush.
-
-Oh, come on.
It's only fair.
Ugh, fine, okay.
It's Ben.
I'm so cozy right now.
I'm gonna fall asleep so quick.
-
The flirting didn't work.
I think I need to try and get over him.
Oh, Elle.
Oh.
-Bye, Charlie.
-Bye!
-Thank you.
-Thank you for coming. Bye.
-Bye.
-Every time.
- Bye!
- Bye.
Bye.
I can't believe
people think you're straight.
Silly.
But, yeah, let's go.
-Bye.
- Ah, I think my mum's here.
- Oh. Let's go and see.
I signed that form
for the Paris trip.
-It's on the fridge.
- Oh, thanks.
Are all your friends
going too?
Yeah. It's a joint
Truham-Higgs language students trip.
Well, then, your Spanish GCSE
will come in very useful.
-You know my friend Nick?
- Yes.
I thought I probably should tell you…
He's my boyfriend.
You're surprised.
Uh, well, I… You know…
He's a very sporty, laddish sort of boy.
I j-- I wouldn't have assumed he was gay.
Being gay has nothing to do with that.
And actually, he's bisexual.
Gay or bisexual, uh,
Nick is… banned from sleepovers
from now on.
What?
Yeah, there will be no hanky-panky
in this house.
Please don't say "hanky-panky."
And I suppose
Nick's going on this Paris trip as well?
Yeah.
So that's why you've been talking about it
nonstop for weeks.
-Bedroom door open at all times.
- I'm leaving.
-No hanky-panky till you're married.
-Stop saying "hanky-panky."
-What…
- No. Mm.
-
You're telling people then?
Yeah.
And you're not worried?
About what?
About getting bullied again?
It's not gonna be like when I got outed.
We just want people
to know we're together.
I'm gonna do everything I can to make sure
Nick doesn't have to deal with what I did.
♪ Let me in ♪
♪ Let others battle… ♪
I can protect him.
I can make sure
that he never feels pressured
or stressed or… scared.
♪ Let me in… ♪
Everything's gonna be perfect.
♪ We don't need to battle ♪
♪ And we're both shouting ♪
♪ Lost in my mind ♪
♪ Was a storm from the beach ♪
♪ The perfect circle ♪
♪ Gave a moment of peace ♪
♪ Now I'm lying on the floor ♪
♪ With our love off the shore ♪
♪ I close my eyes ♪
♪ And imagine ♪
♪ I'm not there ♪