The curse. If Angel achieved
true happiness, even just a moment,
- he would lose his soul.
- Previously on "Buffy the Vampire Slayer":
This is it. The curse.
- What?
- I may be able to work this.
Willow cured him
and somehow he came back.
You must have known
it was wrong to see Angel.
I wanted to wait.
For Angel to go psycho again
the next time you give him a happy?
Why, Daniel, wherever are you goin'?
- You... you're not human.
- Not of late, no.
- What do you want?
- I'm hungry, Daniel.
- And seeing as you're in my debt...
- Please, I can't.
A man playing at cards should have a
natural intelligence or a great deal of money.
And you're sadly lacking in both.
So I'll take my winnings my own way.
The Lord is my shepherd; I shall not want.
He maketh me to lie down in green pastures...
Daniel, be of good cheer.
It's Christmas.
It's going to be warm, with temperatures
continuing in the high 70s
throughout the holiday weekend,
- Hi.
- Angel.
So, are you shopping?
You're probably not shopping.
I couldn't sleep.
Vampires are probably not big
on Christmas, now I think about it.
Not as a rule.
But you're good?
- I'm all right. You?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I'm good. I was just getting
some Christmas gifts for the gang.
I'd better go before the magic store closes.
Angel?
What is it?
And then he just bailed. He didn't say
anything, he just took off. It was so weird.
Angel? Weird? What are the odds?
Do you think something's wrong?
Maybe you should tell Giles.
No. I don't wanna bug Giles.
He's still kinda twitchy
on the subject of Angel.
Must be that Angel-killed-his
girlfriend-and-tortured-him thing.
Giles is pretty petty with stuff like that.
Xander, enough. OK?
Maybe Angel just has the holiday blues.
Everybody gets 'em,
especially when they're alone.
It's just so frustrating.
I'm trying to do the right thing
and stay away from him and get over it.
And then boom, there he is.
I just want a nice, quiet Christmas vacation.
So, you doing anything special?
Tree. Nog. Roast beast.
Just me and mom
and hopefully an excess of gifts.
- What are you doing for Christmas?
- Being Jewish. Remember?
Not everybody worships Santa.
- I just meant for vacation.
- Oh, nothing fun.
Oz and I had planned...
But I guess that's off.
Well, I'll be enjoying
my annual Christmas Eve camp-out.
I take my sleeping bag outside
and sleep on the grass.
- Sounds fun.
- Yeah. I look at the stars, feel the nature vibe.
I thought you slept outside to avoid
your family's drunken Christmas fights.
Yes, and that was a confidence
I was hoping you'd share with everyone.
Well, I'll be in Aspen. Skiing.
- With actual snow.
- I hear that helps.
It must be a drag to be stuck here
in Sweatydale, but I'm thinking of you.
OK, I'm done.
- She certainly has reverted to form.
- It's not her fault.
After what happened,
we gotta cut her some slack.
- That's the Christmas spirit.
- Hello? Still Jewish.
Chanukah spirit, I believe that was.
Anyway, forgiveness is pretty much a big
theme with me this year because of the...
Hey.
OK.
The thing is...
Seeing you with Xander, it was...
Well, I never felt that way before -
when there wasn't a full moon.
But I know you guys have a history.
But it's a history that's in the past.
Well, I guess most history is in the past.
But it's over.
Well, I don't know. I don't know
that it ever will be between you two.
Oz, please believe me.
This is what I do know.
I miss you.
Like, every second.
It's like I lost an arm.
Or worse, a torso.
So...
I think I'd be willing to give it a shot.
Really?
Yeah.
Do you want us to...
to hug now?
Yeah, I'm good for that.
D'you wanna get one with snow on it?
Be very Christmassy.
- I think those are just for display.
- Oh.
You know, honey, I was thinking.
Maybe we should invite Faith
to spend Christmas Eve with us.
I don't know.
Faith and I don't really hang out,
or talk, or make eye contact lately.
Do you really wanna let her spend Christmas
Eve all by herself in that dingy motel room?
- You're still number one with the guilt trip.
- I try.
- I'll ask her.
- You're a doll.
- What about Giles? He doesn't have...
- I'm sure he's fine.
- We could at least ask him and see.
- He doesn't wanna be with a bunch of girls.
Let's split up.
Bunch of 'em up and died on us.
Don't know why.
If you want one,
I can make you a hell of a deal.
No, thank you.
Oh, honey, this one's perfect.
Yeah?
Work, dammit!
Hey.
What's goin' on? Scary monsters?
Nope.
We're having Christmas Eve dinner
at my house, and if you didn't have plans...
Your mom sent you down, huh?
- No.
- Well, thanks, but I got plans.
There's this big party I've been invited to.
It should be a blast.
OK. Cool.
But if you change your mind, the offer...
It's nice of you, thanks,
but I got... I got that big party
that I've been invited to, so...
I like the lights.
Yeah, well, 'tis the season.
Whatever that means.
Just a minute!
Hello.
I'm...
I'm sorry to bother you.
Sorry. Coming from you, that phrase strikes
me as rather funny: sorry to bother me.
- I need your help.
- And the funny keeps on coming.
I understand I have no right to ask for it,
but there's no one else.
All right.
I can't come in unless you invite me.
I'm aware of that.
Come in.
I've been seeing...
I've had dreams lately. About the past.
It's like I'm living it again, it's so vivid.
I need to know...
- I need to know why I'm here.
- Here? Back on earth?
I should be in a demon dimension
and suffering an eternity of torture.
- I don't feel inclined to argue with that.
- But I'm not.
I was freed. And I don't understand why.
- Knowing would give you peace of mind?
- It might.
Is that something you ought to have?
Because, to be blunt, the last time you
became complacent about your existence,
it turned out rather badly.
What?
Don't you see her?
Who?
I can't.
I propose a toast.
Well, it's nice to be back in London.
Please, I should return to the party.
- Margaret, there's no hurry.
- Mistress will be wondering...
She'll be wondering how to get
Reverend Chalmers into bed,
and will not notice the absence of canapés.
- Stay with me.
- Sir, people might talk.
I'll be put out in the streets.
My little boy would...
I can't lose this job.
- Then you best keep quiet.
- You're hurting me.
Cry out, call for help. I'm sure Mistress will
believe your behaviour beyond reproach.
- Please.
- Come.
Make a scene, shall I?
No.
We'll be as quiet as mice.
No matter what.
Sir.
My son!
He'll make a fine dessert.
Trouble sleeping?
- You're not here.
- I'm always here.
- Leave me alone.
- I can't.
You won't let me.
What do you want?
To die in bed surrounded by grandchildren,
but I guess that's off the menu.
- I'm sorry.
- You're sorry.
For me? Don't bother.
I'm dead. I'm over it.
If you wanna feel sorry for someone,
feel sorry for yourself.
- But I guess you've already got that covered.
- Look, I am sorry
for what I've done.
What else can I say to you?
I don't wanna make you feel bad.
I just want to show you who you are.
- You had a dream about Angel.
- I was in Angel's dream.
- I'm not sure that's...
- There was stuff I couldn't possibly know.
It was Angel's past. He was dreaming it
and somehow I got sucked in.
There's something wrong with him.
I know. I've seen him.
He wanted to know why he was back.
Is there away for us to find that out?
- Possibly. I've been looking.
- Well, let me look, too.
I'm not seeing him any more.
I'm trying to put all this behind me.
And I won't be able to as long as we're doing
guest spots in each other's dreams.
So we'll help him?
Yes.
Where do we start?
I'm aware I haven't been the mostest best
friend to you when it comes to Angel, and...
I don't know, maybe
I've finally got the Chanukah spirit.
Well, we start, unsurprisingly, with research.
Xander -
Black Chronicles,
And, Buffy - the Diary of Lucius Temple,
An acolyte of Acathla, an expert on demons.
You can skip the passages on his garden,
unless you're keen on growing heartier beets.
Are you sure this is how
you wanna spend your vacation?
It's the most exciting thing I've got planned.
Who else can claim that pathetic a social life?
Hey, guys. What're we doin'?
He's gonna come over on Christmas Eve
cos my parents are out of town.
- We're gonna watch videos.
- That's good, right?
You guys are back.
It's good. It's perfect.
In an awkward, uncomfortable sort of way.
I just don't know how to make Oz trust me.
Xander has a piece of you
that Oz just can't touch.
I guess now it's just about
showing Oz that he comes first.
I guess.
Thanks.
- Hey! He likes beets.
- I read that one already.
We're not getting any closer.
The thing I remember most
was thinking how artful it was.
In the dark they looked
just like they were sleeping.
It wasn't until I bent down and kissed them
good night that I felt how cold they were.
You grabbed me and I thought:
"Who would go to so much trouble
to arrange them like that?"
But you see...
That's what makes you
different than other beasts.
They kill to feed.
But you took more kinds of pleasure in it
than any creature that walks or crawls.
- Oh, God.
- Yeah.
Cry out. Make a scene.
I was to be married that week,
but then, as I recall, you knew that.
- It wasn't me.
- It wasn't you?
A demon isn't a man. I was a man once.
Oh, yes. And what a man you were.
A drunken, whoring layabout
and a terrible disappointment
to your parents.
I was young.
- I never had a chance to...
- To die of syphilis?
You were a worthless being
before you were ever a monster.
Stop it!
I don't wanna hurt you, Angel,
but you have to understand.
Cruelty is the only thing
you ever had a true talent for.
It's not true.
Rest.
You mistake it for a curse, Angel, but it's not.
It's your destiny.
I'll show you.
- You want her.
- No.
Take her. Take what you want.
Pour all that frustration
and all that guilt into her and you'll be free.
No.
You can't live for eternity with all that pain.
This is what you are
and this is why we brought you back.
Take her.
And then you'll be ready
to kill her.
Hey, Buffy. Take a look.
These letters contain references
to an ancient power known as the First.
- First what?
- Evil.
Absolute evil. Older than man, than demons.
It could have had the power
to bring Angel back.
These guys.
I saw them in my dream. I fell asleep up there.
You had another dream? With Angel?
What happened?
Oh, we don't need to get sidetracked.
- Who are these guys?
- They're known as Bringers or Harbingers.
They're high priests of the First.
They can conjure spirit manifestation
and set them on people.
- Influence them, haunt them.
- These guys are working the mojo on Angel.
We gotta stop 'em.
You can't fight the First, Buffy.
It's not a physical being.
- Well, I can fight these priest guys.
- If we can find 'em.
It's the Slayer.
What brings the Slayer down here?
Hey, Willy. How you been?
Keeping outta trouble. As God is my witness.
So what can I do for you? Coupla drinks?
Yeah, let me get a double shot of...
- information, pal.
- Three priests. They call themselves...
- The Bringers.
- Bringers. Harbingers.
- They have a no-eyes kind of look.
- Doesn't ring a bell.
How about I ring that bell for ya?
- Does the threatening come now?
- Maybe you shouldn't help.
They'd have come to town recently. They'd be
holed up somewhere, summoning the First.
Well... I heard a few things.
You know - from the underground.
- The underground?
- Yeah. From things living under the ground.
There's been migration out of Sunnydale
from the lower inhabitants.
Something's scaring them off. And these
are things that are not easily scared.
- Could be your priest guys are underground.
- Where?
I do not know.
OK.
- Thanks.
- See you around.
You did great, by the way.
I was very intimidated.
Really?
- Thanks.
- Let's go.
Hey, kid.
Merry Christmas.
Man, is it hot. It was so nice and cool in there.
Yeah. A nice, cool waste of time.
We know underground, that's a start.
Sure! In a town with
14 million square miles of sewer.
Plus a lot of natural cave formations
and a gateway to hell.
- Yeah, this does resemble square one.
- I don't know what to do.
I think right now the best plan
is to deck the halls with boughs of holly.
Look, we'll catch the bad guys -
sooner or later.
Willow?
I got videos.
Hi.
Why don't you come sit down?
Ever have that dream where
you're in a play, and it's the middle,
and you don't know your lines
and you kind of don't know the plot?
Well, we're alone and we're together.
I just wanted it to be special.
How special we talkin'?
Well, you know.
We're alone and we're both
mature younger people,
and so...
we could...
I'm ready to... with you...
We could do that thing.
- Where are you going?
- No, I'm not going. Just a... dramatic gesture.
That's pretty special.
Oz, I wanna be with you.
First.
I think we should sit down again.
Oz...
I'm ready.
OK. Well, don't take this the wrong way...
but I'm not.
- Are you scared? Cos I thought you had...
- No, I have.
But this is different.
I mean, you look great.
And you got the Barry working for you,
and it's all... good.
But when it happens...
I want it to be because
we both need it to for the same reason.
You don't have to prove anything to me.
I just wanted you to know.
I know.
I get the message.
There we go.
Nothing like a fire
to keep away the blistering heat.
Oh, come on. It's lovely.
Maybe I should turn the air conditioning on.
- Angel's on top again?
- What?
Angel or star?
Star.
Hey.
Looks like that whole party thing
was gonna be kind of a drag.
I didn't really have anything...
You know.
I'm glad you came.
Here.
Why don't you come in
from the entire lack of cold?
That one is for your mom.
They're pretty crappy.
Faith, you made it.
- Oh, that is so thoughtful.
- They're crappy.
I'm gonna go upstairs and get your gifts.
Some nog?
OK, Mom, don't touch yours
cos then you're gonna know what it is.
Angel.
Buffy...
What is it?
I gotta...
Look, I had to see you.
I don't know. I...
You shouldn't be...
Just tell me what's going on.
She wants you to touch her.
What are you waiting for?
Look, you have to stay away from me.
You came to see me
to tell me that I can't see you?
Angel, something is doing this to you.
You just have to control it, OK?
- I know you're confused.
- I think you're the one who's confused.
I think you need to...
She wants you to taste her.
Think of the peace.
You'll never have to see us again.
- Angel, how can I help you?
- Leave me alone!
Stay with Mom in case he comes back.
I'll play watchdog. I don't get it, though.
- I'll explain later. Everything, I promise.
- Watch your back.
Giles, we have to do something. Soon. Now.
I'm still not sure what.
Find me these priest guys.
Find me something I can pummel.
- Let's not lose our heads.
- Giles, he's slipping.
I think we're losing him.
You realise if he truly becomes a danger,
you may have to kill him.
Again.
Can you do that?
- I can't do it.
- You have to do it.
- What else are you good for?
- Get away from me.
Couldn't you just feel her?
Couldn't you almost smell her skin?
You never were a fighter, Angel.
Don't start tryin' now.
Sooner or later you will drink her.
- I'll never hurt her.
- You must. Have you learned nothing?
- As long as you are alive...
- Then I'll die.
- You don't have the strength to kill yourself.
- I don't need strength.
I just need the sun to rise.
You're not supposed to die.
This isn't the plan.
But it'll do.
"A child shall be born of man and goat
and have two heads,
and the first shall speak only in riddles."
No wonder you like this stuff.
It's like reading the Sun,
Yes.
- Priests?
- Yes, but more posturing, I'm afraid.
"They are the harbingers of death.
Nothing shall grow above or below them."
"No seed shall flower, neither in man nor..."
They're rebels and they'll never be any good.
- Nothing specific about their haunts.
- Let me see that.
"The harbingers of death."
"Nothing shall grow above or below..."
What?
All right. Ten more minutes of chanting
and then you guys have to go to bed.
I'm impressed.
- You won't get Angel.
- You think you can fight me?
I'm not a demon, little girl.
I am something you can't even conceive.
The First Evil.
Beyond sin.
Beyond death.
I am the thing that darkness fears.
You'll never see me, but I am everywhere.
Every being, every thought,
every drop of hate.
All right, I get it! You're evil.
Do we have to chat about it all day?
Angel will be dead by sunrise.
Your Christmas will be his wake.
- No.
- You have no idea what you're dealing with.
Let me guess.
Is it... evil?
Dead by sunrise!
Angel!
I bet half the kids down there
are already awake,
lying in their beds,
sneaking downstairs,
waiting for day.
Angel, please. I need you to get inside.
There's only a few minutes left.
I know. I can smell the sunrise
long before it comes.
I don't have time to explain this.
You just have to trust me.
- That thing that was haunting you...
- It wasn't haunting me.
- It was showing me.
- Showing you?
- What I am.
- Were.
And ever shall be.
I wanted to know why I was back. Now I do.
You don't know.
Some great evil takes credit for bringing
you back and you buy it? You just give up?
I can't do it again, Buffy.
I can't become a killer.
- Then fight it.
- It's too hard.
- You have to get inside.
- They told me to kill you.
You were in the dream. They told me to lose
my soul in you and become a monster again.
- I know that. What does it matter?
- Because I wanted to!
Because I want you so badly.
I wanna take comfort in you. And I know it'll
cost me my soul and part of me doesn't care.
I'm weak. I've never been anything else.
It's not the demon in me
that needs killing, Buffy. It's the man.
You're weak. Everybody is.
Everybody fails.
Maybe this evil did bring you back,
but if it did it's because it needs you.
And that means that you can hurt it.
Angel, you have the power
to do real good, to make amends.
But if you die now,
then all that you ever were was a monster.
- Angel, the sun is coming up.
- Just go.
- I won't.
- Do you think this is simple?
You can never understand
what I've done. Now, go.
- You are not staying. I won't let you.
- Leave!
Am I a thing worth saving, huh?
Am I a righteous man?
The world wants me gone.
What about me?
I love you so much.
And I tried to make you go away.
I killed you and it didn't help.
And I hate it.
I hate that it's so hard,
and that you can hurt me so much.
I know everything that you did
because you did it to me.
God,
I wish that I wished you dead.
I don't.
I can't.
Buffy, please.
Just this once,
let me be strong.
Strong is fighting.
It's hard and it's painful and it's every day.
It's what we have to do
and we can do it together.
But if you're too much
of a coward for that, then burn.
If I can't convince you that you belong
in this world, then I don't know what can.
But do not expect me to watch,
and don't expect me
to mourn for you, because...
While most of California
will have a balmy Christmas,
an extreme cold front has sprung up
out of nowhere round Sunnydale,
where they are reporting
heavy snow fall for the first time ever,
Sunnydale residents won't see the sun at all
today, that cold front isn't going anywhere,
temperatures in the high 30s means you
better bundle up if you're going outside.