Are we the first?
Are we the first to arrive here?
Mr. Wilson!
Is the interpreter with you?
I'm not a, uh, professional interpreter.
My occupation is cartography.
I'm a mapmaker.
Can you translate French into English
and English into French?
Yes, yes, I explained to
the team leader in Villa Hermosa.
I'm just a little taken by surprise.
How long have you
been working on this project?
I've been with
the American team from the beginning.
In fact, I saw you at the Montsoreau
conference which ended well...
...especially for you.
Especially for the French.
If it isn't too late, my congratulations.
They're all there! All of them!
Check for landing marks!
Mr. Lacombe wants
the numbers off the engine blocks!
M-447148!
W-445529!
Number 445529, check!
Approximately 46 gallons
in the right tank!
447149, check!
Tell me something.
What the hell is happening here?
- It's flight number 19!
- Nineteen what?
It's that training mission from
the naval air station at Fort Lauderdale.
They were doing target runs
on an old hulk.
Who flies crates like these anymore?
No one! These planes
were reported missing in 1945.
But it looks brand-new!
Where's the pilot?
I don't understand!
Where's the crew? Hey!
How the hell did it get here?!
He says this guy is local.
He was here last night.
He saw it happen.
Sunburn?
He says the sun came out last night.
He says it sang to him.
Harry, keep an eye
on that point-out I gave you.
He's on 122.5.
I'll be right back.
Indianapolis
Center, you have traffic for Air East 31?
Air East 31, negative.
The only traffic I have is a TWA
L-1011 in your 6 o'clock position...
...range 15 miles...
...and an Allegheny DC-9
in your 12 o'clock position, 50 miles.
Stand by one. I'll take
a look at broadband, over.
Air East 31 has traffic 2 o'clock,
slightly above and descending.
Air East 31, roger.
I have a primary target
about that position now.
I have no known high-altitude traffic.
Stand by one, I'll check low, over.
Dick, will you check low-altitude,
see if they know who this is?
Center, Air East 31.
The traffic's not lower than us.
He's 1 o'clock now,
still above me and descending.
Air East 31, can you say aircraft type?
Negative, Center, uh, no distinct outline.
Uh, to tell you the truth,
the target is rather brilliant.
It has the brightest anti-collision lights
I think I've ever seen.
Alternating white to red.
The colors are a little striking.
Center, this is TWA 517.
Traffic now looks like
extra-bright landing lights.
I thought Air East
had his landing lights on.
It could be a satellite.
Air East 31, I have a primary target now in
your 10 o'clock position, five miles, over.
- Never seen anything like that.
- Affirmative, 31.
The traffic is proceeding
northeast-bound.
No altitude readout.
Roger, Center. It doesn't
appear he's gonna be a problem now.
He's going to descend
about 1500 feet below me.
Wait a second!
Stand by one.
Okay, Center, Air East 31.
The traffic has turned.
He's heading for my windshield. We're
turning right and leaving flight level 350.
Air East 31,
descend and maintain flight level 310.
Break Allegheny, turn right 30 degrees.
Get on the horn to the 45th Recon Wing,
see what the hell they're testing up there.
This is Indianapolis Center. Are there any
test operations in restricted area 2508?
Air East 31, roger.
The traffic is quite luminous, exhibiting
some non-ballistic motion, over.
Roger, Air East 31. Continue
descent at your discretion, over.
Okay, Center. Descent
at pilot's discretion is approved.
The traffic is approaching head-on,
ultra-bright and really moving.
And right by us! Right now!
Now that was really close.
Air East 31 is out of 340....
Ask them if they want to report officially.
TWA 517,
do you want to report a UFO? Over.
Negative. We don't want to report.
Air East 31, do you wish
to report a UFO? Over.
Negative. We don't want to
report one of those either.
Uh, Air East 31, do you wish to
file a report of any kind? Over.
I wouldn't know what kind
of report to file, Center.
Air East 31, me neither.
I'll try to track traffic
to destination, over.
♪ Of the shape of a square ♪
♪ If you really want to find it ♪
♪ So look with care
For the shape of a square ♪
♪ Can you find it? ♪
♪ Is the door shaped like a square? ♪
♪ No, it's shaped like a rectangle ♪
♪ It has two long sides
And two short sides ♪
♪ If you really want to find it ♪
♪ So look with care
For the shape of a square ♪
♪ Look all around ♪♪
- What are you doing?
- I'm just....
What?
Barry?
Honey?
Barry!
Barry.
All right, everybody to bed!
No way! Dad said we could finish
watching The Ten Commandments!
Roy, that movie
is four hours long, you know.
I told them they'd watch
only five commandments.
Hello? Hi, Earl.
What?
Oh, you know Roy can't drive at night
without me. Heh-heh.
Wait, wait, wait, I can't-- Hey, honey.
Jiminy Cricket! It's Earl on the phone.
Just a second.
- Hello.
- Neary.
Listen to me, now.
Get over to the Gilmore substation.
We've lost the power
up and down the line.
There's a drain on the primary voltage.
Yay!
We've lost half the transformers
at the Kennedy substation.
♪ I looked out this morning
And the sun was gone ♪
♪ Turned on some music
To start my-- ♪♪
Hey! Lights!
Crystal Lake is dark.
I understand the system's failing.
What do you want me to do?
Let it all fail. Let it all fail. We'll pick up
the pieces later after it's fallen.
Let's do things my way, all right?
I got reports of vandalism on the line.
I got eight 90-megawatt lines
down all over.
- Crystal Lake is dark.
- Tolono is completely gone.
It doesn't matter. It's down. It's down!
What's the normal tension for that area?
If there's no wind? Normal tension
for the sag is 15,000 pounds per wire.
I was a journeyman in that area
a few years back.
Good, an expert.
- How would you like the job?
- You're kidding. Where's the seniority?
Well, it's not up to me.
Where's the supervisor?
Supervisor's stuck in an elevator, running
the show from one of the trouble phones.
But I'm in charge here right now,
and you're going to Crystal Lake.
- I am?
- I can't help it.
Everybody's everywhere.
Now, if you have any questions,
get on the horn to me direct.
Got a fresh impedance coming up.
It's not an overload. It's a drain.
Lines M-Mary-10 through M-Mary-15.
Municipal Lighting
is asking to be cut free.
Neary, you know where that is? And grab
a splicing tool and a high-wire act.
And, Neary, don't get creative
out there, just productive.
Remember, he's counting on you
and I'm depending on you.
You tell Municipal Lighting we're going to
candle power in 10 minutes!
Barry!
Help. I'm lost.
- Go, Ed.
- Responding to that 10-16....
Hold on. You're gonna
cough up a little Tolono, right?
Cough up a Tolono
or an interstate, a Highway 90.
A little familiar landmark of some sort.
Cornbread Road, south of 20.
Cornbread?
Power must have been restored
up there.
Couple hundred neighbors in their P.J.s
think it's Saturday night out here.
Dispatch, this is 411.
Do you want me to disregard
that Tolono call?
You're in the middle of the road, jackass!
Can you tell me where Cornbread is?
Turkey!
Eight thirty-four, 834.... F-27.
M-Mary-10 through M-Mary-12. Okay.
Ten-47.
Well, it's all meaningless so far.
Okay, come on.
All right. Four-way stop
leads you to the single-circuits...
...and leads you right to nowhere.
M-Mary-10.
Unit 211, 10-30, five, sev--
Oh, shit.
Ah! Ah!
Unit 211, I'm back on the street.
What do you guys got out there?
I don't believe this!
My God! It's bigger than a house!
This thing is like a barn.
This is absolutely crazy.
What is your location?
Just off Telemark Expressway
and east toward Harper Valley.
Barry.
No!
Watch out!
Oh, my God! Lady! Lady!
Are you okay? I'm sorry.
I didn't even see him. He was just
standing right in the middle of the road.
- Hello?
- Oh, my God.
Hello! Here!
What's the matter with you?
Barry, come back here! Come on, now.
Ice cream!
They can fly rings around the moon.
But we're years ahead of them
on the highway.
This is nuts.
No.
Wait a minute!
What are you guys doing? Hey!
That's Ohio! That's a quarter!
Jesus, look at that. Look at those
suckers. They're glued to the road!
Honey, wake up.
Honey, Ronnie, wake up.
You're not gonna believe what I saw.
- Ronnie.
- Don't! Not now.
No, no, no, listen, Ronnie!
I never would have believed it.
There was this, uh--
In the cab there was this whole--
It went-- It was--
There was a red whoosh that--
Roy, um, Ike called you.
- I gotta get something to wear here.
And, um, McGovern.
They want you to call them right away.
They said they couldn't reach you.
I turned the radio off.
Don't do that.
The phone's been ringing off the hook.
It woke Sylvia up two times already.
And I think you'd better call them.
You know those pictures in the National
Geographic about the aurora borealis?
This is better than that.
This is really-- Come on!
Come on, Ronnie, get up. Come on.
No, Roy, what's wrong?
I don't know if anything's wrong.
Get up. I'm not kidding.
Is it an accident?
It's not an accident. You wanted to
get out of the house anyway, right?
No, not at 4:00 in the morning.
Ronnie, I need you
to see something with me.
It's really important.
Okay. All right. What about the kids?
What? Oh, the kids! I'll get the kids.
Sylvia, come on,
we're going on a little adventure.
Toby! Brad! Come on! Get up.
Up, move, come on.
It's better than Goofy Golf! Come on!
- Go faster.
- I'm going as fast as I can!
Come on.
All right, all right. Oh, hi, Mrs. Harris.
Roy, there's Mrs. Harris.
There better be a good reason for doing
this, because it doesn't make any sense.
All right, Roy, I really think
you've proved your point.
Roy. Roy.
Roy, you're sunburned. Look at you.
Wow.
Honey, what is that?
Roy, what did it look like?
It was like an ice-cream cone.
What flavor?
Orange.
It was orange.
And it wasn't like an ice-cream cone.
It was more like a shell.
You know, it was like this:
Like a taco?
Was it like one of those Sara Lee, um,
moon-shaped, cookies?
Those crescent cookies?
Don't you think I'm taking this really well?
I remember when we used to come to
places like this just to look at each other.
Snuggle.
Is this the bathroom?
Shh!
Psst!
Hey, this is not your toy to play with
every time I turn around.
He looks like a 50/50 Bar.
All right, out of this house.
All of you. Out of my house.
I'm sorry, but you're not
to play with this ever!
Get out while I clean up your mess!
Thank you very much.
Roy, I found this overnight-tanning stuff.
I want you to spray it on half of your face,
so your face looks all even, one color.
It makes my face look yellow.
What does this remind you of, Ronnie?
Then we'll just tell everybody
that you fell asleep...
...under the sun lamp on your right side.
What for?
- Dad, can I ask you a question?
- What?
Are they for real?
That's what for. No, they are not for real.
Now, I want you to go outside
and have a hot dog, okay?
Ronnie, don't tell him that.
Roy, don't talk about this until you know
what you're talking about, okay?
Ronnie, that's crazy. If I can't talk about it,
how am I gonna know what's going on?
- What?
- Mom, I believe in them.
- I believe in them too.
- Oh, no, you don't.
Dad says we do.
No, he does not.
- Do you, Roy?
- Ronnie.
All I wanna do is know what's going on.
Nothing's going on!
It's just one of those things.
Which things? Which things?
- I don't wanna hear about this anymore.
- Ronnie, this is very important!
I'm not just gonna let it lay here.
I'm gonna call somebody about this!
I'm not listening. I'm not listening.
Ronnie, I saw something
last night that I can't explain.
I saw something last night
I can't explain.
I'm going out there again tonight,
you know.
- No, you're not.
- Yes, I am.
No, you're not.
Do they live on the moon?
They got bases on the moon.
At night they come through your window.
This isn't a moonburn,
you know, goddamn it!
You live on the moon. I saw it,
you came through my window last night.
You hurt me!
- You took all my covers.
- Roy's not like that.
- You did!
- He loves his work. Don't say that!
What did he do?
He was with us all night!
Ronnie, I won't have to go tonight.
He is not like that at all!
- I don't believe it. You did!
- Stop yelling at me!
- Shh, shh!
- Can't you tell him about this?
Hello?
I can't believe it.
Roy...
...you got fired.
They didn't even wanna talk to you.
I mean, I don't understand this, Roy.
Roy.
What is happening here?
We were up all night.
I'm not getting a job, you know?
I'm not getting a job.
That's not right.
Hello?
Hi.
Oh, hi, how are you? You came here too?
Yes. Jillian Guiler.
Roy Neary. I'm sorry about
what happened with the kid.
- Good night.
- What?
Look at you.
Oh....
- You got the same burn.
- Ha-ha.
Yeah, but it's better on you.
You got it all over at least.
I gotta tan the other side tonight.
How's the kid? I'm really sorry.
Uh-- I'll be right back.
Raise your head a bit and give me
a smile. Come on, son.
Hey, he's a little young for
a record, don't you think? Hm?
Weird.
I know this sounds crazy,
but ever since yesterday on the road....
I've been seeing this shape.
In shaving cream and pillows....
Damn it, I know this. I know what this is.
This means something.
This is important.
- Here they come!
- Get the camera!
- Out of the northwest!
- Jimmy, come here.
It's like Halloween for grownups.
Trick or treat.
Wait a minute.
I want to know...
...from what direction
did your people hear these sounds?
Where were the sounds coming from?
Where did these sounds come from?
Tell us, please.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
I beg your pardon,
but my English is not good too.
I want to share with you now...
...the breakthrough
that happened in India.
We think it means something.
We think it is important.
To help you learn, I am using
the hand sign created by Zoltán Kodály.
Kodály developed these signs
to teach music to deaf children.
And now....
Here are the patterns.
We just received
two 15-minute broadcasts.
Are these non-random signals?
A hundred and four rapid pulses.
After a five-second interval, 40 pulses.
Another five-second break,
and 30 pulses.
Sixty seconds of silence, and then
an entirely new set of numbers.
Forty, break five.
Thirty-six, break five. Ten.
- A hundred and four rapid pulses.
- Lord.
Wait 60 seconds
and the whole doggone thing repeats.
- Where are these signals coming from?
- Right in the neighborhood.
Light-travel time,
roughly seven seconds.
It's well within the plane of the ecliptic.
Are these non-random signals here,
40, 36, 10, in response to that?
No. They should be. We've been sending
out this musical combination for weeks.
But all we're getting back are numbers.
This could mean the India sounds
reached a dead end.
They don't mean a thing.
There's still so much that we don't know.
How about where the signals originate?
- Excuse me.
- Maybe they're letters.
What letter is 104?
Excuse me.
Before I got paid to, uh,
speak French....
I, uh....
I used to read maps.
This first number is a longitude.
I've got two sets of three numbers.
Degrees, minutes and seconds.
Now, the first number has three digits,
and the last two are below 60.
Obviously, it's not in the right ascension
and declination on the sky.
These have to be Earth coordinates.
There's a globe
in the county supervisor's office.
This is what we need.
Maybe there's a release pin
underneath here.
That's a $2500 globe!
What are you guys doing?
- It's heavy, watch your feet.
- Let me hit the mother.
No, no, clear it through.
All right, everybody, calm down!
Hold it down! Quiet!
That's not right.
The antenna. How dumb! Huh?
- Which way is the antenna pointing?
- Northeast.
That's Wyoming.
We're going to need a geodetic
survey map of Wyoming.
I want this down to the square yard.
Get me a geodetic survey map
of Wyoming.
We not only need....
Toys!
Come on, come on.
Oh, my God!
You can come and play now.
Come in through the door.
One, two, three....
Oh, honey.
Mom, look! The sun's here!
Oh, my God!
♪ The moment you come into view ♪
♪ Just because ♪
♪ My composure sort of slips ♪
♪ The moment
That your lips meet mine ♪♪
Go away!
Bang!
Clean everything up!
- Mom, let me listen.
- Wait a minute. Wait.
- Mom, look!
- Oh, my God.
Come in through the door.
Barry! Barry!
Jillian. Jillian.
May we have a statement?
The report you gave
to the police was really quite spectacular.
We need it for the 6:00 news.
- Jillian.
- Mrs. Guiler?
They got him.
What?
Is it true you're leaving
the state to look for your son?
Has there been a ransom note?
Where would you start looking?
His name is Barry.
Where is your husband now, Mrs. Guiler?
Are you involved
in any kind of parapsychologies?
Turn around, please. Turn around!
You gave the police a report.
Would you mind repeating it
for the television?
Folks, you can go in now. Room 3655.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is a flying saucer.
That's the one I saw.
I swear that's the same one.
It's the one I saw.
It's made of pewter, made in Japan...
...and thrown across the lawn
by one of my children.
I just wanted to point that out
to you to show...
...that we're not all "polished brass"
about these things.
And also point out that last year...
...Americans shot more
than 7 billion photographs...
...at a record of 6.6 billion dollars
for film equipment and processing.
Now, with all those shutters clicking...
...where is the indisputable
photographic evidence?
Major Benchley, I've been
in the news business for a long time...
...and our cameras have never been able
to take a picture...
...of a plane crash as it happened...
...or an automobile accident
and get it on the 6:00 news.
That's right. That's right.
Folks....
There are all kinds of ideas
that would be fun to believe in.
Mental telepathy...
...time travel...
...immortality...
...even Santa Claus.
I know it's no fun to go home and say,
"Guess what happened today.
I was in the shopping center,
there was this tremendously bright light...
...and I rushed outside...
...and it was an airplane."
Excuse me, sir. I didn't want to see this.
I sure wish I had.
You know,
for 15 years I've been looking...
...for these damn silly lights
in the night sky.
I've never found any.
I'd like to,
because I believe in life elsewhere.
Why don't you admit...
...that the Air Force is conducting
secret tests in the Foothills area?
It would be easy to say yes to that.
But I'm not going to mislead you.
This is not the case.
To tell you the truth,
I don't know what you saw.
You can't fool us by agreeing with us.
No, no, no. Hey, come on!
I saw Bigfoot once.
1951. Back in Sequoia National Park.
Had a foot on her, 37 inches. Heel to toe.
Wow.
Made a sound I would not want
to hear twice in my life.
I believe I've encountered
that gentleman myself.
I was sitting on the porch
one night, looking through the screen.
I seen this big white dot in the sky.
It turned red and blue and green.
Further it got away, it just kept pulsating
more and more and more.
UFOs do not represent
a direct physical threat to national security.
We do not support them,
and we encourage you not to.
Let's get in touch with
those Forest Service people...
...or we're gonna end up in
a wilderness area with vehicular traffic.
And that's strictly sacred-cow stuff
to those folks in Wyoming.
If this mission fully develops...
...I get white-knuckled just thinking about
what might be ahead for those folks.
Your flight will be at 2000 hours.
We have a limo that'll take you
to the heliport now.
And, of course, the transportation
will be provided on the other end.
- Look. I still like the flash-flood idea.
- Where are you gonna get the water?
We've had about two inches of rain--
We can survey dams and reservoirs,
tell them one's gonna burst.
And besides that, there's not
enough water in those reservoirs!
Wait! Contaminated water
affects people, crops, animals.
Disease.
- Yeah, epidemic.
- What kind of disease?
Plague. A plague epidemic.
Nobody's gonna believe a plague
in this day and age.
- Anthrax.
- Ranching country.
- Yes.
- There are a lot of sheep in the hills.
That's good. That's good, I like that.
- It'll create a panic.
- But it may not evacuate everybody.
There's always some joker
who thinks he's immune.
What I need is something so scary
it'll clear 300 square miles...
...of every living Christian soul.
- Toby!
- I'm gonna hit you across the street...
- ...tomorrow night!
- Ride your bike--
- You are not!
- Boys.
Toby. Did you finish
your science project?
Aah.
Toby.
- I don't want any potatoes.
- Yeah, just a little bit.
Help yourself.
I hate these potatoes.
There's a dead fly in my potatoes.
It's okay.
Well, I guess you've noticed...
...something is a little strange with Dad.
It's okay, though.
I'm still Dad.
I can't describe it, what I'm feeling...
...and what I'm thinking.
This means something.
This is important.
That's not right.
It's not right.
That's not right!
What is it?
What is it?!
It's not fair.
Tell me.
Well, what do
you know? It's disintegrated.
Happy birthday,
you thing from another world, you.
Oh, thank you!
Well, I guess he's had enough.
Ha, ha!
Are you going to yell at me?
Ronnie? Everything's fine.
All this stuff is coming down.
It's all gonna be like it was.
That's the last straw!
Now I use my secret weapon!
Ooh! Ow.
Roy?
Roy, I'm sorry about last night. Roy!
Roy. Roy, what are you doing?
Jesus.
Roy. Roy.
The plants are fine there!
Roy, can you hear me?
Wait!
What are you--? What are you doing?
You're gonna love it, Ronnie!
- What do you mean?
- You'll really love this.
Roy, what are you doing?
Oh. My--
Oh, Roy!
Aah! My God!
Come on, men!
Dad, after this,
can we throw dirt in my window?
Stop it.
Stop. Stop it.
Ronnie...
...if I don't do this,
that's when I'm gonna need a doctor.
What are you doing?
- I got it.
- What are you doing?
I figured it out, that's all.
- Will you just listen?
- No.
Ronnie, look, you ever look
at something when it's crazy...
...and then you look at it in another way
and it's not crazy?
No, I haven't. No.
Come on, Ronnie. Just listen.
- I don't know what you're doing.
- Just close your eyes.
Close your eyes and hold your breath,
everything will be really pretty.
Roy, you're scaring us now.
Don't be scared.
Just don't be scared. I feel really good.
Everything's gonna be all right.
I haven't felt this good in years.
Everything's gonna be okay. I can feel it.
- Now what else? What else?
- Like this? Like this?
Right.
Like this?
Chicken wire.
Whatever you're doing,
it's against the law!
He's putting it back, Mrs. Harris.
I'll pay you for this.
Take it. Take it.
I'm perfectly fine.
You let go of this fence right now.
You come with me.
Do you want me to hit you?
You let go of that fence!
Toby! Listen to me. Listen to me.
Please. Come on, right now.
We're going.
- I want to stay here!
- Let go of the fence! Come on.
Stay! Stay.
- Where are we going?
- Just get in the car.
- Quietly, quickly, get in.
Get in there, Toby.
Quickly.
- Dad needs some more help!
- Lock the doors! Lock the doors!
Dad needs some more help!
Quiet! Just lock the doors.
Roll up those windows.
Yes, he does!
Dad needs some more help!
Honey, where you going?
- What?
- Where are you going?
Taking the kids to my sister's.
That's crazy. You're not even dressed.
What?
You said what?
Ronnie, wait!
Ronnie, hold it.
Would you hold--?
Would you hold it one minute?
Morning.
What is wrong with me today?
Who is it, please?
It's the mailman.
There's a package for Julie Anderson.
You can just leave it at the door!
Ha-ha-ha. I can't do that. I'm
supposed to C.O.D. Mm-hm, like that.
And besides...
...you and I have to have a little talk...
...about Kim.
Like sands through the hourglass...
...so are the Days of Our Lives.
♪ Here comes the king ♪
♪ Budweiser beer
The king is second to none ♪
♪ When you say Bud ♪
♪ The king is coming ♪
♪ Let's hear the call ♪
♪ When you say Bud, you get it all
When you say Bud, you get it all ♪
♪ Here comes the king ♪♪
Good evening. At the top of the news
tonight, a rail disaster.
At Devils Tower, Wyoming...
...a train loaded with a dangerous
chemical gas went off the rails...
...and has forced
the widest area evacuation...
...in the history of these controversial
Army rail shipments.
Whenever you want me to.
Tomorrow is fine.
I can do other things.
I'm trying to be.
Yes, I am.
The Army and National
Guard are supervising the evacuation.
I am an adult, okay?
Even though there's no such thing.
It was a joke!
--the danger will be over
within 72 hours.
Ronnie, anything you want.
Anything you want, I'll do.
For how long?
All of you?
No. Ronnie,
I wanna talk about this in person.
This is not-- We can't talk about this
on the telephone. All ri--
Ronnie! Don't hang up! Just don't--
--meat should remain unaffected.
This means
order your steak well-done, Walter.
Devils Tower, Wyoming
was the first national monument...
...erected in this country
by Theodore Roosevelt in 1915.
Thousands of
civilian refugees are fleeing the area...
...spurred on by rumors that the seven
tanker cars that overturned...
...at Walkashi Needles Junction were
filled to capacity with GM nerve gas.
In just a few minutes,
we're going to be--
--boasts 400,000 vacationers.
And fortunately, during this mishap
there have been no fatalities.
--forced to evacuate
this area, which in a few minutes...
... will become known as the "hot zone, "
depending on the prevailing winds.
But as it is, this is as close to the disaster
as we've been allowed to get.
--due to a strong
prevailing north-south wind.
Army chemical engineers
and the Wyoming National Guard...
...are making every effort to both
contain the leaking toxins...
...and evacuate an area
of almost 200 square miles.
Everyone is being warned:
Stay out of the area.
Everyone, please, stay out of the area.
--and thousands of others are homeless.
U.S. Army Materiel Command
has issued these new area restrictions:
All roadways north of Crowheart
on Interstate 25.
Shit.
All roads leading into the Grand Tetons
west of Meeteeste.
All multilane
undivided full-traffic interchange...
...railroad, local and historic stage roads
south of Cody.
Why aren't there any fat lines
instead of these thin ones?
Yo!
- Holy mother of--
- You're going the wrong way!
Yo! Turn back around. Back this way.
Hey, what's the matter with you?
Yes, sir. Sorry, officer.
It's just a rental, officer. Just a rental.
My fault! My fault!
Starting with the letter "F," as in "Frank"...
...to the letter "J," as in "Jack"...
...please find your way to the loading
platform for immediate boarding.
Step right up. All right, folks,
I don't want to alarm you...
...but this nerve gas
is odorless and colorless.
The first symptom that you're gonna see
is gonna be a dilation of your eyeball.
So now I'm gonna tell you,
these canary birds are guaranteed...
...to fall off of their perch one hour before
the gas does anything to you.
--last names starting
with the letter "K" to "P"' as in "Peter."
All aboard, please.
You got next-of-kin
in the red zone, buddy?
Uh-huh. My sister.
- What's her name?
- Well, that's okay.
She's probably out of there
by now already.
We got everybody out of here
before noon yesterday.
Tell me her name and I'll tell you
where she's relocated.
That's okay, I can find her myself.
Man, there's more than
20 evacuation stations across the state.
What's your name?
- Smith.
We got orders to shoot anybody
looting around here.
Pass it on, huh?
Roy!
I'm gonna let you buy
two gas masks for the price of one.
- Roy!
- Two birds for the price of one...
...and I hope to see you again!
The train has time to clear the area.
There's no immediate danger
and no need to hurry or push.
Please help each other
by not rushing.
Roy!
I don't care where you go,
just get behind the barricades!
There's no way out!
- What are we doing?
- Look, the only way we're gonna...
...get back in there is to go cross-country.
We gotta break through the fence.
- Then let's go.
- All right, hold on. Hold on.
Watch out!
The police dragged the river for him.
I told them he wasn't in the river.
He wasn't in the river.
Then they went around to every house
within five miles...
...looking inside back-yard refrigerators.
They asked me if I'd seen any strangers
in the neighborhood.
I don't believe it's real.
It's real.
Let's get down there.
Get some gas and get down in there.
What are those?
Look, I guarantee you.
This whole thing is a put-on.
Oh, damn it!
Ma'am, would you please step away....
- This is for your own safety.
- Okay.
All right, one at a time. What do
you want? Get your hands off me!
- How are you feeling?
- I feel fine!
According to my birds, the only bad air
around here is you guys farting around!
- Move them out!
- What's happening?
- Wait. Where are we going?
- All right, go to the van.
Where are you taking her?
Hold it! Why can't we go together?
Watch your step.
Roy.
We have very little time, Mr. Neary.
This is Mr. Lacombe.
- Hello.
- We need answers from you...
...that are honest,
direct and to the point.
Where is Jillian?
Do you realize the danger
that you and your friend have risked?
In coming here,
you've exposed yourself to toxic gas.
Well, I'm alive. We're talk--
We're talking.
This is true, Mr. Neary.
But if the prevailing winds were blowing
from the south instead of the north...
...this conversation would
not be taking place.
There's nothing wrong with the air.
What makes you say that?
I just know.
There's nothing wrong with it.
Go outside and make me a liar.
Uh, look, I wanna talk to
the man in charge.
Mr. Lacombe is the highest authority.
He isn't even an American.
Mr. Neary,
are you an artist or a painter?
No.
Have you been hearing
a persistent ringing in your ears?
Almost an agreeable ringing?
No.
Having headaches, migraines?
Yeah.
An irritation in your eyes
and your sinuses?
Yeah.
Do you have hives?
Do you have allergies?
And burning on your face
and on your body?
- Yes. Who are you people?
- Look at this.
Yeah, I got one just like it
in my living room. Who are you people?
Monsieur Neary, please,
one more question.
Have you recently had
a close encounter?
A close encounter with
something very unusual?
Who are you people?
These people strangers to you?
Yeah. Except for her.
And the two of you
felt compelled to be here?
Yeah, you might say that.
But what did you expect to find?
An answer.
That's not crazy, is it?
Ho, ho, ho.
Hold it, hold it, hold it.
Is that it?
Is that all you're gonna ask me?
Well, I got a couple of thousand
goddamn questions, you know?
I wanna speak to someone in charge.
I wanna lodge a complaint.
You have no right
to make people crazy.
You think I investigate every
Walter Cronkite story there is? Huh?
If this is just nerve gas, how come
I know everything in such detail?
I've never been here before.
How come I know so much?
What the hell is going on
around here?!
Who the hell are you people?!
Is that it?! Answer me!
I didn't come this far
to get taken on any bus ride home!
Five minutes. Five!
We're gonna hold
for a couple of minutes.
You brought in 12 people
to the decontamination camp...
...instead of the evacuation center
where they belong. I'd like to know why.
- Because this means something.
These people have come
from all over their country...
...to a place they have been told
will endanger their lives.
- Why?
Well, because somebody could be trying
to subvert this whole operation...
...by sending in fanatics and cultists
and Christ knows what all.
- Robert.
- Yes.
Thank you very much.
This is a small group of people...
...who have shared a vision in common.
Look.
It's still a mystery to me
why they are here.
Even they do not know why.
Jillian!
- Jillian.
- Don't! You'll be poisoned!
Listen, there's nothing wrong
with the air around here.
The Army's getting us out of here
because they don't want any witnesses.
But if the Army doesn't want us here,
then it's none of our business.
We only wanted to see the mountain.
It was such a coincidence I painted it.
You can take it off!
The air here is better
than it is in Los Angeles. Ha, ha!
Listen, listen. How many of you people
are for getting out of here?
I don't know what's happening
either. And I must find out what's going on.
For every one of these anxious people
who have come here this evening...
...there must be hundreds also touched
by the vision who never made it this far.
Simply because they
never watch the television.
Or perhaps they watched it,
but never made the psychic connection.
It's a coincidence. It's not scientific.
Listen to me, Major Walsh...
...it is an event sociological.
Go for the mountain!
Careful, everybody. Don't hurt yourself.
Hey! Wait a minute!
- My name's Neary!
- Larry Butler!
- How are you doing?
- I'm doing okay! How are you?
- Fine, fine!
- That's good!
Everybody keep their masks on...
...until you're out of here
and out of danger.
Listen, we wanna get out of here!
What's the matter with you?
Major Walsh, Major Walsh.
Yes, sir. I'll have the rest of them
off the mountain in one hour.
Major, I want you to use infrared...
...and get me a photo analysis
of the northern face.
Yes, sir, it's already been ordered.
Major Walsh, listen.
I don't like to do this. We're in enough
trouble with these cattlemen already.
If you can't get them off the mountain
and out of the area by 2000 hours...
...start dusting with EZ-4.
What's EZ-4?
It's a sleep aerosol. Same stuff
that we used with the livestock.
Comes out of Riot Control.
They'll sleep for six hours and wake up
with a hell of a headache, that's all.
We didn't choose this place.
We didn't choose these people!
They were invited!
They belong here more than we.
I should have never given up jogging.
See that notch
in the corner of the mountain?
We can make that one in no time.
Here come three more.
The authority in this park...
...has been superseded by
the United States government.
There's a ravine leading straight up.
I remember it from my painting.
It's an easier climb. It faces northeast.
It's no good. At the top, there's a 300-foot
drop straight down. Get down!
What do you think
is down on the other side?
There's a box canyon on the other side
with ravines and trails...
...if you take this gradual incline
to the right.
I never imagined that.
In my painting, I only painted one side.
There was no canyon
in the doodles I made.
Next time, try sculpturing.
You've given us a hell of a lot of credit.
That's a good hour's climb.
Come on, let's go.
The authority in this park...
...has been superseded by
the United States government.
You are entering
a military reservation...
...and subject to military law.
Call the bastard.
Bahama, this is Pyramid. Over.
Go ahead.
Nothing to report at midstation.
Up ahead
there's thousands of places to hide.
We're gonna need at least three times
the men to cover this in one hour.
Get everybody off the northern face,
then call the dark side of the moon...
...and tell them we're gonna dust.
Get down!
You are entering a military reservation...
...and subject to military law.
Larry! Larry, come on!
Larry! Don't let them see you!
Get down!
They're just crop-dusting. Los Angeles!
- Larry?
- Don't stop!
Don't look back! Come on, come on!
Oh! Roy!
Hurry! We're only 10 feet from the top.
Just a few more feet!
We can slide down the other side!
Come on, hurry. I'll come down.
Don't come down.
Come on, come on. Come on!
- Don't worry. We're gonna make it.
- Roy.
Come on. Come on.
Move it. Move your ass!
Come on.
Roy, come on.
Come on. Please, come on.
Hurry!
Hold it!
Jump! Jump!
- Do you see that?
- Oh, yes.
Good.
Is it on?
Check the speaker system here.
I want this up all the way.
Is this one live?
Are you reading me on this one?
How about here?
- Testing. Testing.
- Okay, one, two, three, four.
Testing. Testing.
One, two, three, testing.
Gentlemen, ladies.
Take your positions, please.
This is not a drill.
I repeat, this is not a drill.
Could we have the lights in
the arena down 60 percent, please?
Sixty percent.
I don't think we could ask for
a more beautiful evening, do you?
Okay, watch the skies, please.
We now show uncorrelated targets
approaching from the north-northwest.
We're the only ones
who know. The only ones.
You see that?
Yes.
Good.
All ground personnel
not D-class approved...
...please evacuate
the center approach marker.
Audio analysis personnel,
behind the double yellow line.
ITC, stereo, time and resistance.
Auto ready?
- Tone interpolation on interlock.
- Altitude and tabling now.
ARP and interlock now.
Speed set at seven and a half.
All positive functions, standing by.
Special ARP teams
tagged C, "Captain," F, "Frank"...
...to the speaking platform.
- Six-two.
- Go ahead.
- Sunset.
- Go.
Okay. Start with the tone.
- Tang.
- Go.
Up a full tone.
Down a major third.
Now drop an octave.
- Cool blue.
- Go.
Up a perfect fifth.
Nothing. Nothing at all.
Give me a tone.
- "Re" to the second.
- Up a full tone.
- "Mi" to the third.
- Down a major third.
- "Do" to the first.
- Drop an octave.
- "Do" one-half.
- Up a perfect fifth.
"Sol" to the fifth.
I know that.
Faster.
Kick that mule!
Let's go!
I'm very happy tonight.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Not a Merle Haggard, but it was great.
Mr. Lacombe?
What is it? What's happening?
Come on. Come on, let's go.
Keep down.
They're talking way over my head.
- Shit.
- Duck, duck!
Photo one.
Fantastic! Keep those reloads coming.
Fantastic!
- You wanna see better?
- I can see fine.
- We can't stay here.
- I can.
- Why?
- Because Barry's not here.
I'm just not ready.
I can't-- I can't stay here.
I've gotta get down there.
I know.
This is data control to all personnel.
We monitor no biologic hazards.
Range safety clear.
Oh, my God.
Holy shit.
There is a safety-hazard zone...
...extending 25 meters from the ship.
Special teams are exempt
and should be aware of low gravity.
Expect some dizziness,
and look out for a static charge.
All departments at operational
during this phase...
...signify by beeping twice.
If everything's ready here
on the dark side of the moon...
...play the five tones.
Give her six quavers, then pause.
She sent us four quavers...
...a group of five quavers,
a group of four semiquavers.
The only thing these phrases
have in common are five signals.
I hope somebody's taking all this down.
What are we saying to each other?
It seems they're trying to teach us
a basic tonal vocabulary.
It's the first day of school, fellas.
Take everything from the lady.
Follow her pattern note for note.
We have a translation interlock
on their audio signal.
We're taking over
this conversation now.
Let's go! Come on!
I am Claude Lacombe.
Frank Taylor...
...Lieutenant J.G.,
United States Navy Reserve...
...064199.
Lieutenant, welcome home.
This way to debriefing.
Harry Ward Craig...
...Captain, United States Navy...
...043431.
Captain, would you come
right this way?
Welcome back, Navy. Welcome back.
- Craig, Harry Ward.
- "Captain, United States Navy...
...0434311."
Disappeared off Chicken Shoals,
flight 19.
Matthew McMichael, Lieutenant,
United States Naval Reserve...
- ...0909411.
- Lieutenant.
Good to have you back.
Furlow, Otis B...
...Lieutenant J.G., United States Navy.
They haven't even aged.
Einstein was right.
Einstein was probably one of them.
Erickson, David A...
...Lieutenant J.G.,
United States Navy...
...0639552.
Henkle, Robert F...
...Lieutenant J.G.,
United States Navy....
Reported missing July 1955,
Pensacola, Florida.
Monsieur Neary...
...what do you want?
I just wanna know
that it's really happening.
I went up in the air,
and I saw our house.
I saw you going up in the air.
Did you see me running after you?
- Yes.
- Yes?
All right, now we have to talk.
He wants to speak about
Mr. Neary's case.
Swensen, Matthew Daniel...
...reported missing April 1976.
- Are they going away?
- Yes.
Wait a second, wait.
He says these are ordinary people
under extraordinary circumstances.
Delores, Rudolph E...
...reported missing
December '51, Bisbee...
...Arizona.
Goodbye.
Monsieur Neary...
...I envy you.
Mr. Neary, I'm told that we can count on
your complete cooperation.
- What type of blood do you have?
- I don't have the slightest idea.
- What is your date of birth?
- December 4th, 1944.
Have you been inoculated
against smallpox, diphtheria?
Is there any history of liver disease
in your family?
May the Lord be praised at all times.
May God help us
and grant us a happy journey.
Show us your ways.
And lead us along your paths.
God has given you his angels
charge over you.
Grant these pilgrims,
we pray, a happy journey...
...and peaceful days, so that with
your holy angel as a guide...
...they may safely
reach their destination....
Goodbye!