Welcome to New Tokyo
International Airport. Welcome.
- Welcome to Tokyo.
- Thank you very much.
My name is Kawasaki. Nice to meet you.
I've heard of you. Thank you.
For you.
Thank you.
- And Mr. Mori from Suntory.
- Hi.
And Miss Shibata.
Hey, I need that.
And Mr. Awinami.
Nice to meet you.
All right.
Thank you.
And Mr. Tanaka.
And we will pick you up
in the morning?
Okay.
See you tomorrow.
Great. Short and sweet.
Very Japanese. I like that.
- My pleasure.
- Yeah, get some sleep, will ya?
We're all... You're all really tired,
I'm sure. See you tomorrow.
Good night. Thank you.
Thank you...
What's this?
Something good?
Thank you.
Mr. Harris, welcome to Park Hyatt Tokyo.
Yeah.
This way, please.
Mr. Harris,
pleased to welcome.
Thank you.
Have a nice stay with us.
This way.
Mr. Harris,
welcome to Park Hyatt Tokyo.
Thank you.
Enjoy your stay with us.
Thank you very much.
I'm in your arms
And you are kissing me
But there seems to be
Finish this drink, then
we'll go to a jazz club. Yeah.
You see that guy?
Yeah.
You know who that is?
It's not him.
It looks like him,
but it's not him.
Can you believe it?
Okay, maybe it is.
He's here with us. I'm gonna go talk to him.
Shut up. Shut up.
Bob? Bob Harris?
You're awesome, man!
Sunset Odds.
Loved it.
Man, that car chase...
I couldn't believe it.
Four buses... And he took that thing
and everything exploded.
I heard he did his own driving.
Did you do your own driving?
I did.
Cool.
So, what are you doing here?
Yeah.
Um, seeing friends.
Seeing friends.
Yeah? Great.
We're here on business.
I can see it in your eyes
Later.
See you, Bob.
Keep it up.
Are you awake?
John.
Go to sleep.
Aah.
Moshi moshi.
All ri...
Yeah, I'm coming down.
Okay.
I gotta go to work.
I love you. I'll see you later.
Okay. Bye.
Mr. Bob-san.
Suntory whiskey.
Casablanca. Bogie.
Suntory time.
Um, he want you to turn,
look in camera.
Okay?
That's all he said?
Yes.
Turn to camera.
All right, does he want me
to... to... turn from the right,
or... turn from the left?
Passionate. Camera. Passion.
Right side,
and, uh, with intensity.
Okay?
Is that everything? I mean, it seemed
like he said quite a bit more than that.
Whiskey.
Gently.
Tension.
Like an old friend,
and into the camera.
Okay.
Whiskey.
It's Suntory time! Okay?
- Okay.
- Okay?
- Hey, come on!
Come on, come on, come on.
For relaxing times,
make it Suntory time.
Cut-o!
Cut-o, cut-o, cut-o, cut-o, cut-o!
Uh, could you do it slower...
and with more... intensity?
Suntory time.
For relaxing times,
make it Suntory time.
Cut-o, cut-o, cut-o, cut-o!
Hello?
Lauren?
Charlotte! Hey!
Hey.
Oh, my God. How's Tokyo?
It's great here.
It's really great.
Um, I don't know...
I went to this shrine today.
And, um,
there were these monks
and they were chanting.
And I didn't feel anything.
You know?
And, um, I don't know...
I even tried ikebana,
and John is using these hair products.
I just... I don't know who I married.
Look, can you wait a second?
Just hold on. I'll be right back.
Okay, sure.
Sorry.
What were you saying?
Nothing. It's okay.
I'll call you later. Okay?
Okay. Have the best time.
Just call me when you get back.
Bye.
Love you. bBye.
God!
At the fitting today,
they had all these...
rock and roll clothes,
but the band
wasn't tough at all.
The label guy just kept saying,
"More lock and loll,"
but it's just so much better if they're just
skinny and nerdy like they came in, you know.
They're making them wear all these
Keith Richards clothes, and it's just ridiculous.
They should let them be who they are.
Don't you think?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's exactly
what I was saying.
But then you try to...
I mean, you know...
That's what I think.
Do you think this is done?
I don't know. I don't know.
Would you... Would you
please stop smoking?
I like to.
I don't really smoke that much.
It's just so bad for you,
though.
Well, I'll stop later.
Welcome back, Mr. Harris.
Yes, Mr. Harris.
Please. Thank you.
Mr. Harris?
Yes?
Mr. Kazu sent me.
Oh?
May I enter?
Thank you.
Do you like massage?
I don't think
I... I like massage anymore.
Mr. Kazu sends
premium fantasy.
My stockings... "lip" them.
"Lip" my stockings.
Yes, please.
"Lip" them.
What?
Hey! "Lip" my stocking!
Hey! "Lip" them?
"Lip" them? What?
"Lip" them. Like this.
"Lip" them.
Rip them?
"Lip," yes.
You want me
to rip your stockings?
Yes, "lip" my stockings, please.
Rip your stockings. You want me to rip
your stockings. Yes. Please? Please? Please?
All right, I'm gonna rip your stockings,
and you tell Mr. Kazu we had a blast.
Oh, no! Mr. Harris!
Oh, my God!
Don't touch me!
Mr. Bob Harris,
don't touch me!
Just "lip" my stocking!
Oh, no, Mr. Harris!
Oh, no! Help! Help!
Yeah... Yeah.
Help, please! Help, please!
Okay.
Mr. Harris, help, please.
Careful with those.
Oh! Help, please! Help, please!
Come on. Come on.
Let me go, Mr. Harris!
Oh, no! Let me go!
Come on. Come on.
Ohh! Let me go! Let me go.
Oh, crap.
Please let me go.
With pleasure.
Oh, no, Mr. Bob Harris,
don't let me go! No!
No! Oh, no,
Mr. Bob Harris!
Ohh! Oh, please.
Let me go, please!
Mr. Harris! Good morning.
Hi.
We just got a request from Tanabe Mori.
He is the Johnny Carson of Japan.
It is a big honor
to be invited to his show.
Can you stay here
until Friday?
Uh, I'm surprised and honored, but I think
I need to check with my agent.
Okay, I believe I may have
a previous commitment.
Sure.
I understand.
Shall we go?
Yes.
I think you should do it.
No, hear this, Fred.
I gotta be on a plane
Thursday night.
We're looking into it, Bob.
They really want you to stay
and do that talk show.
Apparently,
he's a really big deal...
Johnny Carson of Japan.
Yeah.
Bob, these people
are paying you a lot.
Would you please consider it?
I already have.
I-I gotta get out of here.
As soon as I can.
All right, you're scheduled to leave Friday,
but we'll hold it for you Saturday.
You're breaking up, Fred.
There's no reception in this studio.
Forget it.
Call me back.
So, can you put your hand
close your face, please?
I'm sorry, Naka. What?
Can you put your hand
close your face?
I don't get that close to the glass
until I'm on the floor.
How's this?
Yes.
You want a whiskey?
This is not whiskey. This is iced tea.
If you gave me real whiskey...
I need mysterious face.
Can you show mysterious?
Mysterious.
I think I know what you want.
You want this, right?
I need more mysterious and, uh...
More mysterious. Yeah. I'll just try to think,
"Where the hell's the whiskey?"
You are a movie star, yes?
Yes, I should be doing movies, yes, but...
And "Lat Pack. "
"Lat Pack. "
You know "Lat Pack"?
Rat P... Rat Pack?
Rat Pack. Yes, please.
Oh, right, right.
I need more tension, please.
More t...
You so gentleman, yes?
A-ring-a-ding-ding.
Yeah.
"Sinatora. "
You know "Sinatora"?
Old Blue Eyes.
Yeah.
That's good.
That's more of Dino. That's Dino.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Great.
Joey Bishop would you like?
Yes. Just change film.
Are you drinking?
No?
Am I drinking?
As soon as I'm done.
Okay, close your hand,
please.
Close your hand.
Yeah... Close it?
Yes.
Close your face, please.
Close my...
Yes. Sorry.
And, uh, 007?
He drinks martinis, but okay, I got it.
007, yeah.
"Loger" Moore?
"Loger"Moore?
"Loger" Moore.
You know "Loger" Moore?
Roger Moore?
Yeah.
Okay. I... I...
- I always think of Sean Connery. Seriously.
- No, no.
Didn't you get the Sean Connery one over here?
No. "Loger" Moore.
Yes.
"Loger" Moore?
No...
Yeah. Okay.
Yeah, okay. Good.
More. Please.
You mean "more," or "Roger Moore"again?
Yeah. Yeah.
Good.
And sexy!
Are you going
To Scarborough Fair
Parsley, sage
Rosemary
And thyme
He's really sad.
Thank you.
We're glad to be here.
We're Sausalito.
They're beautiful. They're beautiful, yeah.
You know?
Send these over
to that table over there.
Old temple?
An old temple?
Yeah.
Oh, beautiful, man.
Excuse me, sir.
From the woman over there.
Oh! Oh, th-they are?
Really?
Yeah, yeah.
Wh-What's... What's...
Is Japan...
Is it mainly Buddhism here?
Yeah, it's Buddhism.
CD or...
Yeah, CD.
Playing her...
Oh, she plays... guitar?
Guitar. Guitar.
That's a beautiful job.
Help!
Good morning.
Are you okay?
Yeah. Fine.
Car is outside.
Shall we go?
That's what I told him.
He never listens.
Yeah.
John?
Oh, my God! John!
What are you doing here?
Uh, oh, w-well, you know, uh, w...
I'm just here, uh, shooting a band.
What about you?
I'm here promoting that action movie I did.
Hyah! You know!
I'm doing 20 million interviews a day.
It's crazy.
God, it is so good to see you!
Yeah. Yeah.
So, how long are you gonna be here?
We're here for a week.
I'm gonna go shoot
in Fukawaka.
Oh, it's amazing!
Yeah. Oh. Oh, yeah.
It's amazing.
You know... Oh, this is...
this is my wife, Charlotte.
Hi! It's really nice to meet you!
Hi. Nice to meet you.
Hello!
Yeah!
Wife?
Yeah. Yeah.
John. John.
You are
my favorite photographer.
Oh, come on!
No, you are. I only want you to shoot me.
It's true!
I have the worst B.O. Right now.
I'm so sorry.
No, no, no.
But, listen, um...
- Let's all go out for a drink sometime.
- Yeah.
You know? Call me. Okay?
Yeah. Okay.
Listen,
I'm under Evelyn Waugh.
Shh. Okay?
Okay. Yeah.
Okay, arigato, arigato.
Moshi moshi!
Evelyn Waugh?
What?
Evelyn Waugh was a man.
Oh, come on.
She's nice.
What? You know...
You know, not everybody went to Yale.
It was just a pseudonym,
for Christ's sake.
Why do you
have to defend her?
Well, why do you have to point out
how stupid everybody is all the time?
I thought it was funny.
Forget it.
Well...
Hey, John, we gotta go.
Oh. Yeah.
Bye.
Did you ever wonder
what your purpose in life is?
This book is about finding
your soul's purpose or destiny.
Every soul has its path,
but sometimes that path is not clear.
The Inner Map Theory is an example
of how each soul begins with an imprint,
all compacted into a pattern
that has been selected by your soul...
before you've even gotten here.
You know, I guess the reason
why I like Japan the best...
out of all Asian countries...
is because I really feel
close to, um, Buddhism.
I really feel...
I really believe in reincarnation.
That's part of what drew me
to Midnight Velocity as well,
because although Keanu dies,
he eventually
gets reincarnated.
So there's hope...
There's hope in reincarnation, I think.
What was it like working
with Keanu Reeves?
He was always so...
He was always, you know, giving me ideas...
and, you know, really helpful.
He made me feel
really comfortable, so...
And we both have two dogs,
and we both live in L.A.,
so we have all these
different things in common.
So, you know, we both
really like Mexican food...
and yoga and...
karate!
Mexican food. Yoga.
Konnichi wa.
Hello. Hi.
okay.
Okay.
Hai. Okay. Hai. Hai.
He got married
a couple of times...
To some nice women.
Beautiful women too. I mean, you and I
would be crazy for these women.
But there were
always rumors.
I never liked his acting,
so I never gave a damn
whether he was straight or not.
Thank you... Hi.
Thanks.
What can I get you?
Um, I'm not sure.
For relaxing times,
make it...
Suntory time.
Um, I'll have a vodka tonic.
Thanks.
So, what are you
doing here?
Uh, a couple of things.
Taking a break from my wife,
forgetting my son's birthday,
and, uh, getting paid
$2 million...
to endorse a whiskey...
when I could be doing
a play somewhere.
Oh.
But the good news is,
the whiskey works.
What are you doing?
Um, my husband's
a photographer,
so he's here working and, uh,
I wasn't doing anything,
so I came along.
And we have some friends that live here.
How long have you been married?
Oh, thank you.
Two years.
Twenty-five long ones.
You're probably just
having a midlife crisis.
Did you buy a Porsche yet?
You know, I was thinking
about buying a Porsche.
Twenty-five years.
That's a...
Well, it's impressive.
Well, you figure you sleep
one-third of your life.
That knocks off eight years
of marriage right there.
So you're down
to 16 and change.
You're just a teenager
at marriage.
You can drive it, but there's
still the occasional accident.
Yeah.
What do you do?
I'm not sure yet,
actually.
I just graduated
last spring.
What did you study?
Philosophy.
Yeah, there's a good buck in that racket.
Yeah.
Well, so far
it's pro bono.
Well, I'm sure you'll figure out the angles.
Yeah.
I hope your Porsche works out.
Cheers to that, huh?
Cheers to that.
Kanpai.
Wish I could sleep.
Me too.
One, two, three,
and okay.
All right.
One, two, three, four.
And one, two, three, four.
And one, two...
Wait! Take me with you!
How'd it go, huh?
Oh, it was good, you know.
I'm tired.
Yeah, I-I-I gotta go downstairs
and meet Kelly for some drinks.
She wants to talk about some photo thing.
Maybe I'll go downstairs with you.
Oh, you wanna come?
Yeah, sure.
Okay. Yeah.
You
Stepped out
of a dream
Everybody is always, like,
"Kelly, you are anorexic. "
And I'm, like, "No, I'm not. "I eat
so much junk food, you wouldn't believe it.
Just because I have
a high metabolism.
Because I thought
you were anorexic too.
Everybody does. Everybody thinks that.
Yeah, 'cause you look so...
Thank you!
I know, but it's...
I mean, I eat whatever.
I have a really high metabolism.
Yeah.
But, um...
My dad
was an anorexic.
Really?
Oh, really?
Yeah.
He, um, fought on the American side
of the Bay of Pigs in Cuba.
He was taken prisoner, and the whole time
he was there they tortured him about food.
Every day they told him
they put poison in the food.
So they would always make themselves
throw up after every meal.
That's horrible.
That's terrible.
That's some crazy shit.
You don't think he sounds kinda goofy?
No!
You know that break beat, right?
Well, I been takin' it to some next level shit.
Like, I'll take that and put
a delay on it, so it's like...
So it's, like, evolving,
the beat.
So it, like, sounds hella large
on the track. You know what I'm sayin'?
No.
No?
You don't listen to hip-hop?
Oh, my God!
You guys gotta listen.
I tried this power cleanse.
It's so amazing.
Okay, promise me you'll try it.
Will you try this power cleanse?
I did it last week, and it's amazing.
I'll be right back.
It's so good to get
the toxins out of your body.
With all, like, the pollution,
all, like, the...
Hello.
You ever switch seats?
Uh, I like this one.
If I fall, someone will notice.
Yeah.
So, you having a nice time?
Can you keep a secret?
I'm trying to organize
a prison break.
I'm looking for, like,
an accomplice.
We'd have to, first,
get out of this bar.
Then the hotel, then the city,
and then the country.
Are you in, or are you out?
I'm in.
Good.
I'll go pack my stuff.
Get your coat.
See ya.
I hope you've had enough to drink.
It's gonna take courage.
Oh, look.
The label got me these.
Mmm, I love Cristal.
You wanna have some?
Well, I'm...
I gotta go. I mean, I...
Y-You know,
you don't have to stay.
I mean...
You don't have to go, do you?
Well, I...
I know. You're gonna be
working the whole time.
I'll have a much better time here. I'll call
Charlie and those guys. - Yeah! Call those guys.
And I'm gonna be back
on Sunday, and I...
I love you, you know.
Okay?
I love you.
I'll see you. Okay? Yeah, it's just gonna be
a couple of... a couple of days.
Bye.
I love you.
Hello.
How are you?
Good. How are you?
It's a cool pool, isn't it?
Yeah, it's nice.
Get any sleep?
Not yet.
How about you?
No. Not yet.
How long you staying for?
I'll be in the bar
for the rest of the week.
Well, that's good.
Um, I'm going out with some friends later,
if you wanna come.
Sure.
Okay. I'll see you later.
Okay.
See ya.
Oop...
"Bob, which one do you want
for your study?
I like the burgundy,
but whatever you want. "
Which one is burgundy?
Hold on!
Hold on.
You really are
having a midlife crisis, huh?
Really?
Yeah, I was afraid of that.
I kept telling myself that I just wanted
to be ready in case we go to war tonight.
My bathroom
is messier than yours.
And it's not like
you're not tryin'.
Here, will you cut the tag out for me?
Sure.
You're too tall.
Uh, anybody ever tell you
you may be too small?
Whose is this? "A Soul's Search:
Finding Your True Calling. "
I don't know.
I have that.
Did it work out
for you, then?
Obviously.
Okay.
Where's your shoes?
They're over here.
- Where's your room key?
- It's in my bag.
- And where's your bag?
- It's right here.
Let's go.
Wait!
There's the elevator.
I gotta go.
Hi! How are you?
Hi, Charlie!
Um, Bob,
this is Charlie Brown.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
How are you? Nice to meet you.
- This is Bambi.
- How are you, Bambi?
His real name's Hayashi, but...
Why do they call you Charlie Brown?
Everybody say, "He looks like Charlie Brown."
You know, Snoopy, man.
Oh, I'll be right back.
Bob, over here. These are my friends.
Very beautiful.
She's "B," and she's Rico,
and she's Myumi.
- Myumi. How are you? I'm Bob.
- Oh! Bob.
Bob from
United States, man.
Ahh!
Hi, Bob.
Maybe you'd like to
sing backup for me.
This is my surfing teacher.
- He's your surfing teacher?
Sometime, sometime.
You're a surfer?
Oh, oui, oui.
The emperor's house? Cool.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Oui.
Cool!
Right.
You don't have anything...
Do you have anything b...
Hey.
Hey. How you doin'?
- Good. How are you?
- My Japanese is getting better.
We started speaking English.
Charlie.
Ooh! Get out, guys!
- I'm leaving!
They'll sting!
Whoo!
Who are these guys, anyway?
Hey-hey-hey-hey-hey!
Oh, no.
Hi.
Come on!
Hey, guys! Over here!
Hurry up! Hurry up!
Hurry up!
Wait!
Our tour guide!
Hurry up!
Yeah?
Gorgeous.
Gorgeous?
Blonde and black.
Well, it's a feelin'I get
- Cheese. Cheese-o!
- Cheese!
Yeah, yeah... Hi.
It's a feelin'I get
Hi, I'm Hans.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Charlotte.
Hi.
Last weekend, I went surfing.
Right.
About seven people, you know.
Some friends.
And we camp over there
on the beach.
In fact, we made a kind of...
Wait. What kind of weed is it?
I don't know.
Baby, when I saw you turnin'
at the end of the street
I knew our time was gone
Into blank pages
Just understand I was afraid
to be a simple guy
I tried my best to smile
But deep inside my heart
I felt like the shell
that a crab comes in
I guess I couldn't
live without things
A fascist regime
It made you a moron
A potential H-bomb
God save the queen
She ain't no human being
There's no future
In England's dreaming
As I walk through
This wicked world
Searchin' for light
in the darkness
Of insanity
I ask myself
Is all hope lost
Is there only pain
And hatred
And misery
And each time
I feel like this inside
There's one thing
I want to know
What's so funny 'bout
peace, love and understanding
I'm winkin' at ya
Gonna make you, make you
make you notice
Gonna use my arms
Gonna use my legs
Gonna use my style
Gonna use my sidestep
Gonna use my fingers
Gonna use my, my, my
My, my, my
Imagination
'Cause I'm
Gonna make you see
Nobody else here
No one like me
— I'm special
- Special
So special
Special?
I gotta have some of your
Attention
Give it to me
Ladies and gentlemen,
Mr. Bob Harris.
Thanks. This is hard.
Oh, Jesus.
I could feel at the time
There was no way of knowing
Fallen leaves in the night
Who can say
where they're blowin'
As free as the wind
Hopefully learnin'
Why the sea on the tide
Has no way of turnin'
More than this
You know there's nothing
Tell me one thing
More than this
Ooh, there's nothing
Close my eyes
Feel me now
I don't know
How you could
not love me now
You will know
With her feet down to the ground
Over there
And I want you, love, to know
You can't hide
Oh, no
From the way I feel
Hello.
Hey.
Hello, Bob.
Hey, you know, those carpet samples...
you were right about the burgundy.
It wasn't even close.
Blows the others away.
I'm glad you like it.
I saw a great house tonight
that you would've loved, and...
that burgundy would've been good
in this house, really. - Really?
A guy designed his own house
and built it.
Oh, yeah? I wish I'd seen it.
He's a fashion guy.
All these fashion people were there.
And, uh, there were
Japanese surfers there,
and the guy was playing
really, really, really great music.
I should've found out what it was
and brought some...
I'll bring some back.
I'll try to find out.
That sounds great.
Can you hold on?
You have to have something
for breakfast.
Do you want some cereal?
Tell her I said she's gotta eat something.
I'm just trying to get her
to eat something.
Yeah. Tell her I said
she has to eat something.
Your dad says eat something.
No.
Eat. Tell her I said so.
She won't eat anything. Forget it.
Look, I'm glad you're having fun.
It's not fun. It's just...
It's just very, very different.
Maybe that's good.
Um, I have to get
the kids off for school, okay?
So, can I call you in a while?
I might not be up.
It's-It's, like, 4:00.
Well, you better get some sleep.
You have work in the morning.
No, actually,
they gave me tomorrow off.
That must be nice.
All right. Well, thanks
for checking in. I gotta go.
All right. Have a great, great night.
All right.
I mean, I guess have a great morning, huh?
Good night, Bob.
Good night.
I love you.
That was a stupid idea.
I was feeling tight,
you know?
Shoulders and neck.
So I called down
and, and had a, uh,
shiatsu massage in my room.
Mmm, that's nice.
And the tightness has
completely, uh, disappeared...
And been replaced by...
unbelievable pain.
Just staggering, unbearable pain.
Ooh, that's too bad.
Yeah.
I'm in pain.
I got my foot banged up, and...
Wanna see it?
How do you say no?
Oh, my gosh.
I know.
That's... How...
When did you do this?
I did it the other day.
It hurts, you know?
Didn't you feel any pain? Your...
Yeah, it really hurt.
It was...
Yeah. That toe is almost dead.
I gotta take you to a doctor. You can't
just put that back in the shoe.
No. I don't think so.
Well, you either go to a doctor,
or you leave it here.
He's smiling.
You like that idea?
See, they love black toe
over in this country.
You got a sharp knife?
Gotta be, you know, in this country...
somebody's gotta prefer a black toe.
Uh, "brack" toe.
Or we should probably hang around
until someone orders it.
Hey, what's with the straight face?
Hospital regulations.
Get in there.
All right. Thank you.
All right.
Careful, okay?
No, don't!
No!
Hey, use the horn, fella.
Let's try "mixed internal. "
Yeah. Switched to beer, huh?
Go.
Go. Go.
You might want to switch to sake.
Stop.
Hi.
Yeah. We need a doctor.
Hai.
For, uh, her...
emergency room.
It's not an emergency.
I just hurt my foot.
Okay, do we fill this out?
We go over there?
Which number?
We're not going to another hospital,
so whatever you say is okay.
Okay.
Could you put that back
in the garage for us?
Irun desuka.
"In desuka"?
Nihon ni.
Japan.
"Appuh. "
Japan "appuh. "
Japan...
"Appuh. " "Appuh. "
After?
Japan...
"Appuh. " Nannen.
"Nannen. "
Ahh-ah, so.
How's that song go?
Is that for me?
Yeah, it can be for you.
Hey, Bob, it's Charlotte.
Um, I'm going to meet Charlie and those guys
at this place called Orange around 10:00,
so I'll fax you a map
on how to get there.
I hope you can come
and meet us. Bye.
Suckin'on my titties
like you wanted me
Callin'me all the time
like Blondie
Check out my Chrissie be-Hynde
It's fine all of the time
Like sex on the beach is
What else is in the Teaches of Peaches
Huh, what
Suckin'on my titties
like you wanted me
Callin'me all the time like Blondie
How long have you been here?
I couldn't say.
Where's Charlie and those guys?
Um, they're takin' a dance class.
Why, what
What, right
Can I get you a couple drinks?
Let's go.
Okay.
Like you wanted me
Callin'me all the time like Blondie
Thank you.
He's got blockers.
They've got room to run.
He's cutting back.
He cut back.
He's dancin'. He's dancin'.
Where'd he go?
There you are.
Say "Hi. "
Hi. You ready?
Come on.
Thank you, Tokyo!
Nobody does it better
Makes me feel sad for the rest
Nobody does it
Half as good as you
Baby, you're
The best
You two.
Both of you.
I wasn't lookin'
But somehow you found me
I tried to hide
from your love, yeah
No, no. Not here.
It must be over there.
You know, the first time I saw you,
you were wearing a tuxedo at the bar.
You were very dashing.
I liked the mascara.
But the first time I saw you
was in the elevator.
Really?
You don't remember?
I guess you do kind of blend in, huh?
Did I scowl at you?
No, you smiled.
I did?
Yes, it was a complete accident.
A freak. I haven't seen it since.
Just that one time.
Like that, but bigger.
Bigger. Yeah, big... big...
Well, not that big.
My goodness.
Marcello, come here.
Hurry up.
Why do they switch
the "R"s and the "L"s here?
Oh, for yuks.
You know, just to mix it up.
They have to amuse themselves.
'Cause we're not makin' 'em laugh.
Let's never come here again,
'cause it would never be as much fun.
Whatever you say.
You're the boss.
I'm stuck.
Does it get easier?
No.
Yes.
It gets easier.
Oh, yeah?
Look at you.
Thanks.
The more you know
who you are,
and what you want,
the less you let...
things upset you.
Yeah.
I just don't know
what I'm supposed to be.
You know?
I tried being a writer, but...
I hate what I write.
And I tried taking pictures,
but they're so mediocre,
you know.
Every girl goes through
a photography phase.
You know, like horses?
You know?
Take, uh, dumb pictures of your feet.
You'll figure that out.
I'm not worried about you.
Keep writing.
But I'm so mean.
Mean's okay.
Yeah?
What about marriage?
Does that get easier?
That's hard.
We used to have
a lot of fun.
Lydia would come with me
when I made the movies,
and we would laugh
about it all.
Now she doesn't want
to leave the kids, and...
she doesn't...
need me to be there.
The kids miss me,
but they're fine.
It gets a whole lot more complicated
when you have kids.
Yeah. It's scary.
It's the most terrifying day of your life
the day the first one is born.
Yeah. Nobody ever tells you that.
Your life,
as you know it,
is gone.
Never to return.
But they learn how to walk,
and they learn how to talk, and...
and you want to be with them.
And they turn out to be the most...
delightful people...
you will ever meet in your life.
Hmm, that's nice.
Where'd you grow up?
Um, I grew up in New York,
and I moved to Los Angeles
when John and I got married.
But it's so different there.
Yeah, I know.
John thinks I'm so snotty.
Hmm.
You're not hopeless.
Hello?
Mr. Harris? A fax for you.
Yes.
Okay.
Can you send it up?
Do you think you can kick it under
the door, slide it under the door, please?
Do you want I send it to your room?
Just slide it under the door, please.
Thank you. Okay. All right, bye.
Thank you, Mr. Harris.
Hey, Ms. Kawasaki.
It's Bob Harris.
Yes, I would love
to do his talk show.
I would.
I would love
to change my plans and stay.
American movie star.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Mr. Bob Harris!
Come on!
Da de da de, da de da dah.
Da de da dah!
Whoo!
Come on, Bob.
Bobby, come on!
Whoo! Nice to meet you.
He said you guys are
e-mailing together.
Ah. He wants to
show you his dance.
Japanese dance step.
Uh... Uh... Japanese dance.
Do I... Do I have to
dance with him?
To-tung a-tung. To-tung a-tung.
To-tung a-tung. To-tung a-tung
Bobby, Bobby, Bobby, Bobby...
Welcome, Bob. He was saying, "Welcome, Bob."
What?
Hello?
Bob?
Hi, Lydia.
Is this a bad time?
No, it's always a good time.
Look, um, your burgundy carpet
isn't in stock.
It's gonna take 12 weeks.
Did you like any of the other colors?
Whatever you like.
I-I'm completely lost.
It's just carpet.
That's not what I'm talking about.
What are you talking about?
I don't know.
I just want to get healthy.
You know, I want to take
better care of myself.
I would like to start
eating healthier.
I don't want all that pasta.
What?
I would like to start eating,
like, Japanese food.
Well, why don't you just stay there,
and you can have it every day?
How are the kids doin'?
They're fine.
They miss their father.
But they're getting used to
you not being here.
Do I need to worry
about you, Bob?
Only if you want to.
Bob, I got things to do.
I gotta go.
Okay.
I'll see you...
I mean, I'll talk to you later.
Okay.
Okay, bye.
Bye.
Matthew Smellick!
Matthew "Snellick. "
Thank you. Thank you so much.
We'll take a really short break,
and we'll see you in a minute.
Hi. Uh, champagne.
Thanks.
Hi.
Midnight at the oasis
Send your camel to bed
Shadows paintin'our faces
Traces of romance in our heads
Heaven's holding a half moon
I got it.
Have a rough night?
Um, I'm going to that place,
that sushi place in Daikanyama.
You wanna come?
Yeah, but I can't right now.
Midnight at the oasis
Send your camel to bed
Yeah, I guess you're busy, huh?
Shadows paintin'our faces
Traces of romance in our heads
Hello?
Hello? Bob, it's me.
It's Lydia, your wife.
Oh, I'm...
I couldn't hear ya.
Hey, you want to talk to Zoe?
Yeah.
Zoe, come say hello
to your father.
No. Uh, she just ran into
the other room.
It's okay. It's okay.
Okay, um, her ballet recital
is Sunday. Don't forget.
I didn't forget.
Well, travel safely.
I'll see you soon.
Mommy!
Okay.
Okay. Bye.
Bye.
Well, she is closer
to your age.
You could talk about things
you have in common,
like, um,
growing up in the '50s.
Maybe she liked the movies
you were making in the '70s,
when you still were making movies.
Wasn't there anyone else there
to lavish you with attention?
I'm switchin' to beer.
Okay?
Biru?
I can't tell the difference.
We'll have
two of these, okay?
To your nearest exit...
and leave the building.
Await instructions
from the authorities.
That was the worst lunch.
So bad.
What kind of restaurant
makes you cook your own food?
When are you leaving?
Tomorrow.
I'll miss you.
I'm so into you
When you walked into the room
There was voodoo in the vibes
I was captured by your style
But I could not
catch your eyes
I don't want to leave.
So don't.
Stay here with me.
We'll start a jazz band.
I am so into you, baby
Good night.
Good night. Okay.
Okay.
Okay. Good night.
Good night.
Good morning, Mr. Harris. Have a nice flight.
Thank you.
Good-bye
I'll be one minute.
Charlotte, I'm down in the lobby,
and I'm leaving now.
Um, I was calling...
to see if you still
have my jacket.
If you could you bring it down,
but you're not there,
so this is good-bye,
and, uh...
So,
I guess, good-bye and enjoy
my jacket which you stole...
from me.
Hello.
How are you?
I'm good. How are you?
Mr. Harris...
Thank you for coming. Enjoy your, your trip?
I had a great time.
I had a very good time.
Excuse me. Ar-Aren't you Bob Harris?
Yes, I am.
I'm such a big fan. So nice to meet you.
Thank you very much. Nice to meet you.
What are you doing here in Japan?
I have to go right now. Excuse me one second.
Oh, okay. Well...
Hi. Thank you.
Hi.
You're welcome.
Thought I'd missed you.
Are you going right now?
Yeah. And my bodyguards are in here.
All right. Aren't you gonna wish me
"Have a good 'fright,"' or something?
Yeah, right.
Okay. Well, bye.
All right.
- Can I take one more picture?
- Sure.
Hai.
Hey, hold on here. Let me out.
Thank you.
Hey, you.
Okay?
Okay.
Bye.
Listen to the girl
As she takes on half the world
Moving up and so alive
In her honey dripping
Beehive
It's good, so good
All right.
So good
Walking back to you
Is the hardest thing that
I can do
That I can do for you
For you
I'll be your plastic toy
Eating up the scum
Is the hardest thing for
Me to do
Just like honey
Free
To learn
Last time
With you
You're always
Wonderful
I wanted you
I do
Free
To go
I know
You
City girl
You're beautiful
I love you
I do
I
Could love
All night
With you
City girl
You're beautiful
I love you
I do