Swan...
He has no other name.
His past is a mystery,
But his work
is already a legend.
He wrote and produced
his first gold record at 14.
In the years since then,
he has won so many others...
That he once tried
to deposit them in Fort Knox.
He brought the blues to Britain.
He brought Liverpool to America.
He brought folk and rock
together.
His band, The Juicy fruits,
Single-handedly gave birth to
the nostalgia wave of the '70s.
Now he is looking for
the new sound of the spheres...
To inaugurate his own Xanadu,
his own Disneyland,
The Paradise,
the ultimate rock palace.
This film is the story
of that search...
of that sound,
of the man who made it,
the girl who sang it...
and the monster who stole it.
♫ We'll remember you ♫
♫ Forever, Eddie ♫
♫ Through the sacrifice
You made ♫
♫ We can't believe
The price you paid ♫
♫ For love ♫
♫ Little Eddie Mitty
Born in jersey city ♫
♫ Started singing
When he was five ♫
♫ Never knew his father
And mother didn't bother? ♫
♫ To catch his last name
Fast as he came ♫
♫ He was off and flyin'
Times were really tryin' ♫
♫ Eddie and his mother alone ♫
♫ Soon another mister
And soon a baby sister ♫
♫ Mama kept swingin'
And Eddie kept singin' ♫
♫ For love ♫
And now the tragic story.
Eddie's sister, Mary Louise,
Needed an operation.
To get the money he would have
to become an overnight sensation.
♫ Eddie believed
The American people...
Had wonderful,
love-giving hearts.
His well-publicized end
he considered would send...
his memorial album
to the top of the charts.
♫ And it did!
♫ Good-bye ♫
When a young singer dies
to our shock and surprise...
In a plane crash
or a flashy sports car,
He becomes quite well-known
and the kindness he's shown...
has made more than one
postmortem star.
Well, you did it, Eddie.
And though it's hard
to applaud suicide,
you gave all you could give
so your sister could live.
All America's
choked up inside, man.
♫ We'll remember you
Forever, Eddie ♫
♫ Through the sacrifice
You made ♫
♫ We can't believe
The price you paid ♫
♫ For love ♫
You know, it just seems like yesterday
I found Annette in that church choir.
I got her singing lessons.
I taught her how to dress.
I got her first club job,
and I paid off a columnist.
He did a beautiful story on her.
I taught her who to be nice to,
who to...
I fed her the drugs to get her
through the road tours.
I made her record a hit.
Then I sold her to you.
You made her the biggest thing in rock.
So now what does she do?
She fires us,
cancels her Vegas date...
And wants to give free concerts
for starving gook orphans.
She was more than a piece to me.
She was the light of my life.
And now she's gone.
There will be
a 20-minute intermission...
Before the next show.
We sued her.
We couldn't lose.
We had her
in an ironclad contract.
It was a lock. It was over.
It was closed.
I even bribed the judge.
He ruled against us. Said we couldn't
sign anyone to a life contract.
Said we were a disgrace to the profession.
A disgrace, he said!
I was the one that made her the money-grubbing
whore she was, and he calls me a disgrace.
What do you want me to do?
Break her.
Is that all?
Isn't that enough?
Annette is nothing,
finished, washed up.
But she's at the top
of the charts.
That's today, Philbin, today.
Tomorrow she'll be forgotten.
Besides, we have more important
business, you and I... the Paradise.
I know, boss. We've looked everywhere.
You just don't seem to...
Listen.
What?
♫ Out of place as a crying clown
Who could only frown ♫
♫ And the play went on
For hours ♫
♫ And as I lived my role ♫
♫ I swore I'd sell my soul
For one love ♫
♫ Who would stand by me ♫
♫ And give them back
The gift of laughter ♫
♫ Yeah, one love ♫
♫ Who would stand by me ♫
♫ And after makin' love
We'd dream ♫
♫ A bit of style ♫
♫ We'd dream
A bunch of friends ♫
♫ Dream each other's smiles ♫
♫ And dream it never ends ♫
♫ I was not myself last night
In the mornin' light ♫
♫ I could see
The change was showin' ♫
♫ Like a child who was always poor
Reachin' out for more ♫
♫ I could feel
The hunger growin' ♫
♫ And as I lost control ♫
♫ I swore I'd sell my soul
For one love ♫
That's it.
What?
The music to open the Paradise.
After all these years,
I've finally found it.
You want that creep to open the Paradise?
No, not him.
The music.
Listen to the music.
♫ What do I do with him? ♫
♫ And lay beside me
While we dream ♫
You'll think of something.
♫ A bit of style ♫
♫ Dream a bunch of friends ♫
♫ Dream each other's smiles ♫
♫ And dream it never ends ♫
♫ All my dreams are lost ♫
♫ And I can't sleep ♫
♫ And sleep alone
Could ease my mind ♫
♫ All my tears have dried ♫
♫ And I can't weep ♫
♫ Old emotions ♫
♫ May they rest in peace ♫
♫ And dream, dream
A bunch of friends ♫
♫ Rest in peace ♫
♫ And dream, dream
It never ends ♫
Mr. Leach?
Hello? Yeah.
My name's Arnold Philbin.
Hello. Look, I scout
talent for Swan,
and, uh, he's interested
in your stuff.
The Swan?
That's right.
He said your sound could be real big.
Did he really say that?
I was sittin' next to him. Oh, if
Mr. Swan would produce my music,
the whole world
would listen to me.
The game plan exactly. But you need
a lot of work, a lot of polishing.
Oh, I know, Mr. Philbin.
I-I have a long way to go.
Right. Now, do you have
any tapes of your stuff?
No, but it's all
written down here.
Well, why don't you give us just two or
three of the really good up numbers...
Two or three up numbers?
You don't understand.
The scope of this cantata is 200 or 300
pages long, and I haven't finished yet.
Well, never mind the sonata.
We just want the songs.
It's not just songs.
It's more. It's much more.
I don't get you, kid.
Well, it's a whole series of songs
that tell the story of Faust.
Who? What label is he on? Faust.
Faust was a legendary German magician
who sold his soul to the devil...
For worldly experience
and power.
What is this, kid, school time?
I got a plane to catch.
Look, a song is a song.
You either dig it or you don't.
Now, I like your stuff, kid.
I think it's terrific.
You know what?
What?
I think The Juicy Fruits
are gonna dig it.
The Juicy Fruits? I'm not
promising anything. First...
I'm not gonna let my music be
mutilated by those grease-balls!
I'm the only one
that can sing "Faust"!
Relax, kid.
It was just an idea.
Swan makes all these
decisions, you know?
I'm-I'm sorry. I...
It's just that I've worked
so hard on this thing.
Uh, it's okay, kid.
Boy, you sure got some temper.
I'm sorry. I don't know
what comes over me.
It's all right. Just relax. Take it easy.
Why don't you give me the music,
Swan'll take a look at it on the
plane and we'll get right back to you.
But if you ask me, I think we're
gonna produce your first album.
Really?
Hello.
I'm Winslow Leach.
Yes?
Mr. Philbin said...
Mr. Swan was gonna call me
about producing my first record.
Mr. Philbin said he'd get right back to me.
That was a month ago.
One moment, please.
Taxi! Taxi, taxi!
Follow that car.
♫ Never thought
I'd get to meet the devil ♫
♫ Never thought I'd meet him
Face to face ♫
♫ Heard he always
Worked alone ♫
♫ And that he seldom wrote
Or used a phone ♫
♫ So I walked right up
To meet him at his place ♫
♫ All my dreams ♫
♫ I can't sleep ♫
♫ All my dreams are lost ♫
♫ Oh-oh-oh
All my tears have dried ♫
♫ And I can't weep ♫
♫ Old emotions ♫
Where'd you get that song?
Well, I got it from Philbin,
to audition with.
Sing it again.
Why?
Go ahead, sing it.
♫ All my dreams are lost ♫
♫ And I can't sleep ♫
♫ Sleep alone
Could ease my mind ♫
♫ All my tears have dried ♫
♫ And I can't weep ♫
♫ Old emotions ♫
♫ May they rest ♫
♫ In peace ♫
♫ And dream ♫
That's incredible.
How'd you know it went like that?
I wrote the song.
If you wrote this stuff,
then why aren't you in there with
Swan auditioning the singers?
I don't know. There must be some mix-up.
Oh, sure.
They must not know who you are.
Your name's not on the music.
Well, that's funny.
Swan heard me sing that song.
Why is he auditioning girls for my cantata?
I only sing it solo.
Haven't you heard?
What?
He's opening the Paradise with it.
You're kidding!
Do I look like a kidder? He's
opening the Paradise with my cantata?
- Yes. Isn't that great?
- Gee, I wish he'd told me.
He's just auditioning girls
for a backup chorus.
But you're really a fine singer. You shouldn't
waste your time singing in a chorus.
I don't care
where I sing this music.
Hey, look, could you help me?
I know I can sing these
songs better than anybody.
And with your help, I'm sure I
could get a part in the chorus.
- Sure, I'd love to help you.
- you're not just doing this to be nice, are you?
I would never let my personal desires
influence my aesthetic judgment.
Wh-what's that mean?
It means
I think you're terrific.
Do you?
Hey! All right,
let's everybody get in line.
Gotta quick it up a little bit.
Move in quietly.
One, two, three, four!
Come on, come on.
Five, six, seven, eight!
Oh, wait, wait.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Stop. What's that? A boyfriend?
I'm Winslow Leach, the composer.
That's great. But Swan's
only seeing girls today.
But I have to see him.
Don't give me a hard time.
If you want to see Swan,
call and make an appointment.
I did that,
and they threw me out.
Then they don't want to see you.
But I wrote the music.
Look, why don't you
just get out of here!
Winslow, I'll tell him
you're out here.
Okay. I'll wait for you.
Good luck.
Why won't he just let me sing?
That was awful!
What's the matter?
Philbin tried to... I just can't do it.
I came here to sing.
That doesn't sound like an audition.
Leave me alone!
I'm sorry. Did you tell him who I am?
What's your name?
Hey, come here, buddy!
Do you guys know where
a good department store is?
Yeah. We'll take you.
we'll go right now.
When do we get to sing?
I don't think much singing
goes on around here.
I've been here 12 times, and I still don't
get to sing. I just get to come back.
What do you do here?
You'll see.
Can't you sing on your back?
I've never tried.
If you can sing standing up,
you can sing lying down.
Oh! Ah! Why don't you
take your slip off?
No, I'm saving it for Swan.
He won't miss anything
if you do it now.
You're being auditioned right now.
What do you mean?
The whole place is bugged.
You're kidding.
No. No. Swan's
watching us right now.
Come here.
What are you doing?
Swan likes to watch us.
Watch us doing what?
Doing each other.
Really?
That's how he gets turned on.
Does he like blondes?
I like blondes.
Do you mind?
I hate to bother you,
but, that's right...
Oh, just hold me close.
I just... Oh, I just need someone
to help me warm my voice up.
Swan!
Oh, Mr. Swan. You remember me.
I'm Winslow Leach.
Swan!
Over here, Swan.
Swan! Swan!
Oh, Swan! Swan!
Oh, Swan!
Get this fag out of here.
Mr. Swan, it's me, Winslow.
Don't you remember?
I gave Mr. Philbin a copy of
my cantata... You know, "Faust".
You were supposed
to look at it and do it.
And you're auditioning
girls for my cantata!
I'm Winslow Leach!
I wrote it!
Hey, where are you going
with me? Hey, Swan!
Oh, Swan.
Telephone.
Hey! Hey!
That's him! What do
you think you're doing?
- Nothing.
- What are you, some kind of pervert?
No, sir. I'm, I'm,
I'm Winslow Leach, the composer.
What are you doing
outside the Swanage?
Listen, officers,
you've gotta help me.
Mr. Swan's got my music, and he's
pretending he doesn't know me.
He had me thrown out
of the mansion and beaten up.
Didn't want to buy what
you had to sell, did he?
He-he didn't say anything
about buying anything.
Hey, jack, what's that
he got in his purse?
I don't know, Joe.
Why don't you take a look?
- I think I will.
- Mr. Swan said he had it on him.
What do you know.
Smack, Jack.
Do you know what you could get
for pushin' in this state?
Life!
But I'm innocent! Swan
stole my music and framed me!
One, two, three, four!
Welcome to Sing Sing.
We are very fortunate to be included here
in the dental health research program.
This is a volunteer program
funded by the Swan foundation.
You are all volunteers.
All your teeth will be pulled.
Teeth are a source of infection,
and it pays
to be on the safe side.
Sir, pardon me?
I'm not a volunteer.
I'm innocent. I don't want
you to take my teeth out.
Oh. How many men here
are innocent?
Raise your hands.
All innocent.
And good morning, everybody.
This is Windy Greg here on WCHT.
Well, Swan has another golden
disc to deposit in Fort Knox.
His fabulous group,
The Juicy Fruits,
On the death label,
has taken the charts by storm.
And get this, kids. Friday night,
you can see The Juicy Fruits live...
At the grand opening
of the Paradise.
That's right. Swan's rock palace
is scheduled to open at last...
and with this dynamite sound.
So let's hear it again. The Juicy
Fruits singing Swan's "Faust".
Never!
Hey, get away
from that record press!
Okay, let's move this ladder.
What's that?
I take the tire and I shove it
right in his mouth.
Then he really
gets mad at me, you know?
Look.
All right, this is the
last time we're gonna go through it.
You see Swan up there?
He's listenin'.
He' watchin' this whole thing,
so don't make me look bad again.
All right, watch the microphones. I
want to see plenty of movement up there.
Harold, you leave her alone.
Put her down!
All right, let's get goin'.
Will ya, please?
All right, look...
Carburetors, man.
That's what life is all about.
♫ That's what life
Is all about ♫
♫ That's what it's all about ♫
♫ I was not myself
last night, lost a fight, ♫
♫ My woody barely running ♫
Come on, let's get it
goin' over here.
- Come on, that's it.
Get the car over there.
All right, girls.
Just a second, Linda.
You got a very nice body.
♫ I finally lost control
and tore my tuck 'n roll ♫
♫ Upholstery ♫
This is just a rehearsal.
You're not gettin' paid to be clothed.
Don't touch me!
You wanna get paid?
Yeah, I wanna get paid.
Get back out there.
♫ What our life is all about ♫
Come on, let's move it out here.
That's it. Come on.
♫ Upholstery ♫
♫ Where my baby
Sits up close to me ♫
- Where do you think you're goin'?
I gotta get out of here.
What are you talkin' about?
What sign are you?
Leo. So what?
You're okay. I gotta get out of here.
Come with me.
♫ Of all life's mysteries ♫
I swear to god. You see Swan
sittin' in that box up there?
Yeah, right. Well, he
doesn't show up every day.
Now, if he comes down here, do
you really want me to tell him...
That it's not in the stars for you
to ride off the stage in this car?
I told you,
I just don't feel good.
You're gonna feel a lot worse
if you don't do what I tell ya.
I've got this headache. I think
something's loose up there.
No, there's something weird down here.
Take one of these.
Can I take these with me?
Just take the pills.
♫ That's supposed to be ♫
♫ What life is all about ♫
I want big smiles now.
Look out at the audience.
That's it.
♫ Upholstery ♫
♫ When my baby
Sits up close to me ♫
♫ That's supposed to be ♫
♫ What our life is all about ♫
♫ All about ♫
♫ Upholstery ♫
♫ When my baby
Sits up close to me ♫
♫ That's supposed to be... ♫
♫ What life is all about ♫
♫ Upholstery ♫
♫ When my baby
Sits up close to me ♫
♫ That's supposed to be ♫
Why, Winslow, good to see you.
Been looking for you everywhere.
Killing me won't help you.
My god, you're horrible.
Don't rush off.
Look at yourself.
Look at yourself!
What's that horrible sound you're making?
Can't you talk?
Look around you, Winslow.
You've destroyed
your face, your voice.
And now you're trying
to destroy the Paradise.
Haven't we all had enough?
I can give you the power to create again.
I can make you somebody.
We'll have to start
all over again, Winslow,
Only this time working together
instead of against each other.
The time for your sound is now. People
are going to want to hear your music.
I mean what I say.
Tomorrow I'll put a whole new group
together who'll do your songs your way.
You don't have to believe me. Come to
the auditions and see for yourself.
Trust me!
Trust me.
♫ Caught up
In your simple feelin' ♫
♫ Got no time
For a simple feelin' ♫
Next. ♫ Thought I knew you
But I don't... ♫
What's your name, sweetheart?
Phoenix.
All right,
Let's see what you got.
Do I get to sing this time?
Oh, you mean
you're really a singer?
Yes, I'm a singer.
Well, try to forget it.
We're not lookin' for singers.
We're lookin' for screamers.
I'm not a screamer.
I'm a singer.
Phoenix.
Swan here.
I want you to answer
a question for me.
Yes?
What would you give me to sing?
Anything you wanted.
Anything?
Would you give me...
your voice?
Try me.
♫ Caught up in your
Wheelin', dealin' ♫
♫ You've got no time left
For simple feelin' ♫
♫ I thought I knew you ♫
♫ But I didn't know you at all ♫
♫ Trapped inside
Your world of worry ♫
♫ You miss so much
When you always hurry ♫
♫ Well, slow down, baby ♫
♫ You'll only get hurt
If you fall ♫
♫ Well, you told me one time
That you'd be somebody ♫
♫ That you weren't workin'
Just to survive ♫
♫ But you're workin' so hard ♫
♫ That you don't even know
You're alive ♫
♫ Workin' so hard
To be somebody special ♫
♫ Not working just to survive ♫
♫ Well, you're special
To me, babe ♫
♫ And what I don't see, babe ♫
♫ Is where you go
Once you arrive ♫
♫ Where we go once we arrive ♫
♫ Then all the evil
That takes possession ♫
♫ Until your pipe dreams
Become obsessions ♫
♫ You scare me, baby ♫
♫ And we should have
Nothing to fear ♫
♫ I'm no child
But I can't help wonderin' ♫
♫ It seems like some kind
Of spell you're under ♫
♫ You're listening, baby ♫
♫ But somehow
You don't really hear ♫
♫ Well, you told me one time
that you'd be somebody ♫
♫ That you weren't workin'
Just to survive ♫
♫ But you're workin' so hard ♫
♫ That you don't even know
You're alive ♫
♫ Workin' so hard
To be somebody special ♫
♫ Not working just to survive ♫
♫ Well, you're special
To me, babe ♫
♫ But what I don't see, babe ♫
♫ Is where we go once we arrive ♫
She's good, isn't she?
♫ Where you go once you arrive ♫
Then let's talk.
♫ I was not myself last night ♫
♫ Out of place as a cryin' clown
Who could only frown ♫
♫ And the play
Went on for hours ♫
♫ And as I lived my role ♫
♫ I swore I'd sell my soul
For one love ♫
♫ Who would stand by me ♫
♫ And give me back
The gift of laughter ♫
♫ One love ♫
♫ Who would stand by me ♫
♫ And after makin' love
We'd dream ♫
♫ A bit of style ♫
♫ Dream a bunch of friends ♫
♫ Dream each other's smiles ♫
♫ Dream it never ends ♫
Filters.
♫ I was not myself last night
in the morning light ♫
♫ I could see
the change was showing ♫
Dolbys.
♫ Like a child who was
always poor, reaching out for more ♫
- Perfect.
- ♫ I could feel the hunger growing ♫
♫ And as I lost control ♫
♫ I swore I'd sell my soul... ♫
How's that? Try it.
Phoenix.
Try it again.
- Phoenix.
- And again.
Phoenix.
Well, at least you can talk. You can plug
yourself into the console for singing.
You really think
she's that good?
She's too good for you.
I'll hire her anyway.
She could be my voice now.
Oh, could she? Really? Yes.
Then let's get down to business.
I want you to stop
terrorizing the Paradise...
And rewrite your cantata...
for Phoenix.
That way we both
get what we want.
You get your cantata sung by the
right singer, and I open Paradise.
Rewrite my cantata? We have no
time to waste. Just one week.
You must lock yourself in here
and do nothing but write.
I could write it for her. It will be
performed here live, and Phoenix will star.
My cantata? For her?
I'll get fantastic musicians.
The hall has great acoustics.
I don't trust you, Swan.
You've ruined my music before.
Forget about The Juicy Fruits.
Who wants nostalgia anymore?
I don't trust you.
You don't have to.
Here's a contract. Everything
I've said and more is in it.
I'll read it.
At your leisure.
"Party of the first part gives the party
of the second part and his associates...
"full power to do with him
at their pleasure,
"to rule, to send, to fetch
or carry him or his,
be it either body, soul,
flesh, blood or goods."
What does that mean?
That's a transportation clause.
"All art..."
"All articles which are excluded
shall be deemed included."
What does that mean?
That's a clause
to protect you, Winslow.
Anyway, what difference
does it make?
What choice do you have?
I'll rewrite my cantata.
But you best play what I write.
Ink isn't worth
anything to me, Winslow.
Now sign.
Excellent.
And now we're in business.
Together... Forever.
I'll rewrite my cantata,
but you best play what I write.
Ink isn't
worth anything to me, Winslow.
Now sign.
Excellent.
Now we're in business.
Together... Forever.
♫ Half asleep I hear a voice ♫
♫ Is it only in my mind ♫
♫ Or is it someone
Calling me ♫
♫ Someone I failed
And left behind ♫
♫ To work it out
I let them in ♫
♫ All the good guys
And the bad guys ♫
♫ That I've been ♫
♫ All the devils
That disturb me ♫
♫ And the angels
That defeated them somehow ♫
♫ Come together in me now ♫
Tasty, Winslow, tasty.
I know, boss,
but I thought you liked her.
I do. She's perfect.
But you know how I abhor
perfection in anyone but myself.
Then Phoenix is out?
No, not out,
Just a backup singer.
No, my cantata needs
something really... Heavy.
♫ Half asleep I hear a voice ♫
♫ I hear a voice ♫
♫ Is it only in my mind ♫
No, no.
♫ Or is there someone calling me ♫
♫ Someone I've failed
And left behind ♫
Wrong. Wrong again.
♫ To work it out I let them in ♫
♫ All the good guys
And the bad guys ♫
♫ That I've been ♫
Pretty, but... No.
♫ All the devils
That disturb me ♫
♫ And the angels
That defeated ♫
♫ Them somehow ♫
No.
♫ Come together in me now ♫
There's something he'll like.
♫ Like a circus ♫
♫ On parade ♫
♫ Seldom close enough to see ♫
♫ I wander through an angry crowd ♫
♫ And wonder
What's become of me ♫
♫ To work it out
I let them in ♫
♫ All the good guys
And the bad guys ♫
♫ That I've been ♫
♫ All the devils
That disturb me ♫
♫ And the angels
That defeated them somehow ♫
♫ Come together in me now ♫
How come they get to shoot Swan and
we don't get to take any pictures?
Because they've got
exclusive rights to his life.
Where's he coming in from? Transylvania.
My boss'll go anywhere for a new sound.
Remember, no pictures of Swan!
Gentlemen, I want to tell you
of our latest work.
It's an opera.
A kind of pop cantata.
It was written
by the late Winslow Leach.
It tells the story of a young man
who sells his soul to the devil...
To become a pop star.
It will be the first
Rock version of Faust.
We'll be recording at
The Paradise, uh, Friday night.
Live on the death label.
- Mr. Preiser.
Yeah, Mr. Swan, who's gonna be
singing this, The Juicy Fruits?
No, no. They're
a reflection of the past.
Gentlemen,
I give you the future.
Beef.
Winslow.
What?
- Good morning.
- Hi.
- What day is it?
- Thursday. Today is Thursday.
Breakfast.
Ah.
A pick-me-up.
Uh, how's it coming? I don't
mean to rush you, of course.
Don't worry.
It'll be finished.
How's Phoenix doing?
I can't wait to hear her sing.
Phoenix is doing beautifully.
Can't wait to meet you, by the way.
Tomorrow night's the big night.
Tomorrow night.
♫ Why do you try ♫
♫ Why you got to ♫
Man, you better get yourself a castrato
for this, 'cause it's out of my range.
- Something bothering you?
- This was scored for a chick!
I'm not doin' it in drag.
You can sing it
better than any bitch.
You don't know how right
you are, Goliath.
Okay, boys.
From the bridge. Hit it.
♫ Our paths crossed and parted ♫
♫ This love affair was started ♫
♫ Long, long ago ♫
♫ Oh, this love
Survives the ages ♫
♫ And in its story
Lives are pages ♫
♫ Fill 'em up
May ours turn slow ♫
♫ Whoa, whoa ♫
- Who says I can't sing it?
- I like it. Keep working on it.
Drop an octave here,
Change a line there.
Give it a beat.
Make it completely yours.
- Let's go.
- Far out.
Doesn't that
kind of change the whole thing?
You heard what he said.
Make it yours.
As long as it sounds good, nobody's
gonna care what it's about.
- Is that so?
- Nobody cares what anything's about.
- Is that right?
- Who the hell listens to lyrics anyway?
Dry up, tubbo.
Seal it now.
This creep gets no comps.
My music! Swan!
- What was that?
- What was what?
Oh, I knew I shouldn't be screwing
around with a dead man's music.
This place is... Possessed.
- What are you talkin' about?
- You tryin' to tell me
you didn't hear that shriek?
That was somethin' trying to get
out of its premature grave,
and I don't want
to be here when it does.
Opening night prima donnas.
Look, iron man, if you're so
uptight, take a shower and cool off.
My pleasure... Bones.
♫ Life at last ♫
♫ Salutations
From the other side ♫
♫ Do you realize that all of you
Donated something horrible ♫
♫ You hated
That was part of you ♫
♫ Well, I'm your
Nightmares comin' true ♫
♫ I am your crime ♫
♫ Whoo, life at last ♫
♫ Sit and listen
While the fun begins ♫
♫ Hearts are broken
Bad guy wins ♫
♫ Sit and listen
All the cuttin' up is easy ♫
♫ And it isn't for the queasy
Or the weak of heart ♫
♫ Well, you had better start
For home ♫
♫ While there's still time... ♫
Never sing my music again.
Not here, not anywhere.
Do you understand?
Never again.
My music is for Phoenix.
Only she can sing it.
Anyone else that tries, dies.
All right, tickets.
Come on, let's see your tickets.
This is a ticket holders' line.
Everybody's got to have a ticket here.
Everybody have a ticket?
You, you got a ticket?
Sure, I have a ticket.
All right, get back in line.
Take care of the rest of this line.
Frank, open that gate.
Where the hell do you think
you're goin', tinker-bell?
Cincinnati to see my mother.
You're gonna miss the show.
- Ain't gonna be no show.
- What?
Listen, Philbin,
there really is a phantom.
He was just in my shower.
He threatened my life.
He said his music
is just for Phoenix.
Only she can sing it.
Anyone else who tries...
Dies.
What the hell
Are you talkin' about?
Tsk. Look, Philbin,
I am a professional.
I have been in this
business a long time.
Now, if I don't want to do a show,
it's not because I got stage fright.
It's because some creature from
beyond doesn't want me to do the show!
Now, gangway! Bullshit.
Now, how did that really happen?
Can't you feel the vibes
in your own house?
Bad, sport.
Real bad.
I mean, the karma's so thick around
here, you need an Aqua-Lung to breathe.
I know what it is.
Oh, you do, huh?
You wanna know what it is?
Why don't you tell me what it is?
Speed, that's what it is. Speed?
What do you know about it?
You just pass the stuff out!
I take it!
I know drug real from real real!
Do me a favor and take this.
No!
That'll bring me down.
Well, listen, my friend,
you better come down.
You better
get yourself together.
You got a show to do.
This is opening night.
Can you still sing?
Sure, I can still sing.
Help! The phantom! Help!
♫ We need a man
That is simple perfection ♫
♫ There's nothing
That's harder to find ♫
♫ Someone to lead us
Protect us and feed us ♫
♫ And help us
To make up our minds ♫
♫ We need a man
That's sophisticated ♫
♫ Quiet and strong
And well-educated ♫
♫ Where to go
What to do ♫
♫ Could it be
Somebody super like you ♫
♫ We need a man
That can stand as a symbol ♫
♫ And symbols
Have got to be tall ♫
♫ Someone with taste
And the tiniest waist ♫
♫ With his help
Would not life be a ball ♫
♫ If we had fun
He would not restrain us ♫
♫ If we got caught
He would just explain us ♫
♫ Where to go
What to do ♫
♫ Could it be
Somebody super like you ♫
♫ We pledge allegiance
To his gracefulness ♫
♫ And charming manners ♫
♫ With a voice
That's both sides' choice ♫
♫ He'll bring us
To our knees in admiration ♫
♫ He is king of all who see
And hear his perfect pitch ♫
♫ And more surprises ♫
♫ When his time has come
A stallion rises ♫
♫ We need a man with
A head on his shoulders ♫
♫ A nose that is
Simply divine ♫
♫ A Hollywood smile
And a perfect profile ♫
♫ And with eyes that
Would sparkle and shine ♫
♫ Long flowing hair
For the crowning glory ♫
♫ There'd be a man
Who could tell our story ♫
♫ Where to go
What to do ♫
♫ Could it be
Somebody super like you ♫
♫ We pledge allegiance
To his gracefulness ♫
♫ And charming manners ♫
♫ With a voice
That's both sides' choice ♫
♫ He'll bring us
To our knees in admiration ♫
♫ He is king of
All who see and hear ♫
♫ His perfect pitch
And more surprises ♫
♫ When his time has come
A stallion rises ♫
♫ Rises ♫
♫ Life at last ♫
♫ Salutations
From the other side ♫
♫ I can see that you're
The devil's pride ♫
♫ Do you realize
That all of you donated ♫
♫ Something horrible you hated
That was part of you ♫
♫ I'm your nightmares
Coming true, I am your crime ♫
♫ Life at last ♫
♫ Sit and listen
While the fun begins ♫
♫ Hearts are broken
And the bad guys win ♫
♫ Sit and listen All the cuttin' up is
easy and This isn't for the queasy ♫
♫ Or the weak of heart ♫
♫ You had better start for home
While there's still time ♫
♫ I'm the evil
That you created ♫
♫ Gettin' horny
And damn frustrated ♫
♫ Bored stiff
And I want me a woman now ♫
♫ All right ♫
♫ Whoa ♫
♫ Oh ♫
♫ Oh, yeah ♫
♫ I'm the evil
That you created ♫
♫ Gettin' horny
And damn frustrated ♫
♫ Each of you must
Stop and try me ♫
♫ All of you
Might satisfy me ♫
Somebody get
a fire extinguisher.
We want Beef!
Somebody get rid of him.
Phoenix, get out there and sing.
You're crazy. Look, some maniac
killed Beef so you could sing.
Don't disappoint him, or else there
will be more bodies out there.
♫ Our love ♫
♫ Is an old love, baby ♫
♫ It's older ♫
♫ Than all our years ♫
♫ I have seen
In strange young eyes ♫
♫ Familiar tears ♫
♫ We're old souls ♫
♫ In a new life, baby ♫
♫ They gave us a new life ♫
♫ To live and learn ♫
♫ Some time
To touch old friends ♫
♫ And still return ♫
♫ Our paths have
Crossed and parted ♫
♫ This love affair was started ♫
♫ Long ♫
♫ Long ago ♫
♫ This love
Survives the ages ♫
♫ In its story
Lives are pages ♫
♫ Fill them up ♫
♫ May ours turn slow ♫
♫ Oh ♫
♫ Our love ♫
♫ Is a strong love, baby ♫
♫ We give it all
And so receive ♫
♫ And so with empty arms ♫
♫ We must still believe ♫
♫ All souls last forever ♫
♫ So we need never
Fear good-bye ♫
♫ A kiss ♫
♫ When I must go ♫
♫ No tears ♫
♫ In time ♫
♫ We kiss ♫
♫ Hello ♫
Phoenix.
Swan.
Is Beef...
Dead.
Let's not talk about that.
Let's talk about you.
I like your name.
We won't have to change it.
You're going to be
a very big star, Phoenix.
We'll finish the cantata tomorrow night.
We'll record. We'll go on tour.
And then...
There are no words to express
what you're going to become.
I'll do anything you want.
I owe you everything.
Just give me that crowd again.
Tomorrow night. Tomorrow
night they'll be yours.
Mine.
And all I want is your voice.
Is that all?
No. We'll go
to Swanage and celebrate.
I'll wait for you in the car.
Phoenix! Phoenix!
Beef, Beef, Beef, Beef!
He wouldn't listen to me.
Where the hell is she? Philbin,
have you ever seen such a crowd?
No, and I never
wanna see another one.
Look at them. They've
really been entertained.
They never want
the show to stop.
The Paradise is more
magnificent than I ever dreamed.
Sure. How often is a rock star
fried on stage? Quite an attraction.
Don't hurt me.
I would never hurt you, Phoenix.
You know me.
I'm Winslow. Remember?
But Winslow's dead.
No, not quite.
What do you mean? Who are you?
Why do you wear that mask?
Because Swan's taken my voice,
my music, and given me this!
And now he wants you.
But you're all I have left.
Phoenix, no one will sing
in this Paradise again.
No one's ever gonna sing my "Faust" again.
No one but you.
Phoenix, leave this place,
or I will destroy you too.
You're crazy.
Why should I go with you?
Don't you hear them down there?
Why should I give that up?
They want more now.
They want much more.
They want more than
you could ever give.
- I'll give them whatever they want.
- No, Phoenix!
Get your hands off me!
I'm telling you, with that freak on
the loose, the Paradise is finished.
The Paradise is just beginning. Tomorrow
night, Phoenix will finish "Faust".
There she is.
The freak that killed Beef
is up on the roof.
Philbin, get the police.
Don't think about it. Tonight is
your night. I won't have it ruined.
Swanage.
♫ Our love ♫
♫ Is an old love, baby ♫
♫ It's older ♫
♫ Than all our years ♫
♫ I have seen
In strange young eyes ♫
♫ Familiar tears ♫
♫ We're old souls ♫
♫ In a new life, baby ♫
♫ They gave us a new life ♫
♫ To live and learn ♫
♫ Some time
To touch old friends ♫
♫ And still return ♫
♫ Our paths have
Crossed and parted ♫
♫ This love affair was started ♫
♫ Long ♫
♫ Long ago ♫
♫ This love
Survives the ages ♫
♫ In its story
Lives are pages ♫
♫ Fill them up ♫
♫ May ours turn slow ♫
♫ Oh ♫
♫ Our love ♫
♫ Is a strong love, baby ♫
♫ We give it all
And so receive ♫
♫ And so with empty arms ♫
♫ We must still believe ♫
♫ All souls last forever ♫
♫ So we need never
Fear good-bye ♫
♫ A kiss ♫
♫ When I must go ♫
♫ No tears ♫
♫ In time ♫
♫ We kiss ♫
♫ Hello ♫
Winslow,
what a foolish thing to do.
Didn't you read
your contract closely?
See where it says "terms of
agreement". Can you read what it says?
"This contract
terminates with Swan."
No more suicides, Winslow.
You gave up your right to rest in
peace when you signed this contract.
What if you do find a loophole? Is
that what you're thinking? Forget it.
That stays sealed only as long
as I have the power to bind you.
If I am destroyed,
that gaping wound opens.
You might say we terminate together.
Now get back to work.
I need a whole bunch
of new love songs for Phoenix.
And if you as much as say "boo"
to anyone at the Paradise,
you'll never see Phoenix again.
- No!
- Oh, yes.
- About the love songs, perhaps a duet.
- Never!
I'm under contract too.
Hey, Swan. Are we gonna get
to shoot pictures of you tonight?
What's this rumor you're
gonna wear a mask on stage?
Hey, how can we shoot you
if you got a mask on, man?
You can't, fools. Philbin, it was genius
making the end of the opera a wedding.
You mean Faust, instead of
burning in hell, he gets the girl?
Yes. And you, Philbin,
will be the priest.
I ain't never been a priest before.
That's terrific.
Swan, you remember me,
don't you?
You do, don't you? Swan!
Do you know him?
Well, we went steady
together in high school.
You're kidding. You're old
enough to be his mother.
This was taken twenty years ago.
My god. He doesn't
look any different.
Saturday November 19th,
1953.
Today I have decided
to kill myself.
And being the greatest
showman of my time,
I'm recording live
for the Swan archives.
Why?
It's simple.
I'm getting old.
I can't bear it.
To see this beautiful face
ravaged by the forces of time.
If I can't be young forever,
I'd rather end it all now.
- Why not?
- What?
Stay young forever.
I'm real, and I'll leave if you want.
But you did call me.
I didn't call anybody.
You said you wanted
to be young forever.
Well, here I am.
But I am stoned.
You're not real.
It really doesn't matter
what happens, does it?
What is going to happen?
For openers, you're going
to look like me forever.
Oh, this is too much.
I guess you're
supposed to be the devil.
I go by many names.
And you will make me
young forever?
This image will age
in your place.
This picture
gets old instead of me?
Yes. And you must watch it every
day just to see how lucky you are.
I'm just crazy
about pictures myself.
And the tape from which the picture
comes must be guarded at all costs.
- Why?
- When it goes, you go.
What do I have to do?
It's all here.
Read it carefully...
And then sign
at the bottom in blood.
Blood? My blood?
Messy, I know. But it's the only
way I can bind you. Tradition.
What do you have to lose?
Nothing.
I was gonna
use this on my wrist.
Your soul is damned either way.
- What soul?
- Don't waste it.
Now sign.
Ink isn't worth
anything to me, Winslow.
Now sign.
Just sign this,
and it will all be legal.
Till death do us part?
This is too much.
Come and sign. You don't want to be late
for your own funeral... wedding, do you?
Don't you think we're
rushing things a little? Ow.
Oh, blood. Stop wasting it.
Sign your name.
P-h-o...
Remember. She must be hit just as
Philbin says, "till death do you part".
Wait a minute. This may be
none of my business or anything,
But if you're gonna kill her,
why do it here tonight?
An assassination live
on television coast to coast...
That's entertainment.
When it goes, you go.
Swan, Swan, Swan, Swan!
Do you, Phoenix, take Swan to be your
wedded husband to have and to hold...
from this day forward
for richer, for poorer,
for better, for worse, in
sickness and in health? - I do.
And do you, Swan, take Phoenix
to be your wedded wife...
to have and to hold
from this day forward...
for better, for worse, in sickness
and in health till death...
- Oh, my god. Your face, what's
happened to your face?
- Winslow!
I don't understand.
Your voice, remember?
You promised me your voice.
Our contract, remember?
Winslow.
♫ Roll on, thunder
Shine on, lightning ♫
♫ The days are long and
The nights are frightening ♫
♫ And nothing matters anyway
And that's the hell of it ♫
♫ Winter comes
And the winds blow colder ♫
♫ While some grow wiser
You just grew older ♫
♫ You never listened anyway
And that's the hell of it ♫
♫ Good for nothing
Bad in bed ♫
♫ Nobody likes you and you're
Better off dead good-bye ♫ ♫ Good-bye ♫
♫ We've all come to say Good-bye,
good-bye ♫ ♫ Good-bye, good-bye ♫
♫ Born defeated
Died in vain ♫
♫ Super destructive
You were hooked on pain ♫
♫ And though your music
Lingers on ♫
♫ All of us
Are glad you're gone ♫
♫ If I could live my life
Half as worthlessly as you ♫
♫ I'm convinced that
I'd wind up burning too ♫
♫ Loved yourself
As you loved no other ♫
♫ You'd be no man's fool
You'd be no man's brother ♫
♫ We're all born to die ♫
♫ And you know, you know
That's the hell of it ♫
♫ Life's a game where
They're bound to beat you ♫
♫ And time's a trick
That can turn to cheat you ♫
♫ And we only waste it anyway
And that's the hell of it ♫
♫ Good for nothing
Bad in bed ♫
♫ Nobody likes you
You're better off dead ♫
♫ Good-bye we've come to say
good-bye ♫ ♫ Good-bye ♫
♫ Good-bye, good-bye ♫
♫ Good-bye ♫
♫ Born defeated
Died in vain ♫
♫ Super destructive
You were hooked on pain ♫
♫ And though your music
Lingers on ♫
♫ All of us
Are glad you're gone ♫
...The End...