I have a secret
What is it?
I'm just so attractive!
Why can't Koreans acknowledge
other people's merits?
That's why there are no heroes here.
I've dated a lot, you know.
But it's all a waste of time.
Another man just fell
head-over-heels for me!
They say princesses are lonely
and they're right.
I just blame it all on my charm.
I'm really not lonely.
I'm not lonely at all!
Please Teach Me English
My name is Young-Ju Na
and I'm 25 years old.
I'm an entry-level public official.
Didn't I tell you not to call me
at the office?
How many times do I have to...
Those born in '79 may get into a fight,
Stay away from gatherings. A fight?
Excuse me?
May I help you?
Hi. Um. They billed me over a hundred
thousand won for my electricity.
Um. How in the world is that possible?
I'm a single resident.
I don't have a rice cooker.
I don't have a television set.
Um. I think this must be a mistake.
Can you help me with that?
Hey! Miss! Hey! Look at me!
Say something for Christ's sake!
Doesn't anyone here speak English?
Miss! Where are you going?
You know if you've been there.
There's only one thing you can do.
Just smile.
Why are you laughing at me?
Do I look funny to you?
Time over.
Time what?
Over.
We held the 88 Olympics 15 years ago,
and made the 2002 World Cup semi-finals.
Now the 45,000 public officials of Seoul
lead the way on the road to the world!
- Not having anyone in our office who
- It can't be me.
Speaks English is embarrassing.
I have never, ever been picked for
anything at school.
Never won even the cheapest lottery ticket.
I'm just plain unlucky.
Lady Luck just despises me.
Let's hear it for Miss Young-Ju Na.
I'm sure she'll do us proud.
Can we get a new grill here!
Pass the bottle.
Making me study English because of just
one foreigner is ridiculous.
What is she saying?
You want more pork?
Oh, you want to sing? Sing a pop song!
Pop song! Pop song!
I don't want to
go to a language school.
Everyone's obsessed with English.
What's wrong with being born in Korea
and just knowing Korean?
What brought you here?
"[Spin the bottle]"
Did you see him? He's so cool.
I thought I was going to die.
At the institute.
I'm signing up.
A native speaker's class, of course.
I've been coming here long enough.
Thank you. Bye.
Bye.
Excuse me, lady.
Mister, I haven't got time for games.
Move it.
You are beautiful!
- Thank you
- Bye.
Look here.
We never met. And I don't have time.
I've made up my mind to study.
I'll be going.
But look.
My glasses are broken.
So they are.
You should be careful.
You need to take a level test.
Why?
Come on! Come on!
You can't speak a single word of English, can you?
My reading comprehension's okay.
Could you write it down?
Honey! What was your score on the
college entrance exam?
Oh, baby! Welcome to Korea!
Did you take the TOEFL or TOEIC test?
You great sexy girl!
Are you crazy?
No. I'm Park Moon-Su.
Oh my God!
I only stopped by, you see.
Can't I come back next time?
Can you speak English?
Hey! You're so cute.
Fancy meeting you here.
Is this all you?
Wow, that's so cool.
Evaluation Impossible
Not my type.
I'm concentrating on studying.
Looks like I'll be doing a lot of
studying, and nothing else.
The women here make me want to cry.
Is this level A?
Sorry about your glasses.
What?
I'm sorry.
Hello, everyone.
Nice to meet you.
Catherine Presley. This is my name.
Please call me Cathy.
I think we're going to have a really
good time together over the next few months.
As long as you guys study hard.
You kids do your best and I'll do my best.
Kids?
Isn't my Korean good?
Why? You're shocked?
Please tell me why you
want to learn English.
And after that choose
an English nickname.
Because everyone does it. Right?
English is a necessity.
Actually, this is my nineteenth institute.
More like the twentieth.
I don't see anything special yet.
And my nickname is Betty.
What's with you? Not again.
My new boss is a foreigner
so meetings are in English.
Frankly, I don't understand much.
We old-timers know words and grammar,
but can't carry on a conversation.
Mr. Lee! Mr. Lee! Can you come
and join us, please?
Would Richard be okay?
Richard. A king's name.
And next...
Would you pick one for me?
It's your nickname. Why should
I think of one for you?
Because... you are my beautiful teacher!
Okay. Um... Elvis!
Your sideburns remind me of the superstar.
Okay?
Elvis?
Good! Thank you very much!
You're very welcome.
And...
I'll just use my real name.
Everyone must have an English
nickname in this class.
Just pick any name!
My parents gave me my name.
I'll just be 'Young-Ju'.
No.
Why are you being difficult?
[You're not some kind of nationalist!]
[Nationalist.]
Choosing your English nickname
is a part of studying.
Think of an English name!
Now, you introduce your partner
to the class in English.
The person next to you
is your partner.
His nickname is Elvis.
And...
he is salesman...
and
handsome man.
And...
The end.
And next is the superstar.
What's your name again?
Na Young-Ju.
Na Young-Ju. Doesn't want a nickname.
- How do you say "plain" in English?
- Normal!
- Nor... ru-mal, Nor... ru-mal. Thank you.
- She is Normal.
Not nor... ru-mal... Normal.
She is normal.
She is normal!
Correct.
Very good!
A sweep! 3 cards!
[Was it two go? Three go!]
Yes! I'm selling!
Gambling brings out your true nature.
Always.
Really? Then what am I like?
You're nice.
What do you mean?
Nice is good for a woman.
Cut the cards!
Women who stand out have difficult lives.
There's nothing special about me?
This is the ninth game.
How many times did you sit out?
Seven times?
See! Your life is meant to be plain.
Plain?
Yeah, plain.
PLAIN!
How could you say that to your daughter?
Bah!
Cathy.
It's Cathy.
Cathy! One question.
What is your question, Elvis?
What is your handphone number?
Not handphone.
My mobile phone number is private.
Okay. My joke.
How do you describe a beautiful
and sexy lady?
Gorgeous.
Gorgeous?
Yeah. Everyone,
Repeat. Gorgeous.
Gorgeous.
Gorgeous equal Cathy.
Really!
Hello!
I picked a nickname, but you didn't ask.
It's Candy!
Candy!? That's it for today, everyone.
See you next time.
Bye.
Bye, Cathy.
I should have called myself "Normal".
Wait for me!
Size 5. Candy, you have
such cute, little feet.
Thank the gods! I have found
the owner of this shoe!
I'm an entry-level public official.
Aren't you getting in?
This is the man I've
been waiting for!
What number are you taking?
Number 111.
Me, too...
I see...
[I don't like subway trains.]
They say the subway is a
lunch box for cannibals.
Yeah...
es, I'm an idiot.
Hey? It's here. It's here.
I'm sorry.
What a ditz!
Stamp my heart with a seal of love!
Sorry to all the studs in Korea.
I'm already taken.
Wow, 2 minutes and 35 seconds!
I tied Dad's record.
We have a saying.
You can read a person's life in their feet.
Obviously you are graceful and classy.
And will continue to forever...
You are just too much.
Did you know...
you have such small, exquisite
feet for someone of your stature.
Really.
Yes, yes. Wrap these up.
Bye-bye, cutie pie!
Please, come again.
Miss Lee. I'll ask something
in English and you answer!
I'm busy.
It's easy. Translate this.
I love you long!
You think I'm stupid?
I've loved you for a long time.
Me too, Miss Lee.
Right?
No. The answer is
"I will love you for a long time."
Welcome to our store.
Try on anything you like.
Do you have these in size 5?
These are size 5.
I think these would look good on you.
Aren't they... too plain?
Plain is good, you know.
Take a seat and try them on.
And throw these away.
You should just sell the plain ones,
or else not have those on display.
Here you go.
I have a lot of plain ones at home.
Hi, Yunjin. I've been so busy, baby.
So many overseas business trips.
I don't even have time to
go to the bathroom.
I'll call you back later.
What is it! Wait, wait, wait.
Wait.
You good-for-nothing bum!
You're eyeballing
a married woman now!
What married woman?
Ms. Lee in the ladies' bags section!
Her second child is already crawling!
Second?
The nerve of that woman,
pretending to be available.
What a witch.
You're a disgrace to me,
just like your lousy father!
What? Mom!
If you ever say I'm like him again,
I'll move out!
Pronunciation is very important
Listen, look,
Repeat.
Russia!
Good! Next word.
Italy
Excellent!
Now, get your bodies into this one.
Brazil
Candy, why aren't you doing it?
Try it by yourself!
Brazil
Zoo
Shape your lips like a doughnut.
Sorry!
Cathy, how long do we have to do this?
What did you say?
I'm leaving for the U.S. Any day.
When do we get to speak?
I can study pronunciation with a tape.
I don't need to pay for that.
Don't you agree?
Hey, Jolie!
I've been to almost 20 institutes.
But this is the slowest class.
Koreans are always rushing everything.
Do You want to learn how
to speak English well?
Then do as I say!
I came here to learn quickly.
I don't have money to burn, you know?
And she talks condescendingly in Korean.
It's because her Korean's not that good.
My Korean is fine.
That's it for tonight! See you next time!
Ashtray.
Unification.
Side dish.
This is a tough one.
Adoption.
Adoption?
He doesn't know.
Adoption.
Wow! That's amazing.
How do you memorize all that?
I just memorized some vocabulary.
What good is vocabulary when
you can't even open your mouth.
Don't you have to go home
and cook something?
Why don't you go cook!
English is all about words. This guy
in my hometown ate two dictionaries.
Now he's at Seoul National University.
That was in the old days.
I hear yelling in English is the
hottest thing nowadays.
They say you start talking fluently
after only 30 days!
Where do they teach that?
That's where I need to go.
That's no good. It's too embarrassing.
Elvis... I have a question.
What's your cell phone number?
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
It's the alcohol, that's what it is...
I think I'm drunk.
Your shoes are too small.
I'm a size 5! You want to see?
Ladies first. Sit down.
No, no.
Sit down, Elvis. Please.
Will you just sit down and
stop embarrassing me!
I'm okay.
Okay, okay. You're creasing it.
Sit.
Just sit down.
I'm okay.
All right. I'll sit.
Where are you going?
Hold on.
I had this custom made.
What?
What style do you like?
I like casual, but I usually wear suits.
No, no. What kind of woman?
Woman?
I don't care.
I might look at her character? Why?
By any chance...
Did someone ask you to ask me?
Tell them that for the next 3 months,
I'm only studying.
I won't have time for anything else,
so she should forget about me.
That's what I'd like to say,
but that would be bad manners.
Is she pretty?
In 3 months, I'll have a lot of time.
I wouldn't say pretty...
But she has a great character.
And she has little feet.
Is her English good?
A little.
When I find a woman to love,
I'll confess to her in English.
"I love you" in Korean is so corny.
"I love you, darling."
English feels different, doesn't it?
But if she doesn't understand English,
that would be embarrassing.
English, I will master you completely!
Come on, English!
Come on Elvis!
I AM NOT NORMAL
What has she been drinking...
I'll call the police
if you don't get down!
I love you!
Honey, call the police! Now!
Good night. E-L-V-l-SSSSSSS!!!!!!
I am the king of English!
Catherine! Wait! Coming soon!
Every gorgeous woman.
I'm Park Moon-Su.
Korean-American lawyer searching for birth mother
years after being adopted to the U.S.
Mom.
Mom, come on over here!
Come on, come on!
You have to yell to speak English?
You don't want to say anything
when you meet her?
You want to be a fool?
Your posture is important.
Bend your legs!
Straighten your back!
Hold your stomach in!
Right?
I! LO VE! VICTORIA!
I...
Make your voice ring out through Seoul!
Don't be so timid!
Loudly this time.
- I!
LOVE!
- Victoria!
- Bacteria!
We're trying to sleep here!
What the hell!
Yesterday... I worked on my English.
On a mountain top.
Elvis, you try.
What did you do yesterday?
Very sorry.
So many absences! You can't
even answer simple questions.
If your English is bad,
you must study hard.
[Foundation-elementary level]
Foundation,,,
Heavy traffic.
Do you have a problem with me?
Apologize quickly.
That's it. From now on you will speak
only English during this class.
Only English!
It will be difficult at first,
but if you try, you will get better.
Speaking Korean is not allowed in this class.
Only English!
I'm sorry.
What a temper.
I know.
Is it over?
Why isn't it coming?
Is there a strike?
Elvis, you know...
Only English!
If you don't have anything
special to do this weekend
Would you like to go to a movie
on Saturday with me?
You understand?
She's asking what the
Saturday movie is.
What was it?
No.
Hello.
Oh, Cathy. I am Elvis.
This phone is Cathy phone! Tonight?
No problem! Coming soon. Yes!
Are you meeting Cathy?
You are... meeting her.
You're meeting Cathy.
Hey, taxi!!
Go then.
He really went to see her.
Driver, follow that cab!
Are you mental? This is a bus.
This is who I am!
A public official!
Where exactly do you work?
Step on it! You'll lose him!
Don't worry. No one has ever
shaken me off yet.
I'm getting off!
Driver!
Hey, Mike. You've been busy?
Excuse me? Excuse me
Hi? Remember me? I'm the guy who had
the wrong electricity bill! Remember?
Hello?
Hi. Yeah. That got taken care of.
Did you do that?
You don't know what a problem
that was for me.
Do you want a drink?
Can you handle Whisky?
One glass, please.
Ladies and gentleman!
The talent guest you have
all been waiting for!
You can call me Tony.
How can I address you?
Thank you!
No, No, How-can-l-address-you?
My Address?
Address?
Guro-dong.
Guro-dong! That's a beautiful name.
Nice to meet you Guro-dong. Cheers!
Me? Again?
She's had enough. She's drinking
everything he gives her.
Are you OK?
Are you drunk?
Do you need to go home? Um...
If you want, I could drive you home.
I have a really nice car.
Thank you, Jessie!
Elvis, do you dance well?
Okay.
Is there anyone else?
Can you tap dance?
Sure!
Come on.
Wait.
Beautiful couple!
Cathy and Elvis will tap dance!
My technology!
What the hell is she doing?
Are you okay?
Elvis... Run, quickly... Run... RUN!
Candy.
Can you get up?
What?
What do you want?
This is medicine.
And this is soondae.
And deokbokki.
And I made Korean pancakes.
Have all of it.
What's all this?
Candy!
Am I a bad teacher?
Do you like Elvis that much?
It's carrot!
(Of course!)
I don't care for him.
He's kind of cute, but he's not my type.
Cathy, you are my good friend!
Help yourself.
I don't know who that could be.
Tyson, what are you doing here?
What's wrong with your head?
Oh, Don't worry about it.
You're far away from home.
I thought you might like this.
Thank you! I love pizza!
Candy's here, too. You want to come in?
I have more deliveries.
Oh That's a shame!
Then see you later.
You know... Cathy.
[Language reflects their personality.]
You should learn to speak polite form.
But it's so hard.
If it's hard, just say "yoo" at the end.
You?
You?? I don't understand.
Like, this. I love yooooo...
Bye.
I love yooo...
You want more? You eat a lot!
No wonder your butt's so big.
Hi, Cathy.
Good evening everyone!
Good evening, Cathy!
Please, look at the board.
These are your partners from now on.
Good?
But Cathy!
Sit down!
Sit, sit sit.
Why are you following me?
We're partners.
That's not final. Sit down here.
At other institutes,
we changed partners every day.
This man no good...
no change... no money...
I want to change, too.
Okay...
You can use Korean.
Stop!
We need teamwork to improve your English.
Meet your partner often
outside of class and practice.
Hi, we are team.
Yes!
You don't want me as a partner?
No. It's a good thing.
We're in class... You shouldn't...
Let's think of only English!
Candy, don't ever wear sexy clothes.
Let's study really really hard!
I don't wear sexy clothes.
That's right... Sorry.
You're welcome.
Oh, no!
That's all right!
Thank you. - You're welcome.
Sorry. - That's all right.
This is annoying.
How come you speak so well!
You could be like me. Really.
Where are you from? Brazil?
No! I'm American.
I know you. You are my sister Victoria!
Yes, You're my brother Moon-su?
Yes, I love you!
Oh- Victoria,
Do you love your mother?
You're making a fool of yourself!
Let's use only English at home!
Nonsense! Turn it on,
before I get really nasty!
Mencius' mother moved three times
for her son's education!
Maybe her kid was smart!
Or I'll run away from home.
Our daughter is studying so hard!
I've never been so moved.
Honey!
Go on out then.
Then I'll just have to stop
giving you my paycheck.
Wait!
Darling...
Okay, okay, okay. Puke?
No, no, no, no.
Okay, okay. Water. Water.
Es, water!
Yo, yo, yo. What's up, mommy.
Basketball, get out of here.
Give me the money, please.
- Water.
- What's up, Daddy!
Who are you?
Thank you.
Oops! Oh, I'm sorry.
Where my stamp?
Oh, my goodness!
Good-bye, child!
Your English is terrible.
Try to speak in full sentences.
That way you can improve your English.
Are you okay?
Yes, no problem!
Oh, now it's time for me to study.
We have piles of notices to send out.
You can't go today!
Young-Ju, you're going to class?
Es, sir!
So we're neighbors but haven't seen
each other for a while, right?
That's right. Say something to your neighbor.
Hey. Hi.
- Hi.
- Yeah.
Why don't you say something?
I'm so happy to see her that
I don't know what to say.
Just say anything. Candy, you go first.
My mobile phone number is 011-3...
Candy.
Oh, sorry. My e-mail is w-o...
Candy. That's enough.
Tyson and Betty. Your turn.
What time is it now?
Did you have lunch?
Tyson! You have to speak out your
answers to improve your English.
All right?
Yes. Cathy.
Yeah, go on. You don't need me.
Were you embarrassed back there?
A little.
Sorry very much.
Candy. It's "Thank you very much."
Not "Sorry very much".
I mean, I'm not that good,
but you're really not improving.
You have to admit my pronunciation
got better, right?
I listen to CNN every night.
Now I understand almost 90%.
Do you understand any of it?
Understand, my ass.
I have to watch my soap opera.
She looks like she understands...
the way she's frowning and all.
Mom, I'm home!
Hurry up. Get in here.
Who is it? Give me that.
Hello?
It's Moon-Young, isn't it?
It sounds like her voice.
Be quiet!
- Can you speak English?
- Okay!
Good! It's only two weeks left.
And... I miss you. I miss you!
She say's she's "Miss Yoo".
- Anyway, it's nice to hear your voice...
- Can't you say something in English?
I AM speaking in English.
Okay? It's English, too!
Hello? Hello?
What do... how do?
What?
What is your Saturday movie?
Can you hold? I'll get someone else.
Hello? I'm Luna Kim.
Victoria wants me to say hello
to her mother.
Why couldn't I remember "How do you do?"
I'm not going to meet her.
How could I look her in the eye?
What is it now?
When your father ran off
with another woman...
I wasn't sure I could
raise you two by myself.
But the more I think about it,
I should have raised you both,
if I had been a good mother.
Not again!
I'm sick and tired of
learning English, too.
Good. We both could have
made a huge mistake.
You shouldn't have had her
if you couldn't raise her.
You shouldn't have looked for her
if you were going to give her away.
What is this!
I would have thrown you away
if I'd known you'd be like your father!
Yeah, keep going.
Take all my money while you're at it.
It's for you.
Hello. This is Young-Ju's cell phone.
Candy?
Who on earth is making crank
calls at this hour?
What, Elvis?
If you're Elvis, I'm Nam Jin.
Listen. "In a green field..."
Hello.
Candy!
Are you cold?
No! Not at all.
I called too late, didn't I?
No, it's only one o'clock.
I can't believe you came out
just because I asked you to.
Of course!
I was dreaming about you.
And then you called. Strange, isn't it?
Why was I in your dream?
It's not like I have nowhere to go.
We were studying in class as usual.
Open.
We're taking over this building.
Drop all your weapons.
You're under arrest.
Shut up! We will now conduct a level test.
Failure to answer will result
in the gas chamber. Do you understand?
You!
Me?
What kind of woman do you like?
I like gorgeous woman!
Passed! Stand up!
- You!
- You talking to me?
Shut up! Just answer me in English!
What is your favorite movie?
What?
Listen carefully!
WHAT-IS-YOUR-FAVORITE-MO VIE?
M-O-V-l-E, MO VIE!
Oh~! Movie!
Quiet!
Zero-Zero-Seven!
Double-O Seven. You mean James Bond?
Yes!
Why?
Elvis! Help me! Elvis!
SOS!
I'll be back!
Why did you pick that movie
when you couldn't even explain?
Have you ever dreamt about me?
What?!!!
You have, haven't you?
You dreamt about me!
Just once.
I was so shocked because you were in it.
Why?
It was a beach in Miami, not Korea.
My Emmi Restaurant
[(Mom's Sushi Bar)]
No way. I don't wear bikinis.
Just listen. It's my dream!
You looked really gorgeous in my dream.
Unfortunately, you were sleeping.
Then you saw me naked!
You had a swimsuit on.
It was a bikini!
I couldn't help myself.
I have to touch this woman.
I have no choice. Just do it!
Never! Never!
That's it.
Elvis, never stop.
To be continued.
[To take off her clothing]
D. None of the above.
A.
Oh, my goodness! You stripped me naked!
I checked the dictionary after I woke up.
The answer was B.
Then nothing happened.
You wanted me to strip you?
Of course not.
How could you get that wrong?
It's fun talking to you
late into the night.
Really?
Why do you like talking to me?
When I look at you...
I don't think of women.
So it's really comfortable.
All I think of is studying English.
You're leaving?
This isn't your bedroom.
Why are you sleeping out here?
It's embarrassing.
Lower your voice. Everyone's sleeping.
Who's listening?
Is this loud? Then say so!
What will I do with you!
Would you stop hitting me?
Did you eat?
No, you were probably chasing some girl.
How come you turn silly
at the sight of every skirt?
At least your dad had taste. He had me.
I'm sick of that story.
There are plenty of good girls after me.
You'd want any of them
to be your daughter-in-law.
You see what you want to see.
I doubt there's anyone decent.
There's a public official, you know!
A public official? Who is she?
That's enough. Let's go in.
How old is she?
I'm teaching her English.
She's not that bad.
So how old is she!
Doesn't think of women.
See me as a woman.
What are you mumbling?
I see it in your eyes. You want me.
Your eyes look really big
without your glasses!
I get that a lot.
People say they could dive in
because they're like lakes.
Now that I look closely...
You look just like an alien!
Their faces are this small
and have almond-shaped eyes!
Doesn't everyone say that?
Everyone. Look at me! We're going
on a picnic this weekend.
My foreign friends are going, too.
We're going to Candy's
grandfather's house.
I hear it's in a beautiful village.
Then we have to stay overnight!
I can't stay out overnight.
Candy
Stop!
My grandfather has a famous pig.
It was on the news. Didn't you see it?
Did you see it?
The pig that understands English.
What kind of pig is that?
Well, you spread letters on the ground.
You say "A!" and it brings the A.
You say "B!" and it brings the B.
It even knows some words, too.
No way!
Really!
There are so many of you.
Nice to meet you.
Are these all your friends?
There're all shapes and sizes.
These are my classmates, and the
foreigners just came along.
This is Cathy, our English teacher.
Thank you for teaching our
little granddaughter, Ma'am.
It's nice to meet you!
Why, this woman...
Thank you, too!
Grandma, how have you been?
It's been ages.
Candy, where's the famous pig?
Yeah, that pig?
It was here, but we ate it
at the last village party.
Oh, my God! Why eat such
a great pig? Why?
You made it up, didn't you?
No, I didn't.
I thought there really was a pig
that knew English.
I need to ask a favor. It's real easy.
Just memorize a few letters.
I have to show Moon-Su I wasn't lying.
I suggest you cooperate quietly.
Why? No?
Do you know I like bacon?
[Pork rib.,, bacon.]
A looks like this. Easy, isn't it?
And these are B and C.
They're easy to tell apart.
Pick one of the three. C!
Oh, you pig!
What are you doing here?
You have something in your eye?
No. They're originally like this.
You have to try a different
teaching method. Be gentle.
Give me that.
What a sexy sow you are.
Boars must drool over you!
Hey, you want to have some fun
with this handsome guy?
Which one is 'A'?
A. A. Go on.
Don't shake it. She won't come.
That's it!
She's running away!
Young-Ju!
There she is! Stop right there!
There she is.
Elvis, grab her!
Where are your shoes?
I lost them while I was running.
That was clumsy of you.
Why do you squint like that?
I kept them open extra-wide before.
It's bleeding!
It's all right.
No. It's not all right.
Get on my back.
I'm fine. I'm too embarrassed.
Come on.
I'm heavy, aren't I?
Keep your eyes open
comfortably from now on.
Okay.
I was heavy, wasn't I?
Yeah.
Go Candy!
How did you find them?
I used to be a scout. A boy scout.
Thank you so much!
Shall I get you a pair of shoes?
Oh, no.
Do you have red ones?
I've always wanted red ones.
I'll get you ten pairs so you can
wear them for life!
Really?
You cold?
No cold.
Happy!
Good people in this scenic village
The fresh air and the peaceful silence
It opens up my heart.
Me, too.
I wish to live like the wind and clouds!
Me too.
That doesn't seem like you.
I was just kidding.
I know I don't seem like that.
Plain, boring, and not sexy.
Stop that!
Ou did at first, but I take back
what I said about you being normal.
You're different, you know.
Special?
I'm special to you?
You could say that.
Don't you want to say
something in English?
Not yet.
Then when?
After I learn more.
Let's go in.
Okay.
Goodnight, Young-Ju.
I found it in the yard.
When did that fall out?
I saw the picture. She's hot.
Yeah.
What does she do?
She's a lawyer in New York.
Her English is great.
Americans get frustrated talking to her
because her pronunciation is so good.
That's why you learn English.
Yes.
I want to see her.
Sun Tzu's The Art of War states that...
knowing the enemy brings victory.
Let's go for lunch.
Age? A little younger than me.
I bet she had her face done.
But English... No contest!
I've lost the will to fight
now that I know my enemy.
Orange juice please.
No, we have only coffee.
Okay, milk coffee please.
No. We have no milk.
You're cutting class today, too?
You got dumped, didn't you?
So you're quitting altogether?
How are your classes going?
I'm not going back. No, I can't.
Why is it a disgrace not
to be able to speak English?
I was never uncomfortable
not knowing any English until now.
You use it maybe one week
in all the years you study it.
It's crazy!
I gave up on English but
I got a perfect score in Korean!
If you pressure me, I'll file
a complaint with City Hall!
I didn't say anything.
Is something wrong with them?
No, no.
Weird.
What are you doing here so late?
It's the last week of class...
You have to come tomorrow.
No.
Why?
I hate English.
It's Elvis. Isn't it?
What happened between you two anyway?
Stop talking about him.
I know you are good teacher, good friend,
but from now stay out of my life.
It's none of your business.
Candy... I am sorry.
What?
Young-Ju, you are not the
person I thought you were!
And you know... For someone
who says they hate English,
you speak it very well.
Today, I'm just going to ask you
some questions about your plans.
Remember to answer in English. Jolie?
Oh, yes.
I have a plan...
Oh! Candy!
Hey!
Young-Ju is here.
I thought you'd given up.
Hey! Welcome, my partner!
Don't use English when
you can't speak it well.
And stop taking an interest in me.
So many men want me.
Maybe I should date a negative
speaker. (She means native speaker)
- Long time no see!
- I miss you...
Everybody, tomorrow is our last class,
so why don't we all go out together and celebrate.
I have one suggestion!
I quit the pizza place and now
I work in a Korean restaurant.
I'll buy all of you lunch.
Really!
You're coming tomorrow?
I don't think I can.
That meeting is tomorrow.
Please.
I'll try.
Your English is really good now.
I was bad.
No, it was for the best.
I'll be over him in no time.
Game is over.
Moon-Su!
Nice to meet you.
Call me brother Moon-Su.
I'm your brother.
Try on the suit you'll be wearing.
I'm picking it up at the
dry cleaner's at noon.
Is this for Moon-Young?
No, it's for someone else.
You're at it again.
Another girl?
You worry about your problems.
Stop worrying about everything else.
Don't talk to me like that.
You're giving them to that
public official, aren't you?
You got it all wrong.
She couldn't be further from my mind.
That's the problem with you.
You don't see what you have.
If you buy a woman shoes,
she'll run off in them.
Where are you going? Moon-Su!
I'll be right back.
How is it?
It's really good.
This pork is simply delicious.
But where's Elvis?
I think he said he had an appointment.
How do you say "sambap" in English?
Do they have "sambap" in America?
Wouldn't they call it "sam-rice"?
It's "sambap" in English, too.
I was eating that when
I got picked to learn English.
Candy isn't a size 5!
Hong, is there a size 6 of red strip shoes?
Yeah, bring them over.
"Victory Soccer Team Ladies' Shoe Dept"
Why? I can't. I'm in a jogging suit.
Taxi!
His name is Park Moon-Su
and he's not bad looking.
He's in my class,
but he didn't come today.
He's not here either?
No.
Then where is he?
Candy, she's looking for Moon-Su.
She would know.
Hey.
Are you the public official?
You know me?
Could you find my good-for-nothing son?
I have to go to Amiga or Omega Hotel with him.
Wait till I get my hands on him!
Could you take me there?
The girl from the picture?
Getting engaged already?
Let's go!
She doesn't look as good as
in the picture.
Mother? I'm Victoria.
Please, have a seat.
Mother? You're not even married.
You cow!
Okay, I sit. Because Mother want.
Oh, you speak English. Good. Translate for me.
Please don't cry.
Past is past. I don't remember anything.
I just came here to say hello...
It's good to see you.
Tell her this first.
I didn't do it because I hated you.
I deserve to be punished.
My mind has never been at ease.
Wondering if you're eating well,
if people were good to you.
That's too long.
Tell her everything. Please!
What did she say?
Hmm... Mother said...
What's "punished"? "furnished"?
Please tell her not to cry.
You be quiet. She cry because of you!
Isn't that too short?
English is like that.
Did you say she's pretty?
And thanks for growing up well?
That's...
She said you are beautiful.
But, the picture is better.
What?
You stay here.
I don't think I introduced
myself... Hi... I'm Victoria.
What's wrong? Is it me?
You think I shouldn't have come?
Yes!
Did you say yes?
Yes.
Mother hate you. Moon-su hate you.
And everybody hate you.
Why?
Why?? Because... Because...
You are not Korean!
Ok! Tell her I came with good intentions.
And that I hope she's happy.
You might as well go sightseeing
since you're here already...
Good day, sir.
I told them not to write this on the back.
Or at least have it in English.
Soccer team for ladies!
I can't do anything with this.
Hi. Victoria.
I'm Elvis.
Nice to meet you.
I love you. Victoria.
I love you, too.
I didn't mean to do that to that girl.
I just blurt out things
before I think about them.
I'm not a bad person.
I'm sorry, Moon-Su!
What are you talking about?
She said she was staying here.
We have no Bacteria or Bacterium
staying at our hotel.
We're meeting her at the coffee shop!
Where were you? I already met her.
But she's gone.
Why?
I went out to cry and
she just disappeared.
That public official girl was with me.
What girl?
That girl you talked about.
She's wearing your shoes.
We have to find Moon-Young first!
Could you check to see if...
Please believe me. We do not lie to our clients.
She was here just 5 minutes ago!
Are you calling me a liar?
I'm sorry. Mom, stay over there.
Go where?
Would you just go!
Why, you lousy...
Her name is Victoria.
She's a lawyer from the U.S.
I was out playing golf, you see.
Please check again.
She checked out.
What is it? Get up.
This isn't our house!
You want me to get you a blanket?
You can't go! Don't go!
Don't go, don't go. Never! Never! Never!
Over my dead body!
Victoria, get out. You out car!
Victoria! Please forgive me.
I'm a liar! Mother said...
Mother... Mother like you... Moon-su want you.
What are you talking about?
Please calm down and let me go.
They are waiting for you.
We have to leave now.
There'll be a lot of traffic.
Please don't go, Victoria!
Please.
Don't just sit anywhere.
Victoria, I'm your brother.
Call me brother Moon-Su.
You know? Mother everyday
see your picture.
Really. She's always looking at it.
I've seen her with it all my life.
Mother...
My baby!
Brother!
A lady asked me to give you these shoes.
My shoes.
Where's that girl?
My one-sided love is over.
Nothing ever happens in my life.
That's normal.
Because I really AM normal.
Young-Ju!
Candy?
Young-Ju Na!
Young-Ju! Candy!
Candy?
It's me, Elvis!
Candy! Young-Ju!
Candy, it's me, Moon-Su.
Candy!
Young-Ju! Candy!
Young-Ju!
Candy!
I have something to tell you.
Victoria isn't my girlfriend.
She's my sister!
So stop hiding from me!
Candy!
Who's Candy?
I may be a player, but I wouldn't
date my own sister!
I have principles, you know!
You're weird to think that.
God, he's so loud.
So he's admitting he's a playboy?
Is he retarded or what?
It's because she's his sister.
We're getting off here, right?
Yeah.
Hold on. Then who's younger,
Victoria or the playboy?
You are!
Don't piss me off!
He said Victoria thought
her brother was a playboy.
You're sure?
Okay.
Victoria is his sister?
That's right.
Sure.
Young-Ju Na!
Here he is again.
Hey, then who's Candy?
You're Candy.
Come here, you jerk.
I'm Park Moon-Su and
I have to see you today!
Young-Ju!
Candy!
I just need it for a minute.
Young-Ju Na!
Why are you always taking my paper?
- Victoria is my sister...
- What did I ever do to you?
What is she doing?
Young-Ju?
Young-Ju.
I've never really dated anyone.
So, what I mean is...
You're so slow! You want to
go out with her, right?
Yes!
I do.
I love you!
I really love you.
No, you don't.
There is no way you could.
You said when you really loved
someone, you'd propose in English.
So it's not me.
Of course not. I'm so plain...
Someone like you wouldn't like me.
No, "love" sounds better in Korean.
Then does "kiss" sound better in English or Korean?
Well, there are a lot of people here...
So what I'm saying is...
What a cute little baby!
Is it a boy or girl?
Our little princess.
She looks just like you.
Yeah, you think?
Look at her! She looks just like me!
Absolutely!
Enjoy your day. Bye, bye. Have a nice day!
Mommy!
Our baby spoke for the first time.
She'll learn to speak.
She'll learn English too someday
and it will be hard.
Then I'll tell him to speak up boldly
for someone will answer him.
She wet herself again!
Honey, get me a diaper.
I left them in the car.
Why did you do that?
You expect me to go?
No, I'll go.
I came to my hometown. I'm very happy.
Because I have a beautiful wife.
But I have a problem.
She keeps speaking Korean, not English.
She sells seashells on the seashore.
Korean is so beautiful.
Beautiful!
Now, I drive a cab.
I often go Incheon airport, because I can talk to foreigners.
Oh, I also have something to confess.
This is my wife...
We didn't mean to hide it.
I'm taking our Yoo-Jeong to Canada.
We'll be staying there for about two years.
I'll be a long distance father for a while.
If you cheat on me, I'll kill you.
I'm going abroad to study.
America? No. I'm going to China.
I think I could master
Chinese in short time.
Call me if you come to Beijing.
See you!
Scene 49, cut 3, take 2
Their faces are this small
and have almond-shaped eyes!
Doesn't everyone say that?
You'd want any of them to be your daughter-in-law.
There are plenty of...
I'm an... wait...
Sorry. - That's all right.
How come you...
I have no choice. Just do it!
Those kind of thoughts came to me!
Cut!
God! Scary!
How did you do that? How?
I don't know.