They've sure been under there a long time.
I don't like it.
I'm worried.
And I'm very concerned.
Well, I'm not!
The Friz wouldn't let anything happen to the
Magic School Bus! Ever!
She might not have a choice, Wanda. A VMl is a
very powerful person.
A very powerful person!. I thought a VMl was a
Vehicle Maintenance lnspector.
It is, Ralphie.
But Carlos just called Junket a Very Powerful
Person.
He's BOTH, Ralphie! A VMl and a VPP!
Well, Mr. Junket... a bus for all seasons, don't
you think!.
It's missing a SPRlNG or two -
and it's ready to FALL apart, if that's what you
mean.
Look at this! There's acid all over the paint...the
fenders are dented...
and the roof looks like it got hit by a meteorite!
Ah! I know. Isn't that wonderful!.!
This engine doesn't look any better!
Looks can be so deceiving, can't they!. That
engine runs like a dream.
Well, I don't know how, your sparkplugs are shot!
It's a miracle this bus even starts!
To the contrary, Mr. Junket. My bus is reliable,
responsible and dependable.
Well...now it's ex-pendable!
And therefore, I'm recommending that your bus
be sent to the junk yard!
Oh, no! Junket wants to junk it!
HE can't do that! Not our bus!
I realize our bus may not look its best right now -
but I assure you there is absolutely nothing
wrong with it.
Why, there's even something magical about it.
Magical!.! Really, Ms Frizzle!
I don't recall anything in the safety manual about
magic.
I have a suggestion. Why don't you take a test
drive with me and the kids!.
Let me prove to you that from engine to exhaust -
my bus is as fit as any bus in the fleet!
Ah! Sorry, I have to get back to the office and
accept my award
for Vehicle Maintenance lnspector of the Year.
I heard all about it. Congratulations.
You did!. How nice. Well, I suppose we could
take a short drive.
Class!. Time to take chances,
get messy and take Mr. Junket for a ride! To the
bus!
What if the bus doesn't pass the test!.
What if the engine stalls!.
Comfortable, Mr. Junket!.
You must be joking! The seats are saggy and the
springs have sprung!
Just feel the power.
It's almost as if we're flying up this hill, don't you
think!.
I've had smoother rides on a roller coaster!
I don't know how I let you talk me into this.
The junk heap is too good for this bus!
I wish Mr. Junket wouldn't talk about our bus that
way!
Maybe if we told him how much we love it - he'd
change his mind.
I doubt it, Feeb.
Juknket's going to scrap our bus unless we do
something to stop him!
Chill out, you guys. If I know Ms Frizzle - she's
got a plan.
Then again, maybe she doesn't.
"Oh... dear... what can the matter be..."
I knew it! I knew I shouldn't have listened to you!
I knew I shouldn't have taken this test drive. Now
I'm going to miss my award!
Here's your cap, Mr. Junket.
Oh! I just can't seem to find the problem. The
engine just stopped working.
However-
That's it! I've had it!
This bus is condemned!
The first phone I see I'm calling a tow truck! This
bus is history!
I'll be back!
Don't you just love it when things like this
happen!.
It adds such spark to the day!
What are we going to do!. He's going to take our
bus away!
Not if we can start it before he gets back!
Hurry Ms Frizzle! Hurry!
Nice noise, bus... but is it the right noise!.
Maybe Mr. Junket was right. Maybe our bus lS
busted.
No way, Tim! We can't let our bus down. We've
GOT to get it started!
But how can we get it working if we don't even
know how it works!.
I know how it works! Sort of I mean, an engine
makes the bus run, right!.
Well, that's certainly fuel for thought!
But we put gas in before we left.
Yes, but the gas tanks all the way in the back...
and the engine's all the way up here!
I knew that!
Then maybe...the gas isn't getting from back
here...
to all the way up here for some reason!
If we could just follow the gas to the engine - we
could find out the problem!
How can we possibly do that!.
All set, Keesha!.
HEADS UP!
Why'd I even ask...This is a field trip, isn't it!.
Look at it this way, Arnold. If we don't fix the bus
now -
there may never be another field trip!
Let's go! We've got a bus to save!
HlT lT, LlZ!
Hey, what happened!.
What's going on!.!
Where are we going!??.!!!
I know that smell... its gasoline!
I HATE that smell!
Get used to it, Arnold. We're inside the bus's gas
tank!
Okay. So the question is, how does the gas get
from all the way back here -
to all the way up to the engine!.
That way! The gas is going into some kind of
tunnel or pipe!
As Christopher Columbus said when he set sail
to look for America...
All aboard for PARTS unknown!
Stroke! Stroke! Stroke!
Faster! Faster!
The sooner that bus is out of my life the better!
Friz to Liz... Friz to Liz...Come in please...
We're moving out of the fuel tank, Liz, and into
the fuel line.
Stand by! Ready! Set! Duck!
It's a tight squeeze in here.
I guess gas doesn't need a lot of room to get to
the engine.
Look up ahead! The gas seems to be trying to
get through...
but it's blocked by something!
Is it just me, or is that peanut butter I smell!. It lS
peanut butter!
Maybe this is what's stopping the gas from
getting through to the engine.
And without gas - the engine won't run! That's it!
Make way for the gas!
But what's peanut butter doing inside the fuel
line!.
Good question!
JUNKET!
We're almost there! Step on it! I'm getting an
award today, did I tell you!.
Twice!
Line's clear, Ms Frizzle!
The gas is flowing again!
Then the engine should start, right, Ms Frizzle!.
We'll soon find out! Seats, everyone! TURN THE
KEY, LlZ!
Where are we!.
Are we inside the engine, Ms Frizzle!.
Technically, no. We've just been pumped into the
carburetor...
ah my favorite place! Keep pumping Liz!
I don't get it! We got the gas flowing - how come
the engine won't start!.
Maybe it needs more than just gas.
Maybe it's too chilly in here for the gas to work.
I feel a draft, too.
It's coming from that opening, up there.
Right you are, Tim!
Air! Of course! Don't you remember what we
learned in Fire Safety!.
You need air for things to burn - and since a
running engine burns gas -
the engine needs gas AND air to run!
Well, we're not getting THAT much air.
That's because something's covering the
opening.
A peanut butter sandwich!.
JUNKET!
YOU ever win an award!.
Let's just get that bus, okay!.
Yeah. Sure.
How come I have to be on the bottom!.!
The class-stack up was MY idea!
It's really stuck! Wait... I think I'm getting it!
Almost...GOT lT!
LOOK OUT!
WHAT lS THAT! OH, NO! A TOW TRUCK!
There's a tow truck out here! They're going to tow
us away!
Hold on, Arnold!
Now that we have gas and air, maybe the engine
will work!
Start it up, Liz!
LlZ! Oh! Come on, Liz, don't quit on us now!
Champions thrive on adversity! TURN THE KEY,
LlZ!
Hold it! Is that awful hunk of junk trying to start!.
I thought everyone had gone for help.
There's lots of air now!
Okay, so here's where the gas and air mix
together. So where does it go next!.
Now I know what a tossed salad feels like!
C'mon! Put the pedal to the metal, Liz!
Where are we now!??.!
I think we're trapped!
Something's wrong! Liz stopped turning the key!
Where did everybody go!??.!
Any body home!.
Thought for sure I heard this mechanical mistake
for a motor trying to turn over.
I must be working too hard.
All right, let's get outta here.
I knew I should have stayed home today!
HEY!!WAlT FOR ME! COME BACK HERE!!!I
HAVE AN AWARD TO PlCK UP!
I had such a good speech to give. Now I'll
NEVER get to give it! HELLLLLP..!.!!
HEY, GUYS! I DON'T KNOW lF YOU CAN HEAR
ME DOWN THERE BUT WE'RE BElNG TOWED
AWAY!
Oh bad oh bad oh bad bad bad!
Where's Liz!.
I don't know...
Friz to Liz! We're in the cylinder.
Liz! Try the key again!
Oh, boy! We're in real trouble now!
SHE'S ALL YOURS, MlKE! THE ¡®VMl' SAlD TO
CRUSH lT!
WHAT HAPPENED NOW!!??.
What was THAT!.
THlS lS ARNOLD! WE'RE lN THE JUNK
YARD!!!
What are we goanna do!. What are we goanna
do!. What are we goanna do!.
I wish I knew! I wish I knew!
NO! STOP! LET US DOWN!
ARNOLD! What's going on up there!.!
IF WE DON'T GET OUT OF HERE NOW -
WE'RE GONNA BE SMASHED!
We hear you, Arnold. Liz! Come in Liz!
I know this is difficult for you, but you have got to
turn the key!
We're moving! LlZ!!!
Hey! We're going down like an elevator.
That smells like... I think I smell gas!!!
Yeah, now the gas is following US!
Not to worry, class. When it comes to pistons -
what goes down must go up!
Maybe now the engine's going to start!
Oh! It should, Ralphie.
This heart-warming chamber is where
all three ingredients we need to get the engine
started come together.
Gas...
Air...
And... what else!.
LOOK OUT! WE'RE GONNA GET CRUSHED!
What happened!.
NOTHlNG happened! The engine STlLL won't
start!
At least we didn't get crushed!
STOP, YOU'RE GOlNG TO CRUSH US! GO
AWAY! DON'T DROP THAT!YOU'LL BE SORRY!
I don't get it, Ms Frizzle. We HAD gas - we HAD
air -
and the bus STlLL didn't run!
Maybe the engine is burned out.
That's it! That's what's missing! The engine burns
gas, remember!.
We need to find a way to get it to burn!
According to my research,
you have to be very careful around gasoline
because it burns so easily.
That's right, DA! In fact, a big fire can start with
just a little spark.
Gas, air and a spark! That's the 3 ingredients!
Did you say spark!. Like a sparkplug!. Like that
thing up there!.
What an explosive discovery, Carlos!
But, I don't see any sparks.
No wonder! More peanut butter!!!
Oh, no! We're going down again!
I'll get the peanut butter!
Oh no, there's more gas and air coming in.
Hang in there, Carlos!
Way to go, Carlos!
You cleaned off the spark plug!
It's a sticky job, but someone's got to do it!
Hey! Look at all that gas and air coming in!
The engine should fire up now!
Get ready to blow this joint!
Wait a minute! Just how big is this fire going to
be!.
As we travel with the burned gases, let's enjoy
the enchanting exhaust pipe
a tunnel of exotic fumes and dark surprises
that will take us into the metallic maze known
as...the muffler!
We did it, Ms Frizzle! We got the engine running
again!
And not a second too soon!!!
We gotta get the bus outta here!
Hit it, Liz! The Mesmer lobber should work now!
I don't think I'm going to like this!
Way to go!
We got gas to mix with air!
Added a spark and kaboom!
We've got the engine running again!
Liz, that was fantastic!
HlP HlP HOORAY! HlP HlP HOORAY!
Hold it! Where's Arnold!??.!
There he is, on the carburetor!
He's on his way to the cylinder!
Now he's about to go through the exhaust
system!!
Arnold, are you all right!.
I'm fine, Ms Frizzle. Anyone wants a peanut
butter sandwich!.
AR-NOLD!
Speaking of peanut butter. Where's Mr. Junket!.
We'll be right with you, Mr. Junket.
You hang on now, Mr. Junket!
Here he comes.
But Ms Frizzle, we can't let Mr. Junket know the
bus is magic.
HE CAN'T KNOW WHEN HE CAN'T SEE, can
he!. COVER ME!
You okay, Mr. Junket!.
You must have been scared.
Let me fix your cap.
Let me brush you off.
Okay bus, here we go...
EXCUUUUSE ME! EXCUUUUSE ME!
That's strange! I... I thought for a second that the
bus was a tow truck!
Hop in, Mr. Junket! There's still time to get your
award.
Looks like I owe you and your class an apology,
Ms Frizzle.
As my Great Aunt Jeanine used to say,
a good engine is worth the price of ignition!
Is that Magic School Bus!. Is that Magic School
Bus!.
Magic School Bus!.
Magic School Bus.The Producer speaking.
Hi I just watched your show on Engines - it was a
real blast.
Only one question. Do you really expect us to
believe that Ms. Frizzle
and her class could stay alive inside a real
engine when it's running!.
It's more than three thousand degrees in there!
We know that.
It was just our way of showing you how an engine
works
up close and personal. Thanks for calling.
Magic School Bus.
Is this the producer!.
At your service. What can I do for you!.
About your engine show -
peanut butter is a pretty silly way to stop an
engine from working.
Silly, maybe - but it would sure gum up the
works.
Then why didn't they use gum!.
Thanks for calling. Why didn't I think of that!.
Magic School Bus.
Glad you're still there. My dad's a Vehicle
Maintenance lnspector and he told me
gasoline is extremely dangerous, either kids NOR
adults should ever play with it.
You're right,
and Dorothy Ann told the kids that when they
were inside the cylinder.
Oh yeah, I forgot.
But, that's okay, you can't be told that often
enough. Hold on a sec.
Hey! Careful with that gasoline, Liz!
Any other questions!.
Well, aren't there a lot more pieces to an engine
that you mentioned in your show!.
A lot. Like the radiator to keep the engine from
getting too hot.
And the battery that makes the sparkplug spark.
BUT WE CAN ONLY SHOW SO MANY lN A
THlRTY MlNUTE PROGRAM.
WOULD YOU MlND CALLlNG BACK!.!
LlZ!HEY, LlZ! TURN THAT THlNG OFF - I CAN'T
HEAR!!!
Magic School Bus. Producer speaking.