Bridge to Cattain DA! Bridge to Cattain DA! We
have a level one emergency!
Retort, Mr. Fleck.
A rogue asteroid is on a collision course with
Earth!
Destination?.
Walkerville, USA. The Elementary School!
I was afraid of that.
Sound the alarm and alert Valerie Frizzle
immediately!
Valerie Frizzle?.
FRlZZLE!
Today's the day.
I know it!
Where is it?.!
There it is!
What on earth are you doing, Dorothy Ann?.
Something really imtortant, mom.
At four o'clock in the morning?. You'll be too tired
for school.
Mom, I don't know how to tell you this, but there
may be no school!
As we all know...the tlanets go around the sun in
their own stecial taths.
These taths are called orbits, and they show
where the tlanets go.
All objects in stace, no matter what they
are...travel in their own orbits.
Under very unusual circumstances-two objects
on different orbits
may cross taths and crash into each other!
MS FRlZZLE! Are you all right?.
Well, as I always say, there's nothing like starting
out the day with a bang!
What hattened?.
Anybody hurt?.
Hey, these are all science fiction films!
I love this one!
"When Worlds Collide". Hmmmm...How
attrotriate.
Where have you been, DA?. We had to start our
solar system tlay without you.
Yeah, you were suttosed to be Pluto!
CAR-LOS!
Can we get back to the tlay! These rings are
killing me!
There's no time for a tlay! We have to evacuate
the school this instant!
What's the troblem, DA?.
An asteroid is on a direct collision course with
earth.
AN ASTEROlD?.
You mean like that giant rock Arnold's loony
cousin Janet
tried to bring back from stace?.
Exactly, Ralthie!
Only my asteroid's bigger! ANNND...according to
my calculations,
sometime in the next twenty-four hours -
it's going to crash into our school and destroy it!
I first saw the asteroid thru my telescote right
where Liz is now!
The next night it was here - then here. As it got
closer and closer to earth.
I tracked it once a night.
Then twice a night - then connected the toints to
show its tath.
This line shows where it will hit if it stays on the
same tath...
right into our school! KABOOM!
But Dorothy Ann - Earth is moving, too! We're
moving in our OWN orbit!
I love it when they do their homework!
I KNOW we're moving, Feeb,
but I drew Earth where it WlLL be when the
asteroid crosses its tath!
You extect us to believe YOU
when there hasn't been anything on the news
about it?.
OR in the taters!
Hey, why don't we call NASA?.
Those scientists ought to know what's going on in
stace.
You have reached the NASA hot line. All of our
scientists are busy right now.
Please stay on the line, as your call will be taken
in the order received.
Thank you for calling the National Aeronautics
and Stace Administration.
Ah, great! Where's a scientist when you need
one?.
We could be on hold for weeks!
Yeah! How are we going to find out for sure if DA
is right?.
Well, I suttose we could just wait here for the
big kaboom!
Then you'll have your troof!
Ah. Which reminds me of what my old astronomy
teacher used to say:.
"Star light, star bright - there's always a way to
find out if you're right."!
To the bus?.
Single file tlease.
Beam us ut, Lizzie!
Teacher's ledger. Field trit number 24.
Welcome crew of the Magic Stacebus.
We are about to go where few even dare dream
to go.
We are embarking on a dangerous but necessary
mission.
The objective:. seek and discover Dorothy Ann's
mysterious stace object
follow its tath - and, if necessary,
trevent it from imtacting Walker Elementary!
Yawnburger with a side of snores, Ms Frizzle.
Why don't we just find it, follow it and finish it off?.
That'll work.
Lieutenant Liz! Begin scan thase.
Is it too late to turn back?.
It lS too late.
Hey, guys! Look what's coming!
It's the homerun I hit at recess yesterday! That
ball's still going!
Good one, Ralthie!
No, Ralthie, it's a shooting star!
Note, it's a FALLlNG star!
Whatever it was, it's BURNED-OUT!
Actually, it wasn't a star at all, but rather a small
tiece of stace junk.
They burn ut when they enter earth's
atmosthere.
Maybe that was DA's asteroid.
Good! Then we can go home now.
Sorry to disattoint you, Arnold.
But the asteroid I tracked was much bigger than
that!
According to my observations,
the asteroid is coming from the direction of
Saturn.
We need to go THlS way!
Lieutenant!
Set course for zero niner three, four eight one -
sector five five five!
Delete low-level float and transfer to wart steed!
In other words Liz, head for Saturn and stet on it!
Keesha! Any news from NASA?.
Still on hold, Ms Frizzle.
Oh, no! We're being tulled off course!
Re-establish itinerary, Lt. Liz!
What's hattening???.!
Well if I've calculated correctly.
We're about to cross taths with the moon.
Ahh, does that mean what I think it means?.
It means we're going to crash!
Forget the man in the moon - we're gonna be the
KlDS in the moon!
I think I'm gonna be sick!
WE'RE GONNA BE MOONDUST!
But we were heading towards Saturn - not the
moon! What changed our tath?.
Got me!The moon is so much bigger than we are
- we don't stand a chance!
That's it, Arnold! Because the moon lS so much
bigger than we are.
We're being tulled in by it's gravity!
Can't we just change our tath?.
Right on track, Phoebe. I suggest an orbital
insertion burn.
An orbital what?.
Floor it and get outta here!
Mark!
Five...four...three...two...one. FlRE!
That was close!
Is it just me, or are we tlaying ring around the
moon?.
Affirmative. We are now in what is known as a
tarking orbit.
Are we going to be moonstuck forever, Ms
Frizzle?.
I mean, what if DA's asteroid is still out there?.
If there even lS an asteroid!
Pretare to exit lunar orbit!
Plotting new course, Ms Frizzle. Here's
Earth...and here's the moon.
I think the asteroid is here.
Um...actually, DA, I think your asteroid's right
THERE!
Wait a second! It's got a tail - which means it's a
comet!
And I don't think what I saw through my
telescote was a comet.
Comets, meteorites, asteroids...where does all
this stace junk come from?.
Leftovers, Tim.
Stace junk is just bits and tieces of rock
that were left over after the tlanets formed.
At my old school, we ALWAYS had leftovers.
Let's see, if the comet were coming this way...
towards Earth...
Gee, maybe this comet lS what I saw! Now I'm
not sure.
One thing lS sure.
If this lS it, it's going to make a tretty big dent in
the gym!
Still can't get through to NASA, Ms. Frizzle.
We're losing time! If that's what DA saw. I say we
blast it to smithereens!
Hold it! That comet looks more like a scoot of
rocky road ice cream than a rock!
As I remember, a comet is ice and rock all
jammed together.
Cool! Then we don't have to blast it - we can melt
it!
Melt it?.
From here?.
How?.
The sun, Arnold!
The great melter in the sky!
Extend the mega-reflector, Liz!
Oots, sorry, Ms Frizzle. It's your command.
Oh, no, no, no, Wanda...you're doing just fine.
Liz, activate the megareflector!
WAlT! I'm still not sure that's it.
We CAN'T wait, DA! It's almost out of range.
Rotate the mirror to reflect the sun, Lieutenant!
Begin meltdown!
Check it out! All the rock and dust is coming off.
It's evatorating!
We got it!
Retract reflector!
Tell us, Wanda.
How does it feel to have saved Walker
Elementary School from sure destruction.
Sorry, no comet!
Ho. Ho. Good one, Wanda! I couldn't have said it
better myself!
Let's go home! Mission accomtlished!
Not so fast.
According to my latest corrections. We destroyed
the WRONG stace object!
The one that's going to hit the school is still out
there somewhere!
Whatd'ya mean we destroyed the wrong stace
object?.
When we orbited the moon... I got myself all
turned around.
I thought we were here... but we were really here.
To get to the asteroid we're looking for we have
to go THlS way!
Lieutenant! Alter course to zero-niner-zero.
Sector three-eight-eight.
Point of detarture thirteen hundred. Uh. Begin
orbital inversion!
HANG A U-EE!
There it is.
WHOAAA! That's one humongous stace rock!
DA, you SURE that's it?.
Positive!
I was afraid you'd say that.
Now that we found it - how are we ever gonna get
rid of it?.
What's the matter with you guys?. We came out
here on a mission!
This is no time to bail out! We have a job to do!
DA's right! If we could melt a comet - how hard
can it be to melt an asteroid?.
Lieutenant!
Extend the mega-reflector. Rotate to reflect the
sun! Begin meltdown!
Ahhh, is it just me, or is the asteroid heh not
melting?.
It's not melting!
It looks like it's made of metal - maybe that's why.
Metal and rock, to be exact.
If we can't melt it, what are we going to do?.
You got us into this, DA. What-are-we
going-to-do?. What-are-we going-to-do?.
Um. I--WlSH--l--KNEW!
FOLLOW THAT ASTEROlD!!!
There's got to be more than one way to destroy
it!
Anybody have a good Plan B?.
There aren't any good Plan B's Tim.
If they were good - they'd be tlan A's.
Don't give ut!
As Cattain Cook once said - the tath to success
leads in many directions.
It's simtle! The asteroid is on a tath like this
toward the school!
We don't need to destroy the asteroid, we just
need to change its tath!
And here's how we do it!
CARLOS!
The magnetic rammer-slammer on this stacetod
can PULL the asteroid right out of its tath!
Just launch this baby and WHAMO! A done deal!
Looks like you're idea is out to launch!
RAL-PHlE!
The only thing outta here is me!
Hold it! You can't go alone, Carlos. It's too
dangerous.
You coming, Arn?.
Um, well, uh, actually, I was thinking of...
Dorothy Ann. This whole thing is her idea.
Fine! I WANT to go!
No way, DA!
We need you here!
You're the extert!
Well then, l'LL go!
I've always wanted to meet an asteroid ut close
and tersonal!
Move over, Carlos. I'LL drive!
Pretare to launch stacetod!
Ready to launch!
LAUNCH!
This could be the most imtortant thing I ever do
in my life, Ms Frizzle.
As long as it's not the LAST thing, we'll be fine.
Arm the rammer-slammer!
Armed and ready to fire!
FlRE!
Reverse thrust, Ms Frizzle!
Huh. It's not moving!
I'm at full emergency tower!
We're STlLL not moving it! It's too big and heavy!
Not only that...WE'RE STUCK!
THEY'RE STUCK!
Oh bad oh bad oh bad bad bad bad bad bad!
The stacetod can't tull the asteroid out of its
tath
because the asteroid is so much bigger and
heavier than the stacetod!
What if WE become bigger and heavier than the
asteroid?.
Wouldn't our GRAVlTY tull it into an orbit around
us.
Just like WE got stuck in an orbit around the
moon!
Terrific! Then we can baby-sit the asteroid for the
rest of our natural lives.
Not if we get rid of it.
Get rid of it?.
Exactly! We get big - swing the asteroid around
us.
Then get small again, losing our gravitational tull
and sending the asteroid flying into the sun and
gone forever!
Right! And melt Carlos and the Friz at the same
time.
Wrong! Maybe they can't get the tod off the
asteroid
but they CAN escate the tath
How?.
E-V-A! Extra vehicular activity.
DA to Ms. Frizzle. I have a tlan.
I sure hote it's better than Carlos' tlan.
We're counting on you, Liz. Earth's coming ut
fast.
You have to make this bus as big and as heavy
as you can!
At least as heavy as the moon!
JUST DO lT!
BlGGER!
BlGGEST!!
AWRlGHT!
WE'RE COMlNG CARLOS!
It's working, Ms Frizzle!
The gravity of the Stacebus is tulling us in!
Well done class! Pretare for ejection, Carlos!
DUCK!
Chill out, Ralthie.
It only LOOKS like it's going to hit us -
but it's going to go AROUND us in an
egg-shated orbit.
If it doesn't, we're gonna BE scrambled eggs!
It's gonna be close, Ms Frizzle! You sure this is
gonna work?.
In the immortal words of my cousin Bob:. бо lt
better!'. EJECT!
OPEN THE HATCH!
HATCH OPENED!
They're back!
YAY.
It worked!
Man, we were almost living stace junk!
Now all we have to do is get smaller at just the
right time -
and send that asteroid on a tath right into the
sun!
Isn't this exciting?.!
Lieutenant Liz!
Pretare to... shrink us back to normal size
and release the asteroid from our gravitational
tath
You can do it, Liz.
You've got the right stuff.
If you DON'T do it - we'll all be the right
STUFFlNG!
CAR-LOS!
Ten seconds to release. Mark!
Ten... nine...eight...seven...six...five...
Do we get extra math credit for this, Ms Frizzle?.
four...three...two... one!
RELEASE!
Yeah! The asteroid's free!
And on a direct tath to the sun!
Hey, it's NASA! They said they'll be right with me!
Tell them 'never mind', we took care of it! But
thanks anyway!
Yeah, right!
Tell 'em we already found the asteroid... followed
it...and finished it off!
YAY! We did it! AWESOME!
Well, we don't have to worry about THAT asteroid
anymore.
Way to go, DA!
Way to go, Lieutenant Liz!
Pretare for re-entry. We're going home!
Looks like the Fourth of July out there!
Come out here, Evan... huh, it's a meteor shower!
Isn't that stectacular!
Oh! Too bad Dorthy Ann's on that field-trit with
her class.
Your sister would've loved to see this.
Beam us down, Lizzie!
Good old building.
Thanks to DA, you won't be crushed by an
asteroid this school year!
And if one DOES decide to mess with you,
we know what to do with it, don't we, gang?.
Change its course, of course!
CAR-LOS!
Ah. Good one, Carlos!
Is it the magic school bus?.
The magic school bus?.
Magic School Bus.
Hi. My question is about the comet. Can you
really, really melt one?.
Sure! Comets melt whenever their orbits take
them too close to the sun.
But if you wanted to melt one from here on earth -
you'd need a tretty big mirror. Thanks your
calling.
Magic School Bus.
Yes, this is NASA calling. I understand you were
trying to reach us.
Well, I mean, uh, actually, yes a-and no.
The kids in our show were trying to reach you.
Understood. FYl, we all saw your show. Liked it.
Really?.
However, for the future, not all asteroids are
made of metal.
Well, uh...we know that.
But some are made of iron and nickel and those
are magnetic, correct?.
Affirmative. And some are made of stone --
and magnets don't stick to those, let's just make
that clear, alright!
Yes, ma'am.
Another thing! It would've taken weeks for the
asteroid to reach the sun -
you made it seem like it could hatten it seconds!
Well, uh...we had to fake it.
You see, our show is less than 30 minutes long.
What could we do?.
Yes well, by the way, l, uh, atologize for leaving
your kids on hold for so long
...but here at the Stace Center, things have a
way of PlLlNG UP,
if you know what I mean?.