Isthere really a dinosaur here, Dr. Skeledon?.
Come on over here, kids!.
Well, there she is!. What do you think?.
Wow!. A real live dinosaur!.
Actually, Ralphie, it's dead.
But what are they doing to it?.
Digging up and dust-busting the fossilized bones
of dinosaurs is the only way
we paleontologists have of tuning in on
what a BONE-afide dinosaur really looked like...
So that's just another DOA, Dr. Skeledon?.
A DOA?.
A dinosaur outta action.
Actually, Carlos, it's a TROA: a Tyrannosaurus
Rex outta action!
Wow, a T. Rex! The killer of the killers, the
meanest of the mean!
I don't think dinosaurs are so terrible.
Then how come the word dinosaur means
¡®terrible lizard'?.
According to my research, dinosaurs WERE NOT
lizards.
That's right, Dorothy Ann, they WEREN'T,
but they WERE reptiles, just like the lizards of
today.
And most of them weren't very terrible.
How do we really know?.
Dinosaurs became extinct so long ago,
no human being ever saw one.
Even if they could have seen one,
they wouldn't have lived to tell about it!
Now, what makes you so sure of that, Carlos?.
MS FRlZZLE!
A teacher-saurus!
Anyone know what you call a 65 million year old
dinosaur egg?.
EGG-stink. Get it?. Extinct?.
Good yoke, Ms Frizzle.
So, everyone digging the dig?.
Yeah, cool! It's great! We love it!
From the looks of things, Valerie, you really got
into it yourself.
Just like old times, huh, Carmina?.
Like the time we went to Scotland in search of
the Loch Ness Monster.
That must have been in pre-historic times.
I heard that Arnold!
Here, Bonesy, add this to your collection.
Fantabulous! One of the best examples of
a fossilized egg I've ever seen.
Ah! Come along class... Sorry to dig and run,
Bonesy...
...but we have to get back. Thanks for a peek at
the past.
Oh! What are old friends for, Val?.
¡®Leave no stone unturned' - that's my motto!
Speaking of stones, Dr. Skeledon, can I see that
rock... I mean egg?.
Sure, Arnold. Just be careful with it. We don't
find many of these.
I have some great rocks at home, but nothing like
this one!
Too bad we couldn't find a
real live T. Rex instead of that rock!
Just think about it...all that fighting and
slaughtering!
Now THAT woulda been a field trip!
As far as I'm concerned, the only safe dinosaur
is a dead dinosaur!
Come on, you guys, dinosaurs couldn't have
been THAT mean!
Get real, Phoebe!
Dinosaurs are the biggest and meanest animals
that ever lived.
You know, Carlos, to REALLY understand a
dinosaur,
you need to walk in its shoes. Isn't that right,
Bonesy?.
With knobs on it, Val!
DR. ¡®S'! Come quick!
Bye kids, I'm history!
WAlT! DR. SKELEDON! YOUR ROCK!
Buckle up, Arnold!
But I've still got Dr. Skeledon's rock!
You'll have plenty of time to give it to her when
we get back.
Get back?????. Why do I have a sneaking
suspicion...
As I always say,
you can turn the clock back, if you've got the right
hands.
Right, Liz?. Here we go!!
Is it just me or did someone hit rewind?.
The dig is un-digging!
We're going back in time!
Wow! We've never done this before!
Whoa, at this rate, we're gonna be unborn!
Now I'll never know what I was going to be when l
grow up!
On the other hand, Phoebe, there's no time like
the past
to take chances - make mistakes - and GET
MESSY!
Why is it so cold?.
Because we're back in the l-lce Age!
That was a million years ago!
Isn't there somewhere warmer we can go, Ms
Frizzle?.
Not someWHERE, Wanda...someWHEN!
I think we're breaking the reverse time travel
speed limit!
Look! The volcano! IT'S UNERUPTlNG!
We're almost there!
Just a few... million...years...to...go!
Goodness gracious! We've reached the Late
Cretaceous!
We've gone back so far back in time that
Dr. Skeledon's rock has unfossilized back into an
egg!
What did you EGGS-pect, Arnold?.
Once an egg - always an egg!
But what's Dr. Skeledon going to say!
Now, don't worry, Arnold,
you've got plenty of time -- millions of years, in
fact!
Now let's get out there and EXPLORE!
The best thing about time travel is
that it's easy on the tires.
Ms Frizzle... How far back have we come?.
Oh... 67 million years... give or take a month or
two...
67 MlLLlON YEARS!
That means we'll probably see...
DlNOSAURS...!!!
RUN...!
OH... NO!!
Thanks, Liz. Dr. Skeledon wouldn't
have been very happy if her egg broke.
I wonder what kind of dinosuar laid an egg this
big?.
What?.
Hang on, Phoebe!
I'm trying! Aah!
Come back with my egg, you thief -it doesn't
belong to you!
Come to think of it... It doesn't belong to me,
either!
AR-NOLD...!
Now, now, don't play with your food, little
Alamosaurus.
Oh bad oh bad oh bad bad bad bad bad!
Hurry, before it eats us for lunch!
Seems to me, it wants to eat the leaves - not us!
Tim, they're still DlNOSAURS...
ferocious, mean, nasty, DlE-NO-SAURS!
Quick! Onto the bus before they come back!
But Ralphie, I think they're plant-eaters, not
meat-eaters!
Yeah! But what if they're just taking a break
between the salad and
the main course... US!
I don't know, Carlos. I think maybe salad WAS
the main course!
A perplexing proposition, isn't it?.
Are dinosaurs ferocious or friendly?.
Sweet or savage?. What is it, Liz?.
Arnold?. Phoebe?.
An Ornithomimus???.
See, I knew this would happen. The dinos did
them in!!!
Any sign of them, Dorothy Ann?.
Not yet.
What was that?.
The sound of a hungry dinosaur ordering
an Arnold-burger.
And Phoebe-fries...to go!
The noise is coming from a bunch of
Parasaurolophus
drinking water and eating plants.
Maybe those monsters already ate Arnold and
Phoebe,
clothes and all!
How can you even think that?. They're just
minding their own business.
Yeah, sure. Now they're washing ¡®em down with
a drink of water.
You heartless--
Carlos, did you ever think maybe they're just
thirsty?.!
YEAH! Bloodthirsty for Arnold!
Come back here, you egg-napper!!!
Uh, nice dinosaur. Good boy.
...You think he's a plant eater or, or a meat
eater?.
I don't know. Maybe he only eats eggs.
And little kids!
Come on, Arnold, let him go. It's just an egg.
But it's Dr. Skeledon's egg! And it's up to me to
get it back to her!
Gee, what a guy!
According to my research, those horn things help
them to--
Stab their innocent victims!
No Carlos! Help them make NOlSES!
Is it really noise?.
Maybe its their way of talking to each other.
Talking to each other?.! Yeah, right,
they're saying "Mmm-mmmm! That guy with the
glasses was good!
Actually, I think they're talking about us!
Now, class, let's not time-travel to
any hasty conclusions.
Ms Frizzle's right.
They're not acting like bloodthirsty killers.
Chock up another vegetarian, Liz!
Hey, look! There's Arnold and Phoebe!
They're still alive!
Let me see!
That critter they're chasing looks awful small to
be a dinosaur.
Oh! Don't judge an Ornithomiumus by its cover,
Carlos!
Dinosaurs come in all shapes and sizes.
Hey! If we could just send a message to those
Parawhatchamacallits to get out of the way,
we could get across the river and save Arnold
and Phoebe!
Dino-mite idea, Carlos!
WHA-HOOOOOO...!
It worked!
They're leaving!
They got the message!
Over the river and through the woods, to Arnold's
and Phoebe's rescue we go...
Oops... maybe NOT!
Where are we?.
Look! Eggshells!
It kinda looks like a nest I once found.
EGGS-actamento, Wanda! And since most of
these shells are pretty trampled,
I'd say the babies hatched a few months ago.
What kind of babies?.
Big ones!!!
And here comes Mama.
It doesn't look to me like she wants to fight.
Maybe she thinks we're her babies
and just wants to take care of us like a good
mother should.
If she sees us - she'll eat us! Dive for cover!
Oh, no, what if she wants to...
... FEED US!
Grrrross...!
Berries that have been chewed and spewed
are nutritious... and delicious...
...and the babies just love a good A-B-C fruit
salad!
What's an A-B-C fruit salad?.
ALREADY BEEN CHEWED!
I say we make a run for it before we're D-E-F!
D-E-F?. What's that?.
Digested, eliminated and forgotten!
Carlos, wait! They're not meat-eaters. They're
even good mothers!
Come along, class!
Are you sure that dinosaur came up this way?.
I'm only sure of one thing, Phoebe.
If someone would have told me that I'd be
chasing a hungry dinosaur -
I would have gotten off the bus a few million
years sooner!
I knew the bus would be around here
somewhere.
Looks like it made some friends!
Friends! Are you kidding! Come on,
we've got to find Arnold and Phoebe before it's
too late!
Before those dinos---
Don't say it, Carlos. The Triceratops won't hurt
us.
They're plant eaters, just like the others.
Here you go, little one!
Uh oh...
It's a pack of troodons! And they DO eat meat!
No kidding! That's not a head of lettuce he's
chasing!
Oh bad!
Cool! The Troodons can't get to the baby
Triceratops
because the big ones are protecting it!
Oh good!
But they CAN get us!
Not with these, they can't!
Tricerashields! My own little invention, of course!
What are they doing now?.
They're trying to figure out which one of us to eat
first!
I don't think so, Carlos,
Iooks to me like they want an easy lunch without
a fight.
The horns scared them away! They were afraid
of getting hurt.
Phoebe, THE EGG! It's next to that big rock!
Now Dr. Skeledon won't be mad at me. It's stuck!
Something tells me we shouldn't be here!
Like what?.
Like THAT!!!
RUN...!
OH, NO...!
What's that noise?.
Sounds like thunder!
Whatever it is, it's scaring the Triceratops.
STAMPEDE...!
That's the last stampede I want to be in!
Yeah, we coulda been dino-dust!
But the Triceratops weren't after us.
They just wanted to get away from the Troodons.
Well... we still have to find Phoebe and--
ARNOLD!!!
There's the bus, Arnold... FASTER!
Is it just me, or is that a real, live Tyrannosaurus
Rex behind them?.
Correctosaurus, Ralphie,
and the T.Rex was the biggest meat-eater of all
time!
Or should I say, lS!
C'MON!!
HURRY!!
YOU CAN MAKE lT!!!
OH NO! I'M DEAD MEAT NOW!
ARNOLD!
He's gonna eat us!
WHOA! Dino breath!
Oh, baaad! When was the last time you
brushed???.!
HELP!
GO AWAY!
Hmmm, wonder if this insurance policy covers
dino-damage?.
Hey, you big bully! Leave my class alone!!
Why doesn't he pick on someone his own size?.!
Maybe he's on a diet.
Maybe he's afraid he'd get hurt - remember the
Troodons?.
Ah! You know, this would be the
perfect opportunity to study the digestive system
of a T. Rex.
MS FRlZZLE! DO SOMETHlNG!!!
Okay, class...think big!
Oh, great! Nothing happened!!
Excuse me.
ARNOLD?.!!
You can put that bus down, now.
GET ¡®lM, ARNOLD!
GlVE lT TO ¡®lM!
Come on, short arms. Put up your dukes!
Thank you.
Oh, yeah?.!
Gee, the T.Rex doesn't act so tough against
someone his own size.
Yay!!
Way to go, Arnold!!
You did it!!
Boy, did you look mean, Arnold.
But we all know you're really not.
And you didn't even have to throw a punch.
You know something, I don't think the T.Rex
wanted to fight anymore than I did.
And he CERTAlNLY didn't want to take any
chances!
OR get messy!
One thing's for sure,
there are a lot more plant-eating dinosaurs than
meat-eaters.
And those that DO eat meat aren't bloodthirsty
monsters.
Yeah, they're just looking for a quick meal without
getting hurt.
So I guess you guys are right. Dinosaurs aren't
so mean after all.
And I can give Dr. Skeledon back her egg.
... Except I'm too big to fit into the bus.
With a few adjustments, you could BE the bus!
RAL-PHlE!
Well, time to go small!
It's a good thing you didn't stay home today,
Arnold.
Well, I'll sure be glad when this is a rock again -
it's a lot safer.
Let's go class! We've got a long drive back to
school!
Yeah, like 67 million years!
Fun sure flies when you're having a good TlME!
DR. SKELEDON... I almost forgot to give you
back your egg.
I'm sure it was safe with you, Arnold. Thanks.
Up here, Dr. ¡®S'!
What an unusual geologic formation.
I wonder what strange creature left that?.
I'd say it was a Sneakersaurus!
CARLOS!
Is it the magic school bus?.
The magic school bus?.
Hello?. Is this the Magic School Bus?.
For me?. Hello. This is Dr. Carmina Skeledon
speaking.
Is this the Dr. Skeledon that was just on the
Magic School Bus show?.
Why, yes! What can I do for you?.
Well, I've been trying to reach the Producer but
he's all tied up
and I have some probing questions about the
Dinosaur show I just saw.
Dig away.
First of all, everyone knows that nobody's ever
seen a real live dinosaur.
You're absolutely right. But we do see lots of
fossils
of the bones which made up their skeletons.
Okay, so then how can you say which dinosaurs
were herbivores
and which were carnivores?.
Oh! That's easy! Fossil teeth!
The plant eaters, you see, had flat grinding teeth
and the meat eaters had pointy cutting teeth.
Well, thank you for calling! Goodbye!
Kids these days, they are just so inquisitive!
Hello?.
Hi. I was wondering if nobody's ever seen a real,
Iive dinosaur then how could you possibly know
that
a Parasaurolophus made a noise like this?.
Oh! That's very good! And you are right -
no one knows exactly how dinosaurs behaved
OR
what they sounded like.
You see, we use our imaginations and make
educated guesses.
So all that stuff about the T. Rex not being so
mean
was another one of your educated guesses,
right?.
Absolutely right. Thanks for calling.
Wait a minute! So no one's ever travelled back in
time and seen real dinosaurs?.
Absolutely not. Time travel is impossible.
Even for Ms Frizzle?.
Even for Ms Frizzle...
Thanks a lot, Doc!
Like it or not, I don't think even Ms. Frizzle could
go back in time...
Still, it would make a good field trip... IF it were
possible...
but of course it's not.