Good morning! And welcome to the weekend
edition of lN YOUR FACE!
The only TV show that asks the question: What's
REALLY going on here?
I'm your host, Gerri Poveri. This just in!
The Monster of Walker Lake has just surfaced
again!
Mom, hurry... Iook! The Monster's back!
This I've got to see!
Here is an exclusive photo of the monster as it
reappeared this morning
at the crack of dawn!
Whoa... unreal!
I couldn't agree with you more, Wanda.
Gerri Poveri would do anything for a story -
even if it means making it up!
But Mom, what if the monster is real?.
What if l, Wanda Lee...
am the first person to make contact with the
Monster of Walker Lake.
Oh no! My whole class beat me to it!
How come the monster never came up before
now?.
Maybe it came up because it was hungry.
May be so, Feeb. But if I were a monster,
it would take a lot more than a banana to get ME
back to the surface!
Okay, but if it lS hungry - we have to feed it.
If it won't come up for the banana, I'll send the
banana down to it.
Oh, no! A banana floats!
That's OK. I like banana splits better.
CARLOS!
Well, if I can't get the monster to come up here.
I'll send my camera down there!
Hey, my monster-cam floats, too! Who would've
guessed?.
If we want to see that monster,
we'd better find a way to turn these floaters into
sinkers!
Maybe we should use my mother's calzone
instead of a banana -
they go down like rocks!
Did you see it yet?. Did you TOUCH it?.
What took you so long?. We thought you'd be the
first one here.
Yeah, well I'm going to be the first one down
there!
I'm going to the bottom of the lake to find the
monster!
I don't know, Wanda. hat would Ms Frizzle say?.
It's the weekend, Phoebe. No school. No Ms
Frizzle.
Look look! Oh, look! It's coming toward us!
THE MONSTER!
Good morning, class!
MS FRlZZLE!
Nothing like a dip in the deep!
Are you looking for the monster, too, Ms Frizzle!?.
Well, if you don't look, you'll never see!
And what you don't see can be very hard to find.
You look like you have that sinking feeling,
Wanda.
Want to float something past me?.
Gerri Poveri showed a picture of the monster on
TV! It HAS to be true!
Pictures CAN be faked, you know!
To prove it's really real, you need evidence... and
there isn't any.
And what do you do when there isn't any
evidence?.
Go home?.
No, you look for it! I'm going after the monster
myself!
This is a warning! Monster alert! Stay out of the
water.
I repeat, stay out of the water.
Hey! It's Gerri Poveri!
For updates on the Monster of Walker Lake,
watch the next edition of "ln Your Face"!
YOU HEARD ME FOLKS...STAY OUT OF THE
WATER! RETURN TO THE SAFETY OF YOUR
HOMES!
Wait a second! She doesn't own this lake!
We can look for the monster if we want to! Can't
we, Ms Frizzle?.
Not only that - we can take chances, make
mistakes get wet!
Hey! Is it just me, or does this sound like a field
trip?.
I propose an underwater expedition to learn the
whole truth
and nothing but the truth about this monster!
A splashing idea, Wanda!
HlT lT, LlZ!
All right!
Cool! An underwater field trip!
Ready to dive Ms Frizzle?.
Ready but unable, Wanda.
Oh! The sinker linker's rusted.
Somebody forgot to swab the deck
and dry the sinker linker the last time we went
under.
Without it, we can't sink at least not
automatically...
But we've got to get down there! This is our
chance to make history!
BE history, you mean!
As my Uncle Wilbur used to say,
"Uh, you can lead a bus to water - but you can't
make it sink."
Yes we can, Ms Frizzle! There's got to be way!
Let's see...the banana floats and the rock sinks.
They're the same size, but the banana is light,
and the rock is heavy.
If something is heavy enough, it sinks. What will
a banana-rock do?.
Good one, Phoebe! The extra weight of the rock
is making the banana sink!
Yo, monster! Lunch time!
That's it!
The monster?.
Where?.
What's it look like?.
No, not the monster - EXTRA WElGHT!
That's how we're going to get to the bottom of
this!
How many more of these do we have to fill?.
Enough to sink the bus!
Hey, Wanda! We've almost got enough extra
Weight!
Uh, this one should do it!
Look out! Here we come!
HURRY!
Come on Liz.
All aboard for the last bus going down!
Dive! Dive!
Sinking... sinking...sunk!
Something about this field trip seems fishy to
me...HA! HA!
CAR-LOS!!!
You were right, Phoebe,
nothing like adding a little extra weight to make
something sink.
You think underwater monsters like peanut butter
and jelly?.
I don't know, but if you feed it - I'll film it!
Are we going to keep sinking until we hit bottom?.
Sinking only ends when you hit bottom, Arnold!
HARD LEFT!
Looks like I've got some competition!
Well... not for long!
What is that?.!
We're losing our weights!
Oh, no! We're rising to the surface!
Right you are, Phoebe! Can you feel the water
pushing us up up up up?.
Oh, isn't floating to the surface exciting?.
No! SlNKlNG is exciting! I DON'T WANT TO
FLOAT!
No one's going to ruin my story - especially a
bunch of nosey kids!
OH NO! Oh, boy! We're floating again!
Ah! Isn't it delightful?. Water can be such pushy
stuff
Push water out of the way and it pushes back.
It's the water's push that's making us float.
But we've got to find that monster, Ms Frizzle!
We're sunk if we can't sink!
As my Uncle Verne always said,
"Arrr! There's more than one way to sink a floater!
"Coming Liz?.
What're we goanna do?. What're we goanna do?.
Maybe if I put enough heavy rocks in here and
seal it up tight.
My monster cam will sink! Say cheese, down
there!
It works!
Now how am I going to feed the monster?.
Send him your sandwich USS.
USS?.
United Sinking Service! Heh-heh-Uh-huh, just
pitch it out there.
Hey! My bread's not sinking, it's floating!
Check it out! Phoebe! There's your bread!
Now I'll NEVER get to feed the monster! Oh!
The poor thing will starve! Oh well...
Hey, Phoebe, don't look now, but your bread ball
just sank!
I don't get it. If they both weigh the same -
why does a bread slice float and a bread ball
sink?.
Did someone say ¡®sink'???.
Over here, Wanda. Instant replay!
There, see it?.!Your bread ball is sinking!
So, what's the difference between a bread slice
and a bread ball?.
Okay, I give up. What's the difference between a
bread slice and a bread ball?.
It's not a joke, Ralphie!
The only difference I can see is that the ball is a
lot smaller than the slice.
Ooh, a BlG point, Keesha! They weigh the same
-
but the big one floats, and the small one sinks!
Does that mean you can take something that
floats...
and crumple it down smaller - and it'll sink?.
Now you're thinking, Wanda! Make it small
enough and even a cork will sink!
I get it!If we crumple the bus small enough, it'll
sink, right?.!
Now you're thinking SlNKlNG! Class, prepare to
crumple!
All right! Let's crumple this floater into a sinker!
It'll be a tight squeeze - but not to worry - we're all
friends!
Liz, activate the Crumple Zones!
But I STlLL don't get it! We weigh the same,
so how does being smaller make us sink?.
Maybe it's because the more we crumple in...
the less water we shove out of the way!
NOW I get it! The less water we shove out of the
way -
the less the water pushes back on us!
Yes! And down we go! A sinking we will go, a
sinking we will go.
Don't these children ever give up?.
Cut it out, Phoebe!
It's crumpled enough in here without you
squirming around like an eel!
I'm just getting ready to feed the monster when
we find it.
When I find it, you mean!
We bottomed out, Ms Frizzle!
We're as low as we can go!
WAN-DAAAA! Where're you going?.
Wait a sec! We're going up!
What happened?. Why didn't we stay sunk?.
We were okay until Wanda left.
Of course!When Wanda left, it made us lighter!
Wanda! Come back!
WAAAAAAN-DA!
LOOK! The monster's got Wanda!
We have to get back down there!
How?. The water's shoving us up again!
I've got it! Let's get smaller!
Oh, I'm afraid we can't do that, Ralphie! The
Crumple Control's jammed!
We need something heavy to weight us down -
but what?.
I know!
CARLOS!
What's he doing?.
He's letting water into the pontoons!
The pontoons are filling up with water!!
Now one side's heavier than the other!
I see what he's doing! Water's heavy, right?. More
water - more weight!
And down we go!
GOOD ONE, CARLOS!
Hang in there, Wanda, we're coming down!
If that little girl finds my monster, why... I'm sunk!
HELLLLLLLP!
Let go of me! Get away!
Oh, all right, you asked for it!
What?. It's nose just floated away!
My mother was right!
Ooh! There is NO monster! It's all just pretend!!
And I get to reveal it all on ¡® In Your Face'!
You mean, YOU did this?.
Well, I had no choice, did l?.!
I mean, when your ratings are sinking like mine
are -
you need a boffo-socko expose' to make ¡®em rise
up again.
But this is dishonest!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no. I, I prefer to use the
phrase ¡®creative journalism.
Call it what you want - you won't get away with it!
Nobody's going to believe you - why, you're just a
little kid!
We'll see about that!
If nothing else, she's a feisty little kid!
Where's Wanda?.
And where's the monster?.
What if the monster ate her?.!
But I wanted to feed it!
PHOE-BE!
Just kidding. Wanda!
Here she comes!
Are you okay?.!
Did you find the evidence you were looking for,
Wanda?.
What happened to the monster?.
The monster is a fake!
What?.
The real monster is Gerri Poveri.
She set the whole thing up just to get people to
watch her show.
We have to get back to the surface and stop
her!The truth must be told!
The truth is the pontoons are completely filled
with water.
Which means we're sunk -- for good!
Hold it! We know how to sink a floater, right?.
So there must be a way to float a sinker!
Easy! Remember how we got lighter when
Wanda left?.
Oh, no! Do I have to go out there again?.!
Push on, Arnold, I think you're wading into
something.
Well, I was thinking that if the water in the
pontoons weighs us down.
what if we push the water out with something
lighter?.
And what is a LOT lighter than water?.
AlR!
Pump hoses in place!
Do you think this is going to work, Ms Frizzle?.
Only one way to find out.
Pumpers start your pumps!
It's working! The air is pushing the water out!
We're getting lighter!
We've got lift off!
Ah, now that we're lighter - the force of the water
pushing up
is greater than our weight pushing down!
And that means we can stop Gerri Poveri from
floating a lie
to the unsuspecting public just to boost her
ratings!
Sink again, little girl!
What happened?.!
We stopped going up!
Oh, no! We're going down again!
The corks are gone and the air is escaping!
As my old Uncle Windchill used to say,Air today,
gone tomorrow!"
Look! It's Gerri Poveri!
What do we do?.!What do we do?.! What do we
do!?.
The inflatable genius of Gerri Poveri is about to
rise to the surface!
It's showtime!
This is Gerri Poveri, reporting live from Walker
Lake...
It's no use. What's sunk is sunk.
Look!It's Gerri Poveri's fake monster!
It's rising to the surface!
There must be something we can do!
We have to get lighter!
Wait a second! What about getting bigger?.
Remember my bread slice?.!
Crumpled and small it sank... but when it was big,
it floated!
So if we uncrumple the bus, we'll get bigger,
push more water out of the way and float to the
surface!
Good idea, DA!
Ms Frizzle - maybe you can uncrumple from the
inside!
You got it, Wanda! Come on, Liz! Use those
uncrumpling muscles!
It's working! The bigger the bus gets, the more
the water is pushing on it.
No kidding! We're turning this sinker into a super
floater!
Bring the monster-cam, Tim! I've got an idea!
We'll be right back!
Going UP!
Underneath a deceptively calm surface
the residents of Walkerville are gripped with fear.
But the recent sightings of the so-called monster
have caused this reporter to be more than a little
skeptical.
Hey, hey, what's going on?. HEY!
OH!! M-M-M-MY CAMERA!
OH, MY CHOPPER! OH, OH, OH! MY STORY!
OUR story, you mean! Ready Tim?.
Ready!
So that's all that remains of the monster of
Walker Lake.
I know we ruined your story, but the truth had to
be told.
Well, I have to hand it to you, you're certainly a
brave bunch of kids.
And your camera work is excellent, Tim.
Thanks, Gerri. Hi, mom!
We may have been brave, but you were wrong to
perpetrate this hoax.
You owe your public an apology.
Yes, yes, right you are, Wanda. To these kids
here
and to all my viewers out there I'm so sorry.
So let's look once again at the shot which got you
a spot on this show and me
an offer to star in a new underwater
action-adventure series.
How did you do it?.
We knew that monster was big enough and light
enough to float.
So, all we had to do was let it loose.
And you know the rest.
Your very own monster ended up lN YOUR
FACE!
Yes, well...did...did't.
Well You must be very proud of your class, Ms
Frizzle.
Well, Gerri, as you yourself once said, the
truth...always floats to the surface!
Is it the magic school bus?.
The magic school bus?.
Well, nothing like a good hoax to get you your
own series! I love show business.
Uh! Should I let it ring?.
No, no - could be my agent.
Hello?.
I just saw your show where the bus floated and
sank
by pushing water in and out of those big tank
things.
Well, that's ridiculous.
Why?.
I don't know about any bus,
but that's how submarines switch from floating to
sinking and back again.
By pushing water in and out of big tanks inside
the hull.
They do?.
They do, and goodbye!
Now, do I have everything?.
Oh, I don't believe this! Hello! Whatever it is you
want, make it quick.
I bet you I could make a solid copper penny float.
Ah-ha, no way! That would be so heavy it'd sink,
no matter what.
Uh-uh! All you've got to do is
get it to push more water out of the way to hold
its weight.
So smash it thin and flat with a hammer.
And then bend up the edges to make a copper
boat. Then, it'll float.
Gee! Thanks for the tip! And thank you for the tip,
Liz. Bye-bye!