And Keesha said, "let there be night!"
And I say, "let there be Ms Frizzle!"Where is she
anyway?
Yeah, our parents will be here any minute.
Oh! Hope they like our display of nocturnal
animals.
Animals that come out at night are my personal
favorites.
I don't know about you guys, but parent-teacher
conferences make me nervous.
I vant to suck your blood!
Chill out, Arnold, it's just me. Your ordinary
creature of the night.
Knock it off, Ralphie...there are no vampires.
They only exist in your imagination.
That's what you think! Bats are just vampires in
disguise.
Come on, guys, the Friz wants us to set up the
attic, too.
The vampire looked around the room of
half-humans - half bats,
and said: ''Attention my beloved children, at last
the moment
I've been waiting for is here.''
Whoa, it's dark up here.
uh... (heh) why don't I go get a flashlight.
What's the matter Mr. Vampire Expert...afraid of
the dark?
No, l'm not afraid! I just can't see, that's all.
Maybe You can't, Ralphie...but THAT can!
Ooh...a bat! A REAL creature of the night.
uh, it sure is creepy!
I don't know, I think it's kinda cute.
Creepy or cute, this is ONE animal of the night
we know very LlTTLE about!
Maybe that's why we're afraid of them. We don't
really know much about them.
Don't hurt it!
Don't let it get me! I don't want to be turned into
a-a-a vampire!
Relax, Ralphie, this is real life, not some made-up
story!
That little bat has as much chance of being a
vampire as...What was that?
YlKES! MS FRlZZLE!
Good evening, class!
Ah, I see you found my animal of the night.
So dark of wing and keen of craft, of all night
fliers, the master's a bat!
That's just the kind of thing a vampire would say!
Come on, Ralphie, you've been reading too many
comic books!
Ah. Come, come, don't be afraid. Let me show
you the secrets of being nocturnal.
When you're a creature of the night - you wear
the color of night,
so you won't be seen by your enemies.
You stay hidden until the sun has set.
The darker the night, the safer the flight.
And of course, being nocturnal - you feed only
during the night.
Ralphie!
Is something wrong?.
Wrong?. No, uh uh. Nothing. No.
Ah, the PARENTS have arrived.
This is my grandmother, Ms Frizzle.
Ah! How nice to finally meet you. Keesha has told
me so much about you...
I could just eat you up.
Did you hear that?. Ms Frizzle wants to eat
Keesha's Grandmother!
Ralphie, dear, aren't we going to say hello to Ms
Frizzle?.
Actually, Mom, I uh...she uh...she's kinda busy
right now.
Oh, Ralphie, stop being a pain in the neck.
You think l'M a pain in the neck. Just wait!
Ah, Dr. Tinelli, how good to see you again.
And you, Ms Frizzle. Ralphie's been raving about
your field trips.
Yes, well, I do so enjoy taking him under my
wing.
Heh-heh. um. Excuse me, please.
You gotta believe me! The Friz must be a
vampire!
The Friz CAN'T be a vampire - she's our teacher!
Maybe during the day - but what about at night,
huh?.
Didn't she say ¡®the darker the night - the safer
the flight'?.
She was talking about BATS! If it's dark they
blend in -
and their enemies can't see them.... It says so
right here in my book!
Vampires like the dark, too! And NlGHT is when
they strike -
which is exactly why Ms Frizzle wanted our
parents here after dark!
Stop it, Ralphie!
Our parents are here at night because they're too
busy during the day.
And that's all!
Your attention, please!
Before we all visit the classroom,
I thought for the parents-only portion of the
evening
, we might go someplace more...suitable,
more... uh...brrrreath-taking!
Come along, I won't bite.
NOW do you believe me?.
Is this a field trip, Ms Frizzle?.
It is indeed, Mr. Perlstein. Arnold adores them.
At Phoebe's old school, we never had field trips.
This is gonna be fun.
What about the children?. Aren't they coming with
us?.
Don't you worry about the children, Mrs.
Franklin...they'll be taken care of.
Yikes! We're next!
Wonder where Ms Frizzle's taking them?.
I don't know, but we have to find out! Follow that
bus!
Ooohh! You've gone too far, Ralphie!
There's no reason for us to spy on their meeting!
Stay here if you want, Keesh.
But how are you going to feel
if you're grandmother starts sleeping in a box in
the basement?.
That's absolutely ridiculous! huh, But I guess
there's no harm in making sure.
Hit it, Liz!
We're here!
I bid you welcome!
BATS! Night flyers, we used to call ¡®em.
Why would Ms Frizzle bring our parents to a
place full of bats!
AND mosquitos!
Because she's a VAMPlRE, that's why! What
more proof do you need?.
Ralphie! Ms Frizzle CAN'T be a vampire, because
vampires DON'T exist!
I'm sure there's a perfectly logical explanation for
all this -
and l'm going to find out what it is!
Well, go ahead, Ralphie, open the door.
It was YOuR idea!
Move aside, you weasly wimps! I'LL do it!
Now what!
Okay. We can go back to school now.
No we can't, Arnold. We've got parents to save!
Come on, there's a window over there!
Admit it, Ralphie, this vampire thing is a bunch of
junk! You're making it up!
Oh, yeah?. Then explain why Ms Frizzle...is
making our parents drink blood!
Ah, to the creatures of the night long may we fly
together.
Hold it! They're not drinking blood -
it's tomato juice, like Ms Frizzle served at the
class picnic.
Oh, yeah?.!
The only way to stop a teacher vampire is to drive
a textbook through her heart!
Let's go!
Get away, you bloodsuckers! Vampires?.!
No, mosquitos!
Huh. More bats!
We're gonna be eaten alive!
Wait a minute!
Hey! The bats don't want to eat us, they want to
eat the mosquitos! Look!!
Which PROVES they aren't vampires!
Right! And give me back my book!
It's rough.
Good place to hang from - if you've got claws.
How dark is it in here?.
Dark enough to sleep in - night OR day.
What lS that smell?.
Bat poop, Mr. Perlstein. Get used to it.
Bat GuANO, to be more exact, Mr. Ramone. It
makes excellent fertilizer.
Walk this way please...
It certainly is stuffy in here.
It's the breath of a billion bats, Dr. Tinelli.
Well, you know what they say. Bat breath is
better than no breath at all.
MR. RAMONE!
Oh good oh good - little pink babies.
Ah, yes, the children of the night.
Ohh, aren't those bat babies cute!
SEE, Ralphie?.! Bats are mammals not vampires.
Their babies drink milk, not blood!
Get down! The Friz is coming!
I can look if I want to!
Can not!
Can so!
You know, I didn't know that bats take care of
their young.
Ah, indeed they do, Mrs. Franklin. Bats make
excellent mothers.
Even on a wall full of pups, they recognize the
sound of their own.
Oh. Just like me. I'd know the sound of my
Keesha anywhere.
CAN SO!
Can not!
Keesha!?.!
Hmmm, no one out there...only some juicy tidbits
for the bats.
¡®Kidbits?.!' She's talking about us! She's gonna
feed us to the bats.
We gotta get help!
She said ¡®TlDbits' not ¡®kidbits!
Ralphie, what are you trying to do?.!
Get us outta here before she turns us ALL into
vampires! Wonder what this does?.
Nice one, Ralphie. You turned the bus into a bat!
And THlS is turning into a field trip!
Where're we going?.
I don't know, it's too dark to tell.
Is - is it just me or does everything look really
weird?.
Well, what'd you expect?. The bus is a bat,
remember?.
What if we crash into something?.
Whew! That was close!
Look out look out!
Bats, bats everywhere!!
And they're making so much noise!
I didn't hear that before the bus turned into a bat!!
Awesome! How does the bus keep from running
into stuff?.
It must be because it's a bat, that's how!
The Bat-Bus knows how to get around in the
dark, like them.
But HOW?.!
I think it's got something to do with that pinging
sound.
I don't know about you guys, but that pinging is
killing my ears!
I can tell you this...every time the bat opens its
mouth I hear a ping!
Yeah! And then its ears wiggle! I think it's
LlSTENlNG to the echo of each ping!
I hope the Bat-bus is listening now or we're
gonna crash!!
Wow! That's it!
When the sounds echo back -
the bat bus knows something's there and doesn't
bump into it!
That must be what the bats are doing...when they
make that funny sound!!
They're using echoes to locate things...
Echoes to locate...echolocation.
Bats don't need to see with their eyes - they can
see with their ears!
Weird! But cool! Bats use sound to get around!
Moths, dead-ahead!
Oh, no! Don't tell me that the bus is hungry!
Ick! At least we know how bats grab a bite to eat!
Oooh! Yuck! Disgusto!
And night is a good time for bats to eat,
because they're experts at finding food in the
dark.
Not because they like to scare people, Ralphie.
Yeah, well, we don't have time for midnight
snacks.
We have to get back to the castle!
Come on, Ralphie, admit it - bats are cool.
And if you were a night animal - you'd want to be
one!
I would not!...Or would l?. A bat could fly back to
the castle in the dark -
find a way inside - and save his parents from
Count FRlZuLA!
Ralphie! What are you doing?.
Winging this thing back to the castle!
Yep, Ralphie, you sure know how to wing it!
This wasn't exactly what I had in mind.
Hey, I love being a bat! Bet I can do 0-60 in three
seconds flat!
Watch me, Tim! I can turn on a dime!
It's not bad being a bat!
You can catch a drink on the fly...and a fly on the
drink!
Hmm, not bad.
Or snag a moth on the wing...WlTH your wing!
I wish I could turn off the moon. That light gives
me the creeps.
Yeah, me, too! Wonder why?.
OWL ALERT!
OWL ALERT!!!
YllllKES!
THAT'S why we avoid light! Our enemies can see
us in it!
¡®The darker the night, the safer the flight'. Just
like Ms Frizzle said.
And she oughta know. She's the QuEEN of the
night!
By now our parents could be...
What if Ralphie's right?. What if Ms Frizzle lS a
vampire!
No way! It's not true! Ralphie's NEVER right!
Attention parents of my dear beloved children!
It's the Friz!
At last, the moment l've been waiting for has
come!
That's exactly what the vampire in my comic book
said! TO THE CASTLE!
Wait for me!
I don't want to believe it - but l'm beginning to!
Prepare yourselves, for your time has come!
Oh! Something terrible's happening!
And who would like to be my first victim?.
I TOLD you she was a VAMPlRE!
Take me, Ms Frizzle. Take me!
GRANDMA!
DON'T YOu DARE BlTE MY
GRANDMOTHERRRRR!!
¡®The darker the night...the more I think Ralphie's
right'!
The Friz COuLD be a vampire!
Yeah, and I don't want my dad to have nose
flaps!
So, what are we waiting for?. Let's go!
It's really really dark down here.
Yeah. We'll never find Ms Frizzle!
We're bats, guys, remember?. To find a location -
use echolocation!
FOLLOW ME!!!
MORE BATS!!!
There must be millions and millions of them!
Yeah, millions of PARENTS turned into bats!
This way!
Bat or no bat, I just don't like the dark. WAlT
FOR ME, GuYS!
Wha-what happened?????.
You forgot! If a bat can't hear, it can't tell where
it's going! Come on!
Hold on, Grandma!
I heard Keesha! Let's go!
There she is!
They're in the next room! Listen.
So what do you think of our field trip, now?.
I can't believe I let you do this to me!
My neck will be sore for a week.
GASP! That's my MOM! LET'S GO!!!
Maybe we SHOuLD have stayed home tonight!
Dad! You took the words right out of my mouth!!!
What about the kids, Ms Frizzle?.
Will they suffer the same fate as us?.
Of course! They're MlNE, too, aren't they?.
I love you anyway, daddy! I'll love you...forever.
We can't let the Friz get away with this!
What are we going to do?. What are we going to
do?. What are we going to do?.
Make sure she never does this again!
Whew! Huh?. Enough blood rushing to the head!
Everyone down now.
Time to get back to school to see the class
project.
Aw, do we have to?. I could hang around for
another hour.
MR. RAMONE!
That was incredible! I really felt like a bat.
Me, too. I used to be afraid of bats - but not
anymore.
As I always say, to be a bat - is to love a bat.
It's no wonder Phoebe loves your field trips, Ms
Frizzle.
I'm so glad we transferred her from that other
school.
As Keesha says, they're simply magic!
She doesn't know the half of it! Nice going,
Ralphie!
More bats! They must be coming home from night
school.
Is it just me, or do those bats look like our kids?.
Oh. Why so they do! uh! What a wonderful
co-winky-dink!
How could you ever think Ms Frizzle was a
vampire?.
I can't believe we listened to you!
Hey, she LOOKED like a vampire -uh-MOVED
like a vampire -
and TALKED like a vampire.
In any decent movie - she would've BEEN a
vampire!
Not good enough, Ralphie! It was only your
imagination!
I-l'm sorry. I-I was wrong about the Friz.
She's really a good teacher who just...gets
wrapped up in her work!
And you were wrong about bats, too.
Okay, they're NOT vampires.
They're nocturnal animals that use echolocation
to fly at night.
And WHY do they come out at night?.
They come out at night to feed. Okay?.
And WHAT do they feed on?. Come on, say it.
Okay, okay, okay! They feed on insects - not
human blood! You happy now?.
Keesha may be happy, but the BAT news is -
WE'RE STlLL BATS!
Fangs for reminding us, Carlos.
PHOE-BE!
YAY LlZ!!!
Let's go home!
Hey! What do you know! It's our kids!
Keesha, what are you doing here?.
Ralphie, I know that guilty look. What's going on?.
uh, heh, nothing, Mom. Really!
Oh, l'm sure they were just ¡®hanging
around'.(giggle) Right, Ralphie?.
Right, Ms Frizzle! And bat's all!!
Is it the magic school bus?.
The magic school bus?.
Good evening.
uh... is this the Magic School Bus?.
You found us. We're just wrapping up things here
at the castle.
I'm the producer - how can I help you?.
Cool! I have some questions about your show on
¡®Bats'.
I'm hung up on a few things.
You're not the only one. What's on your mind?.
First of all, if vampires AREN'T real -
how come everyone's always talking about them
and putting them in books,
movies and TV shows like yours?.
Because the idea of vampires is scary.
And people like to be scared by make-believe
monsters.
Okay. Next question. How come there was only
one kind of bat on your show?.
There are almost 1,000 different kinds, you
know?.
You're right, more than almost any other kind of
mammal. And they live all over the world.
And though most of them eat insects, some eat
pollen, nectar, fruit, frogs, fish,
other bats...and even lizards! Bet no one told Liz
that, huh?.!
uh, well, those kinds of bats were banned from
the set.
And we had very tight security.
Another thing.
The only bat sounds we can hear are the
squeaks bats make when they communicate.
And we really can't hear the sounds bats use to
echolocate -
they're too high-pitched for us to hear.
Hey, give us a break.
You know, if we didn't use a little movie magic
you wouldn't have understood how they worked.
Okay, l'll give you that one.
But here's something I don't think you wanted to
mention.
There ARE three kinds of bats who DO feed on
blood!
Yes, but they're only called vampire bats
because the people who named them had heard
make believe vampire stories.
Not only that, vampire bats don't even suck
blood.
They make a tiny cut in the animal, and lap up
the blood that comes out.
uh, well that's true. But bats don't really bother
people.
How come you know so much about bats,
anyway?.
Vell, vat do you tink?.
You're za only vons who know anyting about za
creatures of za night?.
I'm just kidding! Did I scare you?.
Who me?. Oh, no. TV producers don't fall for that
kind of stuff.
Thanks for calling.