Heads up guys! Here it comes!.
Aaah! Very good, class...but let's see a little more
spirit!
Move those bodies! Get your BACK into it,
Arnold!
Good - Now, bend your KNEES, Wanda. That's
it!
I got it! I got it!
More WRlST, Carlos! It's all in the WRlST!
Poor, Ralphie. He doesn't look very happy
cleaning the bus all by himself.
It's his turn, Phoebe. Besides, we're ALWAYS
doing things for Ralphie -
Iike how many times have I clapped the erasers
for him?.
Or cleaned the hamster cage?.
You know!
Just yesterday he asked me to change the water
in the goldfish bowl for him
¡®cause he was late for soccer practice.
I tell"ya, Liz, all this ELBOW grease is wearin' me
out.
... I gotta take a break.
If only I had a robot that could do my work for me.
Think about it, Liz, we'd never have to clean the
bus again.
Hey, a guy can dream, can't he?.
The truth is: What is the highway of life all about
If  not to enjoy the detours?.
Like practicing my hook shot...
OR PERFECTlNG MY CURVEBALL...
Or working on my slapshot.
That's it, Liz!!! I could make a robot!
HEY, GUYS! I HAVE A BRlLLlANT lDEA!
What would you say if I built a ROBOT to do all
our chores?.
A robot!
Cool!
Oh no.
I'd say that was the silliest idea you've ever had!
Silly is as silly does or doesn't.
Oh, excuse me, Ralphie. I need to get out of the
sun.
You can't be serious, Ralphie. You can't build a
robot!
Oh yeah?.! Wanna bet?.!
Sure! But if you can't come up with a robot -
no baseball, no basketball and no soccer...
AND, you have to do ALL the chores! Still wanna
bet?.
Well, I can do it if everybody helps.
I mean, once the robot's built
NONE of us have to do chores again!
Maybe we CAN do it.
We won't know unless we try.
Way to go, Wanda. Keesha... You got a bet!
Hold on there Bus!
What happened to the bus???.!
Hmmm... Looks like the mesmerglobber blew a
gasket!
Onto the bus, class! This is an emergency!
Ms Frizzle, wait!
Sorry, we have a busy, busy day ahead! No time
for waiting!
Only time for taking chances - making mistakes -
getting messy!
Hop in, Ralphie!
Wonder if this could be another...nah,
it couldn't be.
It lS a field trip.
Excuse me, Ms. Frizzle!!! But there's something
important I have to do.
Well, you're on the right bus, Ralphie -
because where we're going - there's something
for EVERYONE to do!
We're here!
Presenting, "The One-of-a-kind,
Satisfaction-Guaranteed, Service-with-a-scowl
Body Shop'!!!
YlKES!!!
Whoa, look at all that stuff! Just what I need to
make a robot!
How do we get across, Ms Frizzle?.
Across???.!
It's gonna get us!
Aha! It GOT us!!!
Wow!! This is incredible!
COOL!!
LOOK OUT BELOW!
Long time no see, Valerie.
They must know each other!
Class, meet Radius Ulna Humerus:.
magical mechanic at large.
Humerus, as in upper arm bone?.
Or R. U. Humerus, as in in really funny?.
I love it!
CAR-LOS!
R.U. is the genius who taught me everything l
know about busonautics.
You musta forgotten it all...
...or else this bus has acquired a split personality.
Or else it's the mesmerglobber behind the
shrinkerscope -
which I believe is still under warranty.
I'll check it, Val,
but you caught me at a bad time. I'm expecting
another customer.
More important than moi?.
No one's more important than you, my little toggle
bolt.
My little toggle bolt?????.
Let's get crackin'!!
Now that the coast is clear, let's start building
that robot!
I still say it'll never work.
We don't even know where to start.
It's simple! All we have to do is build a robot that
looks like me.
Like this?.
I'm serious! How hard can it be?.
Just attach a doohickey like this to something like
this!
Hmmm, be right back.
Watch your fIank, my little sprocket!
Careful, my feisty fIywheel.
IG-Nl-TlONNNN...!
Hmm, the Bus has never done that before.
It's definitely not the mesmerglobber!
Oh well, maybe it's the plangdabber.
Excuse me, Ms Frizzle.
Let's say you wanted to uh...to build something.
You mean, build character?.
Build a new and better tomorrow?. Or build a
robot that would do all your chores.
Um...probably closest to that last one...
You CAN'T build a robot...
...UNLESS you know how your own body works.
You know how it works?. Huh?.
Well...not exactly.
Your body needs support to hold it up!
It's got to have structure!
And to find out about that...
...you need my special Megariffic lntrascopic
KlNETO-EXAMlNOMETOSCOPE!
"MlKE' for short!
Which l, of course, keep hidden away
where no nosey kid can find it!!
Pretty clever, my shining shock absorber.
I think so!
Hear that, Ralphie?. Structure's the thing.
Gotcha, Ms Frizzle!
Okay, so to find out how my body works I need to
know about structure
- but what's MlKE got to do with it?.!
Wonder what THlS button does?.
Wow! Check out all those bones!
I've got it! My bones must be the STRUCTURE
Ms Frizzle was talking about!
Cool! I mean... it's chilly in here.
Looks to me like your bones support all the other
parts of your body.
And some of them are like neat little cages
protecting your squishy parts
Iike your heart and your lungs!...See?.
That's it! My robot needs structure!
All we need to do is find some stiff parts like
bones and
Ralphiebot is born!
Don't forget our bet, Ralphie.
Forget it?. I'm about to win it! Step back,
everyone!
I command you, Ralphiebot - MAKE ME A
SANDWlCH!
Let's see, there's bus detail, eraser patrol, chair
management...
QUlET! I need to concentrate!
...Listen to me, Ralphiebot... MAKE ME A
SANDWlCH! NOW...!!!
Can you make me a sandwhich, please?.
Please?. How about half a sandwich?.
He doesn't move or bend.
He doesn't do anything!
Just like Ralphie...
Hey, where's Arnold?.
Over here, you guys!
Wow! Look at that!
Arnold's tying his shoe. What's the big deal?.
Check it out!...Arnold's elbow lets his arm bend in
the middle?.
That's the difference between us and Ralphiebot!
I see now! It's not the bones themselves that let
someone move...
... it's the way they're joined together.
Of course! It's the JOlNTS that let the BONES
move! Don't go away...
Hurry back, Ralphie. Radius' other customer will
be here any minute.
Can I come out now?.
Find the problem yet, R. U.?.
One thing's for sure, your levitation linkage is
leaking!
Sorry, my little--
S'cuse me, Ms Frizzle... but let's say you need to
make some connections,
but you don't know how?.
You mean connections as in meeting the right
people?.
Connections as in a cable-TV hookup?.
Or connections as in joints to let your bones
move?.
Um, probably closer to the last one.
Everything HlNGES on making the right
connections, my boy.
Time to BUCKLE down before my next
appointment gets here!...Catch my BENT?.
This door hinge is perfect!
It goes back and forth - but not sideways,
just like Ralphie's elbow joint!
This shower head has a joint that can move in
ALL directions!
Just like Ralphie's shoulder!
And this thing's got a whole SERlES of joints.
Perfect for a backbone that BENDS and TWlSTS.
Now Ralphiebot can move and do all the things l
do!
At my old school, we weren't allowed to make a
robot that could move!
Well, Keesh?.
Ready to admit that this is the greatest idea in
the history of kidkind?.
We'll see, Ralphie...we'll see.
Ralphie, it's amazing!
Yep. Kinda reminds me of me.
I command you, Ralphiebot,
bow to your Ruler and Master:. Ralphie the
Magnificent!
It's not bowing.
Do you blame it?. I wouldn't either.
C'mon you guys!
I don't get it! It's got BONES for STRUCTURE!
It's got JOlNTS for FLEXlBlLlTY!
Why won't it MOVE???.!
Aha! You lose, Ralphie!
No way! If I can move - it can move!
C'mon, guys! We gotta find out how to make that
robot move!!
This red and blue button must do something!
What'dya see, what'dya see???.!
I see your muscles pulling your bones up and
down and back and forth.
Hey! Do that again... That's it! The missing link!
It's your MUSCLES that pull your bones to make
them move!
Exactly! The reason the robot didn't move a
muscle was...
Because he didn't have any!
Well...didn't everybody know that?.
But where are we going to find some muscles?.
LlZ...!!!
I've got it!
Look at this! These things work just like
muscles! One pulls this way...
And one pulls the other way.
That makes sense, because according to my
research -
muscles can only pull on things - not push them.
"Seems to me, if we all pull together,
we can make Ralphiebot move!
Let's do it!
He's even more than I'd imagined he'd be!
I think it's really going to work!
An amazing combination:
bones for structure, joints for fIexibility -
and muscles for MOVEMENT!
Well, he's certainly an improvement on the
original - that's for sure.
Personally, Keesha, I think you"re jealous cause
I'm gonna win the bet. But that's okay...
... because none of us'll ever have to do chores
again
when I say 'Ralphiebot, clean the bus!'
Um, guys... I think he moved!
(CHEER...)
Hey! Where's he going?.!
Ralphie, do something! Stop him!
I COMMAND YOU!...STOP!!! STOP!!!
I knew I should've--
Don't say it, Arnold!
MS FRlZZLE...LOOK OUT!!!
Oh my! A Ralphiebot!
Ms Frizzle, get out of the way!
Ms Frizzle!...Are you okay?.!
I'm better than okay, Ralphie!
I'm blown away by your ingenuity! Yeee-haw!!!
Sorry, Ms Frizzle. I... I didn't tell him to do it!
Yes, you did, Ralphie.
He heard you say you wanted him to CLEAN
THE BUS!
HELP!
Me and my big mouth!
Ralphie do some thing...!
LlKE WHAT?.!
Take charge, my boy!
Show "im who's boss!
You're right, Mr. Humerus.
Ah, call me R. U. WHEE-HAW!
This is your Master speaking! COOL lT!
That's better. HEY! I said COOL lT!
NO! I didn't mean SOAK the BUS... I meant
STOP!
I don't think he's going to stop until he's finished.
Or we're finished!
Do something, Ralphie!
WHAT?????.!
Get a grip, Ralphie!
I've GOT a grip!
Think! If your body needs joints and muscles to
move...
Then...uh...RlGHT! WlTHOUT muscles - it
couldn't move at all!
Ah, excellent observation, Ralphie.
But how do I get rid of the muscles?.
I'll help you, Ralphie!
Yo, Keesh! Thanks!
COME BACK HERE!
C'mon Keesha,
we've got to immobilize those muscles,
un-hinge those hinges and de-bone that robot
before it wipes out our entire class!
KEESHA, GET ME THAT SCREWDRlVER!
Bet's off, Ralphie. Do what you have to do!
You're okay, Keesha!
No joints... no movement!
No muscles... no movement!
I really wish I didn't have to do this but it's the
only way.
Kinda hate to see the robot go like that. The kid
did a good job.
Ah, that's my Ralphie.
No movement... No nothing!
You OK Ralphie?.
Looks like you stopped him alright!
I take back what I said, Ralphie -
the robot wasn't such an improvement after all.
Tell me about it.
I took a chance - I got messy...
...and what do I have to show for it?.
Don't feel bad, Ralphie. You didn't do anything
wrong.
Yeah, you were on the right track.
And we DlD find out that bones and joints and
muscles
are just as important for a robot as they are for
us.
Maybe next time it'll work.
Hope so. Good help is always hard to find.
Why Liz...thanks. I'm touched.
So I guess it all goes to prove something, doesn't
it, Ralphie?.
Yep... When you've got all the moves like I do -
it's pretty hard to make improvements!
Unless you're a magic school bus,
that is.
There was nothing wrong with the shrinkerscope,
my little wingnut - and you knew it!
Looks like your other customer never showed up,
R. U.
Oh yes, they did...
As I always say,
Is it the magic school bus?.
The magic school bus?.
Well I'll tellya this, Liz - it's the first time Valerie...
Ms Frizzle, has paid my mechanic's fee in robots!
Get that, will"ya?.
Body Shop - where the best come to get better!
Hi! The Producer over at the Magic School Bus
told me to talk to you.
I just watched the show on Body Mechanics and l
think
you know a lot more about fixing things than you
do about human bodies.
Is that so?.! For instance.
Well, for instance, there are a lot more bones and
muscles
in the human body than you actually showed.
Of course there are.
And did YOU know there are 27 bones in the
hand alone?.
...And it takes 14 muscles to make a funny face!
That's pretty amazing. But what about ligaments
and tendons?.
You didn't even talk about them!
You're right, kid, but we can't show everything in
a half hour.
Ligaments are bands that hold the bones at your
joints together -
So they don't move too far in the wrong direction.
And tendons hook your muscles to your bones so
you can hop and jump around.
People aren't the only things that work that way,
you know.
Of course not! Cats, dogs, horses, snakes,
fish...
...even lizards need bones and joints and
muscles to move.
But some animals, like insects, don't have bones
at all.
Instead, they have a stiff covering on the outside
which works with the muscles on the inside to let
them move.
Come on, it takes more than bones, joints and
muscles to build a real robot!
I mean, it would need a battery or an engine for
energy -
and some sort of brain to control it.
Are you saying that the Ralphiebot is
BRAlNLESS???.!
Well, yeah, I guess so.
Well, all I can tell you is this - for not having a
brain,
he makes a pretty good sundae!
Thanks for checking in.