This is really embarrassing, Wanda.
It's okay, Arnold, you're with me.
What if somebody catches us in here?.
Who's going to catch you in the girls bathroom,
Tiffany?.
Tiffany?. Who's Tiffany?. I don't know any Tiffany.
Yeah, right. Whatever you say, Arnold.
I say we don't need this water!.
My model of the waterworks shows exactly how
water is collected and stored
and cleaned and delivered and-
Yawn burger with a side of snores!.
As your partner, I cannot do a report on water
without water!.
That's enough. I take the bucket to class, you
clean up.
O. K.
Oh, and don't forget Ms Frizzle's keys!. Hi, Tiffany.
Hi, Wanda. Hi, Tiffany.
ARNOLD!.
TlFFANY!.
TlFFANY!. WAlT... I can explain!
Oh, maybe I should have stayed home today!
Come on, Arnold! It's time for your report!
Yikes! I knew I should have stayed home today.
Careful Wanda! You'll drown my waterworks!
Arnold, a properly constructed waterworks cannot
drown!
WHAT'S THAT NOlSE?.!
Good morning, class.
Good morning, Ms Frizzle.
Ah! Everyone ready to find out where water goes
and what it does?.
Ready when you are, Ms Frizzle.
Actually, I'd rather hit the Surf Ride at Water
land.
Ah! Water land! Of course!
The perfect introduction to our investigation of
water!
Are you suggesting that we really go there?.
I don't see why not.
Yeah! Oh, boy!
What a great idea!
Wait! Going to Water land has nothing to do with
a serious study of water.
Sure it does, Arn.
We could think about a mighty river as we're
riding the Floomerang!
This brochure shows the new Storm cloud
Simulator they just built!
And we could appreciate rainfall on the Raindrop
Parachute Ride!
But what about our report?.
It's all about how we use waterworks
to get clean water where we need it when we
need it. See?.
Ah! It really is quite wonderful, Arnold.
But compared to Water land, it's DRY...
DRY... DRY!
Water's no fun unless you're in it!
Ah, water...what goes around, comes around.
A veritable merry-go-round of moisture! To the
bus!
Yay!
Water land! YAYYYYY!
Wow. Look at the rain gauge. It really rained a
lot!
Yeah, more than two inches in the last hour.
According to my research, that's a school record
for rainfall.
Come on, you guys. We're gonna study some
SERlOUS water!
Wanda, do you have the keys you borrowed from
me?.
Oh! Never mind. I have a spare key...somewhere
in here. I think.
Here it is!
And here we go!
Wait a minute! I have a hunch...this is not...the
way to Water land!
This is a...FlELD DRlllllP!
What happened???.!
Welcome to the REAL Water land!!!
Where EVERYTHlNG is water! Even us!
I HATE getting wet!
As I always say, Arnold, a little water never hurt
anyone.
This is awesome!
I hope we're not going to stay in this rain gauge
all day - that would be boring!
And we wouldn't want that...
Is it just me - or is it getting really warm?.
Ms Frizzle, what happens when water gets
warm?. Do I really want to know?.
Gosh! I'm rising into the air!
WHOAAAA...SEE¡®YA!
Ralphie! Is it just you or are we ALL FLOATlNG
into the air???.!
When water is warmed by the sun...it
evapora-a-a-ates!
You mean, we're EVAPORATlNG???.!
Hellllp!
At least being water meant we stayed on the
ground! I want to be water again!
We still ARE water, Arnold. When water
evaporates, it turns into water VAPOR!
It's a gas, Arnold!
We've been VAPORlZED!
I get it! First we were a liquid -then we became a
gas! I still don't like it.
ah-ah-CHOOOOOO! It's getting c-c-c-c-cold up
here!
Hey! I'm un-vaporizing!Look at my hand!I'm
turning into tiny droplets!
That's because we're changing back into a liquid.
We're condensing!
Water is as water does!
Ms Frizzle! You turned into a clouuuuud!
Ohhh! Isn't this heavenly?.!
Wow! I never knew a cloud was water, too!
Hey! We're moving...!!!
This is Fantastic!
DUCK!
It's not easy being a cloud.
NOW where are we goiiiiiiiiiing...!
Wherever we're going?. It looks to me like it's not
our choice.
As someone once said "Clouds are the playful
fancies of the mighty wind."
Does that mean that clouds go wherever the wind
takes them?.
In a word, Keesha...YYYYYES!
Oh bad oh bad oh bad bad bad!
Then we could end up ANYwhere!!!
Right as rain, Arnold! Water goes EVERYwhere!
OHHHH, NOOOOO!!
I always wondered what it would be like to be a
cloud! I love it!
Hey, watch it!
Lighten up, Arnold! You're a cloud!
Now we're one BlG cloud!
But clouds don't go to school!Clouds don't give
reports - they stay in the air!
We'll NEVER get dow-ow-ow......ownnnn!Oh
nooo!
Arnold?.
We fell out of the cloud!
Water ALWAYS falls out of the
clouds...eventually!
It's raining!
WE are the rain, Phoebe!
This is even better than the Raindrop Parachute
Ride!!
Hope you don't mind our dropping by-eee!
Hey! A Frizzle Drizzle! Ha ha.
Go with the flow, class!
Wait for us, Ms Frizzle!
We're outta control!
Don't worry, Arnold!
Wanda, we're thousands of miles from school,
raining into some strange forest.
We're almost on the ground, and then we'll
stahhhh...
OR NOT!
Is it true that water always runs downhill?.
YES!
OH, NO!
Waterworks, water runs...waterfalls...
LOOK OUT BELOW!
Where's all this water going in such a hurry?.
Water always flows to the lowest spot, Phoebe!
And we're almost there!
THE OCEAN?.
Well, that was an interesting field trip. Can we go
back now, Ms Frizzle?.
Oh I'd like to help you out, Arnold, but...
Oh, no! We're evaporating again!
I love this part!
Who knows what happens next?. Hands?.
We c-c-condense into water droplets.
But we've b-b-been there! D-done that!
And it won't be the last time, Arnold! What
happens next?.
We become clouds!
Then we get blown who-knows-where by the
wind.
Ah! And next?.
And fall somewhere else as rain again.
Ahh! Excellent observation, Wanda!!
Are you suggesting that water never, ever stops
moving?. EVER???.!
In the words of my Great Aunt Mathilda...
NO Here we go again!
You mean, water keeps evaporating -condensing
- raining -collecting... FOREVER?????.!
Ah! Bingo! That's why its movement is called the
water CYCLE!
But water has to go somewhere!
It does! It goes around and around and around
and around...
We could be water for the rest of our lives!
We could stay stuck in the water cycle forever!
Wait a minute! This is a field trip, right?.
I mean, we've got to get back by three
o'clock...don't we?.
Oh, no! It's already three o'clock. I'm gonna miss
batting practice!
And I've got a dance lesson!
Not to worry, mates. It's only three o'clock in
London.
LONDON?.
How do we get outta here?.!
I've got it, Ms Frizzle! Since you're the one who
turned us lNTO water,
just turn us back into regular KlDS!
Ah! Unfortunately, Keesha,
I can't do that
because the key I used to turn us all into water is
ALSO water!
Well, don't you have another key?.
Would you care to take that one, Wanda?.
Well, I um... I borrowed Ms Frizzle's keys
when Arnold and I um went into the uh girls
bathroom um...Arnold?.
I... uh, l... I left the key in the bathroom.
AR-NOLLLLD!!!
But that's not all. I also forgot to empty the sink...
And I think I forgot to turn the water off all the
way. What if the whole school is flooded?.
Arnold! How could you?.!
Well,... if, if we'd just done our reports in the first
place -
none of this would've happened!
LOOK OUT!!!TAxl CAB AT 3 O'CLOCK!!
What do we do now?.!
Remember the water cycle! What comes after
raindrops?.
EVAPORATlON!
That was close!
I knew I should've stayed home today!
It's cloud time again you guys!
Seems to me, the only way out of the water
cycle... is to stop being water!
Ah! An absorbing solution, Keesha.
I've got it! Clouds are water and can go
everywhere, right?.!
Wherever the wind blows, Wanda.
So what if we could blow our clouds wherever we
want to go?.
I think that could be arranged.
Awesome! The bus can blow us back to school!
Then we can rain down, find the spare key...
and stop being water!
And I can turn off the faucet and save the school!
Here we go!
IT'S OUR SCHOOL!
And it's not flooded!
I'll get the key!
Almost there!...WHOOPS!
LlZ! Where's the key?.!
LlZ!
Here we are, Wanda!
Did you see the key?.
That's not all I saw!
The bathroom's flooding - and Liz is stuck in the
faucet!
Maybe she was trying to escape!
We've got to get inside!
But how?. We're only water.
I KNOW! The waterworks!
THE WATERWORKS?.
The REAL waterworks - the one my model is
modeled after!
It gets water to where we need it! And we're
water -
and we're needed in the girls bathroom!
And I know how to get us there!
Arnold! You're a genius!
I am?.
To the waterworks!
The reservoir!
That's where the water is stored and that's where
the waterworks start!
Class... prepare to rain!
There's no turning back now! We're in the
reservoir!
At last I get to give my report!
According to Arnold's research
a reservoir is where the water we drink is
collected.
Arnold, if this is the water we drink it's pretty
disgusting!
Yeah! It's full of dirt - Yuck! I can't believe we
drink this stuff!
Things are sure getting mixed up in here but it
doesn't look any cleaner.
Yeah, Arnold. What is this white stuff?. More
junk?.
Actually, it's alum - and if you'd look closely,
Carlos, you'll note that the dirt is actually sticking
to it
and thereby cleaning the water!
It tickles!
Yeah, but now the water is full of alum blobs!
How do we get rid of this stuff?.
This way to the settling basin!
Look, the dirty alum is settling to the bottom! And
up here! The water's clear!
Are we clean yet?.
Almost! We need to get filtered!On to the filtration
tank, class!
We will now filter through the sand and gravel
which you see below you
to get rid of any tiny particles which may have
slipped through
the cleansing process... so we can get really,
really clean!
Let's go!
HELP!
Gee, thanks, Ms Frizzle.
Ah! Anytime, Arnold. Don't let this DAMPEN your
enthusiasm!
Hey, Arnold, now that we're clean, how much
further to the girls bathroom?.
Ah...this pipe should lead to the school!
C'mon you guys!
Are we there yet?.
Almost!
LOOK!A SEA MONSTER!
WAlT! That tail looks familiar! Why it's...
IT'S LlZ! LlZ! IT'S US! WE'RE lNSlDE THE
FAUCET! YOU CAN PULL YOUR TAlL OUT
NOW!
It must be stuck!
I hate to do this Liz, but it has to be done!
Hang tennnnn...
Hey, your bathroom is way nicer than ours!
Liz, quick! Get the key ring before we evaporate
again!
Only one problem, there's not enough room in
here to transform the bus!
TlFFANY!
Tiffany! Are you okay?.
I think so?. What happened?.
Heh, heh. Well, I guess you could say our field
trip made a real. SPLASH!
Well, as I always say, to appreciate the water
cycle,
you've got to have a good sense of humid!
MS FRlZ-ZLLLLLE!
Is it the magic school bus?.
The magic school bus?.
No, this is another kid. I have a question about
the water cycle.
Water collects, evaporates...
condenses and rains. I know, I know.
But you made it seem like it happens in a few
minutes.
Sometimes, the water cycle can take weeks or
years.
You're right! And water frozen into a glacier can
take
as many as 1 0,000 years before it melts again!
Which reminds me. My mother keeps telling me
to conserve water -
But two-thirds of the earth's surface is water, so
how could we ever run out?.
We won't. While there's plenty of water in the
world -
it's not always WHERE we want it - WHEN we
want it.
In fact, only a tiny part of the earth's water is
drinkable.
Really?.
That's right. So we have to watch how we use it
and be careful not to waste it.
Hey!! Haven't YOU ever forgotten to turn off the
water?.
Sure, but that doesn't make it okay.
I - I agree.
And I promise you Arnold will never do it again.
I heard that one leaky faucet can waste several
gallons of water a day.
That's true.
By the way, you never explained how a cloud
snows.
Oh, you'll have to watch our show on ¡®Weather'
to find out the answer to that.
Thanks for calling. Come on, Liz, let's go home.
It's been a long day.