"Wings are the difference between flying and
not".
"lf you have them you can, if you don't, you
cannot".
With wings you can soar and glide in the breeze,
And dip and turn with incredible ease. "Do
loop-de-loops and shoot thru hoops".
"Fly upside-down. And roll around". "And never
ever leave the sky".
It's goanna crash!
NOSE UP, TlM! NOSE UP! Don't let her rash!
She's my baby!
Chill out, Wanda, I know how to fly this thing. I
designed it, didn't l?.
Based on MY dream - MY idea!
I drew up the plans!
And I helped you build it!
Any questions?.
Your baby's fine, Wanda. Not a scratch.
Someday you'll read about me. Wildcat Wanda,
ace test pilot, queen of the clouds!
Too bad the Frizz wasn't here to see the test
flight.
Afternoon, class.
Good afternoon, Ms Frizzle.
I was just checking the wind conditions for
today's model airplane show.
Nothing like a little moving air to lift the spirits, l
always say!
AND lift the plane. We might even win first prize
with my new wing design.
Wings are wings. What's the big deal?
Try flying without'em, Arnold.
No, thanks. I prefer walking. At least there's
something holding me up.
Ground, Arnold! Dull, dirty, boring ground -
that's what's holding you up! But it's also keeping
you down!
Imagine being inside this plane
streaking through the air at hundreds of miles an
hour -
with nothing but sky above and clouds below!
Streaking thru THlN air, you mean!
Come on, Arnold, it would be pretty hard to
streak thru FAT air!
CAR-LOS!
Let's see, wings and thin air. Now there's a
combo that just might fly!
Oh, no! You're not thinking about a field trip in
Wanda's plane,
are you, Ms Frizzle?.
Of course not, Arnold. I'm THROUGH thinking
about it!
It's time to take chances - make mistakes -
and fly like the wind! Ah... Thank you, Liz.
We can't ALL go,
Ms Frizzle. Somebody has to stay here and
operate the remote controls.
Affirmative, Tim! That puts you in charge of the
ground crew.
I need two volunteers to stay with Tim.
I'll stay, Ms Frizzle! I'll stay!
Oh, Phoebe... why don't you and Liz remain here.
I was afraid you'd say that.
All set for proper shrinkage. Hit it, Phoebe!
Well, uh... here goes! Say 'fly'.
FLYYYYYYYYYY!!!
Amazing!
I love it!
Too bad EVERY kid can't have a portashrinker!
Going up! Single file, please.
You're the best, Ms Frizzle!
The wild blue yonder is yours, Wanda. Go for it!
Yahoo.
Hey, Tim did a great job!
Yeah, he did.
This is fantastic! There's even room for my books.
I think Tim forgot the parachutes.
No need for parachutes. Not with Wildcat Wanda
at the controls.
Come on, Wanda, they're not real -they're only
paint and wood!
Wood or not - we're going where no kid has gone
before!
Can we talk about this?.
Of course, Arnold. But right now
it's time to buckle up and fly right!
You ready?.
All systems go!
Roger!
Prepare for an UPLlFTlNG experience, class.
And hold onto your hats!
Don't you ever listen?.
Happy landing!!!
We're up!
We're flying!
Feel that air moving past us!
They don't call it an airplane for nothing, Keesha!
Looking good, Tim! Can I try it?.
Sure, but be careful.
This joy stick moves the tail rudder back and forth
-
That's what steers the plane wherever you want it
to go.
Got it! Wonder how high it will go?.
We're slowing down!
Oh, my, what an AlR raising development.
The air's not moving as fast as it was before!
According to my research,
when a plane's nose tips up and slows down like
this, it's called a stall.
Stall?. As in 'stop flying'???.!
Hold it! If we stop FLYlNG. That means we
start...
FALLLLLLLLlNG...!!!
It's stalling, Feeb! Nose down...QUlCK!
Great save Phoebe, you did it!
What made it fall like that?.
No air moving past the wings. No moving air - no
lift rock fall!
You pulled it out just in time.
The queen of the clouds is back!
I think l'm goanna be sick!
You better bring them down, Tim. It's almost time
to leave for the Air Show.
Will do, Feeb. Let's see. Where's a good place to
land.
Is it just me...or did Tim just smash the remote
control?.!
You mean we're flying WlTHOUT Tim!
We weren't doing so great WlTH him!
Do something, Wanda! You got us into this!
HELLLPPPP!!!!
What are we going to do, Feeb???.!!
I don't know. This never happened at my old
school.
TlM! PHOEBE! DO SOMETHlNG!GET US
DOWN!
Come on, Liz, choose one!
We have to find our plane before something
terrible happens!
If Ms. Frizzle were here,
SHE'D know how to turn this bus into the best
search
and rescue airplane ever built!
We have wings, why aren't we flying?.
Because there's no air moving past the wings!
Hey! I think we just passed my house!
Take a good look, Carlos. It may be the last time
you see it!
Come on, you weaslely whimps, where's your
spirit of adventure?.!
We're on the path to glory!
How can we be on the path to anywhere if you
can't steer?.!
Hmmm, maybe this has something to do with the
steering. Humph! Maybe not!
I HATE WHEN THlS HAPPENS!
Gotta take action! GET THOSE WlNGS DOWN!
Push your wing down, Carlos!
I'm pushing!
Stand by to lock, Ralphie!
Standing by! PUUUUUUUUSH!!!
Wings locked!
HAAAAAANG ON!!!
As my old flight instructor used to say, two wings
are better than none!
I wish your old flight instructor were here now!
Wait second! If the wings are holding up the
plane - what's holding up the wings?.
The same thing that's holding up Carlos
... MOVlNG AlR!
Hey! I'm FLYlNG! I can feel the air lifting me up!
Me, too!
BUBBLES AT TWELVE O'CLOCK!
See, Arnold! That's why we're staying up!
The BUBBLES are holding us up?.
Not the bubbles! It's the THlN AlR moving across
the wings that's pushing us up!
right, Ms Frizzle?.
You bet your windbreaker Keesha! We all need a
little lift now and then.
Remember, Liz, we need a plane that FLlES!
We're counting on you, Liz.
All right, you did it...sort of!
What happened?. We had TEN wings! Why didn't
we stay in the air!
This heap is too heavy.
Even if it had a HUNDRED wings
it wouldn't get enough LlFT for the air to hold it
up!
Now there aren't even any wings.
Anybody know where we are?.
We're lost - that's where we are! Lost and little!
They won't find us even if they find us!
Excuse me... but our propeller just stopped
turning!
According to my research, the propeller keeps us
moving forward.
Let me understand this. If the propeller isn't
working, we slow down, right?.
And if we slow down there's going to be less and
less air moving across our wings.
Exactly and when there's no air moving across
our wings we...
FALL!!!
We could WALK to where the plane is before Liz
gets us up in the air!
We're up!
But we aren't we getting any higher!
Oh oh! It doesn't look like this plane has enough
power to get us over...
ClTY HALLLLLL!!!
Topflight, Liz!
Nice going, Wanda!
We're doomed. We'll be little model kids forever!
Instead of being Queen of the Clouds - you
should be Queen of the Trees!
Oh, yeah?.
Well, Wildcat Wanda never gives up! Come on,
guys, what made us fly before?.
Um...air moving across the wings!
Roger!
And moving air causes lift!
Double Roger!
Come on, Wanda,
the only way this plane is going to move is if it
falls out of the tree!
Ralphie's right! There is no moving air if WE'RE
not moving!
Ah, the joys of flight! Look at the power of those
wings.
That's it, Ms Frizzle! We can use that bird to tow
us up, up and away!
Only one problem. How do we STAY up?.
Yeah, how does a bird stay up?. It doesn't have a
propeller to move it forward.
By flapping its wings.
Exactly!The propeller does for a plane what
flapping wings do for a bird.
But our propeller isn't turning!
AH! Look what I found!
Wait! I've got it!
Once we get up in the air we can turn the
propeller ourselves.
What a splendid idea!
They could be anywhere, Tim. We'll NEVER find
them!
Charles Lindbergh flew across the Atlantic Ocean
in a plane like this -
all by himself.And he NEVER gave up!
You're right, Tim. We WlLL find them! I'll drive!
Pedals in place, Ms Frizzle! Ready for take-off!
Have a seat, Arnold. Prepare for bird-assisted
takeoff!
As my grandmother Frieda used to say,
a bird on the branch is worth two on the ranch!
We've got moving air and lift! Pedal, guys...
PEDAL!
It's working! Hey pedal pushers;, you're actually
turning the propeller!
We're climbing under our own power! Untie the
rope, Arnold!
Arnold!
Hang on, Arnold!
I'M HANG-llllllllNG...!!!
ARNOLD! ARNOLD!
Oh, I knew I should've stayed home today!
I don't want to be here either, ok?.
ARNOLD!WHAT'S THE BlRD'S TAlL DOlNG?.
Ummm... IT'S MOVlNG BACK AND FORTH lN
THE WlND! SORT OF LlKE HE'S STEERlNG!
HEY! MAYBE I CAN STEER BACK TO YOU!
SOUNDS LlKE THE PROPER COURSE TO ME!
Excuse me, but I need this more than you do.
Left turn, please!
BANK RlGHT, ARNOLD! MORE RlGHT...TOO
MUCH...BANK LEFT...
A LlTTLE MORE...HOLD lT! GOTCHA! SLlDE
DOWN!
Now?.
NOW!!!
GULP!
Way to go, Ace! Smooth move!
IT'S BEEN GREAT FLYlNG WlTH YOU!
THANKS FOR THE LlFT!!
I've got that air-moving-past-our-wings-feeling,
guys...keep pedalling!
We're out of control!
If only this wheel worked I could steer! KEEP
PEDALLlNG!
Too bad we're not a bird.
Arnold, you're a genius! You can help me steer!
I can?????.
Just like you steered that bird!
Exactly! Our plane has a tail, too!
I can't go out there, it's too windy!
Not too worry, Arnold. This will keep you warm
and cozy.
And this will keep you from falling.
You can do it, Arnold.
You've got the experience!
The know-how. The right stuff!
Gee, it's NlCE to be needed!
Whoa! What was that?.!!
I think we're flying over the model airplane show!
Actually, Wanda, I think we are lN the show!
We're losing altitude, Arnold!
NO PROBLEM!
AR-NOLLLLLLLLLLLLLLLD...!!!
SORRRRRR-RYYYYYYY!!!
WHATEVER YOU DO...DON'T STOP
PEDALLlNG!
Huh...Look at that, John! I've never seen a
maneuver like it. Amazing!
Look at all those planes up ahead!
Great! It's the model airplane show!
Tim, look! It's them! They're in the show!
They're also in trouble!
How can you tell?.
'Cause NOBODY'S ever done a triple lmmelman
with a double outside loop!
We've got to save them. DO SOMETHlNG, LlZ!
I hope they see us.
See us?. This plane is so big it could be a planet!
It's Liz! She wants us to land!
Take us down, Wildcat!
Roger, Ms Frizzle. PEDAL!!
I'm getting to pooped to pedal!
Me, too! Next time I want to be the pilot!
WE'RE DROPPlNG TOO FAST! BANK LEFT,
ARNOLD...LEFT!
BANKlNG LEFT!
NOSE UP, ARNOLD! NOSE UP!!!
NOSE UP!
TOO HlGH, ARNOLD...WE'RE GOlNG TO
STALL! BRlNG DOWN THE ELEVATORS!
ELEVATORS, DOWN...YESSSS!
LEVEL OUT ARNOLD, PEDAL HARDER,GUYS,
WE NEED TO KEEP OUR AlR SPEED UP AND
THE AlR MOVlNG OVER OUR WlNGS!
WE'RE PEDALLlNG! WE'RE PEDALLlNG!!
You're doing it, Wildcat! You are flying!
WE'RE COMlN' lN, LlZ! EASE OFF
ELEVATORS, ARNOLD!
EASlNG OFF!
Hold your speed, Tim, they're coming down!
Speed steady!
What an inventive performance!
Way to go, Wanda!
All right, Wildcat!
Hey! Where's Liz?.
WAY TO GO, LlZ!!!
''To both birds and planes wings are a gift,
Air rushing across them gives them a lift''.
But even with wings you need power for speed,
While a propeller must pull for the flight to
succeed. ''
And I must say that steering, I almost forgot,
Is what makes you go where you want to...or
not.'' Thank you.
And thank YOU, Wanda.
It gives me great pleasure to present
the Grand Prize for Model Airplane excellence to
you and Tim...
not only for constructing a plane with superior
design
and exceptional maneuverability -
but for incredible aerobatic ingenuity. What a
show!
Thank you, but this trophy belongs to
EVERYONE in our class.
We couldn't have won it without them. Right, Ms
Frizzle?.
Well, as I always say, sometimes you have to do
the wrong stuff -
to find out what the RlGHT stuff really is!
Is it the magic school bus?.
The magic school bus?.
Is it the magic school bus?. Is it the magic school
bus?.
Magic School Bus, the Producer speaking.
Hi. I just watched your show on flight and it really
blew me away.
But I do have a few questions.
Roger.
My name isn't Roger.
I-l'm not saying it is.
Roger is just another way of saying 'right' or
'okay' in pilot lingo.
Gotcha! Now, about those planes the bus turned
into?.
They were ridiculous! Nobody could've ever flown
them!
Believe it or not, those were real planes.
Uh sure, the first two didn't get off the ground.
But the Wright Flyer was the first airplane to
actually fly!
Okay... I mean, Roger, here's something for you.
Steering a bird or a plane is a lot more
complicated than you showed.
You got that right! Take airplanes, for openers.
They have moveable flaps on the wings as well
as on the tail.
Raise one flap up and the other one down -
and the wing rises for a banking turn to the right.
Reverse the flaps, and the plane will bank to the
left.
Oh, I get it! But here's something I DON'T get.
How does a BlRD fly?.
Ah! Good question!
The movement of a bird's wing is so complicated
-
it took stop motion photography to figure it out.
Birds use their wings both for lift and for push
forward.
Roger! But you didn't say anything about the
hardest part of flying -landing!
Well, we showed it, but we didn't talk about it.
To land, you have to slow down and fly close to
the ground reduce your lift
so you slowly sink until your wheels touch the
ground.
Then cut the power and apply the brakes.
But landing isn't always easy - and even birds
mess up once in a while.
Lizards, too! Hey, thanks for calling the Magic
School Bus.
Keep watching,and keep 'em flying!