Broccoli? You've gotta be kidding!
Who ever heard of a broccoli mascot?
According to my research, broccoli is a very
healthy vegetable.
Besides, all the animal mascots have been done
already!
Get serious, our soccer team
can't be called the Walker Elementary School
Broccolis!
Why can't we just use the old mascot?.
Because it's so old, no one knows what it is
anymore!
Yuck, it's even got moths!
Tim, no! How could you?.
It's just a bug!
Look at it, it's MORE than a bug!
For your information, it says in this book that this
moth is one of over
100,000 different kinds of moths and butterflies
And scientists are still finding new ones! And by
the way,
there are about eight times as many kinds of
moths as there are butterflies!
Excuse me, Phoebe, in exactly six hours,
we're playing the biggest soccer game of the
year...
for which we need a new mascot,
and you've got your head buried in a
BUTTERFLY BOOK!
Actually, Ralphie, it's a butterfly and MOTH book.
There's not a lot of difference, but there's
definitely-
PHOE-BEEEEE!!!
We need a mascot that's different!
It's gotta be so exciting the other team won't
know what hit ~em!!
I got it! I got it!
WHAT???.!
The Walker Elementary School BUTTERFLlES!
You want to name our soccer team the
BUTTERFLlES???.!
And have a mascot that's small...
swatable...
And PRETTY?.!?.
But butterflies are full of surprises!
Like what!!?.
Yeah, like what?.!
Janet!!
The one and only! Arnold's favorite cousin!
I AM your favorite cousin, right Arnold?.
You're my ONLY cousin Janet.
You're so cute.
We know the REAL reason you want to make a
complete wimp
Iike a butterfly the MASCOT!
You do?.
We do?.!
Isn't today's soccer game against YOUR OLD
SCHOOL?.
Janet's right, the Bulldogs are Phoebe's old team.
Whose side are you on, Phoebe?.
I'm on OUR side! I just thought--
Listen, you're looking for a new mascot, right?.
Right!
You want a mascot that's totally different, right?.
RlGHT!!
Then get this! How about the Walker Elementary
School...
um... um...Walker Elementary School... BOG
BEASTS!
YEAHHHHH...
It's new!
It's different!
It's so surprising they won't know what hit them!
ummm...What's a Bog Beast?.
A crafty question, Arnold!
Ms Frizzle!
Anyone know what a Bog Beast looks like?.
Let's see, how about you?. Janet?.
Well, it's ah... probably like...ah... ah...a friend told
me about one.
According to my research, a bog is wet, soggy
ground - like a swamp.
Seems to me, then, a swamp's the place to go to
find a Bog Beast.
But what about our soccer game?.
What's a game without a mascot?. TO THE
SWAMP!!
Not another field trip.
Cheer up, Arnold. A famous poet once said: "All
the world's a field trip -
and all the kids in our class merely guinea pigs."
Or did Ms Frizzle say that?.
Ms Frizzle, does the swamp have butterflies, too?.
The swamp has all sorts of surprises, Phoebe.
I knew she'd say that.
Everyone on the look for a bog beast!
Excuse me, Ms Frizzle,
but we're driving right into the SWAMP!
Not to worry, Ralphie, where the road ends -
adventure begins!
What is this place, Ms Frizzle?.
It's called Butterfly Bog.
I thought those butterflies were flowers.
Looks can be deceiving, Wanda. Often times,
what is - isn't.And what isn't - is.
Aahhh...Aren't they magnificent?.!Some mascot!
If Bluejays can do THAT - what are the Bulldogs
gonna do to your soccer team?.
Or is that what you want to happen, huh, Phoebe?.
NO!
Seems to me, butterflies are SO pretty -
every animal can spot ~em for a mile around.
Yeah, especially bog beasts!
Well...oooh...Come here little butterfly. Forget
about it, Liz!
Hey, do you think a butterfly's beautiful just to be
beautiful
Or is there another reason?.
I think there's more to butterflies than YOU
know...
I just wish it would hold still.
I'll get it to hold still!That'll prove what a wimp it is!
I think this is going to be one of those more
memorable field trips.
Here we are...Bog Beast Landing.
Now what?.
We camouflage the boat so it blends in with the
environment -
then we wait for the Bog Beast.
There's no time to wait! We have to catch one
now!
According to my research,
the best way to catch something is to use some
kind of bait.
Like the biggest, juiciest butterfly in the bog!
Come on, Liz, let's bag us a butterfly!
JANET! NO!
YESSS!
Why don't you pick on somebody your own size?.!
An idea worth expressing, Phoebe...or
compressing!
I'll shrink ~em with the portashrinker!
The Portashrinker?.
OH NO!
What a surprise...We're a different size!!
Oh no! We've shrunk!
And look over there The portashrinker's zapped
out!
Well, I don't care how small I am! I've got
butterflies to save!
Phoebe, come baaaack!
Fly for your lives, butterflies!Fly away! FLY FOR
YOUR...
PHOEBE!
WHAT lS lT?.
WHAT HAPPENED?.
BOG BEAST!
Okay, we've seen the bog beast, let's get outta
here!!
Uh-uh. Not so fast, Ralphie!Since you've never
seen a bog beast.
How can you be sure this is a bog beast?.
It looks more like a snake to me.
Then it's not a bog beast. It's just a--
SNAAAAAAAAKE!
Except it doesn't MOVE like a snake- it moves
like a caterpillar!
Hey, it is a caterpillar.
A caterpillar PRETENDlNG to be a snake!
Got a little nervous, eh Ralphie?. Hey, it FOOLED
me, too!
Gee, I remember when I was BlGGER than a
caterpillar.
And BlGGER than a praying mantis,too!
Don't Praying Mantises EAT caterpillars?.
Not if they think they're snakes!
Exactly, Tim! A delightfully deceitful deception!
I get it!
It's called tricking your enemy by pretending to be
something you're not!!
I'd call it good acting!
I'd call it a Swallowtail caterpillar!
Hey! What if we call our team
the Walker Elementary School Swallowtail
Caterpillars?.!
Caterpillars?.!We'll get laughed out of the game!
Besides, if we don't get back soon, there won't
BE any game!
Caterpillar's are tougher than you think, Ralphie
-
they're survivors. They live by the rule, ~fool or be
food!'
And if it KEEPS fooling them - and keeps
FEEDlNG itself,someday...
it'll change into a chrysalis.
Then it'll turn into a big,beautiful butterfly!
I see one, Liz!
Shoo, butterfly, shoo!C'mon fly away!
Come along now Phoebe.
Oh, it's not fair, Ms Frizzle.
Oh, I know. Janet doesn't stand a chance!
This one's a real JUlCY one!Where'd it go?.
Where is it?.
Okay, wise-guy, where are you?.
There it is... I think.What a disappearing act!
It's camouflaged so you can't see it against the
log!
Another illustrious illusion,Tim!
I always say, if they can't see you, ho ho, - they
can't eat you.
Pile in, class!
So...there you are. The bog beast is going to love
you.
Oh, no! Janet's going to catch that butterfly!
You're mine now, wimp!
SWAMP SWlLL!
YESSSSSSSSSS...! The butterfly got away!
A little mud can't stop us now!
Come on, Liz, we can't catch a bog beast without
a butterfly!
Okay, that's it! I'm unshrinking us all right now!
Before Jumbo Janet crushes us into pieces!
What's that?.
The Dew-Dinger.
The Dew-Dinger?.
Yes. The Dew-Dinger dings when the
portashrinker is too wet to work.
So we're stuck this size until--
Until the portashrinker dries out. So ARNOLD...
Start blowing!
Why couldn't Janet shrink instead of me?. Life
would be so much easier.
Hurry, Arnold!If we don't get bigger by game time,
the other team won't HAVE to crush us -the
BALL will!
This is all your fault, Phoebe - you
and your butterflies!
Maybe Janet was right - maybe you DO want
your old school to win the game.
I do not! And I'm NOT wrong about a butterfly. It
would make a GREAT mascot!
For a place called Butterfly Bog it's not exactly
bursting with BUTTERFLlES One!
I only need one!
Let go! I can't see.Get your hands off!
Janet! I'd know that scream anywhere.
Come on, let's go!
BOG BEEEEAST!!!
It's not a Bog Beast -it's a Zebra Butterfly!
So, Ralphie, how does it feel to be the boy who
cried bog beast?.
Well, it, um... just startled me with it's colors,
that's all!
See?. Even though butterflies are small and
pretty, they're NOT wimps!
They trick you, hide from you, even SCARE you!
That's how they stay alive!
Sounds like the perfect mascot to me!
All in favor of the Walker Elementary School
Butterflies!
NEVER! I'll play for the other team before anyone
calls me a butterfly!
It's a... a... a...
Yeah, we know, Ralphie - bog beast.
BOG BEEEEEAST!
That's not a bog beast!
And those eyes aren't real - they just LOOK like
eyes to fool the enemy.
Ahhh! An inSlGHTFUL observation, Phoebe.
And the EYEdeal name: BuckEYE.
You know, I'm beginning to think Phoebe's onto
something!
Butterflies ARE new and exciting.And they're
tricky!And boy are they surprising!
All the things we want our soccer team to be!
Okay, Phoebe, you win. Maybe there's more to
butterflies than meets the eye.
Especially if they can scare a tough guy like you,
right?.
Ah...well...the Walker Elementary School
Butterflies it is!
Let's take our team to the skies!
Let's be Walker Elementary School
BETTERFLlES!
If you insist.
The biggest, juiciest butterfly yet!
So what do you think, class?.
Well, it's certainly a new sensation, all right.
It's different!
It's surprising!
IT'S JANET!
Do something, Ms Frizzle!
Still wet.
OH NO!!
This butterfly's not only a wimp -it's DlNGY!
Janet's gonna feed us to the Bog Beast!
You won't get away this time!
She's gaining on us!
What should we do?. What should we do?. What
should we do?.
Well, as I always say, when a butterfly -- do as
the butterflies do.
Wait a second!
Is there a button on this thing that'll make us
blend in like real butterflies do?.
You might check the camouflage box.
Oh, no! Which button is it?.
Hurry, Phoebe!
According to my research--
No time for research, Dorothy Ann...
only time for getting messy -taking chances - and
making mistakes!
With all due respect, Ms Frizzle, here's hoping
this isn't a mistake!
Hey! Where'd it go?. It just disappeared!
She's gonna see us!
Everybody quiet!
The portashrinker must be dry by now!Come on,
come on... MAKE US BlG!
Arnold...WAlT! If it's not dry, the dew-dinger...
What was that?.!!
Ah ha! GOT'CHA!
Oh, no! She got us!
Just keep drying!
Come on, Phoebe, you're our last hope!
Think butterfly...think butterfly! That's it! I'll
surprise her with colors!
RED! MORE RED!YELLOW! MORE
YELLOW!ORANGE! MORE ORANGE!BLUE!
And now to trick her with eyespots!
Big...bigger...BlGGEST!
At last...you're mine!
Not yet, Janet!
Hit it Phoebe!
ALL RlGHT, PHOEBE!
Way to go!Nice one
We're safe!
Now THAT deception got a real reception!
Buterflies hide, trick, surprise --
I guess they really can take care of themselves.
What a field trip!
Gee, Janet, what happened to you?.
You almost lost a cousin, Arnold.
It was jump in the swamp - or go head to head
with the Bog Beast!
Oh, really?.
Yeah, and you're not going to believe what it
looked like!
Was it anything like...this BUSSERFLY?.
THAT'S lT! I, cousin Janet, saw the Bog Beast
and- did you say BUTTERFLY?????.
Uh-huh!
You mean there's no such thing as a Bog-beast?.
A bog beast can be anything that lives in this
swamp, Janet!
In this case, it turned out to be a butterfly.
Well, I uh... I sorta knew that -yeah- if l... umm
-yeah-
Janet, you've got it!The best possible mascot!The
BOG BEAST BUTTERFLY!!!
Yeah! Why not?. I guess we were BOTH right,
huh, Phoebe.
The score is tied - only thirty seconds remain.
The Butterflies have the ball.
Phoebe is dribbling it toward the Bulldogs' goal.
Bulldogs, Bulldogs. Fleas-y. Fleas-y. We're
gonna beat ya easy, easy.
Phoebe, Phoebe break the tie. Be our winning
butterfly!
Oh, my! The Bulldogs steal the ball!
Come on, Phoebe, get up!
Remember, butterflies are new and exciting...and
we NEVER give up!
It looks bad for the Butter... Wait! Keesha steals
the ball back!
Carlos kicks the ball to Tim. Tim kicks the ball to
Phoebe!
Ohh! Time is running out!
Five...four...three...two... SCOR...
The Butterflies win...the Bog Beast Butterflies
win! YESSS!
WAY TO GO PHOEBE!
WAY TO GO JANET!
As I always say, there's no surprise like
butterflies!
Is it the magic school bus?.
The magic school bus?.
Hello Hello!
Is this the Magic School Bus?.
Yes, this is the Producer speaking.
Well, I'm from GMM...and I'm steamed!
GMM?.
The Great Moth Majority.
I just saw your butterfly show and from what l
saw,
you don't seem to know that
there are more different kinds of MOTHS than
butterflies!
I DO know that.
But you didn't give them equal time?.
We hardly had time to cover butterflies properly.
Well, MOTHS and butterflies don't just have
eyespots for surprise, you know.
If you say so.
When a bird tries to catch a MOTH or butterfly it
goes for the eyes...
and if it goes for the eyespots all it gets is a beak
full of wing.
Believe me, I'd put a moth in the show...
If I could only CATCH ONE!
Catch one?.! That reminds me.
Janet running around trying to catch a butterfly
with a net
was insensitive and inappropriate field study.
Yes, but that's Janet's character, insensitive and
inappropriate.
That doesn't excuse improper behavior!
MOTHS and butterflies should be left alone.
You're right.
By the way, butterflies aren't only found in the
swamp.
You can find them almost anywhere.
Right again.
You can find them in the forest...the desert...the
mountains... in a shoe.
In a shoe?.
I don't know about a shoe,
but I DO know when the Great Moth Majority is
done with you,
you'll probably be looking for another job.
Funny you should mention that - I'm trying out for
another job right now.
And what would that be?.
NET-WORK producer! Gotcha!!!!!!!!!!!