Thirty seconds and counting!
Twenty-nine...twenty-eight...everything in place,
Arnold?.
Checked and double-checked, Wanda.
The Double-Trouble Wheel of Wonder is ready to
roll!
So are we, Arnold!
We've already sold 689 tickets!
And we just gave the money to the benefit for the
animal shelter!
That's just for openers, Feeb!
We're gonna be the hottest ticket at the carnival!
Crowd control in place!
Stand by to be energized. Three...two...one!
IT'S SHOWTlME!
What happened?.
Everyone's powered up but us?....Arnold?.
Don't look at me, I'm chairperson of the Safety
Committee.
Okay, so who's the chairperson of the
Power-lt-Up Committee?.!
Ah...you are, Carlos.
CAR-LOS!
Is it just me,
or does it take ELECTRlCAL ENERGY to run a
Ferris Wheel?.
Well... Hey, don't blow a fuse! All I gotta do is
plug it in.
Gonna give it the goose,
when I plug in the juice!
Here goes!
YOW! OH NO! It shorted out!
Snap out of it, guys!
We gotta get this wheel moving before the ticket
holders get hopping mad!
Don't know about mad -
but I'm HOPPlNG up and down to ride the
Double-Trouble Wheel of Wonder!
Ms Frizzle!
We need your help, Ms Frizzle.
I LEAP at the opportunity!
Plug me into the problem, Carlos.
That lS the problem, Ms Frizzle. No electricity!
We hooked up the cable and it went kablooey!
No energy - no motion.
No rides on the Ferris Wheel.
And that was the last cable, too!
No need to get hectic over electric!
It's not the ONLY source of ENERGY!
IT'S NOT?????.
Nope, the world's full of energy.
You just have to find it - harness it - and put it to
work for you.
Find it?. Harness it?. Put it to work?. We don't
have time!
Sounds like we need an eXpert! Hey, Mikey!
Come in!
GASP!!! NOT MlKEY!!!
Last time your little brother
helped out we really got burned!
Okay, so we took a ride through my Seer
¡®Em & Sizzle ¡®Em Marshmallow Smoker'.
But you must admit, those marshmallows were
certainly tasty!
Yeah, and I had a heat rash for days!
I'd rather turn this thing by hand than ask Mikey
for help!
That's it! MANpower!
Don't you mean, PERSON power, Ralphie?.
Whatever, Phoebe. Come on, guys uh... people,
let's crank it up!
TURN!
Whew! This is hard!
What a ride! We could probably
go around at least once by sunset!
Come on, Carlos, this is serious!
We need energy to move this thing - not jokes!
If we don't get it moving soon...
...we'll have to call the riot police!
I suppose we COULD refund their money.
We can't do that! What about all those poor,
helpless animals at the shelter?.
What about them?.
Phoebe's right. We can't let them down.
Call Mikey.
It's really just a matter of delivering
the right amount of energy to the right spot.
Mikey! Come in Mikey!
Hang on a sec!!
...Yo Carlos! What's up?.
The Wheel of Wonder is grounded!
I plugged it in and it went kablooey.
No problem, bro. There's a big world out there
loaded with energy.
All we gotta do is find it!
I couldn't have said it better myself!
Clear the runway, I'm on my way!
So what was that about deliverin' the right energy
to the right spot?.
Well... Iet me put it this way, my friend, it's when
motion... makes commotion!
OH NO!!! Gang way!
Hey, that might work!
Whoa! That falling rock turned the Ferris wheel!
You got it! EXCUSE ME!
And if the energy of one falling rock can turn it
once -
imagine what a whole BUNCH of rocks could do!
YO MlKEY!!
At your service and ready to roll!
Hey, Dorothy Ann,
glad to see you got rid of that rash.
EXcuse me, but as head of the Safety Committee,
I don't think falling rocks are a safe thing to use.
Got it covered, Arn! The rocks will fall into one
set of seats
while the people ride in the other!
Why didn't I think of that?.
Yeah, when I was Mikey's age, I was still doing
weight and volume in the sandboX.
Let's go rock hunting, you guys!!
But what about the crowd?. They're getting
restless.
Somebody has to stay here and make sure
they don't tear down the Ferris Wheel next!
Who's gonna do that?.
How 'bout you?.
Uh! Wait a minute... hold it a second--
O. K. Class! Let's rock ¡®n roll!!
But, I'm just one kid. What can I do?.
Wing it, Carlos!
May the rocks be with you soon, Carlos. Buckle
up everyone.
OK, Ms Frizzle! It's rock power we're after.
We want to find it - harness it - and put it to work!
Whatever MOVES you, Mikey! Bus...do your
stuff!
Boulders! Gazillions of them!
All we gotta do now is get ¡®em to the top of the
mountain!
How?. Carry ¡®em one by one - then drop ¡®em on
the Ferris Wheel?.
Speaking of dropping, that's not a bad idea,
Ralphie!
Take chances. Make mistakes.
Get messy!
The Friz thinks of everything!
Don't you think she could have warned us we
were going to eject?.
I heard that Arnold! Now look out below!
Prepare for landing!
YEAH!
Catch you later, class!
Knock knock.
Who's there?.
No fair.
No fair who?.
No Ferris Wheel yet! Ha Ha.
Mikey! Do you copy?. Over!
Ten-four!
Where are those rocks?.
We're workin' on it!
According to my research, oof!, at the rate we're
going -
we should have enough rocks, at the top of the
mountain
by the time I'm sixty-two!
DA's right.
We'll NEVER get enough rocks
to the top of that mountain to power the Ferris
Wheel!
There must be another way!
Ralphie! You chipped it!
They're ROCKS, Arnold, not antiques!
Do something, Mikey. I'm outta jokes and blowin'
hot air!
It's blowin' pretty good here, too!
MY CAP! COME BACK HERE!
Hey, if the wind has enough energy to move
Ralphie's cap like that -
maybe it could move these rocks!
Yeah, right, Phoebe. Like the wind is going to
BLOW the rocks up the mountain?.
Not a bad idea, Keesha! Ever heard of a
windmill?.
The wind turns the blade of the windmill...
that turns a drum...
which moves a conveyor belt...
that carries the rocks up the mountain...
and drops them on the Ferris Wheel!
Wow, I have to hand it to you, Mikey. This is a
pretty cool idea!
Can I have my belt back, now?.
Is it just me, or do we have a little size problem
here?.
Yeah, WHERE are we going to get a windmill big
enough
to move BOULDERS to the top of the mountain?.
As I always say,
where there's a will - there's a windmill!
How far can a dog run into the forest?.
HOW FAR!!!!
Half way! After that, he's running out!(he
FORCES a LAUGH)
Any luck, Liz?.
I didn't think so.
I think the wind is just right, Ms Frizzle!
Then capture it and put it to work, Mikey!
Ready, guys?.
READY!
I don't know, Mikey. I still don't think it's gonna
work.
Hang onto your sombrero, Ralphie. Here she
BLOWS!
Hey! We're moving!
IT'S WORKlNG!
Well, what do you think, Ralphie?.
I think moving rocks is a breeze especially when
the wind is doing all the work!
Let's hear it for wind energy!
It's taking us AND the rocks right up the
mountain!
And into the RlVER!!!
I just ate!!
As the Friz would say... it never hurts to be
prepared!
MlKEY!
HELP!! SAVE US!
Hang on, you guys!!!
Way to go, Mikey!
You saved us!
Awright!
Hold it a second! WE may not be in the water
- but the ROCKS are!
Yeah! How do we get them up the mountain
now?.!
Hey, gimme a break! We harnessed enough
energy to get them this far didn't we?.
But what about that!
RAPlDS!!!
What a ride! Surf city!
I never realized water had so much energy.
Hey! If water has the energy to move US -
maybe we can harness it to move the ROCKS!
Ralphie, how are we going to do that?. Water
can't go UP hill!
But rocks CAN!
See what the water did to our raft?.
It looks like a paddlewheel!
EXactly!! It seems to me, if we hooked some kind
of stick to the paddlewheel--
And, and connected a spoon thingy to the
OTHER end of the stick--
Yeah! So when the spoon thingy gets bent by
the paddlewheel...
and the rocks fall in it SLlNGS 'em up the
mountain! KAPOWlE!
As the Friz would say,
it's time to take chances - get messy and...
where is Ms Frizzle, anyway?.
Hi ho!! One water-driven rock-a-pult for your
eXamination!
Batteries not needed - some assembly required!
Is this water-wheel actually going to get the rocks
up the mountain, Ms Frizzle?.
There's no power like water power, Arnold!
Water energy to the rescue!
AY!
I guess I owe you one, Mikey.
I really didn't think there was enough energy in
the water
to push these paddles hard enough to turn the
waterwheel...
so it could flip the catapult and fire a rock!
Making us the rock-toting champions of the
world! Right, guys?.
YEAH!
Huh oh! I think we yeahed to soon. It looks like
the tension bar's jammed!
I think you're right, Ralphie. See if you can re-set
it.
Uh...isn't there anything else we can do?.
Never mind, Ralphie. I'll do it! What could
possibly happen?.
Careful, Wanda!
Just give it a little tug to the left.
No sweat, Mikey - I've got it covered!
C'mon Ralphie! Help me out here!
Ralphie, come BACK!!!
RAL-PHlE!!!
WHOA!!! I think I'm gonna be sick!!!
Good aim, Ralphie!
What now?.
Wind and water energy only got the rocks to
here...
and we need them up THERE!
AND, unless we think of another source of
energy,
we'll NEVER get our Ferris Wheel turning - which
means
we'll have to take the money back from the
animal shelter.
Maybe we should've called it the Double-Trouble
Wheel of Blunder!
Bad one, Ralphie!
You think YOU'RE depressed, think about our
customers.
Why?. Because they can't ride the ferris wheel?.
No, because Carlos has probably
started doing his impressions by now!
Listen up, people! You will ride the Wheel of
Wonder when I say it is time!
We wanna ride!
I'll be back!
Whoa! Big pile of batteries!! How's it going Liz?.
Ms. Frizzle to Carlos. Over.
Things are heating up, Ms Frizzle.
You better do something quick!
We're working on it, Carlos. Ten-four!
Well class... Anybody have any HOT ideas:.
Carlos said the crowd is really getting STEAMED!
Speaking of steamed, I'm BOlLlNG!
Yeah, me, too! The sun is roasting me.
Wait a second!
If we used wind and water energy to move the
rocks,
maybe we can move them by using...
SOLAR ENERGY!!!
YEAH! But how?. Hmmm... I got it!
Yeah! Let's do it!!!
If we can get enough of the sun's energy to a
canteen,
the water will boil, and--
I know, I know! The water will boil, build up
steam inside...
Yeah, we're cookin', now!
That steam'll build up enough energy to LAUNCH
a ROCKET!
I mean, a ROCK, Ralphie, a rock!
It works!!
They'll be comin' over the mountain when they
come...
Man, talk about too little too late!
You design ¡®em, we deliver ¡®em!
One solar-powered, steam-driven,
rock-launcher...at your service!
YAY!!!
GET BACK! BACK, I TELL¡®YA,
OR l'LL DO MY ARNOLD SCHWARZENEGGER
lMPRESSlON AGAlN!
MlKEY! GET ME OUT OF HERE!
Got it covered, Carlos!
ENERGY TO THE RESCUE!
Ok guys...Iet's get those rocks moving!
The wind's blowing and the rocks are rolling...
Water's flowing.
CatapuIt's throwing!
The sun is shining!
Yikes! It's boiling!
Pressure's right, Mikey!
Time to rock and roll! MS FRlZZLE!
HlT lT KEESHA!
Rocks away!
MlKEY! MlKEY!
What happened, Carlos?.
I think you found a new source of energy.
What's that?.
MlKEY-POWER!!! YEEEAAY!!!
Calm down, folks. No pushing. We'll be here all
day.
Everyone gets a chance to ride the
Double-Trouble Wheel of Wonder.
SiX-ninety-eight...siX-ninety-nine...
we sold seven hundred more tickets for the
shelter!
And they're still comin', Feeb!
We're customerized - revitalized - and
ENERGlZED!
Hi, Ms Frizzle! Hi, Mikey!
Your wind-powered, water-powered,
solar-powered system is in full operation, Mikey.
Rock solid!
Looks that way, Ms Frizzle.
Wind energy harnessed, moving the rocks
smartly up the mountain! Ten-four!
Water energy captured, tossing the rocks toward
the top! Ten-four!
Solar energy making steam!!
We couldn't have done it without you, Mikey!!
Ah, it was nothin', Ms Frizzle.
Nothing but your endless energy and the power
of your imagination!
Is it the magic school bus?.
The magic school bus?.
Magic School Bus - the Producer here.
Just the person I wanted! I'm from the SPCR.
What's the SPCR?.
The Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to
REALlTY!
Uh oh.
I mean, running a Ferris Wheel with falling rocks?.
That's ridiculous!
Uh. True, machines that run on the energy of
falling rocks
probably aren't a good idea.
If your dishwasher ran on falling rocks,
ou might not have many dishes.
So why didn't the kids just use wind power - or
water power -
or solar power directly to run the Ferris Wheel?.
Because the wind
water and solar energy they needed was on the
other side of the mountain.
So they used that energy to move the rocks
so the rocks could move the Ferris Wheel.
Are you saying
there wasn't enough wind, water or solar energy
where the Ferris Wheel was?.
EXactly. There are lots of different sources of
energy,
but unless you can harness them - and move the
energy to your machine -
you can't use it.
Seems to me moving energy can be dangerous
and shouldn't be done carelessly.
That's a good point. Energy is powerful -
and power can be dangerous if you don't know
how to use it.
Okay, that's cool,
and the SPCR doesn't mind a little reality-bashing
in the name of education -
but there ARE limits!
Go ahead, I'm sitting down. What's the problem?.
You really eXpect us to believe that
Mikey had the power to actually knock the bell
clear OFF the hammer-slammer?.!
Listen, just between us,
we had a story conference about that and it was
Ms Frizzle's idea.
You mean Ms Frizzle is REAL?.
Well, she does have her moments. But you didn't
hear it from me, okay?.
Thanks for calling! Bye!!