O.K... Hold this steady!.
HEY D.A.! Get yet nose out of that book!
We need help with this thing.
Just a sec...
we've got to follow the instructions or the whole
thing is going to fall apart!
Good morning, class!
Ms Frizzle!
WOW! A humandoidus-eruptus!
Oh, man.
Carlos, according to my research
it looks to me as if you need one more piece.
If you didn't spend so much time reading and
researching,
you might actually do something!
And if you'd spent more time researching,
you would've known how to put this globe
together!
Gotcha!
I'm afraid you can't put that globe together until
you have ALL the pieces!
SO! There lS a piece missing!
I knew that!
Of course there's a piece missing!
An island so new it hasn't even been discovered
yet!
How can there be a new island?.
Everything's already here.
Yeah! The earth never changes...
Does it?.
Actually, the earth is changing all the time
right under your very own feet!
It is?.
Bet I can find the new island in one of my books.
What's its name?.
How can it have a name if it hasn't been
discovered yet?.
YEEAAH! and besides D.A.,
By the time you find a clue in all these books
we could discover this mystery island and name it
ourselves!
What a positively explosive proposition, Carlos!
Let's shake a leg - if you get my drift!
Ummm...you're not suggesting another field trip,
are you, Ms Frizzle???.
UMPH! Whoa! To the BUS!!!
This is your captain speaking.
On behalf of my flight crew...
I want to welcome you aboard "Magic School
Bus" Airways.
BUS,... DO YOUR STUFF!
Here we GO!!!
Class, at our present speed, the new island
should be arriving...!
...a lot sooner than I thought.
The lSLAND should be arriving?????.
In accordance with Federal regulations, let me
remind you--
...that this is a non-nail-biting flight.
When we find the island, what should we name
it?.
Let's see...
I now declare this island -
which I alone have discovered, to be...Carlos
lsland!
Forget it! That's a silly name for an island!
What would YOU call it?. "According To My
Research" lsland?.
No... that's too clunky. Wait a minute!
... I've got a book of names in here.
You can't even think of a name without looking it
up!
Let's see, we could call it
Paradise lsland.
No... too predictable.
Then there's always...
Gilligan's lsland
No... That's already taken.
Looks like our game's gonna get rained out, Ms
Frizzle.
Oh, don't head for the dugout yet, Ralphie.
Those aren't rain clouds,
they're puffs of smoke and ash.
Which means... We are exactly where we need
to be.
Gee, look at that stuff.
It smells, too.
Don't look at me!
The windows are covered with ashes!!!
Put your seats in an upright position, class, and
prepare for landing.
We can't land now! We can't see where we're
going!
Don't worry, Arnold, we won't be landing for
another few minutes.
Whoops, ho, ho, make that a few seconds.
Not to worry class...
HANG TEN, BUS!!
Like wowwww!
TUBULAR.
We could call it Empirical lsland!
Hmmm... not bad.
All ashore that's going ashore!
I don't see any shore, Ms Frizzle.
That's because we're a tad early, Tim.
As I always say get out there AND EXPLORE!
How does she DO that?.!
Not easily I expect.
Well, in the famous words of Ms Frizzle:. the early
bird gets the island.
Watch it!
WAlT! Oh no! MY BOOKS!
I've got'cha!
COME ON YOU WEASLY WlMPS... PULL!!
We have to go down there, Ms Frizzle. I need
my books to find that island!
Wouldn't it be easier to go to a bookstore?.
Please, Ms Frizzle?. I'm nothing without my
books!
ME-BOOKS! BOOKS-ME!
...CLASS! Prepare to dive!
Coming, Carlos?.
Not me, Ms Frizzle. I'd rather find that island
than D.A.'s books.
Suit yourself, Carlos.
Anchors away, mates!
Um, if you don't mind, Ms Frizzle,
I'd rather keep as much water between me and
the bottom of the ocean as possible.
A lofty idea, Arnold.
Perhaps you could help Carlos person the
life-raft.
If you insist!
And while you two are personing put these on!
Yes Liz?.
Good idea, Liz.
As a Certified Teaching Lizard, you're more than
capable of handling the mission.
Carry on.
Do your stuff, BUS!
BATTEN DOWN THE HATCHES!
Don't be too long.
Come on, Arnold, lets find that island before D.A.
comes back!
Don't you think we should wait here?.
He who hesitates is lost!
Lost. That's the word that bothers me.
C'mon Arnold... Relax, willya?.
I had no idea there were mountains under the
ocean!
If I had my books I could tell you all about
underwater mountains.
Who needs books when you have the real thing?.
My bag! Ms Frizzle! Step on it!
You got it, D.A.! GOlNG DOWN.
Is this the ocean floor?.
Bottoms up, everybody!
Now where'd that bookbag get to... There it goes!
I'll get it!
HUH?. On second thought...
Move aside, Ralphie... I've gotta get my bag.
Ah, here it is.
OH NO!
HOLY, JUMPlN'!!!...
IT'S GOT MY BAG!!
OCT...OCTO.. OCTOPPPP.... OCTOPUS!
Close but no ink, Ralphie
it's a squid, not an octopus.
A squid has ten tentacles -an octopus only has
eight.
Then how come they don't call them "octacles"?.
Good one, Ralphie!
I don't care how many tentacles it's got,
it's got my books! Come back here!
WHAT'S HAPPENlNG?.
IT'S AN EARTH-QUAAAAKE!!!
We're in trouble!
GOT lT! OH, MY....
Oh no! My source of knowledge is GONE!
I tell'ya, something's going on down there.
Maybe, but it can't be an island 'cause an island
isn't underwater...is it?.
Ar-nold!!!
IT WASN'T ME!
Liiiiiiiz...?.!
It's coming from those bubbles!
And there's D.A.'s BOOKBAG!
Great! See if there's a map back to school in it.
Get real, Arnold! We have a chance to make
history!
Maybe there's something in here that can tell us
what's going on.
The bag fell this way. I SAW it! I'm sure I did!
Cheer up, Dorothy Ann, there's more than one
way to discover an island.
I'm getting c-c-c-cold.
The deeper the water - the colder it gets, Wanda.
Even the bus is cold.
If the water's so cold, how come these
funny-looking smokestacks are so hot?.
Good show, Phoe-be!
Something must be heating these things from
underneath.
Is that revelation according to your research?.
How could it be according to my research?. I
don't have my research!!
Bingo! But- if you keep asking questions you'll
keep getting answers!
Hey D.A... Maybe your books sank down there!
I sure hope not. That looks like a canyon in the
bottom of the ocean.
In the immortal words of our very own Ralphie...
...you can't hit a home run unless you swing the
bat. Back to the bus, team!
I wonder if Carlos found the island yet?.
Haaa! Before us???.! Not on your pigtails, D.A.!
"As the sea billowed around them,
it seemed as if the entire earth was going to
explode.
Lars could feel the ocean floor trembling beneath
them
he could almost smell the crust melting...
What are you reading - a cookbook?.
Listen to this! It says right here,
the earth's surface is made up of layered,
crust-like plates of rock.
These plates normally move incredibly slowly,
but sometimes one plate jams under another one.
When the plate slips, we can actually feel the
earth move!
Carlos, you're starting to sound like Dorothy Ann!
I like to think of the world as a toasted bowling
ball with a crust...
...and we're right here on the edge of two pieces
of crust like these.
And sometimes one piece gets shoved under the
other... Oops!
You created an earthquake!
Does that mean we're actually going down
BETWEEN those two pieces of crust???.!
We have to! That's where my books must be!
But there's no space between them. How can we
get through?.
Show, Bus! IT'S ACTlON Tl ME!
This is terrific!
Speak for yourself, D.A.!
Hang on, everybody!
I'm being squished!
It's getting hot in here!
These rocks around us are melting.
You bet they are, class!
WE'RE MEL-TlllllNG...!
It's so hot the earth's crust is melting!
It's supposed to melt, Keesha.
I mean, my goodness, the deeper you go into the
earth Phew! the hotter it gets.
Anyone know what melted rock is called?.
Rock juice?.
Magma.
It must be 2OOO degrees out there!
So there's melted rock deep under the ocean?.
...what's it all mean?.
I think I know!
Heat under the ocean floor
plunging plates of crust...
... melted rock under a mountain...
WE'RE lN AN UNDERWATER VOLCANO!
A VOLCANO?????.!
UNDERWATER???.!
Boingo, Dorothy Ann!
And you figured it out from your own
observations!
Welcome to the Magma Chamber
the heart of a volcano!
How do we get out of here?.!!
Out of a volcano?. How do you suppose?.!
And then a giant fountain of steam shot out of the
water...
...followed by an explosion of--
STOP! I can't take it anymore! You HAVE turned
into Dorothy Ann!
But Arnold... it's all here in this book.
Smelly gasses fountains of steam...
explosions of lava.
Arnold, don't you understand?.
According to my research, we're floating on top of
an undersea volcano!
I KNEW I SHOULD'VE STAYED HOME TODAY!
THE MAGMA'S RlSlNG!
We're gonna get blown sky high!
Wait a minute, wait a minute-- WAlT-A- MlNUTE!
Do we have that long?.
When all this molten rock shoots up out of the
volcano
and hits the air, it'll cool, right?.
Oh, absolutely.
And when it cools - it'll harden into rock, right?.
NEW rock!!
Eventually!
So, all that new rock will build up on top of this
underwater volcano
... until it sticks up out of the water
enough to make A BRAND NEW lSLAND!!!
YESSSSS...!
Oh, no! We've stopped rising!
Something must be plugging up the volcano!
And the magma's squeezing us!
All we have to do to get out is give that rock up
there a push!
We don't HAVE to do anything!
Yes we do, Ralphie!
It's time to take chances,
make mistakes get melted!!!
Into your anti-magma gear, everyone!
According to this book, a lot of stuff gets blown
out of a volcano when it erupts.
Like volcanic ash. Volcanic ash?.!
Pumice and rocks! Pumice and rocks???.!!
And LAVA! LAVA???.!?.
Put them all together and you-- GET ME
OUTTA HERE!
No, Arnold, you get...CARLOS lSLAND!
PUSH!!! This is the chance of a lifetime!
The END of a lifetime, you mean!
Push, Ralphie! Don't let the pressure get to you!
MY HELMET lS CRACKlNG. HURRY!
We can't budge it, Ms Frizzle! WE NEED HELP!!
Come on, Bus!...do your STUFF!!!
It's working!
Play it again, Bus...YEAH!
It's ready to blow!
WA.... HOOOOOOOO!!!
Carlos lsland is about to be BORN!
...Too bad D.A.'s gonna miss it!
I'd give ANYTHlNG to miss it!
Is it over yet?.
It's just beginning, Arnold!
I CAN'T BELlEVE lT!
...the volcano is making new rock! It's actually
making a new island!
D.A.'s really missing something!
DOROTHY ANN?.! Where'd you come from?????.
D.A.! You just missed the coolest eruption you
ever saw!
I didn't miss it! I was part of it!
Where's everybody else?.
Wow! What a ride!
I like being erupted!
But where's Ms Frizzle?.
Hi-ho, everyone! WA-HOOOOO...!
Nice landing, Ms Frizzle!
To Carlos lsland!
Carlos lsland?????.
You mean D.A. Island!
I discovered it -even WlTHOUT my books.
But neither one of you LANDED there first!
LOOK!
Liz?.
Here's your bookbag, D.A.. I never thought l'd
say this,
but I was really glad to have it.
And I was really glad I DlDN'T have it for a
change.
What an experience!
I think we should write a book about it.
"DlSCOVERlNG LlZARD lSLAND' by D.A. and
Carlos.
You mean by Carlos and D.A..
No, D.A. and Carlos.
Carlos and D.A. D.A. AND CARLOS!!!
As I always say, unlike the earth -
some things never change.
Carlos and D.A.
D.A.!!! CARLOS!!!
Is it the magic school bus?.
The magic school bus?.
So, Liz, how does it feel to have your own island
out here
in the middle of nowhere?.
I don't believe this. I'm supposed to be on
vocation.
Hello. Magic School Bus... Producer speaking...
Hello. I just saw your show on volcanoes,
and I've got to tell you, it was unbelievable.
I know, I know.
It takes a lot longer than a few minutes for a
volcano...
...to grow from an undersea mountain to an
island.
And it probably took thousands of years for that
mountain to get as big as it was.
Exactly. But hey, we've only got a half an hour to
tell the story.
I gotcha.
And I totally bought the connection
between the erupting volcano and the making of
an island.
Great! Then you know that a volcano in the sea
is just like a volcano on land.
No, but I do now.
There's no fire in a volcano, only heat,
so the water can't put it out, right?.
You got it.
But not all volcanoes form where a plate gets
pushed down into the crust.
They don't?.
Some volcanoes form where plates pull apart -
and others are just over hot spots in the crust.
Okay,
so maybe you didn't believe the part where the
kids got so close to the volcano.
Oh, come on - it's television!
We all know real kids don't go inside volcanoes
or hang around on rafts when they're erupting.
NO WAY!
I guess not.
So what is it you found so unbelievable?.
That Liz just so happened to have a flag on her
when she landed on the new island!
That is pretty unbelievable... but don't forget...
Liz isn't your ordinary lizard.