Sorry, Carlos!
Hey, Feeb! What's the rush!
It's my weekend to bring Liz home! I have to get
her ready!
OH MY!
What's wrong?
Liz is missing!
MlSSlNG? But she was here yesterday!
She's here every day!
Maybe she moved into another classroom.
No way, Ralphie! Liz loves it here! She'd NEVER
leave us!
Then how come her sunglasses are gone!
And her earphones!
Huh. And her entire habitat!
MS FRlZZLE!
Good morning, class!
Ms Frizzle! Liz is missing!
Oh, I know. And so is the air from my alligator.
I don't get it! Ms Frizzle sounds so unconcerned.
Cold-blooded is more like it!
Did somebody say ¡®cold-blooded'?.
That reminds me, Liz is not going to be here t'...
A note! I found a note!
What's it say?.
I don't know. It's written in lizard. Can you read it,
Ms Frizzle?.
Let's see. "Claw polish, scale moisturizer,
fangpaste..."
That sounds like a packing list!
Then Liz DlD move out!
And I know where! She went to Herp Ha! The
address is right here!
It's not Herp Ha - it's Herp something else! The
rest of the Ha is torn off!
Okay, but what's a Herp?.
Oh, good question, Ralphie! Quite simply, a herp
is a reptile.
And Liz is a lizard which makes her a reptile, so...
So that still doesn't tell us why She'd pack up all
of her stuff and leave us!
What if she's in terrible danger?.
Oh, if only we knew what it was like to be a lizard
- to feel what Liz feels -
to get inside her skin, maybe then, maybe then
we'd know the answer!
I couldn't have said it better myself! To the bus!
Is a rescue mission considered the same as a
field trip?.
"Herp... Haven"
I told you it wasn't Herp Ha!
I don't see anything funny about this place,
anyway.
What kind of place is this?.
YlKES! An alligator crossing!
They're probably there to keep visitors out!
Or keep Liz in!
HEY, LOOK OUT!
Shooooo...that turtle's humongous!
Ah... Mrs. Westlake...how can we serve your
reptilian friend...
I want him toasted and stuffed, just like the last
one.
You do have a sense of humor, Mrs. Westlake.
Ta ta.
Toasted and stuffed?.
Sounds like that turtle is about to become
somebody's dinner!
Oh, no! What if Liz is next?.
Liz ala mode, sprinkled with pecans and a light
honey-chestnut glaze!
Ooo, if only we could get inside!
I think my great Aunt Penny said it best: "A lost
ball can go a long way."
Yes?.
Hi. I am but an innocent school child
who has innocently lost my innocent baseball
over your fence.
May I innocently come in and innocently get it
back?.
There are certain requirements that must be met
before entry is allowed.
Requirements?.
Yes. "Body temperature : changeable. Sweat
glands: none.
Scales or skin: allowed. Hair: not allowed." See
for yourself!
And we definitely do NOT take bats! Thank you.
Good day.
Wait, l--
"Body temperature: changeable".
Well, that let's us out. Our body temperature
stays mostly the same.
That's why we're called WARM-blooded!
Then -- is a reptile called COLD-blooded?.
Ah. It is indeed, Tim! ALL reptiles are
cold-blooded.
Cold-blooded, old-blooded. What we need is a
plan!
Okay. Since they won't LET us in -
we need to get inside without them knowing we're
inside!
What we need is... a DlSGUlSE!
I've got it! A Trojan horse!
No way, DA. They only take reptiles! And a horse
isn't a reptile!
Not a REAL horse, Ralphie! According to my
research, in ancient times,
Greek soldiers built a huge wooden horse and hid
inside it to fool their enemy.
That's it! We turn the bus into a
Trojan...ALLlGATOR!
You sure this is going to work, Ms Frizzle?.
As I always say, ¡®if you can't beat ¡®em, join ¡®em'!
Here we go.
Everyone okay in there?.
Happy as a herp, Feeb! Let's do it!
Man, this is what I call an lNSlDE job!
CAR-LOS!
Remember, keep your eyes open for Liz!
Stand by, we're goin' in!
Yes?. Ah, what a splendid alligator. Would you
like to come inside?.
Yes, but I don't want her toasted and stuffed!
Whatever you say, my dear. We'll just tease her
and squeeze her.
Does she have a name?.
Valerie!
How enchanting. Come along, Valerie.
Wait here!
But uh...Valerie doesn't like to be alone.
No need to be concerned.
We just l-o-o-o-o-v-v-e-e our cold-blooded critters
to death.
What does he mean by that?.
Did you say something?.
Uh... I said I hope she's not, not too fat.
Silly girl, reptiles never get fat!
Wait, l... I was hoping to see how you do
whatever it is you do.
Uh. Really, watching can be so tire some. Relax,
read a magazine.
But, uh, but--
We'll let you know when she's done.
When she's done?.
Yes?. Young lady?.
Liz?. LlZ! Where are you?.
We did it! We 're in!
We're in hot water, you mean!
Cold water, actually!
Cold - hot, either way, we're sunk! How do we get
out of here?.
We can't go out there!
Those are real snakes and alligators crawling
around!
They look like they're looking for something.
As long as they're not looking for us.
Hey, that lizard looks just like Liz!
Maybe Liz was homesick.
One thing's for sure, we can't find Liz by staying
in here!
I recall my great Aunt Beatrice once said,
¡®you know, one good reptile deserves another'.
Great idea, Ms Frizzle! If we become reptiles...
then that guy at the front door won't bother us!
And we can look for Liz and nobody will know the
difference! Go for it!
All right! Gather 'round all you would be reptiles!
Umm... Ms Frizzle,
don't you think someone should stay behind and
keep an eye on the busagator?.
Good thinking, Arnold! The job is yours!
I'll stay with you, Arnold.
Think of your favorite reptile. Ready?.
Say ahhhhh, bus!
Awesome!
Incredible!
COOL!
Cool is right, Ms Frizzle! I'm chilly, ooh!
Any better?.
Uh uh. I'm still cold.
I don't think hiding in your shell is gonna get the
job done, Ralphie.
Looks like we have to move to a warmer place -
like this turtle did over here!
Wait for me! Hey, you're right! The heat
OUTSlDE is making me warmer lNSlDE!
Hm, toasty.
That's it! To FEEL the heat - you have to FlND
the heat!
Ah. You're hot today, Tim! To a reptile, location is
everything.
Come on, guys, Liz is not here! We've got to find
her!
I'll get the door!
Whoa. Good one, Keesh!
Oh, oh, we're dead meat!
According to my research, alligators seldom
attack human beings.
Uh. I hate to remind you, DA, but we're human
beings inside a busagator!
LlZ?. LlZ, I KNOW YOU'RE HERE! Food?.
Suppertime. I love suppertime. reptiles and
lizards too.
We're gonna give it to you.
Ah, fly fricassee with a, umm, light bug sauce,
umm! They'll love it!
MENU?. Please please please let there be no Liz
Delight or Spaghetti and Lizballs.
Phew! Nothing. Whoa, the lizards get just one
meal a week and the alligators get only one meal
a month!
How inhumane! What kind of place is this?.
I just don't get it!
Why would Liz want to leave our warm and cozy
classroom
for a weird place like this?.
Got me! Let's look in here.
Hmh! I'm getting good at this.
Whoa, bake city!
Whew! I'm boiling, too!
That's because we're in the boiler room!
So how come I'm not perspiring like I usually do
when I'm hot?.
No sweat, Tim!
Sweat glands - none! That's what it said on that
scroll!
So I bet reptiles CAN'T sweat to cool down even
if they wanted to!
Hold it! If you have to find heat to feel warm -
maybe you have to find cold to cool down.
Only one way to find out!
I can feel my temperature dropping already.
Amazing! One little move turns a hot foot into a
cool mule!
I can't believe us! We're more worried about
staying the right temperature
than we are about finding the one and only Liz!
Come on, we have to get moving!
Aw, just when I was feeling comfy!
Turn on the heat, DA, I'm c-c-cold!
I g-g-guess there's no heater in a busagator
because it's a reptile!
Then move the busagator to where it's
w-w-warmer!
I c-c-can't do that, either! The b-b-busagator isn't
w-w-working!
It's probably too c-c-cold, that's why!
Maybe if we bring heat to the b-b-bus, we can
g-g-get it to m-m-move!
If we're not careful, we could wind up inside a
REAL alligator.
Excuse me, l... I'm really sorry. I'll never do it
again I promise!
Over here, Arnold! Help me push this heat lamp
to the busagator.
Don't look now, but we're being followed!
Maybe they're upset because we took their heat.
FORGET THE HEAT! BACK TO THE BUS!
But we need it to get the bus moving!
You're going to need more than heat to get you
moving
if that gator gets any closer!
Come on, come on.
THAT WAS CLOSE!
The Quiet Room.
It's like a fridge in here!
Some of these guys look like they've been here
for months!
And that one on the end looks like...
LlZ!
Liz! Wake up! It's us!
She's barely breathing!
I can't hear her heartbeat!
Liz, snap out of it.
What are we goanna do?. What are we goanna
do?. What are we goanna do?.
Come on, Liz! Wake up!
She's not sleeping - she looks like she's frozen!
I don't get it! It feels so cold in here - how come
I'm not shivering?.
Since they don't have sweat glands,
maybe reptiles don't have shiver glands, either.
Come on, Ralphie, there's no such thing as a
shiver gland!
Shivering is just something people do to get
warm.
Right as rain, Wanda!
Since reptiles can't shiver, when they get
REALLY cold,
their bodies just slow way down.
Whoa-oa! I'm slowing...down...too!
Isn't that like hibernation?.
Exxxxxx...actly!
When did you guys become reptiles?.
Phoebe! Un-hiber-nate Liz! Take her some-place
warm!
You poor, tortured creature. So strong, so brave,
so tough in the face of danger.
Feeeeeb! Hibernation isn't dangerous.
It's... restful!
Think of it as a...va...cation.
Look! The heat from my body is warming her up!
I'll take her outside! Let's go you guys! There's no
time to lose!
Don't worry, guys, I'll save you...
Liz... it's us! How are you doing?.
Say hello to freedom!
Pardon me, young lady, where are going with
those reptiles?.
Um... Not this way!
This way!
HELLO?. ANYBODY HERE?.
Arnold... DA...get us out of here!
We c-c-can't!
The b-b-bus is so c-c-cold - it stopped
w-w-working!
May be the bus is hibernating...just like Liz was!
Not cold again! I was just warming up!
Oh, no! That means if we don't get the bus
moving...
we could be reptiles for the rest of our lives!
Liz must be feeling better!
THOSE reptiles aren't cold - they look really
happy!
Is it just me - or is the perfect place here?.
BETTER than perfect! One flick of the tail makes
it's just right!
Yeah! Not too hot - and not too cold, and
coziness is only a slither away!
That's it!
All we have to do to get the bus working again is
to move it over here-
where the temperature's warmer!
I can do that! You guys get in the bus!
You'll be fine once we get you home, won't you
Liz.
Here we go!
Come on, Phoebe, pull!
You can do it!
I made it! We're here!
It's working! The bus is coming back to life!
As I always say, what's good for an alligator is
good for a busagator!
Open the door, Phoebe! We're taking ¡®er out!
All clear!
We're outside!
Yay.
Ready to go home, guys?.
Oh, no! Gators!
Do something, Ms Frizzle! They haven't eaten in
a month!
O. K. Everyone think of your favorite person!
Ready?.
HlT lT!
Come on, Feeb, hop aboard!
Okay, bus, do your stuff!
WAlT! You forgot something!
Be careful, Ms. Frizzle!
Now, what could it possibly be?.
LlZ'S HABlTAT?.
Liz's habitat.Thanks, Harry.
Ms. Frizzle! You know him?.
That I do! Harry is the one who built Liz's habitat.
It just needed a few repairs.
But you mean, this is a GOOD place to be?.
THE place to be, my dear:Harry Herps' Happy
Herp Haven...
Iuxury spa and restful resort for weary and
worn-out reptiles!
Whoa...so you WEREN'T going to freeze Liz?.
Well, we did make her cool and comfy if that's
what you mean.
And you WEREN'T going to stuff her?.
Hardly. But we did make sure she had enough to
eat -
which isn't difficult, since reptiles often go for
weeks without eating.
I guess we're not quite as cold-blooded as you
thought,
although our customers are.
I made arrangements for Liz to stay here for a
well-needed rest while Harry was fixing her
habitat.
I started to tell you, but, well,
I just love it when you find out things for
yourselves.
Ms Frizzle!
Is it the magic school bus?.
The magic school bus?.
Now, believe it or not,
mammals and birds are the only animals that
keep warm from within.
Do all reptiles do things like look for shade and
sunlight
to keep themselves at the right temperature?.
They have to!
While they CAN tell when their temperature is
getting too hot or too cold -
they don't have an automatic heating or cooling
system inside like we do.
I get it!When it gets colder or warmer outside -
cold-blooded creatures get colder or warmer
inside!
Spoken like a true herp-lover!
But what happens if they get TOO cold or TOO
hot?.
Ah. Good question. Normally, reptiles try to avoid
getting into that situation.
Now, if for some reason it gets too cold around
them
and they can't move to a warmer place -
they might bury themselves under leaves -
or find shelter underground, kind of like
hibernating.
I see.So what about Liz?.
First of all, you have to remember that Liz is a
magical lizard.
Second of all,
she'll do anything she can to make her life easier
and more comfortable.
So if I know Liz,
she'll do everything possible
to add a warm-blooded life-style to her
cold-blooded life!
And as Ms Frizzle said,
nothing makes a herp as happy as when the
temperature's just right!