I don't know about you, Phoeb, but I can't stand
vacations.
Why not?. I mean, how can you not like
vacations?.
¡®Cause they always end, that's why!.
That sounds like Keesha!
I've been robbed! Somebody stole my cucumber!
Why would anyone steal a cucumber?.
Especially MY cucumber. I LOVED my cucumber.
I grew it from a teeny-weeny seed. It was a
champion.
At least whoever took it left you a tasty-looking
pickle.
I mean... Iook at my carrot!
Not even a starving rabbit would eat it now!
And my tomato doesn't even look like a tomato
anymore.
It would've been better off stolen.
I don't understand.
How could things so good turn so bad over one
little vacation?.
In the famous words of Ms Frizzle:."Time waits for
no vegetable!"
Let's face it, our county fair has turned into the
city dump!
Heyyy, gimme, five, guys! The kid's back.
Hi, Ralphie!
Hey, how¡®ya doin, Ralphie?.!
Whoaaa, Arnold, I haven't seen anything that
gross since my baseball glove
got rained on and run over by the garbage truck!
In case you forgot, Ralphie, my tomato DlD win
third place.
With the way that tomato looks now, my glove
could've come in second.
Hey... nice pickle, Keesh.
Waitaminute! Holdit! Doesn't anybody care that
somebody stole my cucumber?.!
Stole it?. Who'd ever do such a thing?.
You like cucumbers, don't you, Ralphie?.
Like ¡®em - I love ¡®em!
Hey... hold it a second! You're not trying to say l
stole your cucumber, are you?.
Good morning, class.
Um...isn't it awfully early to be eating a pickle, Ms
Frizzle?.
It's never too early for a pickle... unless it's a
cucumber.
Speaking of cucumbers, Ms Frizzle, mine was
stolen while we were on vacation.
We must have had a thief in here.
Is this what you're looking for, Keesha?.
This isn't my cucumber, Ms Frizzle. It's a pickle!
Mmmmmm!
Mmmmm... Mmmmmm... Mmmm... Mmmm... And
it's almost ready to eat.
Whoa! There's a TON of pickles in here!
You caught me, Ralphie. Oh! I have a private and
powerful passion for pickles!
Something smells funny here.
Your nose knows, Keesha.
Hmmm... Ummmm.... It's the salty brine the pickles
have pickled in.
I'm talking about my PRlZE cucumber, Ms
Frizzle.
And all I know is - the door to this classroom was
locked during vacation-
and YOU had the key!
KEESHA! Are you suggesting that...that Ms
Frizzle... that our beloved
teacher... that she...
Well, she COULD have done something with my
cucumber!
You're right, Keesha. I admit it.
MS FRlZZLE!
I admit that thanks to me your cucumber is gone
- but it isn't missing!
How can something be gone but not missing?.
You see, Keesha...this pickle USED to be your
cucumber. Isn't that amazing?.
NOT amazing and NOT possible! This does not
LOOK like my cucumber...
It doesn't SMELL like my cucumber
and I'm sure it doesn't TASTE like my cucumber.
STOP! You're destroying the evidence!
What evidence?. This isn't a trial.
Maybe it is.
My point exactly! If Keesha eats this pickle -
then Ms Frizzle can't prove it's Keesha's
cucumber.
Right, Ms Frizzle?.
Sounds right to me, Arnold.
I hate to do this, Ms Frizzle, but I have to ask you
some tough questions.
Ah! How exciting! As I always say, one tough
question deserves another.
WAlT! You don't have to answer anything, Ms
Frizzle.
You have the right to remain silent -
you even have the right to dismiss this class!
Why would I want to do that, Arnold?.
I've never been on trial before! Let the trial begin!
Court is now in session.
The case of the missing cucumber:. Keesha vs.
Ms Frizzle.
The honorable Judge Liz Ard presiding -
yours truly speaking on behalf of the Court.
Keesha?. Do you have an opening statement?.
I do. I intend to prove that Ms Frizzle not only
TOOK my prize-
winning cucumber, but also that she did NOT turn
it into a pickle!
Ohh! Bravo, Keesha! I intend to prove the same
thing!
It's so nice when everyone's on the same side.
Ms Frizzle!
Sit down, Arnold!
Kids of the jury, THlS is a pickle.
THlS is a cucumber Not as big as MY cucumber,
mind you, but still a cucumber!
I OBJECT!
What now, Arnold?.! You know that's a cucumber!
Okay, I take it back.
Ms Frizzle is asking us to believe that
a pickle and a cucumber are the same thing.
Now I ask you, do these look the same to you?. I
don't think so.
Does the defense have anything to say in
defense?.
Yes, we do! We will prove that no crime was
committed
and Ms Frizzle is innocent of all charges.
Right, Ms. Frizzle?.
As I already said, Arnold, I DlD take Keesha's
cucumber,
but I did not change it into a pickle.
BUT... I know who did!
You do?????.
They were members of a gang. A small-time gang
with big ideas.
A tiny, troublesome, crowd of two-bit thieves
known as...
the Mike ROBE Gang.
And even though they hang around
a lot of different places they're extremely hard to
find.
Is that because they're always on the run?.
No... it's because they're invisible!
INVlSlBLE?????.!
I think the Frizz's losing it.
Order, order in the court!
OBJECTlON! Ms Frizzle is NOT losing it!
There's a perfectly logical explanation.
Tell them, Ms Frizzle.
Tell them the gang is invisible because they wear
disguises, right?.
Oh, no!
They're invisible because they're too small to be
seen with the naked eye -
yet every second of every day, they're busy
changing the very world we live in!
Ms Frizzle! You're not making this very easy.
I agree! How can Ms Frizzle expect us to believe
that my cucumber
was turned into a pickle by a gang of thieves we
can't even see???.!
Keesha has a point, Arnold. How CAN you prove
that?.
Oh, Arnold....
We're taking the court on a field trip!
A field trip?.!
What am I saying?????.
It's the only way, Arnold.
If you say so, Ms Frizzle. Everyone to the bus!
Kids of the jury,
this field trip will prove to you that Ms Frizzle is
telling the truth.
It will show you that the members of the Mike
ROBE Gang really exist.
You will see with your own eyes that
they have the ability to turn a cucumber into a
pickle!
YAAAAAAY!!!
I OBJECT!
There shouldn't be any applauding until AFTER
we see this lNVlSlBLE gang...
IF they exist
which I doubt! I mean, come on, how can you see
something if it's invisible?.!
As Sherlock Gherkin once said,
cucumber thieves always return to the scene of
the brine!
Buckle up, everyone! Bus, do your stuff!
This is really weird!
Nothing like a little shrinking to get you thinking!
Hey, what's that!
Yeah, but last week you were BlGGER than your
comb!
Now your comb's bigger than ALL of us!
Um...excuse me, Ms Frizzle, but does this really
count as a field trip?.
I mean, we haven't gone anywhere!
Technically, we're still in our classroom.
Here's the button to my favorite blouse! Oh! I
knew I'd find it!
That's it!We're inside the lost and found box!
Hey, look at this!
I never knew Lincoln was inside this building!
How'ya doin', Abe?.
Got it!
LlFT!
Phew! Thanks.
Good thing it wasn't a quarter!
Okay, okay, so we're really small. What does that
prove?.
It proves that when you're small you can see
things you never saw before!
Like this spidermite!
No way! I saw one of those BEFORE we got
small,
though I have to admit, it didn't look so... big!
Yeah, well I bet you never saw one of THESE
before!
Could she, Ms Frizzle?.
Oh! Not likely, Arnold. It's much too tiny.
And it's alive!
It's a kind of yeast called an ascomycete.
Yeast???.! What's yeast doing here?.
Ascomycete grow nearly everywhere.
Cool! But I'd rather find one on your seat than my
seat!
CAR-LOS!
I don't care whose seat it's on!
If it's so tiny you can only see it when YOU'RE
tiny -
that makes it an invisible member of Mike Robe's
Gang...
just like Ms Frizzle said! I rest my case!
Not so fast, Arnold. Just because there are tiny
little creatures here -
doesn't mean they're EVERYWHERE!
And it DOESN'T mean that they turned my
cucumber into a pickle!
Okay, Keesha, you want more proof?.
More evidence?. Pick a place - any place -
I'll show you more invisible creatures! I hope.
Fine! Let's go to the vegetable garden!
Hey, Liz...we're up here!
She can't see us!
She could if she knew where to look.
I changed my mind. I want to land on Liz.
I OBJECT! You said you wanted to go to the
vegetable garden.
Ah! Not to worry, Arnold. No matter where we go -
day or night -
night or day, the Mike Robe Gang will have its
say. Liz it is!
I don't see any creepy crawly creatures.
I do!
Ah ha! Another member of the Mike Robe Gang!
Right, Ms Frizzle?.
Right on, Arnold!
Oh, no! I think Liz thinks we're one of them!
I really hate it when we land upsidedown!
Where are we now???.!
I hope we're not back in the water cycle!
Hmmmm... Unless I'm mistaken, we're inside...
THE HAMSTER'S WATER BOWL!!!
And Liz STlLL can't find us!
I object!
What NOW, Arnold?.!
I object to being the smallest defense attorney in
history!
I object to where we are. LOOK!
I think we landed in the middle of a feeding
frenzy!
What are they???.
Ahh! The fat juicy ones are Amoeba -
and the ones that look like hairy hotdogs are
Paramecium.
Looks like the Underwater Wrestling Association
to me!
Actually, Ralphie, they're more members of the
Mike Robe Gang.
We're under attack!
Gosh, I never knew things like these existed!
But now you do! And not only that, they're
everywhere! Case closed!
Well done, Arnold.
OBJECTlON! Our hamster drinks this water,
right?.
So how can this invisible gang change my
cucumber into a pickle
if our hamster's still a hamster, huh?.! Explain
that!!
Well, uh, uh...it seems to me, ummmmm...
Okay, you want change?.! I'll show you change.
THERE! My tomato! Something is definitely going
on there!
I don't know about you guys, but I hope our
hamster isn't...
To my tomato, Ms Frizzle! AND HURRY!
Here we GOOOOO....
WE'RE GONNA CRASH!
Smooth landing, Ms Frizzle.
I'd rather be on Wanda's carrot!
Here that Keesha?. I told you something was
going on.
Sorry, Arnold, smelly and gushy isn't enough!
I don't see anything here to change my mind but
a rotten tomato!
Ummm, maybe... maybe we need to uh, uh...
shrink some more.
I can't believe I said that.
As my great aunt Chameleon used to say, there's
nothing as constant as change!
No sooner shrunk than sunk!
Yuck! Hard to believe anything would want to
hang out here.
Only one way to find out.
And that way is to...GET MESSY! Into your
anti-fungus suits, everyone!
I knew I should've stayed home today.
WOW! COOL!
Look! More members of the Mike Robe Gang!
They're everywhere!
It looks like they're attacking Arnold's tomato.
We're surrounded!
Ah! Relax, Arnold.
They're funguses - and they're only doing what
comes naturally.
You mean, they're SUPPOSED to destroy the
tomato?.
Hey, even a fungus has to eat.
WOW! COOL!
Hey! Watch it! Whaaaa... What if they eat us
next???.!
Then Ms Frizzle will need a new defense
attorney!
If we were big, couldn't we see this stuff
happening through a magnifying glass?.
Only a very powerful one, Phoebe.
You mean like the mega-magnifyer?.
Your point is a juicy one, Ms Frizzle...
but even though I've seen that Mike Robe's
Gangsters are everywhere
AND that they can make things change
you STlLL haven't proven that they turned my
cucumber into a pickle!
I... OB---JECT!! Just in case that calls for another
shrink.
That won't be necessary, Arnold.
Uh oh! Is it just me, or are we having a TOMATO
QUAAAAAKE!!!
HEELLLLLLLLLLLLPPPPPPPPPPPP.!.!!
Incredible! We're inside Ms. Frizzle's pickle jar!
This is it, Keesha. This is where it all happened.
You mean we're actually at the scene of the
crime?.
FOLLOW ME....!
I object!
It's too late to object, Arnold. LOOK OUT!
It sure is crowded in here!
Ugh! The tomato fungus is still among us! They're
EVERYWHERE!
Ah! Right you are, Wanda. Everywhere and
anywhere.
YYYuck! What's going on here?.!
More destruction! First the funguses ate the
tomato -
now they're trying to eat the pickle!
Looks to me like they've got some competition
from those little squirty things!
The little squirty things are a kind of bacteria --
AND THEY ARE ACTUALLY protecting THE
PlCKLE.
Whoa! Look at those pickle protectors work!
Wipe out! The funguses are history!
Woooch! Pickle juice!
I HATE pickle juice!
So do the funguses!
Hey, check it out!
Now the pickle bacteria are attacking the
cucmber!
What's happening?. I thought the picklers were
the good guys.
They are, Keesha. They're not destroying the
cucumber -- they're SAVlNG it!
So, if it weren't for the pickle bacteria,
the same rotten thing that happened to the
tomato -
would happen to this cucumber!
Yeah! Total annihilation!
I get it! The funguses rot things by eating them
and the pickle bacteria STOP things from rotting
by getting rid of the funguses!
Only one problem - the pickle bacteria's turning
the cuke into a pickle!
Ahh! Not a problem, Ralphie - that's preservation!
A pickle lasts a lot longer than a cucmber!
Don't tell me the pickle bacteria are gang
members too?.
That they are, Keesha. They may be small, but
they make big changes.
And all those tiny living things we've just seen are
called microbes.
Did you say microbes?.
As in microscopic?. So tiny that you need a
microscope to see them?.
So tiny that they're invisible?.!
Just like us!
Tiny... invisible... microscopic...YYYYESSS!!!
Kids of the jury, you've seen with your own eyes
that all around us is an invisible world of
microbes.
A world that includes Amoebas Parameciums
Ascomycetes Funguses...
And, yes, Pickle Bacteria!
And each and every one of these microbes is a
member in good standing
of the MlKE ROBE GANG! Isn't that right, Ms
Frizzle?.
I wouldn't CHANGE a thing, Arnold.
But microbes DO! They make BlG changes - like
turning a cucumber into a pickle!
So, kids of the jury, it's very clear that Ms Frizzle
DlD NOT, I repeat,
DlD NOT turn Keesha's cucumber into a pickle!
And who did?.
THE MlCROBES DlD!!!
So... that pickle is REALLY my cucumber???.!
It is indeed, Keesha.
I rest my case!
Hey, anybody seen the bus?.!
Looks like the bus is in a real pickle!
Members of the jury, have you reached a verdict?.
We the jury, find Ms Frizzle innocent of all
charges. YAAAAAAAAAY!
Thank you thank you thank you!
And thank you, Ms Frizzle.
If you hadn't put my cucumber into the brine
before we left on vacation
it would have rotted just like Arnold's tomato and
Wanda's carrot.
You're a hero.
Well, as you saw, Keesha, I did have a little help
preserving your cucumber.
And turning it into a into a PRlZE PlCKLE!
Well, as my great Uncle Barnard used to say:.
"Cucumbers come and cucumbers go, but pickles
go on forever!"
Case dismissed!!
Is it the magic school bus?.
The magic school bus?.
Take water, for example. Under a microscope,
you can see all sorts of things in water you didn't
know were there.
Like what?.
Well, you might see Trachelomonas...Spirogyra...
Fragilaria....Anabaena... or Evensynura!
So a microbe is ANY tiny organism that you need
a microscope to see, right?.
You got it!
Well, how many microbes would you have to pile
on top of each other
before you could see them with your naked eye?.
Oh, ho ho ho! Millions! But when they DO pile up
like that -
that's when you see them, like with mildew and
mold.
And what about germs?. Those are microbes that
can make you sick, right?.
That's true. But that doesn't mean ALL microbes
are bad.
In fact, most are harmless.
We just called them crooks in the show to make
it a mystery.
Some microbes even help us out.
You mean like the ones that saved Keesha's
cucumber?.
Exactly. Now, some microbes even make the
holes in swiss cheese.
You're kidding!
Nope. Others, like bacteria, change milk into
yoghurt and sour cream.
And yeasts are microbes that help make breads
and pizza dough.
Cool! I love pizza.
I like pizza, too, but I'm afraid you'll have to call
back for your order.
We have a SMALL problem! Thanks for your
questions.
Ho ho ho. Hey, Liz! If you ever get that down, I'll
take one pizza to go:.
cheese, tomatoes, some paramecium, a handful
of lactobactors...
and oh yeah, go easy on the fungus!