HI, OUT THERE!
IT'S ME, STEVE.
HAVE YOU SEEN BLUE, MY PUPPY?
THERE SHE IS!
COME ON IN.
HI, COME ON IN.
WE ARE SO GLAD
YOU'RE HERE TODAY.
YOU KNOW, RIGHT NOW
WE'RE GETTING READY
FOR MAILBOX'S BIRTHDAY PARTY.
HE'S... TEN YEARS OLD!
COME ON.
MAILBOX IS SO HAPPY TODAY
BECAUSE IT'S HIS BIRTHDAY.
AND WE'RE GETTING READY
FOR HIS PARTY.
WILL YOU HELP US?
OH, YOU WILL?
GOOD.
HEY, BLUE?
BLUE?
BLUE...
WHAT?
WHERE?
RIGHT THERE.
HERE?
NO!
BLUE?
OH!
THERE YOU ARE.
THANKS.
SO, BLUE, WHAT
ARE YOU UP TO?
HEY, YEAH,
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE'RE ALMOST
READY FOR MAILBOX'S
BIRTHDAY PARTY.
WE'VE GOT THE STREAMERS,
WE'VE GOT BALLOONS.
MR. SALT AND MRS. PEPPER
ARE MAKING THE CAKE
IN THE KITCHEN.
HELLO, STEVE.
MMM, CAKE.
WE'VE GOT MAILBOX'S
FAVORITE BIRTHDAY
PARTY GAME.
NO?
WHAT "NO"?
BALLOONS, STREAMERS,
CAKE, GAME...
OH, NO!
WE DON'T HAVE
MAILBOX'S FAVORITE
BIRTHDAY PARTY GAME!
WHAT IS MAILBOX'S
FAVORITE BIRTHDAY
PARTY GAME?
DO YOU KNOW?
OH, OH!
BLUE KNOWS
AND WE'RE GOING TO
PLAY "BLUE'S CLUES"
TO FIGURE IT OUT!
I LOVE "BLUE'S CLUES."
♪ WE ARE GONNA PLAY
"BLUE'S CLUES" ♪
♪ 'CAUSE IT'S REALLY FUN!
ARE YOU READY?
NOW REMEMBER, BLUE'S PAW PRINTS
WILL BE ON THE CLUES--
BLUE'S CLUES.
YUP, YOU'RE RIGHT.
WE SHOULD PROBABLY
CLEAN THIS UP FIRST.
OH, OH!
YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED
FOR BLUE'S CLUES-- OUR...
NOTEBOOK!
NOTEBOOK, RIGHT.
COME ON.
BLUE'S CLUES,
I'M SO EXCITED.
OOH... HERE IT IS.
HEY, I CAN TELL
I'M REALLY GOING TO NEED
YOUR HELP TODAY
FIGURING OUT WHAT MAILBOX'S
FAVORITE BIRTHDAY PARTY GAME IS.
WILL YOU HELP ME?
GREAT.
♪ WE GOT TO FIND THE PAW PRINT,
THAT'S THE FIRST CLUE ♪
♪ WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND NOW WHAT DO WE DO? ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE SECOND CLUE ♪
♪ WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
NOW WHAT DO WE DO? ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE THIRD CLUE ♪
♪ PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND, WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WELL, WE SIT DOWN
IN OUR THINKING CHAIR ♪
♪ AND THINK, THINK, THINK
♪ 'CAUSE WHEN WE USE OUR MINDS,
TAKE A STEP AT A TIME ♪
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING...
♪ THAT WE WANT TO DO.
LET'S GO FIND BLUE'S CLUES
TOGETHER.
WHICH WAY SHOULD WE GO?
THAT WAY.
THIS WAY.
NO...
OH, THIS WAY.
THANKS.
♪ WE ARE LOOKING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE ARE LOOKING FOR
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE ARE LOOKING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ I WONDER
WHERE THEY ARE-- YEAH. ♪
♪ WE ARE LOOKING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE ARE LOOKING FOR
BLUE'S CLUES. ♪
♪ WE ARE LOOKING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WONDER WHERE
THEY ARE-- YEAH. ♪
WHAT?
A CLUE!
OH, BLUE?
YOU SEE BLUE?
OH, A CLUE.
YOU SEE A CLUE.
YOU SEE A CLUE?!
SO, WHERE'S THE CLUE?
BEHIND YOU!
IT IS A CLUE!
IT'S A CLUE!
YOU KNOW HOW YOU CAN TELL
IT'S A CLUE?
BECAUSE IT'S GOT
BLUE'S PAW PRINTS ALL OVER IT.
IT MUST BE ONE OF BLUE'S CLUES.
SO, WHAT IS IT?
A TAPE PLAYER.
OH.
OH?
A TAPE PLAYER?
WELL, WHAT DO WE NEED THIS FOR?
SO A TAPE PLAYER
IS OUR FIRST CLUE.
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
NOTEBOOK!
RIGHT, WE NEED OUR
HANDY DANDY NOTEBOOK.
A LINE GOES HERE...
A LINE GOES THERE...
CIRCLES...
A LOT OF LITTLE BUTTONS...
WE HAVE A TAPE PLAYER.
HMM...
I WONDER WHAT GAME WE CAN PLAY
WITH A TAPE PLAYER.
Mr. Salt:
STEVE.
Mrs. Pepper:
Both:
STEVE!
HELLO, MR. SALT
AND MRS. PEPPER.
Both:
HELLO, STEVE.
HOW'S MAILBOX'S
BIRTHDAY CAKE COMING?
Mr. Salt:
REALLY GOOD!
Mrs. Pepper:
WE'RE PUTTING THE
FINISHING TOUCHES
ON THE CAKE AND
NEED YOUR HELP.
OKAY, BUT I NEED
YOUR HELP, TOO.
HAVE YOU SEEN BLUE?
BLUE!
WHAT ARE YOU UP TO?
BLUE'S HELPING US DECORATE
MAILBOX'S BIRTHDAY CAKE.
CAN YOU HELP, TOO?
CAN YOU HELP
PUT THE SPRINKLES ON?
WOW.
LOOK AT THIS PATTERN.
UM...
COULD YOU HELP US FIND
WHAT SPRINKLE GOES NEXT?
OH, OKAY...
PURPLE STAR, GREEN STAR
PURPLE STAR, GREEN STAR,
PURPLE STAR...
WHAT COMES NEXT?
THAT ONE!
YEAH, IT'S THE GREEN STAR.
OH, A GREEN STAR
TO COMPLETE THE PATTERN.
LOOKS GREAT!
OKAY.
LET'S DO
THE NEXT
LAYER OF
THE CAKE.
WHOA, LOOK AT THIS PATTERN!
AWESOME.
HMM...
SO, CAN YOU HELP US
FIND WHAT SPRINKLE
SHOULD GO NEXT?
OKAY...
GREEN STAR, PINK CIRCLE
GREEN STAR, PINK CIRCLE,
GREEN STAR...
WHAT COMES NEXT?
PINK CIRCLE.
YEAH!
THE PINK CIRCLE!
WOULD YOU LOOK AT THAT?
THIS LOOKS SO GREAT.
Both:
GREAT!
ONE MORE
LAYER TO GO.
LET'S DO THE
TOP LAYER OF
THE CAKE.
HMM...
COULD YOU HELP US FIND
WHAT SPRINKLE GOES NEXT?
OKAY...
ORANGE DIAMOND, ORANGE DIAMOND,
YELLOW DIAMOND
ORANGE DIAMOND,
ORANGE DIAMOND AND...
WHAT GOES NEXT?
THAT ONE.
YEAH!
THE YELLOW DIAMOND.
A YELLOW DIAMOND.
WOW, YOU DID A GREAT JOB.
I THINK THIS CAKE IS READY.
THANK YOU.
YOU KNOW, WE JUST
FINISHED THE CAKE
BUT WE STILL HAVE
TO LOOK FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES
TO FIGURE OUT WHAT MAILBOX'S
FAVORITE BIRTHDAY PARTY GAME IS.
♪ WE ARE LOOKING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE ARE LOOKING FOR
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE ARE LOOKING FOR BLUE'S
CLUES FOR THE BIRTHDAY PARTY. ♪
♪ WE ARE LOOKING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE ARE LOOKING FOR...
WHAT?
A CLUE, A CLUE!
DID YOU SEE A CLUE?
WHERE?
SHOW ME?
WHERE'S THE CLUE?
BEHIND YOU!
IT'S ON THE PURPLE SHELF.
AHA!
IT'S ANOTHER CLUE.
YOU KNOW WHAT THIS MEANS?
WE NEED OUR HANDY DANDY...
NOTEBOOK!
NOTEBOOK.
OKAY... ALL RIGHT
SO WE HAVE A... A...
WHAT IS THIS AGAIN?
TAPE CASSETTE.
RIGHT, A TAPE CASSETTE.
RECTANGLE...
AND A CIRCLE HERE,
AND A CIRCLE THERE.
THEN A LINE...
AND WE HAVE... A TAPE CASSETTE.
HMM... SO OUR FIRST CLUE
WAS A...
TAPE PLAYER.
RIGHT, A TAPE PLAYER.
AND NOW WE HAVE A TAPE CASSETTE.
HMM... I WONDER,
IF YOU PUT THE TAPE CASSETTE
INSIDE THE TAPE PLAYER,
WHAT WOULD HAPPEN?
RIGHT, IT WOULD PLAY MUSIC!
WELL, WHAT BIRTHDAY PARTY GAME
DO YOU NEED MUSIC FOR?
Tickety:
STEVE.
STEVE!
HEY, TICKETY.
JUST THINKING
ABOUT BLUE'S CLUES.
WE FOUND TWO.
YOU ONLY HAVE
ONE MORE CLUE LEFT
AND YOU BETTER HURRY,
BECAUSE IT'S ALMOST TIME.
WHEN BOTH OF MY HANDS REACH
MAILBOX THEN IT'S TIME!
MAIL TIME!
AND YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENS
TODAY AT MAIL TIME.
IT'S TIME FOR MAILBOX'S...
Both:
BIRTHDAY PARTY!
OH, HEY, AND I STILL
GOT TO FIND BLUE.
HEY, TICKETY,
DID YOU SEE BLUE COME IN HERE?
YUP, SHE'S RIGHT
OVER THERE.
I THINK SHE'S
HIDING FROM YOU.
THANKS, TICKETY.
I'LL SEE YOU AT
THE BIRTHDAY... PARTY.
DID YOU SEE THAT?
BLUE JUST WENT RIGHT INTO
THE PICTURE OF THAT STORE.
HEY, IT'S A PRESENT STORE!
ARE YOU READY TO GO TO
THE PRESENT STORE WITH BLUE?
COME ON.
♪ BLUE SKIDDOO, WE CAN, TOO.
OH!
WHOA!
LOOK AT ALL THESE PRESENTS!
HEY, I WISH I KNEW SOMEONE
WHO NEEDED A PRESENT--
YOU KNOW, SOMEONE WHO WAS
HAVING A BIRTHDAY OR SOMETHING--
BECAUSE, I MEAN, LOOK AT
ALL THESE GREAT PRESENTS.
MAILBOX.
WHAT?
YEAH, RIGHT, MAILBOX.
YOU KNOW,
YOU REALLY ARE VERY SMART.
HMM.
SO, CAN YOU HELP US FIND
A PRESENT FOR MAILBOX HERE?
LET'S SEE.
A TOOLBOX, A COLORING BOOK
A STAMP COLLECTING BOOK
AND A PAIR OF OVERALLS.
WHICH THING DO YOU THINK
MAILBOX WOULD LIKE THE MOST?
A TOOLBOX?
MAILBOX MIGHT LIKE THAT.
A COLORING BOOK?
MAYBE.
LET'S SEE WHAT ELSE THERE IS.
OVERALLS?
NO WAY!
THAT WOULDN'T EVEN FIT HIM.
NO.
A STAMP BOOK?
YEAH! STAMP BOOK.
A STAMP BOOK-- THAT'S BRILLIANT.
MAILBOX LOVES STAMPS
BECAUSE STAMPS ARE ON LETTERS,
AND MAILBOX DELIVERS LETTERS!
LET'S GET THAT ONE!
THIS IS GOING TO BE SO SPECIAL.
I'M GOING TO GET WRAPPED NOW.
I'M SO EXCITED!
PURPLE STRIPE
WRAPPING PAPER, PLEASE.
PURPLE STRIPE WRAPPING PAPER.
A BIG RED BOW, PLEASE.
A BIG RED BOW.
A GREEN CARD, PLEASE.
A GREEN CARD.
WHOA!
LOOK AT ALL THESE PRESENTS!
OOH.
UH-OH.
DO YOU REMEMBER
WHICH ONE IS OURS?
WELL, COULD YOU
POINT IT OUT TO ME?
OH.
WHICH ONE?
THAT ONE.
OH, RIGHT.
IT'S THE ONE
WITH THE PURPLE STRIPES
AND THE BIG RED BOW
AND THE GREEN CARD.
WE JUST FOUND OUR PRESENT.
♪ WE JUST FOUND OUR PRESENT
♪ WE JUST
FOUND OUR PRESENT ♪
♪ WE JUST FOUND
OUR PRESENT ♪
♪ BECAUSE WE ARE
SO SMART, YEAH! ♪
♪ DO, DO, DO, DO, DO, DO...
UH-OH.
COULD YOU HELP US
FIND OUR PRESENT AGAIN?
RIGHT THERE!
WHICH ONE?
WHEW! IT'S THAT ONE--
THE ONE WITH THE PURPLE STRIPES
AND THE BIG RED BOW
AND THE GREEN CARD.
NOW THAT WE'VE FOUND
OUR PRESENT... AGAIN
LET'S GET BACK HOME
BEFORE WE DROP IT... AGAIN.
♪ DO, DO, DO, DO, DO, DO...
THERE GOES BLUE!
LET'S GO, TOO.
♪ DUH, DUH, DUH,
DUH, DUH, DUH... ♪
PHEW!
A CLUE!
WHAT WAS THAT?
GLUE?
AM I SITTING IN GLUE?
OH, MAN!
OH!
OH, OH, A CLUE!
YOU SEE A CLUE!
WHERE?
RIGHT THERE.
IT'S BEHIND YOU.
I DON'T SEE IT.
OH!
HEY.
THIS CHAIR HAS
BLUE'S PAW PRINTS ON IT.
IT MUST BE ONE OF...
BLUE'S CLUES!
OKAY, ALL RIGHT.
I GOT IT.
I KNOW WHAT TO DO.
WE NEED OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK!
NOTEBOOK.
OKAY.
SO, WE HAVE A CHAIR.
CURVE HERE...
LINE THERE.
FOUR LEGS, AND WE HAVE CHAIR.
YOU KNOW...
WE HAVE ALL THREE CLUES.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT THIS MEANS?
WE'RE READY FOR OUR...
THINKING CHAIR.
THINKING CHAIR!
NOW THAT WE'RE IN OUR
THINKING CHAIR, LET'S THINK.
OKAY.
WE NEED TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT MAILBOX'S FAVORITE
BIRTHDAY PARTY GAME IS.
BLUE'S CLUES ARE:
A TAPE PLAYER...
A TAPE CASSETTE...
AND A CHAIR.
HMM.
SO WE PUT THE TAPE CASSETTE
INSIDE THE TAPE PLAYER
AND THAT MADE...
MUSIC-- RIGHT.
HMM.
SO WHAT GAME CAN YOU PLAY
BY MAKING MUSIC WITH A TAPE
PLAYER AND A TAPE CASSETTE
AND WITH A CHAIR?
MUSIC AND CHAIR.
AND CHAIR.
MUSIC...
WHAT?
MUSICAL BEARS?
NO, MUSICAL CHAIRS.
OH, MUSICAL...
YES!
YES, THAT'S IT!
THAT'S THE ANSWER--
MUSICAL CHAIRS!
WOW.
YOU MAKE MUSIC
BY PUTTING THE TAPE CASSETTE
INSIDE THE TAPE PLAYER
AND YOU PLAY THE GAME
WITH CHAIRS!
THAT'S IT!
THAT'S MAILBOX'S
FAVORITE BIRTHDAY PARTY GAME.
HE LOVES TO START
AND STOP THE MUSIC.
WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES.
♪ WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE JUST
FIGURED OUT BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ BECAUSE WE'RE
REALLY SMART, YEAH! ♪
♪ DO, DO, DO, DO, DO, DO
♪ DO, DO, DO,
DO, DO, DO. ♪
WE ARE ALL SET FOR
MAILBOX'S BIRTHDAY!
WE HAVE THE BALLOONS,
WE HAVE THE STREAMERS.
DO YOU REMEMBER
THE PRESENT WE PICKED OUT?
UH-HUH.
OH, AND HERE COMES
MR. SALT AND MRS. PEPPER
WITH THE BIRTHDAY CAKE
WE HELPED PUT SPRINKLES ON.
Both:
HELLO, STEVE.
CAKE.
AND WE HAVE OUR GAME
OF MUSICAL CHAIRS ALL SET TO GO
BECAUSE WE FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES.
NOW ALL WE NEED IS
MAILBOX TO GET HERE.
STEVE,
IT'S MAIL TIME!
♪ MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME,
MAIL TIME! ♪
♪ MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME!
MAILBOX IS HERE!
♪ HERE'S THE MAIL,
IT NEVER FAILS ♪
♪ IT MAKES ME WANT
TO WAG MY TAIL ♪
♪ WHEN IT COMES,
I WANT TO WAIL... ♪
All:
HAPPY BIRTHDAY, MAIL!
MAIL'S HERE,
MAIL'S HERE.
OH, FOR ME?
IS THIS PARTY
FOR ME?
All:
HAPPY BIRTHDAY!
WOW!
AND...
WE HAVE
A PRESENT FOR YOU.
A STAMP BOOK?
WOW!
I ALWAYS WANTED ONE.
NOW I HAVE A PLACE
FOR ALL OF MY STAMPS.
OH, AND I HAVE A LETTER
TO DELIVER
TO YOU, TOO, STEVE.
ACTUALLY, MAILBOX,
THIS IS A LETTER FOR YOU.
FOR ME?
WOW!
HAPPY BIRTHDAY, MAILBOX!
THANKS, EVERYONE.
THAT'S A REALLY
GREAT LETTER.
AND WE HAVE
OUR SPECIAL, HOMEMADE CAKE.
AND BLUE DID NOT WANT US
TO FORGET
YOUR FAVORITE BIRTHDAY
PARTY GAME, MUSICAL CHAIRS.
WHERE'S THAT
TAPE PLAYER?
I JUST LOVE TO START
AND STOP THE MUSIC.
BLUE TOOK MY SEAT.
GUESS I'M OUT.
HEY, THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR ALL YOUR HELP TODAY.
♪ NOW IT'S TIME FOR SO LONG
♪ BUT WE'LL SING
JUST ONE MORE SONG ♪
♪ THANKS FOR DOING YOUR PART
♪ YOU SURE ARE SMART
♪ YOU KNOW, WITH ME AND YOU
♪ AND MY DOG, BLUE
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING
♪ THAT WE WANT TO DO.
BYE-BYE.
SEE YOU LATER.
BYE.
COME AGAIN.
BYE-BYE.
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING.♪