HI, OUT THERE!
IT'S ME, STEVE.
HAVE YOU SEEN BLUE, MY PUPPY?
THERE SHE IS!
COME ON IN.
HI!
HEY, DO YOU WANT TO HAVE
STORY TIME WITH US?
GREAT, COME ON.
WE'RE JUST ABOUT TO READ
A STORYBOOK TO BLUE.
IT'S CALLED A PUPPY'S DAY.
OH, GREAT, HERE'S THE BOOK.
ALL WE NEED IS BLUE.
BLUE!
UH, DID YOU SEE BLUE?
BEHIND YOU. BEHIND YOU.
WHERE?
UNDER THE BOOK. YEAH.
:
UNDER THE BOOK?
HERE?
OH!
BLUE, WHAT
ARE YOU UP TO?
COME ON, WE'LL READ
YOUR FAVORITE
STORYBOOK--
A PUPPY'S DAY.
NO?
WHAT, NO?
A PUPPY'S DAYISN'T
YOUR FAVORITE
STORY ANYMORE?
WELL, WHAT IS
YOUR FAVORITE,
FAVORITE STORY?
OH!
OKAY, THAT'S
AN INCREDIBLE IDEA, BLUE.
WE'LL PLAY BLUE'S CLUES.
I LOVE BLUE'S CLUES.
♪ WE ARE GONNA PLAY
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ 'CAUSE IT'S REALLY FUN,
YEAH! ♪
NOW, REMEMBER, BLUE'S PAW PRINTS
WILL BE ON THE CLUES--
BLUE'S CLUES.
OH! OH, YEAH, YOU'RE RIGHT.
WE SHOULD PROBABLY
CLEAN THIS UP FIRST.
WELL, LET'S... LET'S BLOW
THIS PAW PRINT AWAY.
WILL YOU HELP ME?
YOU WILL?
:
GREAT!
OH, OH! YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED
FOR BLUE'S CLUES?
OUR...
NOTEBOOK!
RIGHT, OUR NOTEBOOK.
COME ON.
BLUE'S CLUES,
I'M SO EXCITED.
OH, HERE IT IS.
HEY, YOU KNOW, I CAN TELL
I'M GOING TO NEED YOUR HELP
FIGURING OUT WHAT BLUE'S
FAVORITE, FAVORITE STORY IS.
WILL YOU HELP ME?
SURE. YES.
OH, THANKS.
♪ WE GOT TO FIND THE PAW PRINT,
THAT'S THE FIRST CLUE ♪
♪ WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND NOW WHAT DO WE DO? ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE SECOND CLUE ♪
♪ WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
NOW WHAT DO WE DO? ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE THIRD CLUE ♪
♪ PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND, WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WELL, WE SIT DOWN
IN OUR THINKING CHAIR ♪
♪ AND THINK, THINK, THINK
♪ 'CAUSE WHEN WE USE OUR MINDS,
TAKE A STEP AT A TIME ♪
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING...
♪ THAT WE WANT TO DO.
THIS WAY?
♪ WE ARE LOOKIN'
FOR BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ I WONDER WHERE THEY ARE.
Both:
OH, HI, STEVE.
HELLO, MR. SALT
AND MRS. PEPPER.
DID YOU SEE...
SHE'S IN THE GARDEN.
OH.
♪ WE ARE GOING TO THE GARDEN
♪ TO FIGURE OUT WHAT BLUE'S
FAVORITE, FAVORITE STORY IS. ♪
A CLUE! A CLUE!
DID YOU SEE A CLUE?
WHERE?
WHERE'S THE CLUE?
IN THE WHEELBARROW.
OH! OH! OH!
BLUE'S PAW PRINTS ARE
ON THESE... BRICKS.
THAT MUST MEAN THAT THESE BRICKS
ARE OUR FIRST BLUE'S CLUE.
WE HAVE OUR FIRST CLUE!
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
NOTEBOOK!
YEAH.
WE NEED
OUR HANDY-DANDY NOTEBOOK.
OKAY, SO WE HAVE BRICKS.
A LINE HERE...
A LINE THERE...
KIND OF LIKE A RECTANGLE.
AND WE HAVE BRICKS.
HMM.
WELL, I WONDER
WHAT STORY HAS BRICKS IN IT.
HUH!
WELL, I THINK WE NEED TO LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES
TO FIGURE THIS OUT.
Boy:
NO, NO.
JACK AND JILL DID
NOT GO UP A TREE.
IT WAS
SOMETHING ELSE.
HEY, BLUE,
HERE YOU ARE.
HELLO, SHOVEL,
HELLO, PAIL.
WHAT ARE
YOU ALL UP TO?
HI, STEVE.
WE'RE PLAYING
JACK AND JILL.
I'M JACK,
BLUE'S JILL.
:
I'M THE PAIL.
BUT WE HAVEN'T
GOTTEN TOO FAR.
Both:
YEAH.
OH, MAYBE YOU
CAN HELP US.
DO YOU WANT TO HELP
SHOVEL, PAIL AND BLUE
PLAY JACK AND JILL?
SURE. YES.
YEAH, WE'LL HELP.
OH, AND THEN WE CAN LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES
TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT BLUE'S FAVORITE,
FAVORITE STORY IS.
COME ON.
Both:
OKAY. SO JACK...
THAT'S ME.
AND JILL GO UP
A MOUNTAIN.
I'M NOT SURE
IT WAS
A MOUNTAIN.
YEAH.
DO YOU KNOW?
JACK AND JILL GO
UP A...
HILL! HILL!
YES.
Both:
JACK...
THAT'S ME.
AND JILL GO UP A HILL
TO FETCH A PAIL OF...
ICE CREAM.
ICE CREAM?
DID YOU JUST SAY ICE CREAM?
JACK AND JILL ARE FETCHING
A PAIL OF ICE CREAM?
HELP.
WE NEED
MORE HELP.
OKAY, ALL RIGHT.
I THINK WE REALLY
NEED YOUR HELP AGAIN.
DO JACK AND JILL
GO UP A HILL
TO FETCH A PAIL
OF ICE CREAM?
NO.
HMM, JACK AND JILL
GO UP A HILL
TO FETCH A PAIL OF...
WATER!
YES!
YEAH, THAT'S IT.
OKAY,
LET'S DO IT.
OKAY, YOU READY?
JACK...
THAT'S ME.
AND JILL
GO UP A HILL
TO FETCH A PAIL
OF WATER.
JACK FELL DOWN...
I LOVE
THIS PART!
AND BROKE
HIS CROWN...
OH, MY HEAD.
AND JILL COMES...
JILL COMES...
TUMBLING AFTER.
JILL COMES
THE END.
YAY!
THANKS FOR
PLAYING WITH US.
YOU WERE GREAT.
Quartet:
♪ MAIL TIME,
MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME! ♪
THE MAIL'S HERE!
COME ON.
BYE, GUYS.
♪ HERE'S THE MAIL,
IT NEVER FAILS ♪
♪ IT MAKES ME WANT
TO WAG MY TAIL ♪
♪ WHEN IT COMES,
I WANT TO WAIL, "MAIL!" ♪
JACK AND JILL
WENT UP THE HILL
TO FETCH...
THE MAIL!
:
HEY!
THAT'S PRETTY
FUNNY, MAILBOX.
YEAH, HERE'S
YOUR LETTER.
BYE.
BYE, MAILBOX.
WE JUST GOT A LETTER.
♪ WE JUST GOT A LETTER
♪ I WONDER WHO IT'S FROM.
IT'S A LETTER FROM OUR FRIENDS.
WE MAKE UP STORIES
WITH OUR PUPPETS.
ONE DAY A GIRL WENT
OUTSIDE TO PLAY.
PLAY, PLAY, PLAY, PLAY.
SHE SAW A MONSTER.
BUT SHE SAID...
HELLO.
:
ARE YOU
A SCARY MONSTER?
NO!
I'M A SILLY MONSTER.
OOGLA-BOOGLA,
OOGLA-BOOGLA.
THE TWO OF THEM OOGLA-BOOGLAED
ALL THE WAY HOME.
THE END.
BYE.
WOW, THAT WAS GREAT.
OOGLA-BOOGLA.
ALL STORIES ARE GREAT,
DON'T YOU THINK?
OH, HEY!
HEY, BLUE.
IT'S ALMOST STORY TIME.
A CLUE!
OH! A CLUE?
IS THAT THE NAME OF BLUE'S
FAVORITE, FAVORITE STORY?
NO. NO.
OH, YOU MEAN ANOTHER ONE
OF BLUE'S CLUES.
WHERE?
BEHIND YOU.
CLUE NUMBER TWO.
WHAT BIG TEETH IT HAS.
AND LOOK AT THAT TAIL.
HA!
SO, BLUE'S SECOND CLUE
MUST BE A... A...
A WOLF.
A WOLF!
HEY, YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED?
OUR HANDY-DANDY,
SUPER-DUPER NOTEBOOK.
SO...
A WOLF'S HEAD...
THOSE BIG TEETH...
AND, OF COURSE, THE TAIL...
AND WE HAVE A WOLF.
HMM, SO...
WHAT WAS OUR FIRST CLUE?
BRICKS.
YEAH, RIGHT, BRICKS.
NOW OUR SECOND CLUE IS A WOLF.
SO WHAT STORY COULD BLUE WANT
TO READ WITH BRICKS AND A WOLF?
HMM.
MAYBE-- MAYBE--WE SHOULD LOOK
FOR ONE MORE CLUE.
OH, LOOK!
IT'S OUR PHOTO ALBUM.
IT'S WHERE WE KEEP
ALL OUR PICTURES.
WANT TO LOOK AT THEM?
OKAY.
THEN WE CAN LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
OH, LOOK!
IT'S MR. SALT
AND MRS. PEPPER
AND TICKETY TOCK.
OH! AND LOOK, BLUE.
THESE ARE PICTURES
OF YOUR FIRST DAY
OF SCHOOL.
OH!
WELL, THESE PICTURES
ARE ALL OUT OF ORDER.
CAN YOU HELP ME PUT
THEM BACK TOGETHER?
OH, GOOD.
NOW, CAN YOU TELL
FROM THESE PICTURES
WHAT HAPPENED
IN SCHOOL FIRST?
HMM.
RIGHT THERE!
YEAH, THAT'S IT.
BRILLIANT, BLUE.
YOU SAID "HI" TO A NEW FRIEND.
HER NAME IS...
MAGENTA, RIGHT?
RIGHT.
AND THEN WHAT HAPPENED?
RIGHT THERE!
YEAH! THAT'S IT.
THAT'S GREAT.
YOU AND MAGENTA WENT
TO THE PAINT TABLE TO PAINT.
THEN WHAT HAPPENED?
RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S IT!
THAT'S RIGHT!
YOU AND MAGENTA STARTED
REALLY PAINTING.
THEN WHAT HAPPENED?
THAT'S THE ONE.
YEAH!
THAT'S GREAT!
YOU AND MAGENTA GAVE EACH OTHER
THE PICTURES YOU MADE.
WOW! WHAT A GREAT STORY ABOUT
BLUE'S FIRST DAY OF SCHOOL.
HEY, DID YOU HEAR THAT?
THAT SOUNDS LIKE TICKETY-TOCK.
COME ON!
OKAY, TICKETY!
WE HEAR YOU!
SHE'S AN ALARM CLOCK.
HI, STEVE.
HEY, TICKETY.
WE HEARD
YOUR ALARM BELLS.
YES, I WANTED TO TELL YOU:
IT'S ALMOST STORY TIME.
WELL, THANK YOU,
TICKETY.
OOH! OOH! BUT, YOU KNOW,
WE STILL HAVE TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT BLUE'S FAVORITE,
FAVORITE STORY IS.
COME ON!
HEY, BLUE,
WHAT'S GOING ON?
BLUE, I NEED
YOUR HELP.
CAN YOU HELP ME?
OH, HELLO, BABY BEAR.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
SOMEBODY'S BEEN
IN OUR HOUSE
AND MESSED
EVERYTHING UP.
WILL YOU HELP?
YOU WILL?
GOOD.
♪ BLUE SKIDDOO, WE CAN, TOO.
WHOA! THIS MUST BE
STORYBOOK FOREST!
SOMEONE'S BEEN
IN OUR HOUSE!
EVERYTHING IS
ALL MIXED UP.
OH! DON'T WORRY,
WE'LL HELP.
HELLO, STEVE.
Both:
WE'RE GLAD
YOU'RE HERE.
WE NEED TO FIGURE
OUT OUR LUNCH.
YES, WHOSE
IS WHOSE?
WE'RE ALL CONFUSED.
WILL YOU HELP US?
GREAT.
SO, WHICH BOWL OF
PORRIDGE BELONGS TO...
PAPA BEAR?
THAT ONE!
THAT'S MY GREAT
BIG BOWL.
THANKS A LOT.
GREAT JOB!
HOW ABOUT THE BOWL
OF PORRIDGE FOR...
MAMA BEAR?
RIGHT THERE.
MY, OH, MY!
IT'S MY MEDIUM-SIZED
BOWL OF PORRIDGE.
SMELLS GOOD.
GREAT JOB.
DON'T FORGET ME!
OH! YOU WEREN'T HUNGRY,
WERE YOU, BABY BEAR?
THAT'S NOT
FUNNY, STEVE.
DO YOU SEE BABY BEAR'S
BOWL OF PORRIDGE?
THAT'S IT.
YEAH!
THANK YOU.
I KNEW STEVE WAS
JUST JOKING.
THIS IS MY LITTLE
BOWL OF PORRIDGE.
CAN YOU HELP US FIND
OUR CUPS OF MILK?
THREE BEARS DO LOOK
A LITTLE THIRSTY.
MUST BE ALL
THAT PORRIDGE.
WELL, DO YOU SEE
MAMA BEAR'S CUP OF MILK?
THAT'S THE ONE.
JUST THE RIGHT AMOUNT
OF MILK FOR ME.
GREAT JOB!
NOW, HOW ABOUT...
BABY BEAR?
THAT ONE!
MILK MAKES ME
GROW TO BE BIG
LIKE PAPA BEAR!
WHO IS ALSO
QUITE THIRSTY.
DO YOU SEE
PAPA BEAR'S CUP?
RIGHT THERE.
MILK FOR
PAPA BEAR.
JUST THE
RIGHT AMOUNT.
Three Bears:
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
OH, HEY, WE STILL
HAVE TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT BLUE'S FAVORITE,
FAVORITE STORY IS.
WE NEED ONE MORE CLUE.
WHAT WAS THAT?
A CLUE! A CLUE!
DID YOU SAY "A CLUE"?
WHERE?
BEHIND YOU!
OH. OH... OH!
THIS PIG HAS GOT
BLUE'S PAW PRINTS ON IT.
IT MUST BE ONE OF BLUE'S CLUES.
YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO.
WE NEED OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK!
NOTEBOOK.
A PIG'S HEAD.
A BIG ROUND BODY.
A CIRCLE FOR THE SNOUT.
LINES FOR THE LEGS.
AND A SQUIGGLY TAIL.
OKAY.
A PIG!
SO, A PIG IS
OUR THIRD BLUE'S CLUE.
HEY... WE HAVE ALL THREE CLUES.
YOU KNOW WHAT THIS MEANS?
WE'RE READY FOR OUR...
THINKING CHAIR.
THINKING CHAIR!
LET'S GO.
THERE GOES BLUE!
LET'S GO, TOO.
LET'S GET TO OUR...
THINKING CHAIR.
NOW THAT WE'RE IN OUR...
THINKING CHAIR
LET'S THINK.
OKAY, SO, WE NEED TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT BLUE'S FAVORITE,
FAVORITE STORY IS, RIGHT?
RIGHT.
OKAY, SO, OUR
THREE BLUE'S CLUES ARE...
BRICKS...
A WOLF...
AND A PIG.
SO... SO, WHAT STORY
COULD BLUE WANT TO READ
WITH BRICKS...
A WOLF...
AND A PIG?
HMM!
OH, OH! OH, IS IT...
IS IT THE STORY OF THE
LITTLE PIG WHO CRIED "WOLF"?
NO!
NO.
HMM.
WELL, WHAT STORY HAS BRICKS,
A WOLF AND A PIG?
BRICKS, WOLF, PIG.
"THE THREE LITTLE PIGS."
OH!
THAT'S IT!
THAT'S BRILLIANT!
BLUE WANTS TO READ
"THE THREE LITTLE PIGS."
BRICKS FOR THE BRICK HOUSE
IN THE STORY;
A WOLF...
:
FOR THE BIG BAD WOLF;
AND A PIG FOR
"THE THREE LITTLE PIGS"!
WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES!
♪ WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE JUST FIGURED
OUT BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ BECAUSE WE'RE REALLY SMART!
BLUE, LET'S GO GET YOUR
FAVORITE, FAVORITE STORYBOOK
"THE THREE LITTLE PIGS,"
SO WE CAN HAVE STORY TIME!
OOH! THANK YOU, BLUE.
"THE THREE LITTLE PIGS."
OH, HEY, LOOK WHO'S
HERE FOR STORY TIME.
IT'S SHOVEL AND PAIL.
REMEMBER THE NURSERY RHYME
WE HELPED THEM WITH?
WENT UP THAT HILL.
OH, AND LOOK,
IT'S TICKETY-TOCK.
IT'S STORY TIME.
OH, BLUE, LOOK!
MAGENTA CAME-- YOUR
FRIEND FROM SCHOOL!
HEY, AND THE THREE
BEARS ARE HERE! WOW!
ALL RIGHT,
WELL, LET'S READ
BLUE'S FAVORITE,
FAVORITE STORY...
TOGETHER.
"THE THREE LITTLE PIGS."
ONCE UPON A TIME,
THERE WERE THREE LITTLE PIGS.
THE FIRST LITTLE PIG MADE
HIS HOUSE OUT OF STRAW.
BUT THE BIG BAD WOLF CAME...
AND BLEW HIS HOUSE DOWN.
THE SECOND LITTLE PIG MADE
HIS HOUSE OUT OF...
STICKS.
BUT THE BIG BAD WOLF CAME...
AND BLEW HIS HOUSE DOWN, TOO.
BUT THE THIRD LITTLE PIG MADE
HER HOUSE OUT OF BRICKS.
SO WHEN THE BIG BAD WOLF CAME...
:
BIG BAD WOLF.
HE HUFFED... AND HE PUFFED
AND HE HUFFED AND HE PUFFED
AND HE HUFFED...
SORRY.
BUT HE COULD NOT BLOW
THE LITTLE PIG'S HOUSE DOWN.
THE END.
All:
READ IT AGAIN.
OKAY.
COME ON.
HEY, THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR ALL YOUR HELP TODAY.
♪ NOW IT'S TIME FOR SO LONG
♪ BUT WE'LL SING
JUST ONE MORE SONG ♪
♪ THANKS FOR DOING YOUR PART
♪ YOU SURE ARE SMART
♪ YOU KNOW, WITH ME AND YOU
♪ AND MY DOG, BLUE
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING
♪ THAT WE WANT TO DO.
BYE-BYE, SEE YOU LATER.
BYE.
COME AGAIN.
BYE-BYE.