HI, OUT THERE!
IT'S ME, STEVE.
HAVE YOU SEEN BLUE, MY PUPPY?
THERE SHE IS!
COME ON IN.
:
HI.
I'M SO GLAD YOU'RE HERE
ON THIS GREAT SUMMER DAY.
OH.
I SHOULD PROBABLY TAKE THIS OFF.
:
THERE.
HEY, YOU CAN HELP US GET READY
TO GO TO THE BEACH.
COME ON.
BLUE!
LOOK WHO'S HERE
TO JOIN US TODAY.
BLUE?
UM... HAVE YOU SEEN BLUE?
SHE'S RIGHT THERE.
WHERE?
BLUE?
HOW DID YOU GET IN THERE?
OH...
HEY, DID YOU FIND
ALL YOUR FAVORITE
BEACH TOYS?
GREAT--
NOW WE'RE ALL SET
TO GO TO THE BEACH.
WE HAVE YOUR BEACH TOYS,
WE HAVE YOUR TOWEL...
:
MY SNORKEL MASK.
NO? WE DON'T HAVE
EVERYTHING TO GO
TO THE BEACH?
WELL, WHAT ELSE
DO WE NEED TO BRING
TO THE BEACH?
OH, OKAY.
THAT'S A GREAT IDEA, BLUE.
WE'LL PLAY "BLUE'S CLUES"
TO FIGURE IT OUT.
♪ WE ARE GONNA PLAY
"BLUE'S CLUES" ♪
♪ 'CAUSE IT'S A REALLY FUN GAME,
YEAH! ♪
SO REMEMBER, BLUE'S PAW PRINTS
WILL BE ON THE CLUES:
BLUE'S CLUES.
OH, YEAH... YOU'RE RIGHT.
WE SHOULD PROBABLY CLEAN
THIS PAW PRINT OFF.
HEY, YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED FOR
BLUE'S CLUES, OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK!
RIGHT.
COME ON.
BLUE'S CLUES,
I'M SO EXCITED.
OOH! HERE IT IS.
YOU KNOW, I CAN TELL I'M REALLY
GOING TO NEED YOUR HELP TODAY
FIGURING OUT WHAT ELSE
WE NEED TO BRING TO THE BEACH.
WILL YOU HELP ME?
YOU WILL?
GREAT.
♪ WE GOT TO FIND A PAW PRINT,
THAT'S THE FIRST CLUE ♪
♪ WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND NOW WHAT DO WE DO? ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE SECOND CLUE ♪
♪ WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
NOW WHAT DO WE DO? ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE THIRD CLUE ♪
♪ PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND, WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WELL, WE SIT DOWN
IN OUR THINKING CHAIR ♪
♪ AND THINK, THINK, THINK
♪ 'CAUSE WHEN WE USE OUR MINDS,
TAKE A STEP AT A TIME ♪
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING...
♪ THAT WE WANT TO DO.
DID YOU SEE WHICH WAY BLUE WENT?
SHE WENT THAT WAY.
OH, THAT WAY?
BLUE SWAM THAT WAY?
OKAY, GREAT.
LET'S GO.
♪ WE ARE SWIMMING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE ARE
SWIMMING FOR BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE ARE SWIMMING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WONDER WHERE THEY ARE.
WHAT WAS THAT?
A CLUE!
A CLUE.
OH, YOU SEE A CLUE?
WHERE?
ON MY HEAD?
BED.
OH...
THE BED.
UNDER THE BED?
THERE'S NO CLUE HERE.
ON TOP OF THE BED.
OH, OH, ON TOP
OF THE BED.
OH! THERE IT IS--
ONE OF BLUE'S CLUES.
ON TOP OF THE BED!
YEAH, ON TOP
OF THE BED, RIGHT.
IT'S A CLUE!
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
RIGHT, LET'S WRITE
THIS CLUE DOWN
IN OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK.
NOTEBOOK!
SO, WE HAVE A...
WE HAVE A, A...
WHAT IS THIS CLUE?
A BASKET.
A BASKET, RIGHT.
AN OVAL...
A SEMICIRCLE...
THE HANDLE...
AND WE HAVE...
A BASKET.
HMM, SO, WE'RE TRYING
TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT ELSE WE NEED TO BRING
TO THE BEACH.
WELL, WHAT COULD BLUE
WANT TO DO WITH A BASKET?
THINK WE NEED TO LOOK
FOR TWO MORE BLUE'S CLUES
TO FIGURE THIS OUT.
COME ON.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING, BLUE?
OH, TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT TO WEAR TO THE BEACH, HUH?
OKAY.
HMM... CAN YOU HELP US
FIGURE OUT WHAT BLUE NEEDS
TO WEAR TO THE BEACH?
OKAY.
WE'LL DO THIS FIRST,
AND THEN WE'LL GO LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
COME ON.
HMM, SO WHAT SHOULD...
WHAT SHOULD BLUE WEAR
TO THE BEACH?
THAT ONE.
THESE?
THE PAJAMAS?
NO!
THE BATHING SUIT.
OH, THE BATHING SUIT.
SO BLUE CAN GO...
SWIMMING.
SWIMMING!
GREAT.
NOW ALL WE NEED
IS SOMETHING FOR YOUR FEET.
HMM, WHAT SHOES...
WHAT SHOES SHOULD BLUE
WEAR TO THE BEACH?
RIGHT THERE.
THESE?
THE RAIN BOOTS?
NO!
THE SANDALS!
OH, THE SANDALS...
FOR WHEN IT'S HOT.
I CALL THEM FLIP-FLOPS.
THERE GOES BLUE.
LET'S GO, TOO.
KEEP AN EYE OUT
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
THERE'S BLUE.
BLUE.
YOU SAW ANOTHER CLUE?
OH... BLUE'S HIDING.
OKAY.
I GOT IT.
BLUE... WHERE ARE YOU?
BLUE?
IS THAT YOU?
A CLUE.
A CLUE!
YEAH, SHE'S PRETTY
FUNNY, THAT BLUE.
DID YOU SAY A CLUE?
WHERE?
RIGHT THERE.
THERE IT IS--
OUR SECOND CLUE!
OKAY, SO, WE HAVE TO
WRITE THIS DOWN
IN OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK.
OKAY, SO, OUR
SECOND BLUE'S CLUE
IS THIS, THIS...
BLANKET.
BLANKET, RIGHT.
SQUIGGLY LINES,
KIND OF LIKE A SQUARE...
AND A WHOLE LOT OF LITTLE
SQUIGGLY SQUARES INSIDE.
OKAY, SO OUR FIRST CLUE IS...
A BASKET.
A BASKET, RIGHT.
AND NOW WE HAVE A... BLANKET.
HMM...
SO, WE'RE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT ELSE WE NEED TO BRING
TO THE BEACH.
SO WHAT COULD BLUE WANT TO DO
WITH A BASKET AND A BLANKET?
HMM...
I THINK WE NEED TO LOOK
FOR OUR LAST BLUE'S CLUE
TO FIGURE THIS OUT.
♪ MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME,
MAIL TIME ♪
♪ MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME!
THE MAIL'S HERE!
LET'S GO.
♪ HERE'S THE MAIL,
IT NEVER FAILS ♪
♪ IT MAKES ME WANT
TO WAG MY TAIL ♪
♪ WHEN IT COMES,
I WANT TO WAIL, "MAIL!" ♪
MAIL'S HERE,
MAIL'S IN.
GET YOUR MAIL
WHILE IT'S HOT.
THANKS, MAILBOX.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
WE JUST GOT A LETTER.
♪ WE JUST GOT A LETTER
♪ WE JUST GOT
A LETTER ♪
♪ WE JUST GOT A LETTER
♪ WONDER WHO IT'S FROM.
OH, LOOK... IT'S A LETTER
FROM OUR FRIENDS.
HI!
All:
HI, STEVE.
WE'RE PRACTICING SWIMMING.
I'M BLOWING BUBBLES.
REACH OUT
AND TOUCH MY HANDS.
THAT'S IT... REACH OUT.
GOOD.
I CAN GO UNDER WATER.
Man:
OKAY, WHO'S GOING
TO DO IT?
OKAY, WAIT A SECOND.
ALL RIGHT, READY?
NOW, LOOK.
Girl:
MY TURN, MY TURN!
I DID IT!
All:
BYE!
HEY, WE STILL HAVE TO LOOK
FOR OUR LAST BLUE'S CLUE
TO FIGURE OUT WHAT ELSE WE NEED
TO BRING TO THE BEACH.
IS THAT THE... PHONE?
HELLO?
Mr. Salt:
Sink.
Mrs. Pepper:
Float.
Sink.
HELLO?
Hello, Steve.
This is Mr. Salt.
And Mrs. Pepper.
OH... IT'S OUR FRIENDS,
MR. SALT AND MRS. PEPPER.
Sink.
Float.
ARE YOU GUYS HAVING
SOME PROBLEM WITH THE SINK?
Float! Um...
Well, uh...
Can you come help us?
UH... YEAH,
WE'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
YOU'LL COME AND HELP, RIGHT?
GREAT.
LET'S GET TO THE KITCHEN AND
SEE WHAT'S UP WITH THAT SINK.
Float!
♪ WE ARE SWIMMING
TO THE KITCHEN ♪
♪ WE ARE
SWIMMING TO THE KITCHEN ♪
♪ WE ARE SWIMMING
TO THE KITCHEN ♪
♪ TO FIND OUR KITCHEN FRIENDS.
SINK!
FLOAT!
HEY, BLUE.
SINK!
FLOAT!
WHAT'S GOING ON
OVER HERE?
MR. SALT OVER HERE
SEEMS TO THINK THAT
THIS STRAW WILL SINK.
SINK, EXACTLY.
MRS. PEPPER OVER HERE
SEEMS TO THINK
THAT THIS STRAW WILL FLOAT,
BUT IT WILL SINK.
FLOAT!
SINK!
HEY... WHY DON'T YOU
JUST TRY IT?
OH, TRY IT.
OF COURSE.
WE'LL TRY IT.
YEAH, YEAH.
JUST PUT THE STRAW
IN THE WATER
AND SEE IF IT SINKS
OR FLOATS.
OKAY!
OKAY.
WELL, WHAT DO YOU THINK?
WILL THE STRAW
SINK TO THE BOTTOM
OR FLOAT ON TOP?
IT'S GOING TO FLOAT!
THE STRAW FLOATS,
WOULD YOU LOOK AT THAT!
I KNEW IT.
YES... WELL...
I KNEW YOU KNEW IT.
HEY, SO GLAD
WE COULD HELP.
GOOD JOB.
YOU ARE REALLY
GOOD AT THIS.
HEY, LET'S GO LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES...
WAIT!
Both:
ONE MORE THING.
WILL THIS PAPER CUP
SINK OR FLOAT?
OOH... WELL, WHAT
DO YOU THINK?
WILL THE PAPER CUP
SINK TO THE BOTTOM
OR FLOAT ON TOP?
FLOAT.
THE PAPER CUP FLOATS!
YOU REALLY KNOW
YOUR PHYSICS.
NOW LET'S GO LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
WAIT!
Both:
WE HAVE TO HAVE TO KNOW.
WILL THIS METAL SPOON
SINK OR FLOAT?
UH, WELL,
WE'LL HELP YOU
WITH THIS LAST ONE
BECAUSE YOU ARE
SO GOOD AT THIS.
HMM... WELL,
WILL THE METAL SPOON
SINK OR FLOAT?
SINK, SINK!
THE METAL SPOON SINKS!
HAVE YOU DONE THIS
BEFORE OR SOMETHING?
SINK!
FLOAT!
Both:
THANKS FOR ALL YOUR HELP.
HEY, YOU'RE WELCOME.
GOOD JOB.
AND YOU, TOO,
YOU SINK-AND-FLOAT EXPERT.
HEY, DID YOU SEE THAT?
BLUE JUST WENT
RIGHT INTO THAT POSTCARD.
OOH... IT'S A POSTCARD
OF AN ISLAND.
DO YOU THINK WE SHOULD GO, TOO?
OKAY.
♪ BLUE SKIDDOO, WE CAN, TOO.
WOW!
LOOK AT THIS ISLAND!
BEAUTIFUL.
THIS WAY.
AH...
HEY, IT'S BLUE,
WITH STARFISH AND HER FRIENDS.
HELLO.
HI, WE NEED HELP
GETTING TO THE PLAYGROUND.
YEAH.
UH-HUH.
DO YOU SEE
WHICH WAY I SHOULD GO?
WHICH PART
OF THE CORAL REEF
DO YOU THINK STARFISH
WOULD FIT THROUGH?
THAT ONE.
YEAH.
HEY...
YOU FOUND THE WAY
FOR STARFISH.
LOOK AT THAT!
OKAY, LET'S HELP YOU NEXT,
OCTOPUS.
OKAY, DO YOU SEE
THE WAY I SHOULD GO?
WHAT PART OF THE CORAL REEF
DO YOU THINK OCTOPUS
COULD FIT THROUGH?
RIGHT THERE.
YEAH, THAT'S IT.
YOU DID IT AGAIN!
COOL.
ME NEXT?
OKAY, I WANT TO PLAY
ON THE SEESAW.
WHICH PART OF THE CORAL REEF
DO YOU THINK SEA HORSE
COULD FIT THROUGH?
THE MIDDLE, THE MIDDLE.
WHEE!
All:
YAY! THANKS.
YOU DID A REALLY GOOD JOB.
THERE GOES BLUE!
AH...
A CLUE, A CLUE!
A POOL?
OH, YEAH,
LOVE TO SWIM.
NO...
IT'S A CLUE!
OH... YOU SEE A CLUE?
A CLUE?
A CLUE RIGHT HERE
IN THE KITCHEN?
OVER HERE?
THERE IT IS,
OUR THIRD CLUE!
AND IT'S A...
SANDWICH?
OKAY...
WE KNOW WHAT TO DO.
WE NEED OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK!
NOTEBOOK.
OKAY, ONE PIECE OF BREAD...
THE CHEESE...
AND THE OTHER PIECE OF BREAD.
THERE, A SANDWICH.
THAT WOULD BE OUR THIRD CLUE.
OUR LAST CLUE!
YOU KNOW WHAT THAT MEANS?
WE ARE READY FOR OUR...
THINKING CHAIR!
THINKING CHAIR.
AH... NOW THAT WE'RE IN OUR
THINKING CHAIR, LET'S THINK.
OKAY, NOW, WE NEED TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT ELSE WE NEED TO BRING
TO THE BEACH.
OUR BLUE'S CLUES ARE A BASKET...
A BLANKET...
AND... A SANDWICH.
HMM... WELL, WHAT COULD BLUE
WANT WITH A BASKET, A BLANKET
AND A SANDWICH?
OOH, OOH, COULD SHE WANT
TO BURY A SANDWICH AND
A BASKET IN THE SAND
AND THEN COVER IT UP
WITH THE BLANKET?
JUST... COVER IT.
NO...
WELL, WHAT IF, WHAT IF WE PUT
THE SANDWICH IN THE BASKET?
THEN WE WOULD HAVE A, A SANDWICH
IN A BASKET, AND A BLANKET.
HMM... WELL, IF WE SIT
ON THE BLANKET AND EAT
THE SANDWICH
THEN WE WOULD HAVE...
A PICNIC.
A PICNIC LUNCH.
A PICNIC LUNCH!
THAT'S IT!
THAT'S BRILLIANT!
BLUE WANTS US TO BRING
A PICNIC LUNCH TO THE BEACH!
A BASKET TO CARRY EVERYTHING,
A BLANKET TO SIT ON, AND
SANDWICHES TO EAT!
WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES!
♪ WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE JUST
FIGURED OUT BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ BECAUSE WE'RE REALLY SMART.
BLUE, I'M GOING TO FIX
OUR PICNIC LUNCH
SO WE CAN GO TO THE BEACH!
♪ WE ARE GOING TO THE BEACH
♪ WE ARE GOING
TO THE BEACH ♪
♪ WE ARE GOING TO THE BEACH
♪ TO PLAY AND SWIM AND EAT.
ISN'T OUR BEACH GREAT?
OH, HEY, BLUE.
LOOK AT BLUE IN HER
LITTLE BATHING SUIT
AND...
FLIP-FLOPS.
LOOK! LOOK WHO
CAME TO THE BEACH
WITH US.
IT'S MR. SALT
AND MRS. PEPPER.
THIS CUP WILL...
Both:
FLOAT!
FLOAT.
AND LOOK, IT'S
OUR SEA FRIENDS
WE HELPED.
All:
WHEE!
WHAT A GREAT DAY
FOR A PICNIC
AT THE BEACH!
OH... COME ON.
HEY, THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR ALL YOUR HELP TODAY.
♪ NOW IT'S TIME FOR SO LONG
♪ BUT WE'LL SING
JUST ONE MORE SONG ♪
♪ THANKS FOR DOING YOUR PART
♪ YOU SURE ARE SMART
♪ YOU KNOW, WITH ME AND YOU
♪ AND MY DOG, BLUE
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING
♪ THAT WE WANT TO DO.
BYE-BYE. SEE YOU LATER.
BYE. COME AGAIN.
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING♪
♪ THAT WE WANT TO DO.♪