HI, OUT THERE!
IT'S ME, STEVE.
HAVE YOU SEEN BLUE, MY PUPPY?
THERE SHE IS!
COME ON IN.
( barking... )
OH, HI.
COME ON IN.
HEY, BLUE, LOOK WHO'S HERE.
YOU KNOW, I'M TRYING TO REMEMBER
THE WORDS TO THIS SONG.
I THINK IT GOES
SOMETHING LIKE THIS:
* HEAD, SHOULDERS...
SOMETHING, SOMETHING,
SOMETHING, SOMETHING...
OH, WAIT, WAIT.
I THINK I REMEMBER NOW.
I THINK IT GOES:
* HEADS, SHOULDERS,
BACK AND BELLY,
BACK AND BELLY... *
NO!
NO?
WELL, CAN YOU HELP ME?
DO YOU REMEMBER THE REST?
KNEES AND TOES!
OH, YOU'RE RIGHT.
IT'S, IT'S KNEES AND TOES,
KNEES AND TOES. GREAT.
DO YOU WANT TO SING IT WITH ME?
GREAT.
( clears throat )
* HEAD, SHOULDERS
* KNEES AND TOES,
KNEES AND TOES *
* HEAD, SHOULDERS
* KNEES AND TOES,
KNEES AND TOES *
* AND EYES AND EARS
AND MOUTH AND NOSE *
* HEAD, SHOULDERS
* KNEES AND TOES,
KNEES AND TOES. *
ONE MORE TIME, AND...
( barking "no" )
( humming tune )
NO?
YOU MEAN YOU DON'T
WANT TO PLAY
* HEAD, SHOULDERS,
KNEES AND TOES * AGAIN?
( barking "no" )
OKAY. WELL,
WHAT SONG GAME...
( cymbals playing )
DO YOU WANT TO PLAY?
( barking... )
OH! OKAY!
WE'LL PLAY "BLUE'S CLUES"
TO FIGURE IT OUT.
I LOVE "BLUE'S CLUES."
( jazzy ):
* WE ARE GONNA PLAY
"BLUE'S CLUES" *
* BECAUSE IT'S REALLY...
FUN, YEAH. *
OKAY, NOW REMEMBER,
BLUE'S PAW PRINT WILL BE
ON THE CLUES: BLUE'S CLUES.
NOW, ABOUT THIS PAW PRINT.
HEY!
LET'S CLAP IT OFF.
IT'LL BE GREAT.
YOU READY?
OOH.
COME ON.
FASTER!
WOW. ( laughs )
GOOD JOB.
HEY, YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED
FOR BLUE'S CLUES:
OUR HANDY DANDY...
NOTEBOOK!
NOTEBOOK, RIGHT.
COME ON.
BLUE'S CLUES--
I'M SO EXCITED!
OOH... HERE IT IS.
YOU KNOW, I CAN TELL
I'M REALLY GOING TO NEED
YOUR HELP TODAY
FIGURING OUT WHAT SONG GAME...
( cymbals playing )
BLUE WANTS TO PLAY.
WILL YOU HELP ME?
YOU WILL? GREAT.
* WE GOT TO FIND A PAW PRINT,
THAT'S THE FIRST CLUE *
* WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND NOW WHAT DO WE DO? *
* BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
* BLUE'S CLUES! *
* WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE SECOND CLUE *
* WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
NOW WHAT DO WE DO? *
* BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
* BLUE'S CLUES! *
* WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE THIRD CLUE *
* WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND, WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO *
* BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
* BLUE'S CLUES! *
* WELL, WE SIT DOWN
IN OUR THINKING CHAIR *
* AND THINK, THINK, THINK
* 'CAUSE WHEN WE USE OUR MINDS,
TAKE A STEP AT A TIME *
* WE CAN DO ANYTHING...
( barks )
* THAT WE WANT TO DO.
OKAY. LET'S GO.
( barks )
DID YOU SEE WHICH WAY BLUE WENT?
THAT WAY!
OH, OKAY.
HEY, LET'S TAKE...
LET'S TAKE...
( deep voice ):
GIANT STEPS
TO FIND BLUE'S CLUES.
OKAY? OKAY.
* WE'RE GIANT-STEPPING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES *
* WE'RE GIANT-STEPPING FOR
BLUE'S CLUES *
THIS IS FUN.
* WE'RE GIANT-STEPPING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES *
* I WONDER
WHERE THEY ARE. *
A CLUE, A CLUE!
A CLUE?
DID YOU SEE A CLUE? WHERE?
RIGHT THERE.
I DON'T SEE A CLUE.
I'M JUST A GIANT.
OOH! THE CLUE!
THIS... SUN HAS GOT
BLUE'S PAW PRINT ON IT.
( chuckles )
IT'S OUR FIRST BLUE'S CLUE.
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
NOTEBOOK!
RIGHT. WE NEED OUR
HANDY DANDY... NOTEBOOK.
OKAY.
SO...
WE START WITH A CIRCLE...
AND THEN LITTLE LINES
THAT GO OUT LIKE THIS
FOR THE SUN'S RAYS...
AND WE HAVE...
A SUN.
MMM...
OKAY, SO WHAT SONG GAME...
( cymbals playing )
COULD BLUE WANT TO PLAY
WITH A SUN?
HMM.
I THINK WE NEED TO LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
* TWO LITTLE MONKEYS
JUMPING ON THE BED *
* ONE FELL OFF
AND BUMPED HER HEAD. *
* MAMA CALLED THE DOCTOR
AND THE DOCTOR SAID *
* "NO MORE MONKEYS
JUMPING ON THE BED." *
HEY, BLUE.
HEY... MONKEY.
HI, STEVE.
WE'RE PLAYING
"MONKEYS ON THE BED."
WANT TO PLAY?
DO YOU WANT TO PLAY?
GREAT.
THEN WE CAN GO LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
( barks )
OKAY, MONKEY,
WHAT DO WE DO?
WATCH ME
AND DO WHAT I DO.
OH, YOU MEAN MONKEY SEE,
MONKEY DO? ( chuckles )
OKAY, OKAY.
ARE YOU READY TO PLAY?
THIS IS THE FIRST PART.
WATCH.
* TWO LITTLE MONKEYS
JUMPING ON THE BED *
* ONE FELL OFF
AND BUMPED HER HEAD. *
WOW.
YOU WILL HELP ME,
RIGHT?
GREAT.
OKAY, LET'S TRY THIS,
TOGETHER.
* TWO LITTLE MONKEYS
JUMPING ON THE BED *
* ONE FELL OFF AND
BUMPED HER NOSE. *
NO! NO...
NO?
WELL, THAT'S NOT IT?
WHAT IS IT THEN?
HEAD!
( laughing ):
OH, RIGHT, HER HEAD.
AND I SAID NOSE.
OKAY, TRY AGAIN.
OKAY, READY?
LET'S TRY IT AGAIN.
* TWO LITTLE MONKEYS
JUMPING ON THE BED *
* ONE FELL OFF AND
BUMPED HER HEAD. *
YEAH!
THAT WAS GREAT!
READY FOR
THE NEXT PART?
THERE'S MORE?
YOU'LL HELP ME
AGAIN, RIGHT?
OH, GOOD.
* MAMA CALLED THE DOCTOR
AND THE DOCTOR SAID *
* "NO MORE MONKEYS
JUMPING ON THE BED." *
HMM...
OKAY, READY?
* MAMA CALLED
THE DOCTOR AND
THE DOCTOR SAID *
* "ALL OF THE MONKEYS
JUMPING ON THE BED." *
( imitates monkey
chattering )
NO!
NO?
WELL, WHAT DID I
MESS UP NOW?
NO MORE MONKEYS!
( laughing... ):
OH, YEAH, RIGHT.
NO MORE MONKEYS.
PROBABLY DON'T WANT TO
BE JUMPING ON THE BED.
OKAY.
ONE MORE TIME.
OKAY, LET'S TRY THIS
* MAMA CALLED
THE DOCTOR AND
THE DOCTOR SAID *
* "NO MORE MONKEYS
JUMPING ON THE BED." *
YEAH!
LET'S DO
THE WHOLE SONG.
READY?
THE, UH,
THE WHOLE SONG, HUH?
YOU'LL SING IT
WITH ME, RIGHT?
GOOD.
YOU READY?
HERE GOES.
* ONE LITTLE MONKEY
JUMPING ON THE BED *
* ONE FELL OFF AND
BUMPED HER HEAD *
* MAMA CALLED
THE DOCTOR AND
THE DOCTOR SAID *
* "NO MORE MONKEYS
JUMPING ON THE BED." *
THAT WAS GREAT!
( barking )
OH, WE BETTER GO.
WE STILL HAVE TO FIND
TWO MORE MONKEYS.
I MEAN CLUES.
* MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME,
MAIL TIME... *
HEY, YOU KNOW
WHAT THAT MEANS!
MAIL TIME!
* HERE'S THE MAIL,
IT NEVER FAILS *
* IT MAKES ME WANT
TO WAG MY TAIL *
* WHEN IT COMES,
I WANT TO WAIL, "MAIL!" *
( barks )
* IF YOU'RE HAPPY
AND YOU KNOW IT,
WAVE YOUR FLAG. *
Together:
* IF YOU'RE HAPPY
AND YOU KNOW IT *
* AND YOU REALLY WANT
TO SHOW IT *
* IF YOU'RE HAPPY AND
YOU KNOW IT, WAVE YOUR FLAG. *
( laughing )
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
WE JUST GOT A LETTER.
( barks )
* WE JUST GOT A LETTER
* WE JUST GOT
A LETTER *
* WE JUST GOT A LETTER
* WONDER WHO IT'S FROM.
All:
HI, STEVE.
WE MADE UP A SONG GAME.
All:
ONE, TWO, THREE, GO!
* WE GOT A FRIEND NAMED STEVE
AND STEVE PLAYS BLUE'S CLUES *
* STEVE HAS A DOG NAMED BLUE
AND BLUE GOES... *
* WOOF, WOOF, WOOF!
* BLUE'S CLUES! *
* WE TELL TIME *
* WITH TICKETY TOCK *
* TICKETY TOCK *
* WOOF, WOOF!
* BLUE'S CLUES!
* WE GET MAIL FROM MAIL BOX *
* MAIL TIME! *
* TICKETY TOCK
* WOOF, WOOF, WOOF!
* BLUE'S CLUES! *
BYE.
WOW.
NICE MOVES.
* BLUE'S CLUES
* MAIL TIME
* TICKETY TOCK.
( Tickety ringing )
( ringing )
TICKETY.
HI, STEVE.
DID I HEAR YOU
SINGING THIS SONG?
( humming
"If You're Happy
And You Know It" )
OH, YEAH, THAT'S
"IF YOU'RE HAPPY
AND YOU KNOW IT."
MAILBOX WAS JUST
SINGING THAT.
STEVE, THAT'S
MY FAVORITE
SONG GAME.
WANT TO PLAY IT
WITH ME?
DO YOU WANT TO PLAY
"IF YOU'RE HAPPY
AND YOU KNOW IT"
WITH TICKETY?
OKAY. THEN WE'LL GO LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
I'M SO EXCITED!
OKAY, I'LL ACT IT OUT,
AND YOU ALL TELL ME
WHAT I'M DOING.
OH, SO TICKETY WILL
ACT OUT THE MOVEMENTS
AND WE'LL GUESS
WHAT SHE'S DOING.
GREAT. YOU READY?
LET'S GO.
* IF YOU'RE HAPPY
AND YOU KNOW IT... *
WHAT'S THIS?
HMM.
* IF YOU'RE HAPPY
AND YOU KNOW IT... *
* WIGGLE YOUR EARS.
* IF...
NO!
NO?
WELL, WHAT IS SHE DOING?
STAMP YOUR FEET!
OH, RIGHT,
STAMP YOUR FEET.
THAT'S PERFECT.
RIGHT,
STAMP YOUR FEET.
LET'S SING
ANOTHER ONE.
* IF YOU'RE HAPPY
AND YOU KNOW IT... *
WHAT'S THIS?
WHAT IS SHE DOING?
WAVING HER ARMS.
OH...
RIGHT, WAVE YOUR ARMS.
OF COURSE.
Both:
* IF YOU'RE HAPPY AND
YOU KNOW IT, WAVE YOUR ARMS *
* IF YOU'RE HAPPY AND YOU
KNOW IT, WAVE THOSE ARMS *
* IF YOU'RE HAPPY
AND YOU KNOW IT *
* AND YOU REALLY WANT
TO SHOW IT *
* IF YOU'RE HAPPY AND
YOU KNOW IT, WAVE YOUR ARMS *
* OR STAMP YOUR FEET
* OR WIGGLE YOUR EARS
( barks )
* OR WAG YOUR TAIL
* OR CLAP YOUR HANDS.
( both clapping )
( thunderclap )
WHAT'S THAT?
( rain falling )
OH, IT'S RAIN.
A CLUE!
NO, IT'S DEFINITELY RAIN.
NO, IT'S A CLUE!
A CLUE? REALLY?
WHERE?
BUT... ALL I SEE IS RAIN. UM...
OH, THE RAIN IS A CLUE!
( laughs )
OKAY, I'M WITH YOU NOW,
ALL RIGHT.
YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED-- OUR...
NOTEBOOK.
NOTEBOOK!
( humming )
OKAY, WE HAVE SOME RAIN DROPS.
KIND OF LIKE AN OVAL.
THEN SOME MORE RAIN DROPS...
AND A BIG, CURVY RAIN CLOUD.
THERE.
RAIN.
OKAY, SO, UH,
WHAT WAS OUR FIRST CLUE?
A SUN!
RIGHT, SUN.
MMM...
AND NOW WE HAVE RAIN.
HMM.
SO WHAT SONG GAME...
( cymbals playing )
COULD BLUE WANT TO PLAY
WITH SUN AND RAIN?
( thunderclap )
OOH.
YEAH, I THINK WE NEED TO FIND
OUR LAST BLUE'S CLUE.
( Blue barks )
( barking "Blue Skiddoo" )
OH... DID YOU SEE THAT?
BLUE JUST JUMPED RIGHT INTO
THE PICTURE OF THAT... BEACH.
LET'S GO, TOO.
* BLUE SKIDDOO, WE CAN, TOO.
WOW.
( barks "wow" )
THE BEACH.
( barks
"the beach" )
( surf music playing... )
( thunderclap )
OOH, RAIN CLOUD.
STEVE. STEVE!
CRABS.
STEVE, WE MADE UP A DANCE
TO THE SOUND OF RAIN.
RAIN DANCE? COOL.
CAN YOU FIGURE OUT
WHICH ONE OF US
IS DANCING
TO THE RHYTHM
OF THE RAIN?
WHICH ONE OF THESE CRABS
IS DANCING TO THE RHYTHM
OF THE RAIN?
THAT ONE.
OH, THIS CRAB.
YEAH, SEE HOW HIS MOVEMENTS
ARE QUICK
LIKE THE RHYTHM
OF THE RAIN?
( chuckles )
GOOD JOB.
( wind blowing )
OOH... WIND.
OCTOPI.
STEVE, STEVE!
CAN YOU FIGURE OUT
WHICH ONE OF US
IS DANCING TO THE RHYTHM
OF THE WIND?
CAN YOU TELL
WHICH OCTOPUS
IS MOVING TO THE RHYTHM
OF THE WIND?
THAT ONE.
OH, THIS ONE.
RIGHT.
SEE HOW SHE'S
MOVING SLOWLY
AND GRACEFULLY
LIKE THE RHYTHM
OF THE WIND?
HEY... GOOD JOB.
( waves crashing )
DID YOU HEAR THAT?
OH, WAVES.
AND HERONS.
STEVE, STEVE!
CAN YOU FIGURE OUT
WHICH ONE OF US
IS DANCING
TO THE RHYTHM
OF THE WAVES?
OH... HEY, SORRY.
BETTER GIVE THEM
SOME ROOM. SORRY.
THAT ONE!
OH, RIGHT.
THIS HERON IS MOVING
ON ALL THREE BEATS.
SHE'S IN PERFECT
RHYTHM, SEE?
EXCUSE ME.
THANK YOU.
THAT WAS SO MUCH FUN.
HEY, WILL YOU DANCE WITH ME?
OH, GOOD.
FIRST LET'S DANCE TO THE RHYTHM
OF THE RAIN.
OKAY.
NOW LET'S DANCE TO THE RHYTHM
OF THE WIND.
OKAY.
NOW LET'S DANCE TO THE RHYTHM
OF THE WAVES.
WHAT?
OH, A LITTLE SOFT SHOE.
OKAY.
NO, A CLUE.
OH... OH, A CLUE!
YOU SEE A CLUE,
RIGHT HERE ON THE BEACH?
WHERE?
OVER THERE!
OH. THE CLUE!
I'M A CLUE?
YUP. YOU, LITTLE SPIDER,
ARE A CLUE.
ONE OF BLUE'S CLUES.
I'M A CLUE,
HE SAID I'M A CLUE.
NOW WHAT DO YOU DO?
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
WE PUT IT
IN OUR HANDY DANDY...
NOTEBOOK.
NOTEBOOK, NOTEBOOK.
RIGHT.
WE HAVE A CIRCLE FOR THE BODY...
FOUR LEGS ON THIS SIDE...
AND FOUR LEGS ON THIS SIDE...
THEN THE SPIDER'S MOUTH
AND EYES...
A SPIDER.
OKAY.
WELL, WE HAVE
ALL THREE CLUES.
WE HAVE ALL THREE CLUES!
ALL THREE CLUES!
YOU KNOW WHAT THIS MEANS?
WE'RE READY FOR OUR...
THINKING CHAIR.
THANKS.
( barking
"Blue Skiddoo" )
AH...
OKAY, BLUE.
NOW THAT WE'RE
IN OUR THINKING CHAIR,
LET'S THINK.
OKAY, SO WE'RE TRYING TO
FIGURE OUT WHAT SONG GAME...
( cymbals playing )
BLUE WANTS TO PLAY
AND OUR CLUES ARE:
SUN...
AHH....
RAIN...
( thunderclap )
OOH.
AND... A SPIDER.
HI.
OKAY, SO WHAT SONG GAME...
( cymbals playing )
COULD BLUE WANT TO PLAY
WITH A SPIDER, SUN AND RAIN?
HMM.
OH, OH, OH, HOW ABOUT,
HOW ABOUT THE, UH...
THE SUNNY SPIDER THAT GETS
CAUGHT IN THE RAIN SONG?
NO!
NO.
HMM.
WELL, WHAT SONG GAME...
( cymbals playing )
IS ABOUT RAIN AND SUN
AND SPIDER AND...
ITSY BITSY SPIDER!
THE ITSY BITSY SPIDER!
THAT'S IT, BECAUSE,
BECAUSE IT'S ABOUT
A LITTLE SPIDER
WHO CRAWLS UP A SPOUT
AND THEN IT RAINS
AND THE SUN COMES OUT.
THAT'S IT!
WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES.
( jazzy ):
* WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES *
* WE JUST
FIGURED OUT BLUE'S CLUES *
* WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES *
* BECAUSE WE'RE REALLY SMART.
BLUE!
LET'S GO PLAY THE ITSY BITSY
SPIDER SONG GAME.
THIS IS GOING TO BE GREAT!
AH... OKAY.
OH, LOOK WHO'S HERE TO PLAY
BLUE'S SONG GAME WITH US.
IT'S THE MONKEY.
( chattering )
REMEMBER THE GAME WE PLAYED
WITH THE MONKEY?
* TWO LITTLE MONKEYS. *
RIGHT.
OH, AND IT'S
TICKETY TOCK.
HEY, TICKETY.
REMEMBER THE GAME
WE PLAYED WITH HER?
* IF YOU'RE HAPPY
AND YOU KNOW IT,
WAVE YOUR HANDS. *
OH, AND LOOK,
IT'S OUR BEACH FRIENDS.
HEY, GUYS.
OKAY, IS EVERYBODY READY TO PLAY
THE ITSY BITSY SPIDER SONG GAME?
WELL, YOU'LL PLAY
WITH US TOO, RIGHT?
OH, GOOD.
* THE ITSY BITSY SPIDER
WENT UP THE WATER SPOUT. *
HEY, SPIDER.
* DOWN CAME THE RAIN
* AND WASHED THE SPIDER OUT.
* OUT CAME THE SUN
AND DRIED UP ALL THE RAIN *
* AND THE ITSY BITSY SPIDER
WENT UP THE SPOUT AGAIN. *
NICE JOB, SPIDER.
( barking )
OH, YEAH, RIGHT.
NOW IT'S TIME FOR ME
TO PICK A SONG GAME.
OOH, BUT DON'T FORGET
TO SING IT WITH ME.
* NOW IT'S TIME FOR SO LONG
* BUT WE'LL SING
JUST ONE MORE SONG *
* THANKS FOR DOING YOUR PART
* YOU SURE ARE SMART
* YOU KNOW, WITH ME AND YOU
* AND MY DOG, BLUE
* WE CAN DO ANYTHING
* THAT WE WANT TO DO.
BYE, BYE.
THANKS FOR ALL YOUR HELP.
HEY, OCTOPUS, CAN YOU DO THIS?
HUH?
* WE CAN DO ANYTHING! *
( barks good-bye )