HI, OUT THERE!
IT'S ME, STEVE.
HAVE YOU SEEN BLUE, MY PUPPY?
THERE SHE IS!
COME ON IN.
HI.
OH, HI.
COME ON IN.
YOU'RE JUST IN TIME TO PLAY
HIDE-AND-SEEK WITH US.
COME ON.
THIS IS ONE OF MY
FAVORITE GAMES.
OKAY, BLUE,
ARE YOU READY?
ONE, TWO, THREE,
FOUR, FIVE...
SIX, SEVEN, EIGHT,
NINE, TEN.
READY OR NOT, HERE WE COME.
DO YOU SEE BLUE?
OVER HERE?
NO. OVER THERE.
OH.
OH, OVER THERE,
BEHIND THE TOY BOX.
RIGHT.
OKAY, LET'S PLAY AGAIN.
ONE, TWO, THREE,
FOUR...
FIVE...
NO?
YOU DON'T WANT TO PLAY
HIDE-AND-SEEK AGAIN?
OH.
OKAY.
WELL, WHAT GAME DO YOU
WANT TO PLAY NEXT?
OH, OKAY.
WE'LL PLAY "BLUE'S CLUES"
TO FIGURE OUT WHAT GAME
BLUE WANTS TO PLAY NEXT.
♪ WE ARE GONNA PLAY
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ 'CAUSE IT'S REALLY FUN,
YEAH! ♪
NOW REMEMBER, BLUE'S PAW PRINT
WILL BE ON THE CLUES:
"BLUE'S CLUES."
LET'S GO.
OH, YEAH.
WE SHOULD PROBABLY CLEAN
THIS PAW PRINT UP.
OH.
LET'S PLAY SIMON SAYS
TO CLEAN THIS PAW PRINT UP.
OKAY?
OKAY.
PAW PRINT, CLEAN UP.
UH-UH-UH!
I DIDN'T SAY "SIMON SAYS."
OKAY.
SIMON SAYS, PAW PRINT, CLEAN UP.
COOL.
HEY, YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED
FOR BLUE'S CLUES, OUR...
NOTEBOOK!
NOTEBOOK, RIGHT. COME ON.
BLUE'S CLUES,
I'M SO EXCITED.
OOH!
HERE IT IS.
YOU KNOW, I CAN TELL
I'M REALLY GOING
TO NEED YOUR HELP TODAY
FIGURING OUT WHAT GAME BLUE
WANTS TO PLAY NEXT.
WILL YOU HELP ME?
YOU WILL?
GREAT.
COME ON.
♪ WE GOT TO FIND THE PAW PRINT,
THAT'S THE FIRST CLUE ♪
♪ WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND NOW WHAT DO WE DO? ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE SECOND CLUE ♪
♪ WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
NOW WHAT DO WE DO? ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE THIRD CLUE ♪
♪ PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND, WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WELL, WE SIT DOWN
IN OUR THINKING CHAIR ♪
♪ AND THINK, THINK, THINK
♪ 'CAUSE WHEN WE USE OUR MINDS,
TAKE A STEP AT A TIME ♪
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING...
♪ THAT WE WANT TO DO.
OKAY, LET'S GO.
UM, WHICH WAY?
THAT WAY!
OH, OKAY.
LET'S GO THAT WAY.
♪ WE ARE LOOKING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ I WONDER WHERE THEY ARE?
YEAH! ♪
OH, HI, MR. SALT
AND MRS. PEPPER.
HAVE YOU SEEN...
Both:
SHE'S IN THE GARDEN.
THANKS.
♪ WITH A QUACK-QUACK HERE
♪ AND A QUACK-QUACK THERE
♪ HERE A QUACK
♪ THERE A QUACK...
A QUACK?
A CLUE.
OH!
OH, DID YOU SEE A CLUE?
WHERE?
ON THE DUCK.
DUCK?
OH.
ON THE DUCK.
RIGHT.
THIS DUCK... MUST BE
ONE OF BLUE'S CLUES.
IT'S OUR FIRST CLUE.
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
RIGHT, WE NEED
OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK.
OKAY, SO... DRAW A DUCK.
DRAW A CIRCLE FOR THE HEAD.
THE BILL.
A COUPLE OF EYES.
THE DUCK'S BODY.
AND ITS WING.
THERE.
A DUCK.
HMM.
SO WHAT GAME
COULD BLUE WANT TO PLAY NEXT
WITH A DUCK?
WELL, LET'S KEEP AN EYE
OUT FOR MORE CLUES.
MAYBE IT GOES
THIS WAY.
MAYBE, BUT HOW
ABOUT THIS PIECE?
HEY, THAT SOUNDS LIKE
OUR FRIENDS, UM...
OH! SHOVEL AND PAIL.
LET'S GO SEE WHAT THEY'RE UP TO.
OH, LOOK,
THERE'S STEVE.
HI, STEVE.
HEY, SHOVEL.
HI, PAIL.
HEY, BLUE.
UH, WHAT ARE
YOU DOING?
WE'RE PUTTING TOGETHER
OUR NEW PUZZLE.
WANT TO HELP US?
DO YOU WANT TO HELP
SHOVEL AND PAIL
PUT TOGETHER THIS PUZZLE?
GREAT.
THEN WE CAN GO LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
OKAY, SO...
WHAT PIECE ARE
WE LOOKING FOR?
WE NEED A PIECE OF THE
PUZZLE FOR RIGHT THERE.
CAN YOU HELP US?
HMM...
WHICH PIECE OF
THE PUZZLE GOES THERE?
THAT ONE.
OH, THE CIRCLE
PUZZLE PIECE.
IT FITS!
LOOK, BALLOONS.
AND STREAMERS!
HEY...
I WONDER WHAT PICTURE
THIS PUZZLE WILL MAKE?
LET'S FIND THE NEXT
PIECE TOGETHER, TOO.
HMM.
WHICH PUZZLE PIECE
GOES THERE?
THAT ONE.
Both:
YEAH, IT FITS!
CHAIRS.
Both:
WE ONLY HAVE ONE
MORE PIECE TO FIND!
DO YOU SEE WHICH
PIECE WE NEED?
THAT ONE.
IT DOESN'T FIT.
WHAT SHOULD
WE DO?
STEVE, TURN IT AROUND.
TURN THE PIECE AROUND?
HEY, WOULD YOU
LOOK AT THAT!
IT'S MAILBOX'S BIRTHDAY
PARTY, REMEMBER?
YEAH!
A PARTY!
HEY, THANKS
FOR HELPING US
PUT IT TOGETHER.
HEY, BLUE.
BLUE?
HMM, I WONDER WHERE
BLUE'S GOING.
LET'S GO SEE. COME ON.
♪ B-L-U-E,
THAT'S MY PUPPY'S NAME ♪
♪ B-L-U-E, FINDING CLUES
IS OUR GAME ♪
♪ BUH-BA, BUH-BA...
WHOA!
HEY, THAT SOUNDS LIKE
OUR FRIEND...
WHOA!
...SLIPPERY SOAP.
COME ON.
WHOA!
HEY, SLIP... PERY, WHAT'S... UP?
A CLUE!
A CLUE?
WHERE'S THE CLUE?
WHOA.
A CLUE, RIGHT UNDER THERE!
OH!
THERE IT IS!
THE CLUE!
HEY, IT LOOKS LIKE BLUE'S...
RUBBER DUCK.
RIGHT.
WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED--
OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK.
OKAY. SO...
A DUCK.
THERE'S THE HEAD.
THE BILL.
TWO DOTS FOR THE EYES.
THE BODY.
AND THE DUCK'S WING.
WE HAVE A DUCK.
SO, WHAT WAS OUR FIRST CLUE?
A DUCK.
OH, YEAH, RIGHT, A DUCK.
AND NOW WE HAVE A DUCK.
AND...
SO WE HAVE A DUCK AND A DUCK?
HMM.
WELL, WHAT GAME
COULD BLUE WANT TO PLAY NEXT
WITH A DUCK AND A DUCK?
I THINK WE NEED TO...
FIND ONE MORE CLUE!
YEAH. WE NEED TO FIND
OUR LAST BLUE'S CLUE.
COME ON.
♪ BLUE
BLUE.
WE FOUND OUR SECOND CLUE.
HI, STEVE.
HI, TICKITY.
HAVE YOU SEEN BLUE?
I THINK SHE'S
HIDING OVER THERE.
OH.
THANKS, TICKITY.
BLUE.
WHERE ARE YOU?
DO YOU SEE BLUE?
:
I SEE HER.
OH.
OH, YOU DO SEE HER.
WHERE?
AHA!
OH!
BLUE, I...
♪ MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME,
MAIL TIME! ♪
♪ MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME!
THE MAIL'S HERE.
♪ HERE'S THE MAIL,
IT NEVER FAILS ♪
♪ IT MAKES ME WANT
TO WAG MY TAIL ♪
♪ WHEN IT COMES,
I WANT TO WAIL, "MAIL!" ♪
MAIL'S HERE.
MAIL'S IN.
HI, STEVE.
GOT A RIDDLE FOR YOU.
READY?
YEAH.
SOMEONE BRINGS ME THROUGH
SNOW, SLEET AND ICE.
WHEN YOU OPEN ME UP,
FRIENDS SAY SOMETHING NICE.
WHAT AM I?
SOMEONE BRINGS ME...
WHEN YOU OPEN ME UP...
HMM.
DO YOU KNOW THE ANSWER
TO MAILBOX'S RIDDLE?
A LETTER!
ISN'T THAT GOOD?
THAT'S PRETTY CLEVER, MAILBOX.
A LETTER.
HERE IT IS.
THANK YOU.
WE JUST GOT A LETTER.
♪ WE JUST GOT A LETTER
♪ WONDER WHO IT'S FROM?
HI.
HI, STEVE.
WE'RE MAKING OUR OWN PUZZLES.
I'M CUTTING MY PAPER UP
INTO BIG PIECES.
NOW I'LL SCRAMBLE THEM UP.
NO, NOT THERE.
HERE IT IS.
I PUT EVERYTHING
TOGETHER.
A HOUSE.
YOU WANT TO TRADE?
BYE.
WOW.
MAKING YOUR OWN PUZZLES.
THAT'S BRILLIANT.
WHAT WAS THAT?
DID YOU SEE
THAT, BLUE?
WHERE DID THIS COME FROM?
FROM ME, FROM ME.
A GINGERBREAD BOY.
COOL.
LET'S SEE WHAT IT SAYS.
OH, LOOK.
I THINK IT'S DIRECTIONS TO
GINGERBREAD BOY'S HOUSE.
HMM.
CAN YOU HELP ME
READ THIS?
I THINK WE NEED TO GO UP
A, A... WHAT'S THIS?
MOUNTAIN.
OH, RIGHT, RIGHT.
UP A MOUNTAIN AND OVER
A, A... WHAT'S THIS?
BRIDGE.
RIGHT.
SO WE GO UP A MOUNTAIN
AND OVER A BRIDGE
AND THEN, IN BETWEEN
THESE HERE...
WHAT ARE THESE?
APPLE TREES.
OH, RIGHT.
RED AND GREEN
APPLE TREES.
OKAY, SO WE GO UP A MOUNTAIN
OVER A BRIDGE, AND IN BETWEEN
RED AND GREEN APPLE TREES.
YOU KNOW, THIS WOULD BE
A LOT EASIER TO REMEMBER
IF WE SING IT.
SO, HOW ABOUT, UH...
♪ UP A MOUNTAIN
AND OVER A BRIDGE ♪
♪ AND IN BETWEEN
THE RED AND GREEN ♪
♪ APPLE TREES.
THERE GOES BLUE.
LET'S GO, TOO.
WOW! GINGERBREAD BOY
LIVES HERE?
COOL.
UH-OH.
OH, NO.
YUP.
I FORGOT GINGERBREAD
BOY'S LETTER.
HOW ARE WE GOING TO
GET TO HIS HOUSE NOW?
OH YEAH, RIGHT,
BLUE, THAT SONG.
THAT'LL HELP
US REMEMBER.
WHICH WAY SHOULD
WE GO FIRST?
OKAY, SO, WE NEED
TO GO UP A, A...
UP A LAKE?
NO.
YOU CAN'T GO UP A LAKE.
THAT'S SILLY.
HMM.
UP A, A...
MOUNTAIN.
OH, RIGHT.
I REMEMBER NOW, UP A MOUNTAIN.
♪ UP A MOUNTAIN...
OKAY, SO WE WENT
NOW WHERE?
DO YOU REMEMBER WHICH
WAY WE GO NEXT?
♪ UP A MOUNTAIN AND OVER A...
♪ OVER A...
WHAT?
BRIDGE.
OH, RIGHT, I REMEMBER.
♪ UP A MOUNTAIN
AND OVER A BRIDGE ♪
GOOD WORK.
♪ UP THE MOUNTAIN
AND OVER A BRIDGE ♪
♪ AND IN BETWEEN
♪ IN BETWEEN, IN BETWEEN...
DO YOU REMEMBER WHAT
THE HOUSE WAS IN BETWEEN?
THE RED AND GREEN APPLE TREES.
OH, RIGHT.
THE RED AND GREEN
APPLE TREES.
THANKS.
GREAT.
WE'RE HERE.
YOU FOUND MY HOUSE.
OH, WELL...
IT WAS EASY.
HEY, LET'S SING IT
ALL TOGETHER.
♪ UP A MOUNTAIN
AND OVER A BRIDGE ♪
♪ AND IN BETWEEN
THE RED AND GREEN ♪
♪ APPLE TREES.
HEY, THAT WAS GREAT,
GINGERBREAD BOY.
YOU AREN'T DONE YET.
THERE'S STILL ONE MORE
THING TO FIND.
ONE MORE THING?
YOU WILL HELP
ME, RIGHT?
THERE'S A LOT OF
PLACES TO LOOK HERE.
OKAY, GINGERBREAD BOY,
ARE WE HOT OR COLD?
FAR AWAY!
YOU'RE COLD!
FREEZING COLD, STEVE!
OKAY, HOW ABOUT NOW?
AM I HOT OR COLD?
HOT.
GETTING HOTTER.
HERE?
AM I HOT OR COLD?
OKAY... UH, HERE.
HOT.
WHAT WAS THAT?
A CLUE!
IT'S A CLUE!
IT'S A CLUE
ON THIS, THIS...
GOOSE.
YEAH.
HEY, YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED,
OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK.NOTEBOOK.
OKAY.
START AT THE TOP,
DRAW A LONG NECK.
AROUND THE OTHER SIDE.
THERE'S THE GOOSE'S BILL.
TWO EYES AND A WING.
A GOOSE.
A GOOSE, RIGHT.
HMM.
WELL, WE HAVE
ALL THREE CLUES.
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT THIS MEANS?
WE'RE READY FOR OUR...
Both:
THINKING CHAIR.
YEAH, RIGHT.
COME ON.
OKAY, BLUE.
NOW THAT WE'RE IN OUR
THINKING CHAIR
LET'S THINK.
OKAY, SO...
WE'RE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT GAME
BLUE WANTS TO PLAY NEXT.
AND OUR CLUES ARE A DUCK...
A DUCK...
AND... A GOOSE.
OKAY.
SO, WHAT GAME COULD
BLUE WANT TO PLAY NEXT
WITH A GOOSE, A DUCK
AND ANOTHER DUCK?
HMM.
A DUCK, A DUCK, AND A GOOSE.
OOH, OOH, COULD IT BE THE
THE DUCKITY DUCK-DUCK
WITH A GOOSE GAME?
NO!
WELL, WHAT GAME COULD
BLUE WANT TO PLAY NEXT
WITH A DUCK, A DUCK,
AND A GOOSE?
DUCK, DUCK, GOOSE.
OH, YEAH, THAT'S IT!
THAT'S BRILLIANT!
DUCK, DUCK, GOOSE.
BLUE WANTS TO PLAY
OH, YEAH, BECAUSE...
WE JUST FIGURED
OUT BLUE'S CLUES!
♪ WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ BECAUSE WE'RE REALLY SMART.
BLUE, NOW THAT
WE FIGURED OUT
WHAT YOU WANT
TO PLAY NEXT
LET'S GO PLAY...
DUCK, DUCK, GOOSE RIGHT NOW.
OKAY, BLUE, ARE YOU READY TO
PLAY DUCK, DUCK, GOOSE?
HEY, IT'S SHOVEL
AND PAIL.
HI, GUYS.
REMEMBER THE GAME
YOU PLAYED WITH THEM?
A PUZZLE GAME!
RIGHT.
WHOA!
HEY, THAT SOUNDS
LIKE OUR FRIEND...
SLIPPERY.
WHOA!
CAREFUL.
OOH, AND...
TICKITY.
♪ UP A MOUNTAIN,
AND OVER A BRIDGE... ♪
HEY, DO YOU REMEMBER WHERE
GINGERBREAD BOY LIVES?
♪ IN BETWEEN
THE RED AND GREEN ♪
♪ APPLE TREES.
♪ APPLE TREES!
THAT WAS GOOD.
OKAY, BLUE, LET'S ALL
PLAY DUCK, DUCK, GOOSE.
WHOA!
WHEW!
OOH, HEY, COME ON.
HEY, THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR ALL YOUR HELP TODAY.
♪ NOW IT'S TIME FOR SO LONG
♪ BUT WE'LL SING
JUST ONE MORE SONG ♪
♪ THANKS FOR DOING YOUR PART
♪ YOU SURE ARE SMART
♪ YOU KNOW, WITH ME AND YOU
♪ AND MY DOG, BLUE
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING
♪ THAT WE WANT TO DO.
BYE-BYE.
SEE YOU LATER. BYE.
COME AGAIN.
BYE-BYE.
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING.♪