HI, OUT THERE!
IT'S ME, STEVE.
HAVE YOU SEEN BLUE, MY PUPPY?
THERE SHE IS!
COME ON IN.
HI.
HOW ARE YOU?
HEY... COME AND JOIN US FOR...
♪ SONG TIME, LA, LA, LA
WHAT'S GOING
ON HERE?
WHO'S DOING THAT?
RIGHT THERE.
IT'S BLUE.
BLUE?
HA!
THAT'S PRETTY
FUNNY, BLUE.
SO, WHAT SONG DO
YOU WANT TO SING?
HOW ABOUT, UM... OOH!
♪ SHE'LL BE COMING 'ROUND
THE MOUNTAIN WHEN SHE COMES ♪
THE MOUNTAIN WHEN SHE... ♪
NO?
WELL, WHAT SONG
DO YOU WANT TO SING?
OH.
OKAY.
WE'LL PLAY
"BLUE'S CLUES."
THAT'S A GREAT IDEA.
I LOVE "BLUE'S CLUES."
♪ WE ARE GONNA PLAY
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ 'CAUSE THAT'S A REALLY
GREAT GAME, YEAH! ♪
WE'LL PLAY BLUE'S CLUES
TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT SONG BLUE
WANTS TO SING.
HMM, BUT I GUESS WE BETTER
CLEAN THIS UP FIRST.
HEY, REMEMBER, BLUE'S PAW PRINTS
WILL BE ON THE CLUES:
BLUE'S CLUES.
YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED
FOR BLUE'S CLUES, OUR...
NOTEBOOK!
RIGHT, OUR NOTEBOOK!
COME ON.
BLUE'S CLUES,
I'M SO EXCITED!
OOH, HERE IT IS.
HEY, YOU KNOW, I THINK
I'M GOING TO NEED YOUR HELP
TO FIGURE OUT WHAT SONG
BLUE WANTS TO SING.
WILL YOU HELP ME?
OH, YOU WILL! GREAT!
♪ WE GOT TO FIND THE PAW PRINT,
THAT'S THE FIRST CLUE ♪
♪ WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND NOW WHAT DO WE DO? ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE SECOND CLUE ♪
♪ WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
NOW WHAT DO WE DO? ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE THIRD CLUE ♪
♪ PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND, WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WELL, WE SIT DOWN
IN OUR THINKING CHAIR ♪
♪ AND THINK, THINK, THINK
♪ 'CAUSE WHEN WE USE OUR MINDS,
TAKE A STEP AT A TIME ♪
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING...
♪ THAT WE WANT TO DO.
COME ON.
WHAT WAS THAT?
A CLUE, A CLUE.
A CLUE.
OH.
OH, A CLUE?
WHERE?
A CLUE!
IT'S A CLUE.
I STEPPED
ON THE CLUE!
♪ WE JUST FOUND
OUR FIRST CLUE... ♪
BUT WHAT IS IT?
A DUCK.
WELL, WE FOUND
OUR VERY FIRST CLUE.
WE FOUND OUR FIRST CLUE!
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
NOTEBOOK.
YES.
WE NEED OUR HANDY DANDY...
NOTEBOOK.
OKAY.
CLUE NUMBER ONE.
A DUCK.
A CIRCLE FOR THE HEAD.
DUCK'S BILL.
EYES.
THE BODY.
AND A LITTLE WING.
AND WE HAVE... A DUCK.
HMM.
SO, WHAT SONG COULD BLUE
WANT TO SING WITH A DUCK?
WELL, I THINK WE NEED
TO LOOK FOR MORE CLUES.
DON'T YOU?
YEAH! COME ON.
HAH!
HEY.
HEY, WE COULD USE THESE
INSTRUMENTS FOR SONG TIME!
HIT IT, BLUE.
HEY.
THAT'S NOT THE
RIGHT SOUND.
THEY MUST HAVE GOTTEN
MIXED UP IN THE FALL.
WELL, THESE ARE...
MARACAS.
MARACAS MAKE A...
CHU-KA, CHU-KA, CHU-KA-SHOO
SOUND, RIGHT?
THIS ISN'T A CHU-KA,
CHU-KA, CHU-KA SOUND.
WHAT SOUND IS IT?
YEAH, BLUE.
LET'S LISTEN CLOSE
AND SEE IF WE
CAN FIGURE OUT
WHAT INSTRUMENT REALLY
MAKES THIS SOUND.
WILL YOU HELP US?
YOU WILL?
OH, GOOD.
OKAY.
IS IT THE SOUND
OF A TRUMPET?
NO.
IS IT THE SOUND...
OF A FLUTE?
NO.
IS IT THE SOUND OF DRUMS?
YEAH.
OH.
THE MIXED-UP MARACAS ARE
MAKING THE SOUND OF DRUMS.
GOOD LISTENING.
THE TRUMPET'S ALL
MIXED UP, TOO.
WELL, WE KNOW WHAT TO DO.
TRY TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT INSTRUMENT
REALLY MAKES THIS SOUND.
SO... LET'S GET
THOSE EARS READY.
AND TRY TO FIGURE THIS OUT.
IS IT A RECORDER?
NO.
IS IT A CLARINET?
IS IT A FLUTE?
YEAH!
OH.
YEAH.
IT IS THE SOUND
OF A FLUTE.
GOOD WORK WITH
THOSE EARS.
HEY, THOSE INSTRUMENTS REALLY
GOT MIXED UP WHEN THEY FELL.
THANKS FOR HELPING US.
ARE YOU READY, BLUE?
AND A-ONE, AND A-TWO,
AND YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO.
HEY! WHAT INSTRUMENT
IS THAT?
THE TELEPHONE.
WHAT, THE PHONE
INSTRUMENT?
OH. THE TELEPHONE,
RIGHT.
OH, THE TELEPHONE.
HELLO.
Hi, Steve.
We just made up a song.
Can you sing it?
CAN I SING IT?
WELL, I... YOU WILL
HELP ME, RIGHT?
OKAY, GOOD.
SURE. LET'S HEAR IT.
Our song goes like this.
♪ Boom ba cha-cha-la-la,
boom, boom, bop. ♪
BOOM, BOOM... BOOM... BOO.
NO.
WOW.
WILL YOU HELP ME WITH THIS?
YEAH.
THINK I'M GOING TO NEED IT.
♪ Boom ba cha-cha-la-la,
boom, boom, bop. ♪
♪ BOOM BA CHA-CHA-LA-LA...
♪ Boom ba cha-cha-la-la,
boom boom bop ♪
♪ BOOM BA CHA-CHA-LA-LA,
BOOM, BOOM, BOP. ♪
That's great.
♪ BOOM BA CHA-CHA-LA-LA,
BOOM, BOOM, BOP. ♪
Bye!
♪ BOOM BA CHA-CHA-LA-LA,
BYE, BYE, BYE. ♪
BOOM, BOOM, BOP. ♪
LET'S DO IT AGAIN.
♪ BOOM BA CHA-CHA-LA-LA,
BOOM, BOOM, BOP. ♪
WHO'S THAT SINGING?♪ BOOM BA CHA-CHA-LA-LA♪
IS THAT YOU?♪ BOOM, BOOM, BOP.♪
All:
♪ BOOM BA CHA-CHA-LA-LA,
BOOM, BOOM, BOP ♪
FELT FRIENDS...
WERE YOU SINGING
WITH US?
Both:
YEAH.
♪ BOOM BA CHA-CHA-LA-LA,
BOOM, BOOM, BOP ♪
♪ BOOM BA CHA-CHA-LA-LA
♪ BOOM, BOOM, BOP HERE WE GO.
♪ BOOM BA CHA-CHA-LA-LA,
BOOM, BOOM, BOP ♪
THAT WAS REALLY GOOD.
♪ MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME,
MAIL TIME! ♪
♪ MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME!
THE MAIL'S HERE!
♪ HERE'S THE MAIL,
IT NEVER FAILS ♪
♪ IT MAKES ME WANT
TO WAG MY TAIL ♪
♪ WHEN IT COMES,
I WANT TO WAIL, "MAIL!" ♪
♪ BOOM BA CHA-CHA-LA-LA,
BOOM, BOOM, BOP. ♪
HEY, MAILBOX.
YOU'RE PRETTY GOOD AT THAT.
THANKS.
♪ YOU'RE WELCOME.
WE JUST GOT A LETTER.
♪ WE JUST GOT A LETTER
♪ WONDER WHO IT'S FROM?
HI, STEVE.
HI, BLUE.
IT'S ME, DAVID.
WE'RE MAKING MARACAS.
I PUT MY BEANS IN MY MARACA.
I DECORATE IT.
BYE!
BYE.
HEY, BLUE,
ALL THIS GREAT MUSIC
♪ MAKES ME WANT TO SING
AFTER ALL, IT'S ALMOST...
♪ SONG TIME,
LA, LA, LA ♪
♪ BAMP, DO-DAM, DO DO DO
DAMPEY DO... ♪
HEY, WE STILL HAVE TWO MORE
CLUES LEFT TO FIND.
WOW.
DID YOU SEE THAT?
BLUE JUST WENT RIGHT INTO
THE PICTURE OF THAT FARM!
HEY, DO YOU THINK
WE SHOULD GO, TOO
TO SEE WHAT BLUE'S UP TO?
YEAH.
♪ BLUE SKIDDOO, WE CAN, TOO.
WHAT WAS THAT?
A CLUE.
OH! A CLUE!
THERE'S A CLUE, ON
THIS, THIS... WHAT IS THIS?
A BARN!
RIGHT, THE BARN!
HEY, HEY.
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
NOTEBOOK.
RIGHT, OUR NOTEBOOK.
WE NEED OUR HANDY-DANDY
NOTEBOOK.
OKAY.
CLUE NUMBER TWO, A BARN.
TRIANGLE AND A RECTANGLE
FOR THE ROOF.
A COUPLE OF LINES FOR THE BARN.
RECTANGLE DOOR.
AND THE SILO.
WE HAVE A BARN.
SO OUR FIRST CLUE WAS A...
DUCK.
AND NOW OUR
SECOND CLUE IS A BARN.
HMM...
SO WHAT SONG COULD BLUE
WANT TO SING WITH A DUCK
AND A BARN?
THINK WE NEED TO FIND
ONE MORE OF BLUE'S CLU...
DID YOU HEAR THAT?
OH.
OH, IT'S THAT LITTLE CHICK.
WE ALMOST FORGOT ABOUT HER.
COME ON.
♪ HELLO, STEVE♪
♪ HELLO, CHICKS
WHAT ARE YOU UP TO?
WE'RE PUTTING TOGETHER
A SONG SHOW.
WILL YOU HELP US?
WE'VE JUST BEEN
SINGING ALL DAY!
YOU WILL HELP US,
WON'T YOU?
OUR SONG TODAY IS
"ROW, ROW, ROW."
♪ ROW, ROW, ROW YOUR...
OH, NO.
WE'RE MISSING THE LAST
PART OF THIS LINE.
OH, OH.
WELL, I THINK THIS
IS WHERE WE CAN HELP.
♪ ROW, ROW, ROW YOUR...
♪ CAR!
Steve:
IS THAT THE WAY
IT GOES?
NO.
♪ ROW, ROW, ROW YOUR...
♪ BICYCLE
HOW ABOUT THAT CHICK?
DOES THAT SOUND LIKE
THE REST OF THE SONG?
NO.
♪ ROW, ROW, ROW YOUR
♪ BOAT
IS THAT THE
WAY IT GOES?
YEAH!
YES, GREAT!
YOU FINISHED
THE FIRST LINE!
THANK YOU.
♪ ROW, ROW,
ROW YOUR BOAT... ♪
♪ GENTLY DOWN THE...
OH, NO.
WE'RE MISSING
ANOTHER PART.
CAN YOU HELP US FIGURE
OUT WHAT COMES NEXT?
♪ STREAM
♪ RIVER
WHICH IS THE LAST
PART OF THAT LINE?
THAT ONE, THAT ONE.
ME, RIGHT?
ME, YEAH.
♪ STREAM
THERE YOU GO,
CHICK CHORUS.
YEAH.
ROW, ROW, ROW
♪ YOUR BOAT
♪ GENTLY DOWN THE
♪ STREAM
♪ MERRILY, MERRILY,
MERRILY, MERRILY ♪
UH-OH.
MISSING ANOTHER
PART, HUH?
WILL YOU HELP US?
YOU READY TO HELP?
AGAIN?
♪ LIFE IS
BUT A DREAM. ♪
BUT A
DREAM. ♪
♪ LIFE IS BUT
A DREAM. ♪
WHICH CHICK IS SINGING
THE RIGHT ENDING?
THAT ONE.
YES.
ME, ME.
YES, ME.
♪ LIFE IS BUT
A DREAM. ♪
I THINK YOUR CHORUS
IS COMPLETE.
OH, OH.
WHAT A GREAT
IDEA, BLUE.
UM... WOULD, WOULD
YOU PUT ON
YOUR SONG SHOW FOR US?
Chicks:
OKAY, SING IT WITH US.
♪ ROW, ROW, ROW YOUR BOAT ♪
♪ GENTLY DOWN THE STREAM♪
♪ MERRILY, MERRILY,
MERRILY, MERRILY♪
♪ LIFE IS BUT A DREAM♪
THAT WAS GREAT!
OH, YEAH.
RIGHT, BLUE.
WE STILL GOT TO GET
HOME FOR OUR OWN...
♪ SONG TIME, LA, LA, LA
WHAT IS THAT MUSIC?
I THINK IT'S A...
PIANO.
WHERE IS IT COMING FROM?
A CLUE.
NO, I, I THINK
IT'S A PIANO.
OH.
OH, A CLUE!
ONE OF BLUE'S CLUES?
WHERE? WHERE IS THE CLUE?
RIGHT THERE!
OH.
♪ OH, OH, OH!
IT'S A CLUE!
HEY.
COOL.
OH!
OH, SO OUR CLUE
IS THIS TUNE.
SO, WHAT SONG COULD BLUE WANT
TO SING TO THIS TUNE?
HEY, WE NEED OUR HANDY-DANDY,
SUPERY-DUPERY
NOTEBOOK.
OKAY.
SO... A TUNE.
A BIG RECTANGLE FOR THE PIANO.
SOME KEYS.
BIG, BLACK LINES...
FOR THE BLACK KEYS.
AND WE HAVE OUR TUNE.
HEY, WE HAVE ALL
THREE BLUE'S CLUES!
YOU KNOW WHAT THIS MEANS?
WE ARE READY FOR OUR...
THINKING CHAIR.
OKAY.
NOW THAT WE'RE IN OUR...
THINKING CHAIR, LET'S THINK.
ALL RIGHT, NOW...
WE'RE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT SONG BLUE WANTS TO SING.
WHAT ARE OUR CLUES?
WE HAVE A DUCK.
WE HAVE A BARN.
AND WE HAVE A TUNE.
SO, SO WHAT SONG COULD BLUE
WANT TO SING WITH A DUCK, A
BARN, AND SOUNDS LIKE THIS...
HMM...
WELL... WHAT SONG IS
ABOUT A DUCK AND A BARN?
OH, OH.
WAIT, WAIT.
IS IT, IS IT...
♪ RUBBER DUCKY HAD A BARN
♪ E-I-E-I-O
NO.
WHAT WAS THAT?
WHO HAD A FARM?
"OLD MACDONALD HAD A FARM."
YES!
THAT'S IT!
"OLD MACDONALD HAD A FARM."
E-I-E-I-O!
WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES.
♪ WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ BECAUSE WE'RE REALLY SMART!
BLUE WANTS TO SING
"OLD MACDONALD HAD A FARM."
THE DUCK CLUE WAS
FOR THE PART...
WITH A QUACK, QUACK HERE.
THE BARN IS PART OF OLD
MACDONALD'S FARM.
AND THE TUNE IS THE
MELODY OF THE SONG.
♪ OLD MACDONALD HAD A FARM
♪ E-I-E-I-O.
HEY, BLUE, GET READY FOR...
♪ SONG TIME, LA, LA, LA.
OH.
GOT TO GET MY GUITAR.
OKAY, BLUE.
"OLD MACDONALD HAD A FARM."
RIGHT?
OH, LOOK WHO'S HERE
FOR SONG TIME.
IT'S THE INSTRUMENTS.
REMEMBER HOW WE HELPED THEM?
Felt People:
AND REMEMBER THE MADE-UP SONG?
♪ BOOM BA CHA-CHA-LA-LA
♪ BOOM, BOOM, BOP.
OH, AND LOOK.
IT'S THE CHICKS.
REMEMBER THE SONG
WE HELPED THEM WITH?
All:
♪ ROW, ROW, ROW YOUR BOAT...
OKAY, EVERYBODY.
READY FOR SONG TIME.
"OLD MACDONALD
HAD A FARM."
♪ OLD MACDONALD
HAD A FARM ♪
♪ E-I-E-I-O♪
♪ AND ON HIS FARM
HE HAD A... ♪
DUCK!
♪ E-I-E-I-O♪
WITH A...
QUACK, QUACK
♪ HERE, AND A
QUACK, QUACK THERE ♪
♪ HERE A QUACK, THERE
A QUACK, EVERYWHERE A... ♪
QUACK, QUACK.
♪ OLD MACDONALD
HAD A FARM ♪
♪ E-I-E-I-O.♪
HEY, THAT WAS GREAT.
OH, YEAH.
YOU'RE RIGHT, BLUE.
NOW IT'S TIME FOR ME
TO PICK A SONG.
♪ NOW IT'S TIME FOR SO LONG
♪ BUT WE'LL SING
JUST ONE MORE SONG ♪
♪ THANKS FOR DOING YOUR PART
♪ YOU SURE ARE SMART
♪ YOU KNOW, WITH ME AND YOU
♪ AND MY DOG, BLUE
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING
♪ THAT WE WANT TO DO
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING♪
♪ THAT WE WANT TO DO.♪