HI, OUT THERE!
IT'S ME, STEVE.
HAVE YOU SEEN BLUE, MY PUPPY?
THERE SHE IS!
COME ON IN.
HI. COME ON IN.
WE'RE JUST ABOUT TO GO
OUTSIDE AND... PLAY.
HEY.
HAVE YOU GROWN...
SINCE I SAW YOU LAST?
OH, YEAH. YEP.
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU DO, YOU LOOK
A LITTLE BIT TALLER.
BLUE.
UH-HUH.
THERE YOU ARE, BLUE.
BLUE?
WHAT IS SHE DOING?
OH, HEY.
HEY.
YOU KNOW, BLUE...
YOU DO LOOK LIKE
YOU'VE GROWN, TOO.
LET'S SEE.
OH, YEAH.
YEP.
LOOK AT THAT.
WOW!
YOU'VE GROWN THIS MUCH,
A WHOLE...
OH, YEAH, BLUE.
WE WERE GOING
TO GO OUTSIDE AND PLAY.
WHAT DO YOU WANT
TO PLAY? BALL?
NO?
WELL, WHAT DO YOU WANT
TO DO OUTSIDE TODAY?
OH, OKAY.
WE'LL PLAY "BLUE'S CLUES"
TO FIGURE IT OUT.
I LOVE "BLUE'S CLUES."
* WE ARE GONNA PLAY
BLUE'S CLUES *
* 'CAUSE IT'S A REALLY
GREAT GAME, YEAH! *
"BLUE'S CLUES" WILL TELL US WHAT
BLUE WANTS TO DO OUTSIDE TODAY.
SO REMEMBER, BLUE'S PAW PRINT
WILL BE ON THE CLUES:
BLUE'S CLUES.
YOU, UH, YOU THOUGHT
I WAS GOING TO FORGET ABOUT
THAT PAW PRINT, DIDN'T YOU?
NOPE.
LET'S CLEAN IT UP WITH THIS.
JUST A LITTLE WATER
WILL CLEAN THIS RIGHT... UP.
OKAY.
HEY, YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED
FOR BLUE'S CLUES, OUR...
NOTEBOOK!
NOTEBOOK, RIGHT.
COME ON.
BLUE'S CLUES,
I'M SO EXCITED.
OOH.
HERE IT IS.
YOU KNOW, I CAN TELL
I'M REALLY GOING
TO NEED YOUR HELP
FIGURING OUT WHAT BLUE
WANTS TO DO OUTSIDE TODAY.
WILL YOU HELP ME?
OH, YOU WILL? GREAT.
* WE GOT TO FIND THE PAW PRINT,
THAT'S THE FIRST CLUE *
* WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND NOW WHAT DO WE DO? *
* BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
* BLUE'S CLUES! *
* WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE SECOND CLUE *
* WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
NOW WHAT DO WE DO? *
* BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
* BLUE'S CLUES! *
* WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE THIRD CLUE *
* PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND, WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO *
* BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
* BLUE'S CLUES! *
* WELL, WE SIT DOWN
IN OUR THINKING CHAIR *
* AND THINK, THINK, THINK
* 'CAUSE WHEN WE USE OUR MINDS,
TAKE A STEP AT A TIME *
* WE CAN DO ANYTHING...
* THAT WE WANT TO DO.
OKAY.
WE'RE ALL READY TO GROW.
I MEAN... GO.
HMM.
WHICH WAY DID BLUE GROW?
I MEAN... GO.
SHE WENT THAT WAY.
OH, THIS WAY.
OKAY.
* WE ARE LOOKING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES *
* I WONDER WHERE THEY ARE.
A CLUE, A CLUE!
DID YOU SEE A CLUE?
WHERE?
WHERE'S THE CLUE?
BEHIND YOU.
OH.
THE CLUE!
YOU KNOW HOW YOU CAN
TELL IT'S A CLUE?
BECAUSE IT HAS BLUE'S
PAW PRINT ON IT.
WE JUST FOUND
OUR FIRST CLUE.
AND IT'S DIRT!
DIRT?
OUR FIRST CLUE IS DIRT?
WHAT...
WELL, NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
NOTEBOOK!
RIGHT, PUT IT
IN OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK.
OKAY, SO, A BIG CLUMP OF...
DIRT.
IT HAS SOME CURVY LINES
AT THE TOP.
A STRAIGHT LINE ON THE BOTTOM.
AND WE HAVE OUR... DIRT.
SO WHAT COULD BLUE WANT TO DO
OUTSIDE TODAY... WITH DIRT?
HMM...
OH, YOU, YOU THINK WE NEED
TO LOOK FOR MORE CLUES?
YEAH, I...
Mr. Salt:
I THINK YOU GROW AND...
Mrs. Pepper:
SQUEEZE OR SOMETHING.
GROW?
LET'S GO SEE WHAT'S GROWING ON.
OH, I MEAN...
I MEAN GOING ON.
OH, DEAR.
FIRST YOU
GROW THE...
SQUEEZE
OR SOMETHING.
HI, MR. SALT
AND MRS. PEPPER.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
OH!
Both:
HI, STEVE.
WE ARE TRYING
TO MAKE ORANGE JUICE.
WILL YOU HELP?
WILL YOU HELP, TOO?
GREAT.
THEN WE'LL LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
Both:
WHERE DOES ORANGE
JUICE COME FROM?
WELL...
THAT'S A
GOOD QUESTION.
UM, WHERE DOES ORANGE
JUICE COME FROM?
WELL, IT, IT COMES
FROM ORANGES, RIGHT.
AND... ORANGES
GROW ON...
TREES.
TREES. RIGHT.
AND, UH, ORANGE
TREES GROW FROM...
SEEDS.
AH, VOILA!
Both:
ORANGE TREES GROW FROM SEEDS.
OH.
A SEED IS PLANTED.
AND THEN AN ORANGE
TREE GROWS.
WELL... HOW DO WE
GET ORANGE JUICE?
PICK THE ORANGE.
OH, AN ORANGE GETS PICKED
FROM THE TREE.
HUH.
SO, WHERE DOES
ORANGE JUICE COME FROM?
SQUEEZE THE ORANGE.
Steve:
AN ORANGE IS SQUEEZED...
AND THE JUICE IS
POURED INTO A CUP.
WOW.
Both:
THAT'S WHERE ORANGE
JUICE COMES FROM.
OKAY, SO LET ME
GET THIS STRAIGHT.
ORANGE JUICE COMES
FROM AN ORANGE TREE SEED
THAT IS PLANTED.
AND THEN, THE SEED GROWS
INTO A FULL-GROWN ORANGE TREE.
AND THEN, AN ORANGE
IS PICKED FROM THE TREE.
AND THE JUICE IS
SQUEEZED INTO A CUP.
GOOD JOB.
UH...
YOU KNOW...
YOU CAN GET
ORANGE JUICE
FROM A CARTON
Both:
OUT OF THE FRIDGE!
OH, THAT'S BLUE.
WE BETTER GO.
BYE, MR. SALT
AND MRS. PEPPER.
* WE ARE LOOKING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES *
* WE ARE LOOKING FOR
BLUE'S CLUES... *
A CLUE!
YEP, THE SKY IS BLUE.
NO, A CLUE!
OH, A CLUE.
YOU DO SEE A CLUE.
REALLY?
WELL, WHERE IS IT?
WHERE'S THE CLUE?
RIGHT THERE.
I DON'T SEE ANYTHING.
I...
THE CLUE!
IT'S, IT'S A, A,
A WATERING CAN.
YEAH!
WELL, THIS WATERING CAN
IS OUR SECOND CLUE.
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
THE NOTEBOOK.
RIGHT, PUT IT IN OUR...
NOTEBOOK.
OKAY, SO, A WATERING CAN HAS...
HERE'S A RECTANGLE FOR THE BODY.
THEN THE SPOUT.
OH YEAH, THE SPRINKLER ON THE
TOP THAT HAS SOME DOTS.
AND THE HANDLE.
THERE.
A WATERING CAN.
HMM.
SO, WE'RE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT BLUE WANTS
TO DO OUTSIDE TODAY.
AND OUR FIRST CLUE WAS, WAS...
DIRT.
DIRT, RIGHT.
HOW COULD I FORGET?
NOW, OUR SECOND CLUE
IS A WATERING CAN.
HMM.
WHAT COULD BLUE WANT TO DO
WITH DIRT AND A WATERING CAN?
OOH, MAYBE, MAYBE...
MAYBE WE SHOULD LOOK
FOR ONE MORE CLUE.
YEAH.
I THINK THIS ONE
IS LONGER.
DEFINITELY.
COME ON.
I'M NOT SURE,
SHOVEL.
I THINK THIS
ONE IS LONGER.
LOOK, THERE'S STEVE.
MAYBE HE
CAN HELP.
HEY, SHOVEL.
HI, PAIL.
HEY, BLUE.
WHAT ARE YOU
GUYS DOING?
SHH!
WE'RE INVESTIGATING.
INVAMAGESTIMIGATING?
UH-HUH.
WE WANT TO SEE
WHICH INCHWORM
IS LONGER.
SWEATER-VEST MAKING?
Both:
INVESTIGATING!
WANT TO HELP?
OH, YEAH. OKAY.
WILL YOU HELP, TOO?
GREAT.
THEN WE CAN GO
LOOK FOR MORE
BLUE'S CLUES.
COME ON.
I THINK THIS
ONE IS LONGER.
HMM.
CAN YOU TELL
WHICH INCHWORM
IS LONGER?
WHICH ONE?
THAT ONE.
SEE?
THE CURVED ONE
WAS REALLY LONGER.
YEAH.
IT KIND OF GREW.
HEY! NICE
INVESTIGATING.
NOW LET'S GO LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
WHOA, LOOK
AT THAT!
Pail:
THE INCHWORMS ARE
INVESTIGATING THOSE PUDDLES.
HEY, I THINK THAT PUDDLE
HAS MORE WATER.
NO.
MAYBE THIS ONE HAS
MORE WATER.
HEY, GUYS.
WHAT ARE YOU
INVESTIGATING NOW?
THESE PUDDLES.
WHICH ONE DO YOU THINK
HAS MORE WATER?
OOH.
HMM...
DO YOU KNOW?
WHICH PUDDLE
HAS MORE WATER?
THAT ONE.
BECAUSE OF THE STONE.
OH.
THE PUDDLE
WITH THE SMALLEST STONE
HAD THE MOST WATER.
WELL, THAT'S
JUST BRILLIANT
All:
INVESTIGATION.
WHOA!
LOOK AT THAT!
NOW WHICH ONE
HAS MORE WATER?
THE SAME ONE!
* MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME,
MAIL TIME! *
THE MAIL'S HERE!
LET'S GROW!
* MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME!
I MEAN GO.
* HERE'S THE MAIL,
IT NEVER FAILS *
* IT MAKES ME WANT
TO WAG MY TAIL *
* WHEN IT COMES,
I WANT TO WAIL, "MAIL!" *
MAIL'S IN.
COME AND GET IT.
HEY, MAILBOX.
HAVE YOU GROWN
SINCE YESTERDAY?
I THINK A
LITTLE BIT.
YEAH.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
WE JUST GOT A LETTER.
* WE JUST GOT A LETTER
* WONDER WHO IT'S FROM?
IT'S A LETTER
FROM OUR FRIENDS.
HI.
All:
HI, STEVE.
WE'RE AT THE FARM.
Girl:
WE LIKE TO SEE
THE ANIMALS GROW.
THE BABY COW'S GOING TO GROW
HORNS WHEN HE GETS BIG
LIKE HIS MOMMY.
THIS IS A BABY LAMB.
THE LITTLE PIGGY
NEEDS FOOD.
HE'S GOING TO BE THIS BIG.
Kid:
BABY DUCKS ARE GROWING, TOO.
QUACK, QUACK.
All:
BYE, STEVE!
BYE.
WOW.
ALL THOSE GROWING ANIMALS.
THAT'S PRETTY EXCITING,
DON'T YOU THINK?
HEY, WE STILL HAVE TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT BLUE WANTS TO DO
OUTSIDE TODAY.
SO WE OUGHT TO FIND
OUR LAST BLUE'S CLUE.
BLUE?
BLUE.
WHAT ARE YOU UP TO?
BLUE, STEVE, WE ARE
SO GLAD TO SEE YOU.
WILL YOU COME
HELP US?
OKAY, FELT FRIENDS.
WE'LL COME AND HELP YOU.
ARE YOU READY?
GREAT.
* BLUE SKIDDOO, WE CAN, TOO
HMM, IT'S NOT
THE VINE
IT'S THE...
UH...
HEY! UH, WHAT SEEMS
TO BE THE PROBLEM,
FELT FRIENDS?
WELL, WE'RE TRYING
TO FIGURE OUT
WHERE OUR FRUITS
AND VEGETABLES GROW.
OH.
OKAY, WELL, WE'RE
HERE TO HELP, RIGHT?
SO, SHOW US
WHAT YOU GOT.
OKAY, WHERE DO
ORANGES GROW?
CAN YOU SHOW US?
OH... OH, CAN YOU
HELP THE FELT FRIENDS?
CAN YOU SHOW THEM
WHERE ORANGES GROW?
TREES.
HEY, WOULD YOU
LOOK AT THAT!
WE KNEW THAT.
FROM MR. SALT
AND MRS. PEPPER,
REMEMBER?
Both:
YEAH!
ORANGES GROW ON TREES.
OKAY, HOW
ABOUT THIS?
YEAH, WHERE DO
POTATOES GROW?
WHERE DO
CAN YOU SHOW ME?
IN THE GROUND!
OH, POTATOES GROW
UNDERGROUND.
THAT'S WHY THEY ALWAYS
HAVE DIRT ON THEM.
Both:
UNDERGROUND, WOW!
HEY, LOOK
AT THAT.
OKAY, HOW
ABOUT THESE?
YEAH, WHERE DO
GRAPES GROW?
DO YOU SEE WHERE
ON VINES.
THE VINE!
GOOD JOB.
Both:
GRAPES GROW ON
VINES, YEAH!
* ORANGES GROW ON TREES,
ON TREES *
* ORANGES GROW ON TREES
* POTATOES GROW DOWN, DOWN,
IN THE GROUND *
* THEY GROW DOWN IN THE GROUND
* WE GRAPES, WE GROW
ON VINES, ON VINES *
* IN BUNCHES, WE GROW
* IN BIG, OLD BUNCHES ON VINES,
ON VINES, ON VINES... *
ONE MORE TIME.
* ORANGES GROW ON TREES,
ON TREES *
* ORANGES GROW ON TREES
* POTATOES GROW DOWN,
DOWN, IN THE GROUND *
* THEY GROW DOWN IN THE GROUND
* WE GRAPES, WE GROW
ON VINES, ON VINES *
* IN BUNCHES WE GROW
* IN BIG, OLD BUNCHES ON VINES,
ON VINES, ON VINES. *
NOW WE'LL HAVE GROWING
FRUITS AND VEGETABLES.
YEAH, AND SINGING
ONES, TOO.
Both:
THANKS FOR COMING
TO HELP US.
BYE.
HEY, BLUE.
BLUE?
A CLUE, A CLUE.
OH!
A CLUE!
DID YOU SEE A CLUE?
WHERE?
WHERE'S THE CLUE?
A CLUE, RIGHT BEHIND YOU.
OH!
THE CLUE!
IT'S OUR THIRD BLUE'S CLUE...
BLUE'S CLUE.
ONE OF... BLUE'S CLUES.
HEY, WE KNOW WHAT TO DO.
PUT IT IN OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK.
OKAY.
SO, WE HAVE... SEEDS.
SILLY LITTLE JUMPING SEEDS.
OKAY.
OKAY, AN OVAL SHAPE AND A LINE.
ANOTHER OVAL SHAPE AND A LINE.
AND A THIRD OVAL SHAPE
AND ANOTHER LINE.
AND WE HAVE... SEEDS.
OUR THIRD CLUE.
WE HAVE ALL THREE CLUES.
HEY, DO YOU KNOW
WHAT IT'S TIME FOR?
OUR...
THINKING CHAIR.
COME ON.
OKAY, BLUE.
NOW THAT WE'RE IN OUR...
THINKING CHAIR
LET'S THINK.
OKAY.
SO, WE'RE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT BLUE WANTS
TO DO OUTSIDE TODAY.
AND OUR CLUES ARE:
DIRT...
A WATERING CAN...
AND... OH, YEAH, SEEDS.
HMM.
DIRT, WATERING CAN, SEEDS.
OOH, OOH, MAYBE
MAYBE SHE WANTS TO PUT
THE SEEDS AND THE DIRT
IN THE WATERING CAN
AND MIX IT ALL UP.
NO.
MAYBE...
NOT.
WELL, WHAT COULD BLUE DO
WITH SEEDS,
WATERING CAN AND DIRT?
HMM...
PUT THE SEEDS IN THE DIRT
AND WATER.
AND THEN SHE CAN...
PLANT A GARDEN.
PLANT A GARDEN!
YES! THAT'S IT!
SHE CAN PLANT THE SEEDS
IN THE DIRT
AND WATER THEM
WITH THE WATERING CAN.
THAT'LL MAKE HER GARDEN GROW.
WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES.
* WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES *
* BECAUSE WE'RE REALLY SMART.
BLUE.
I'M GOING TO GET SOME SEEDS
AND OUR WATERING CAN.
LET'S GO OUTSIDE
AND PLANT A GARDEN.
* WE ARE GOING TO THE GARDEN
* WE ARE GOING
TO THE GARDEN... *
* NOW THAT I GOT
MY WATERING CAN. *
* WEE-BOP...
OKAY, BLUE.
WE'VE DUG A HOLE
IN THE DIRT.
HERE'S YOUR... SEED.
AND YOUR...
WATERING CAN.
NOW, IF WE
GIVE OUR SEED
PLENTY OF WATER
AND SUNSHINE...
IT'LL GROW UP
TO BE A BIG...
BEAUTIFUL BLUE
SUNFLOWER.
BUT THAT'S NOT TILL LATER.
OH.
OKAY, BLUE.
LET'S PLANT SOME MORE.
ANY ORANGE TREES GROWING?
OH, LOOK.
IT'S MR. SALT
AND MRS. PEPPER.
HEY, GUYS.
OH, AND IT'S
SHOVEL AND PAIL.
REMEMBER WHAT WE
DID WITH THEM?
INVESTIGATE.
AND OUR FELT FRIENDS.
OH, LOOK.
SUNFLOWERS GROW
IN THE GROUND.
IN THE
GROUND.
RIGHT.
WOW, WHAT A DAY.
THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR ALL YOUR HELP.
* NOW IT'S TIME FOR SO LONG
* BUT WE'LL SING
JUST ONE MORE SONG *
* THANKS FOR DOING YOUR PART
* YOU SURE ARE SMART
* YOU KNOW, WITH ME AND YOU
* AND MY DOG, BLUE
* WE CAN DO...
* ANYTHING
THAT WE WANT TO DO.
WOW.
BYE-BYE, SEE YOU LATER.