HI, OUT THERE!
IT'S ME, STEVE.
HAVE YOU SEEN BLUE, MY PUPPY?
THERE SHE IS!
COME ON IN.
HI.
WE'RE SO GLAD YOU'RE HERE.
IT'S ALMOST SNACK TIME.
BLUE? BLUE?
DID YOU SEE BLUE?
RIGHT THERE.
UNDER THE TABLE.
OH.
HA!
BLUE, WHAT ARE YOU
UP TO?
COME ON, IT'S
JUST ABOUT SNACK TIME
AND WE'RE HAVING
GRAHAM CRACKERS.
I HAVE EVERYTHING
READY FOR SNACK.
WE HAVE GRAHAM CRACKERS.
WE HAVE PLATES.
WE HAVE NAPKINS, WE...
NO? WE DON'T HAVE
EVERYTHING READY
FOR SNACK?
WELL, WHAT ELSE
DO YOU WANT WITH
YOUR SNACK, BLUE?
OH!
OKAY...
WE'LL PLAY "BLUE'S CLUES."
THAT'S A GREAT IDEA.
I LOVE "BLUE'S CLUES."
* WE ARE GONNA PLAY
BLUE'S CLUES *
* 'CAUSE THAT'S A REALLY
GREAT GAME, YEAH! *
YOU READY? LET'S GO!
WHOOPS.
I FORGOT, WE SHOULD PROBABLY
CLEAN THIS UP FIRST.
NOW, REMEMBER, BLUE'S PAW PRINTS
WILL BE ON THE CLUES:
BLUE'S CLUES.
HEY, YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED FOR
BLUE'S CLUES, OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK!
NOTEBOOK, RIGHT.
COME ON.
BLUE'S CLUES,
I'M SO EXCITED.
OOH.
HERE IT IS.
YOU KNOW, I CAN TELL I'M REALLY
GOING TO NEED YOUR HELP TODAY
FIGURING OUT WHAT BLUE WANTS
WITH HER SNACK.
WILL YOU HELP ME?
YOU WILL?
GREAT! OOH...
* WE GOT TO FIND A PAW PRINT,
THAT'S THE FIRST CLUE *
* WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND NOW WHAT DO WE DO? *
* BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
* BLUE'S CLUES!
* WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE SECOND CLUE *
* WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
NOW WHAT DO WE DO? *
* BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
* BLUE'S CLUES!
* WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE THIRD CLUE *
* PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND, WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO *
* BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
* BLUE'S CLUES!
* WELL, WE SIT DOWN
IN OUR THINKING CHAIR *
* AND THINK, THINK, THINK
* 'CAUSE WHEN WE USE OUR MINDS,
AND TAKE A STEP AT A TIME *
* WE CAN DO ANYTHING...
* THAT WE WANT TO DO.
COME ON.
* WE ARE LOOKING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES *
* WE ARE LOOKING FOR
BLUE'S CLUES *
* WE ARE LOOKING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES *
* WONDER WHERE THEY ARE.
A CLUE, A CLUE!
OH.
OH, DID YOU SEE A CLUE?
WHERE?
WHERE'S THE CLUE?
I CAN'T FIND THE CLUE.
RIGHT THERE!
OH.
OH, THE CLUE.
AHA.
YOU KNOW HOW YOU CAN TELL
IT'S A CLUE?
IT'S GOT BLUE'S PAW PRINTS
ON IT.
IT'S OUR FIRST BLUE'S CLUE.
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
NOTEBOOK.
YEAH! WE NEED OUR HANDY-DANDY...
OKAY, A BIG CIRCLE.
LINES FOR THE SIDES,
A LINE ON THE BOTTOM,
TWO LINES, AND WE HAVE A CUP.
BUT YOU CAN'T EAT A CUP
FOR SNACK.
HEY, DO YOU THINK BLUE WANTS
TO PUT SOMETHING IN THE CUP?
YEAH!
SO I THINK WE HAVE TO LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES
SO WE CAN FIGURE OUT WHAT SHE
WANTS WITH HER SNACK.
COME ON!
BLUE!
BLUE?
DO YOU SEE BLUE?
WHERE?
UNDER THE BED!
UNDER THE...
I DON'T SEE BLUE.
HA!
HEY, WHAT WAS THAT?
HEY, HEY, BLUE.
THERE YOU ARE.
I'VE BEEN WAITING
FOR YOU.
YOU DIDN'T FINISH
PAINTING MY FAMILY.
WHOA.
CAN YOU HELP BLUE FINISH
PAINTING THE PICTURE?
GREAT.
THEN WE CAN LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
OKAY, LET'S PAINT
THE BIGGEST ELEPHANT
YELLOW.
HMM...
CAN YOU SHOW BLUE
THE COLOR YELLOW?
UH-UH.
NO!
YEAH, THERE IT IS,
YELLOW!
WHY, THANK YOU.
GOOD WORK.
HI, MOM.
THAT WAS AWESOME.
BLUE, CAN WE
PAINT THE ELEPHANT
WITH THE LONGEST TRUNK
PINK NOW?
CAN YOU SHOW BLUE
THE COLOR PINK?
NO.
THAT'S THE PINK.
WHY, THANK YOU.
HOW YOU DOING, BRO?
THAT WAS GREAT!
OKAY, CAN YOU PAINT
THE BABY ELEPHANT
PURPLE?
CAN YOU SHOW BLUE
THE COLOR PURPLE?
NO.
PURPLE, RIGHT THERE.
RIGHT THERE.
THANK YOU.
:
WHAT A PAINTER, THAT BLUE.
AND ALL OF YOU, TOO.
BLUE?
BLUE, WHERE ARE...
IT'S THE PHONE.
HELLO?
Hello.
This is Mr. Salt...
and Mrs. Pepper.
IT'S MY GOOD FRIENDS,
MR. SALT AND MRS. PEPPER.
HELLO, MR. SALT AND MRS. PEPPER.
HOW ARE YOU?
Fine.
Fine. But Blue
is in the kitchen...
and she's making
a really big mess.
UH-OH. ALL RIGHT.
STAY PUT, WE'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
YOU WILL COME AND HELP ME
WITH THIS, WON'T YOU?
YOU WILL? COOL.
ALL RIGHT, WELL, WE BETTER
GET TO THE KITCHEN, AND FAST.
WAIT TILL YOU MEET MY FRIENDS,
MR. SALT AND MRS. PEPPER.
YOU'RE GOING TO LOVE THEM.
* WE ARE GOING TO THE KITCHEN
* TO MEET
MY KITCHEN FRIENDS, YEAH. *
HI, MR. SALT
AND MRS. PEPPER.
HELLO, STEVE.
OH, OOH, HEY.
BLUE...
WHAT DID YOU DO?
BLUE KNOCKED OVER
THE GROCERY BAG.
THAT'S WHAT
SHE DID.
YEAH...
THAT'S A GOOD IDEA, BLUE.
LET'S CLEAN THIS UP FIRST
AND THEN WE CAN LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
I THINK WE'RE GOING TO NEED
YOUR HELP
PUTTING ALL THIS FOOD AWAY.
Both:
OKAY.
LET'S START WITH
THE GREAT BIG CIRCLE.
Both:
LIKE THIS.
OKAY, CIRCLE.
HMM...
I DON'T SEE A CIRCLE.
COULD YOU SHOW ME THE CIRCLE?
IT'S THE ORANGE!
Both:
GREAT!
NOW LET'S PUT AWAY
THE SQUARE, LIKE THIS.
OKAY, A SQUARE.
HMM.
I DON'T SEE A SQUARE.
COULD YOU SHOW ME THE SQUARE?
IT'S RIGHT THERE.
IT'S THE CHEESE.
Both:
WONDERFUL!
NOW LET'S PUT AWAY
THE RECTANGLE.
Both:
LIKE THIS!
OKAY, RECTANGLE, HMM.
I DON'T SEE A RECTANGLE.
COULD YOU SHOW ME
THE RECTANGLE, TOO?
THERE IT IS.
THAT'S THE GRAHAM CRACKERS.
Both:
GREAT!
NOW LET'S PUT AWAY
THE TRIANGLE.
LIKE THIS.
UH, TRIANGLE, HMM.
I DON'T SEE A TRIANGLE.
COULD YOU SHOW ME THE TRIANGLE?
SEE? THE BUNCH OF GRAPES,
RIGHT THERE!
HEY, THANKS FOR HELPING.
AND THANK YOU, TOO, BLUE.
WHOA, LOOK IN THE 'FRIDGE.
OH, NO, THESE STRAWS
ARE ALL OVER THE PLACE.
MAYBE WE SHOULD...
PUT THEM AWAY.
THERE.
NOW ALL THE STRAWS ARE...
PUT AWAY.
WHAT? DO YOU SEE
ANOTHER STRAW?
A CLUE, A CLUE!
WHERE?
I DON'T SEE IT.
AHA!
WELL, NOW, THAT'S ABOUT THE
SILLIEST STRAW I EVER SAW.
OH... OH!
OH, OH, OH!
THAT STRAW HAS BLUE'S
PAW PRINTS ON IT!
IT MUST BE ONE OF...
BLUE'S CLUES!
YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO.
WE NEED OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK!
NOTEBOOK.
LET'S SEE.
THERE'S THE TOP...
A COUPLE OF LINES...
THAT LITTLE BENDY PART...
TWO LONG LINES, AND
A STRIPE DOWN THE MIDDLE.
UH... HMM.
SO WHAT DOES BLUE WANT
WITH HER SNACK?
BLUE'S FIRST CLUE WAS A... A...
A CUP!
RIGHT, A CUP.
AND NOW, BLUE'S SECOND CLUE
IS A... STRAW.
HMM.
BLUE WANTS SOMETHING TO...
SOMETHING TO...
TO DRINK!
DRINK, RIGHT!
WITH A CUP AND A STRAW.
WELL, WELL, WHAT DO YOU THINK
IT COULD BE?
YOU THINK WE SHOULD LOOK
FOR OUR LAST BLUE'S CLUE
SO WE CAN FIGURE OUT
WHAT BLUE WANTS WITH HER SNACK?
SO DO I! COME ON!
BLUE!
BLUE?
* MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME,
MAIL TIME... *
THE MAIL'S HERE.
* HERE'S THE MAIL,
IT NEVER FAILS *
* IT MAKES ME WANT
TO WAG MY TAIL *
* WHEN IT COMES,
I WANT TO WAIL, "MAIL!" *
OKAY, MAIL'S HERE,
MAIL'S HERE!
THAT'S ME, MAIL!
THANK YOU, MAILBOX.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
WE JUST GOT A LETTER.
* WE JUST GOT A LETTER
* WONDER WHO IT'S FROM?
All:
HI, STEVE!
WE'RE HAVING SNACK!
IT'S A LETTER FROM MORGAN,
PERRY, AND BRENT.
Girl:
YOU KNOW WHAT OUR
VERY FAVORITE SNACK IS?
All:
PEANUT BUTTER AND APPLES!
Boy:
WE'RE PUTTING
PEANUT BUTTER
ON THE APPLES.
IT TASTES LIKE, UM...
APPLE JUICE.
I LIKE THIS SNACK
'CAUSE I CAN DO IT MYSELF.
All:
BYE!
BYE.
AH... I LOVE SNACKS, DON'T YOU?
WHOA.
DID YOU SEE THAT?
BLUE JUST WENT RIGHT INTO
THE PICTURE OF THAT FARM.
THAT'S SO COOL.
HEY, I THINK BLUE WANTS US
TO FOLLOW HER.
THERE GOES BLUE.
* BLUE SKIDDOO, WE CAN, TOO.
WHOA, WHAT A GREAT FARM.
LET'S GO LOOK AROUND.
* WE ARE FARMING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES *
* WE ARE FARMING FOR
BLUE'S CLUES *
* WE ARE FARMING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES, E-I-E-I-O *
* WITH A CHICK, CHICK HERE
AND A CHICK THERE *
* CHICK, CHICK HERE
* HERE A CHICK, THERE A CHICK,
EVERYWHERE A CHICK, CHICK. *
EVERYWHERE
A CHICK, CHICK.
OH, I THINK
THIS LITTLE CHICK
IS TRYING TO
TELL US SOMETHING.
HELLO, LITTLE CHICK.
HEY, STEVE, CAN YOU
HELP ME FIND MY FRIEND?
OKAY. WHAT DOES
YOUR FRIEND LOOK LIKE?
MY FRIEND HAS A HAT ON
JUST LIKE MINE, SEE?
ARE YOU READY TO HELP
THIS LITTLE CHICK?
THEN WE CAN LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
MY FRIEND HAS A HAT ON
JUST LIKE MINE.
DO YOU SEE MY FRIEND?
UH-UH.
NO.
YES!
SEE? YOU FOUND
YOUR FRIEND.
Both: YES!
SEE HOW WE MATCH?
THANK YOU
FOR HELPING US.
GREAT WORK!
NOW WE CAN GO LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
HI. CAN YOU
HELP ME, TOO?
CAN YOU HELP ME
FIND MY FRIEND?
OKAY, WHAT DOES
YOUR FRIEND LOOK LIKE?
MY FRIEND HAS A HAT
LIKE MINE.
ARE YOU READY
TO HELP AGAIN?
I SURE HOPE
YOU CAN HELP ME.
DO YOU SEE MY FRIEND?
NO!
NO.
UH-UH.
YES!
SEE? YOU FOUND
YOUR FRIEND, TOO.
Both:
SEE HOW WE MATCH?
THANK YOU
FOR HELPING US.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
GREAT JOB.
NOW WE CAN GO LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUE..
YOU TOO, HUH?
UH-HUH.
CAN YOU HELP ME, PLEASE?
OKAY. WHAT DOES YOUR FRIEND
LOOK LIKE?
MY FRIEND HAS A HAT ON
JUST LIKE MINE.
HAS A HAT ON JUST LIKE YOURS,
RIGHT, RIGHT.
WE KIND OF THOUGHT SO.
YOU READY TO HELP AGAIN?
DO YOU SEE HIM?
DO YOU SEE MY FRIEND?
UH-UH.
NO!
YES!
SEE? YOU FOUND
YOUR FRIEND, TOO.
Both:
THANK YOU FOR HELPING US.
WELL, YOU'RE VERY WELCOME
BUT NOW CAN YOU HELP ME
FIND MY FRIEND?
Both:
CERTAINLY!
WHAT DOES YOUR FRIEND
LOOK LIKE?
WELL, BLUE'S SORT OF
A LITTLE PUPPY WHO'S BLUE AND...
YOU MEAN THAT SILLY PUPPY
ON YOUR HEAD?
BLUE?
WHAT ARE YOU UP TO?
LET'S GO FIND BLUE.
COME ON.
BLUE!
BLUE, BLUE!
BLUE?
WHAT?
A CLUE!
OH. DID YOU SEE A CLUE?
WHERE, WHERE?
WHERE'S THE CLUE?
BEHIND YOU.
OH.... OH...
THAT COW HAS BLUE'S PAW PRINTS
ALL OVER IT!
THAT MUST MEAN THAT
THAT COW IS ANOTHER ONE OF...
BLUE'S CLUES!
HEY, DO YOU THINK BLUE WANTS TO
DRINK A COW WITH HER SNACK?
NO.
OKAY.
WELL, THIS CALLS
FOR OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK.
OKAY, WE GOT THE COW'S HEAD...
A BIG CIRCLE FOR THE BODY...
LINES FOR HER LEGS AND TAIL..
THE HOOVES...
AND AN UDDER...
AND THERE'S A COW.
GREAT!
HEY, NOW THAT WE HAVE
ALL THREE CLUES
THAT MEANS WE'RE READY
TO GO BACK HOME
TO OUR THINKING CHAIR
AND FIGURE OUT WHAT
BLUE WANTS WITH HER SNACK!
GREAT, LET'S GO!
NOW THAT WE'RE IN OUR
THINKING CHAIR, LET'S THINK.
HMM, SO, WE NEED TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT BLUE WANTS WITH HER SNACK.
BLUE'S CLUES ARE A CUP...
A STRAW...
AND A COW.
HMM.
WHAT DO YOU THINK BLUE
WANTS WITH HER SNACK?
HMM.
OH, OH, OH.
DO YOU THINK BLUE WANTS TO
PUT THE COW IN A CUP
AND SLURP IT UP WITH A STRAW?
NO.
CAN'T REALLY FIT A COW IN A CUP.
HMM...
WELL, COWS MAKE
THE SOUND "MOO," RIGHT?
COWS MAKE "MOO" SOUNDS.
COWS MAKE M...
MILK!
MILK! YES!
YES, THAT'S IT.
COWS MAKE THE MILK WE DRINK!
YEAH, THAT'S THE ANSWER
TO BLUE'S CLUES!
BLUE WANTS MILK POURED IN A CUP
AND SHE WANTS TO DRINK IT
WITH A STRAW!
WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES!
* WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES *
* WE JUST
FIGURED OUT BLUE'S CLUES *
* WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES *
* BECAUSE WE'RE REALLY SMART!
HEY, BLUE?
I'M GOING TO POUR
SOME MILK IN A CUP
WITH A STRAW RIGHT NOW
AND YOU CAN DRINK IT
WITH YOUR SNACK!
WE'RE ALL SET
FOR OUR SNACK, BLUE.
WE GOT OUR CUPS OF MILK
WITH STRAWS RIGHT HERE.
OH... OKAY...
STOP WITH THE LICKING.
MMM...
HEY...
LOOK WHO'S HERE!
IT'S THE ELEPHANTS.
RIGHT.
REMEMBER HOW WE HELPED THEM
PAINT THEIR FAMILY?
OH, LOOK.
MR. SALT AND MRS. PEPPER.
RIGHT, THEY BROUGHT THE FOOD
WE HELPED TO PUT AWAY.
LOOK...
IT'S THE CHICKS.
REMEMBER ALL THOSE HATS?
WHAT A DAY!
HEY, THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR ALL YOUR HELP TODAY.
* NOW IT'S TIME FOR SO LONG
* BUT WE'LL SING
JUST ONE MORE SONG *
* THANKS FOR DOING YOUR PART
* YOU SURE ARE SMART
* YOU KNOW, WITH ME AND YOU
* AND MY DOG, BLUE
* WE CAN DO ANYTHING
* THAT WE WANT TO DO.
BYE-BYE!
SEE YOU LATER.
BYE! COME AGAIN.
* WE CAN DO ANYTHING
BYE-BYE.
* THAT WE WANT TO DO.
* WE CAN DO ANYTHING.