HI, OUT THERE!
IT'S ME, STEVE.
HAVE YOU SEEN BLUE, MY PUPPY?
THERE SHE IS!
COME ON IN.
[ barking...]
HI. COME ON IN.
BLUE AND I ARE
PAINTING PICTURES.
I'M PAINTING A PICTURE OF BLUE.
SEE?
BLUE?
DO YOU SEE BLUE?
SHE'S RIGHT THERE!
RIGHT THERE.
[ barks "hello"]
AHA!
[ laughs]
BIRDS.
GREAT JOB, BLUE.
WELL, GUESS YOU'RE ALL
DONE WITH YOUR PAINTING.
[ barks "no"]
NO? YOU'RE NOT DONE
WITH YOUR PAINTING?
[ barks "no"]
WELL, WELL, WHAT ELSE
DO YOU WANT TO PAINT?
OH, OH, OKAY!
WE'LL PLAY "BLUE'S CLUES."
I LOVE "BLUE'S CLUES."
♪ WE ARE GONNA PLAY
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ 'CAUSE IT'S A REALLY FUN GAME,
YEAH! ♪
THIS IS GREAT.
BLUE'S CLUES WILL TELL US
WHAT ELSE SHE WANTS TO PAINT
IN HER PICTURE.
OH, BUT REMEMBER,
BLUE'S PAW PRINTS WILL BE
ON THE CLUES: BLUE'S CLUES.
OKAY... LET'S GET GOING.
OH. [ laughs]
BUT, UH, WE OUGHT TO
CLEAN THIS UP FIRST.
[ humming...]
AH... HEY.
HEY, YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED
FOR BLUE'S CLUES.
OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK!
BLUE'S CLUES!
I'M SO EXCITED.
OOH... HERE IT IS.
YOU KNOW, I CAN TELL I'M REALLY
GOING TO NEED YOUR HELP TODAY
FIGURING OUT WHAT ELSE BLUE
WANTS TO PAINT IN HER PICTURE.
WILL YOU HELP ME?
YOU WILL?
GREAT.
♪ WE GOT TO FIND A PAW PRINT,
THAT'S THE FIRST CLUE ♪
♪ WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND NOW WHAT DO WE DO? ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE SECOND CLUE ♪
♪ WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
NOW WHAT DO WE DO? ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE THIRD CLUE ♪
♪ PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND, WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WELL, WE SIT DOWN
IN OUR THINKING CHAIR ♪
♪ AND THINK, THINK, THINK
♪ 'CAUSE WHEN WE USE OUR MINDS,
TAKE A STEP AT A TIME ♪
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING...
[ barks]
♪ THAT WE WANT TO DO.
GREAT.
WE'RE ALL SET TO GO FIND
BLUE'S CLUES.
BLUE?
BLUE'S... GONE.
WHICH WAY DID BLUE GO?
THAT WAY!
THAT WAY?
OH, OKAY.
I GET IT.
I'LL GO THAT WAY.
THANKS.
YOU'RE COMING WITH ME, RIGHT?
OH, GOOD.
COME ON.
♪ WE ARE LOOKING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE ARE
LOOKING FOR BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE ARE LOOKING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ I WONDER WHERE THEY ARE.
[ humming...]
A CLUE!
A CLUE.
DID YOU SAY SOMETHING?
A CLUE!
OH, YOU SEE A CLUE?
WHERE?
ON THE DOOR!
WHERE IS THE CLUE?
A CLUE!
YOU KNOW HOW YOU CAN TELL
IT'S A CLUE.
BECAUSE IT HAS BLUE'S
PAW PRINTS ON IT.
IT'S A CLUE!
IT'S A...
A DOOR.
RIGHT, IT'S A DOOR.
WELL, NOW WHAT SHOULD WE DO?
NOTEBOOK.
RIGHT, PUT IT
IN OUR HANDY-DANDY NOTEBOOK.
OKAY.
SO.
A LONG CURVE...
A LINE...
AND A LITTLE CIRCLE...
AND A DOOR.
GREAT.
NOW, WE NEED TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT ELSE BLUE WANTS TO PAINT.
HMM... OUR FIRST CLUE IS...
A DOOR... WELL...
NOW WHAT COULD BLUE WANT TO
PAINT THAT HAS A DOOR?
A CLOSET... UH...
OH, YOU THINK WE NEED
TO LOOK FOR MORE CLUES?
SO DO I.
COME ON.
HEY, BLUE.
OOH, UH...
[ whispers ]:
THE WAGON IS LOOKING
A LITTLE SHABBY.
[ barking...]
OH, OH, YOU WANT
TO GIVE YOUR WAGON
A NEW COAT OF PAINT.
WELL, WE'LL NEED
THE SAME COLORS.
CAN YOU HELP US FIND
THE COLORS OF THE WAGON?
OH, OKAY.
WE'LL PAINT THE WAGON
AND THEN WE'LL LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
HMM... OKAY.
LET'S START
WITH THE WHEELS
WHICH ARE THE COLOR...
PINK!
RIGHT... PINK.
HMM... DO WE HAVE
PINK PAINT?
NO.... NO.
WE DON'T HAVE
PINK PAINT?
[ barks]
GOOD IDEA, BLUE.
LET'S MAKE
THE COLOR PINK PAINT.
[ barks]
HOW DO WE DO THAT?
OH...
OH, MAYBE WE SHOULD
MIX A COLOR WITH WHITE
TO MAKE PINK.
WELL, WHAT OTHER COLOR
LOOKS LIKE PINK
THAT WE COULD MIX
WITH WHITE?
RED.
SEE HOW I KIND OF
LOOK LIKE PINK?
RED? OKAY.
LET'S TRY MIXING
TOGETHER RED AND WHITE.
IT WORKED!
BY MIXING TOGETHER
RED AND WHITE,
WE MADE PINK!
YES!
OKAY.
WHAT'S NEXT, BLUE?
[ barks]
OKAY, LET'S PAINT
THE HANDLE NEXT.
THIS COLOR IS...
ORANGE.
OH, YEAH.
WELL, DO WE HAVE
ORANGE PAINT?
NO.
WE DON'T HAVE
ORANGE PAINT,
EITHER?
YOU'RE KIDDING.
WELL...
WHAT SHOULD WE DO NOW?
MAKE ORANGE PAINT!
MAKE ORANGE PAINT.
GOOD IDEA.
WELL, OKAY.
WHAT TWO COLORS CAN WE MIX
TOGETHER TO MAKE ORANGE?
YELLOW!
I ALMOST
LOOK LIKE ORANGE.
YELLOW!
WHAT OTHER COLOR
CAN WE MIX WITH YELLOW?
RED.
I ALMOST LOOK
LIKE ORANGE, TOO.
YELLOW AND RED?
YOU WANT TO MIX THEM
TOGETHER? OKAY.
LET'S SEE WHAT HAPPENS
IF WE MIX YELLOW AND RED.
WHOA!
HOW COOL.
YELLOW AND RED
MAKES ORANGE.
YOUR WAGON
LOOKS GREAT, BLUE.
GOOD JOB.
ALL RIGHT, NOW LET'S GO LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
[ barking "Blue Skiddoo"]
HI, FELT FRIENDS.
HI, STEVE.
HI, BLUE.
WE'RE TRYING TO GET
TO THE OTHER ISLAND.
BUT THIS SAILBOAT ISN'T BIG
ENOUGH FOR ALL OF US.
[ barks]
HEY, GOOD IDEA, BLUE.
LET'S HELP OUR FRIENDS
AND THEN WE CAN LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
HOW CAN WE HELP?
WELL, WE'RE
TRYING TO MAKE
A BIGGER SAILBOAT
WITH THESE SHAPES.
I'M NOT SURE
WE CAN DO IT.
I BET WE CAN.
WILL YOU HELP?
OH, GOOD, COME ON.
OKAY--
WE NEED A SHAPE
THAT WILL BE
THE BOTTOM
OF THE SAILBOAT.
OKAY.
HMM...
WELL...
WHAT SHAPE
COULD WE USE
TO MAKE THE BOTTOM
OF THE SAILBOAT?
NO.
YES.
[ barking]
YEAH.
THE SEMICIRCLE IS THE SHAPE
OF THE BOTTOM OF THE SAILBOAT.
YEAH.
WOW, LOOK!
OKAY, THE NEXT THING
WE HAVE TO MAKE
IS THE MAST.
THE POLE THAT HOLDS
THE SAIL UP.
OKAY.
HMM...
CAN YOU FIND THE SHAPES
WE NEED TO PUT TOGETHER
TO MAKE THE MAST?
NO.
YES!
[ barking]
EXCELLENT.
ALL THOSE SQUARES PUT TOGETHER
MAKES A LONG RECTANGLE. COOL.
IT WILL BE THE MAST!
WOW, LOOK.
NOW WE NEED A SAIL.
OKAY.
HMM...
WHAT TWO SHAPES COULD WE USE
TO MAKE THE SAIL? HMM...
NO.
YES!
[ barking]
OH, THE TRIANGLE
AND THE TRAPEZOID
PUT TOGETHER MAKE
THE SAIL... YES.
LIKE A BIG TRIANGLE.
WE DID IT!
I KNEW WE COULD DO IT.
GREAT!
NOW WE CAN ALL GET
TO THE OTHER ISLAND
ON OUR BIGGER SAILBOAT.
BLUE?
A CLUE!
A CLUE.
SUE?
MY NAME'S NOT SUE, IT'S STEVE.
NO, IT'S A CLUE.
OH.
OH, YOU SEE A CLUE?
WHERE?
OVER THERE.
ON THE WINDOW.
OH! A CLUE!
OUR SECOND CLUE!
LOOK AT THIS, THIS, THIS...
WINDOW, RIGHT... COOL.
HEY, YOU KNOW WHAT WE GOT TO DO.
DRAW IT IN OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK.
OKAY...
[ humming]
A RECTANGLE...
ONE CURTAIN...
THE OTHER CURTAIN...
A LINE
AND A LITTLE SQUIGGLE...
AND WE HAVE...
A WINDOW.
SO, WE NEED TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT ELSE BLUE WANTS TO PAINT
IN HER PICTURE.
THE FIRST CLUE WAS...
HEY, WHAT WAS OUR FIRST CLUE?
A DOOR!
OH, RIGHT, THAT DOOR.
AND NOW OUR SECOND CLUE
IS A WINDOW. HMM...
SO WHAT COULD BLUE WANT TO PAINT
THAT HAS A DOOR AND A WINDOW?
A SCHOOL?
UH... I THINK WE NEED TO LOOK
FOR ONE MORE OF BLUE'S CLUES
TO FIGURE THIS OUT, DON'T YOU?
♪ MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME,
MAIL TIME! ♪
♪ MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME!
THE MAIL'S HERE!
HURRY!
♪ HERE'S THE MAIL,
IT NEVER FAILS ♪
♪ IT MAKES ME WANT
TO WAG MY TAIL ♪
♪ WHEN IT COMES,
I WANT TO WAIL, "MAIL!" ♪
MAIL'S HERE.
HEY, STEVE,
DID YOU KNOW
THERE'S A PAW PRINT
ON YOUR WINDOW?
YEAH, IT'S ONE
OF BLUE'S CLUES.
WHAT A LUCKY
WINDOW!
GOT A LETTER
FOR YOU.
OOH, THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
WE JUST GOT A LETTER.
♪ WE JUST GOT A LETTER
♪ WONDER WHO IT'S FROM?
OH, LOOK, IT'S A LETTER
FROM OUR FRIENDS.
HEY.
Both:
HI, STEVE.
Girl:
WE'RE MAKING THINGS
WITH CLAY.
FIRST YOU MAKE A BALL,
LIKE THIS.
THEN YOU PUT THEM TOGETHER.
THESE ARE THE EYES.
AND ONE NOSE.
AND I'M GOING TO NOW
PUT THE MOUTH ON.
AND THERE WE HAVE A SNOWMAN.
BYE-BYE.
I JUST LOVE TO MAKE THINGS
WITH CLAY, DON'T YOU?
HEY, WE STILL HAVE TO LOOK
FOR OUR LAST BLUE'S CLUE
TO FIGURE OUT WHAT BLUE
WANTS TO PAINT IN HER PICTURE.
[ barking...]
COME ON.
WHAT ARE YOU
BARKING AT, BLUE?
[ barks "Blue Skiddoo"]
DID YOU SEE THAT?
BLUE JUST WENT RIGHT
INTO THE PICTURE
OF THAT MUSEUM.
HEY, DO YOU THINK
IF WE GO, TOO
WE MIGHT FIND
ANOTHER BLUE'S CLUE?
♪ BLUE SKIDDOO, WE CAN, TOO.
WOW... A MUSEUM.
HEY, LOOK AT ALL
THESE GREAT WORKS OF ART.
COME ON.
PAINTINGS, SCULPTURES,
DRAWINGS...
[ barks]
BARKING?
LOOK AT THESE WORKS OF ART.
HI, STEVE, HI, BLUE.
OUR PICTURES
ARE ALL OUT OF ORDER.
THEY DON'T TELL
MUCH OF A STORY THIS WAY.
DO YOU WANT TO HELP
THIS LITTLE CHICK?
OKAY.
AND THEN WE'LL LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
OKAY, SO...
WHICH ONE OF THESE PICTURES
SHOULD COME FIRST?
THAT ONE, THAT ONE.
THIS ONE?
EXCELLENT. OKAY...
SO, ONE DAY, A PUPPY STARTED TO
PAINT A PICTURE ON A SUNNY DAY.
OKAY.
NOW...
IF THAT'S THE BEGINNING
WHICH ONE OF THESE PICTURES
SHOWS THE ENDING?
THAT ONE... THAT ONE.
GREAT!
SO, THE ENDING
OF THE PICTURE STORY IS:
THE PUPPY HAS FINISHED
HER PAINTING.
OH, AND IT STARTED TO RAIN.
SO...
HOW DOES THE MIDDLE GO?
THAT ONE.
YEAH.
LIKE THIS?
OKAY.
LET'S CHECK IT OUT.
[ clears throat]
ONE SUNNY DAY,
A MAGENTA-COLORED PUPPY
GOT A PIECE OF PAPER
AND STARTED TO PAINT A PICTURE.
IT GOT A LITTLE CLOUDY OUT, BUT
SHE PAINTED A FARM ON A HILL.
SHE EVEN PAINTED A LITTLE CHICK
POPPING OUT THE WINDOW
JUST TO SAY "HI."
HI.
AND FINALLY,
WHEN IT STARTED TO RAIN OUTSIDE
THE PUPPY HAD FINISHED
HER PAINTING.
THE END.
THAT'S GR--
[ clears throat]
THAT'S GREAT.
THANKS FOR HELPING.
THANK YOU.
OH... HEY...
[ barks]
WHERE DID BLUE GO?
SHE WENT THAT WAY.
THIS WAY?
THANKS.
OH, LOOK,
IT'S A SCULPTURE OF OUR HOUSE.
HEY, BUT IT LOOKS LIKE
SOMETHING'S MISSING.
A CLUE!
OH, YEAH, RIGHT.
THE ROOF IS MISSING, YEAH.
IT'S A CLUE!
OH...
OH.
YOU SEE A CLUE.
WHERE?
OVER THERE!
IT'S A CLUE!
OUR THIRD CLUE!
AND IT'S A, IT'S A...
A ROOF!
ROOF!
THIS ROOF IS OUR THIRD CLUE!
YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED?
OUR HANDY-DANDY, TRUSTY-RUSTY...
NOTEBOOK.
OKAY...
TRIANGLE...
AND A RECTANGLE...
TWO LINES...
AND WE HAVE A ROOF. HA!
WELL, WE HAVE ALL THREE CLUES.
WE HAVE ALL THREE CLUES!
SO WE'RE READY FOR OUR...
THINKING CHAIR!
LET'S GO.
[ barks "Blue Skiddoo"]
[ hums "Blue Skiddoo"]
AH... NOW THAT WE'RE IN OUR
THINKING CHAIR, LET'S THINK.
OKAY, SO, WE NEED TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT ELSE BLUE WANTS TO PAINT
IN HER PICTURE.
OUR CLUES ARE:
A DOOR...
A WINDOW...
AND, A...
[ barks "roof"]
YEAH, A ROOF.
OKAY... SO WHAT COULD BLUE
WANT TO PAINT
THAT HAS A DOOR,
A WINDOW, AND A ROOF?
COULD IT BE A CAR?
NO!
I GUESS NOT.
WELL, WHAT HAS A DOOR,
A WINDOW, AND A ROOF?
HOUSE.
A HOUSE!
A HOUSE!!
THAT'S IT!
THAT'S THE ANSWER
TO BLUE'S CLUES!
SHE, SHE WANTS TO PAINT
A HOUSE WITH A DOOR,
A WINDOW AND A ROOF!
WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES.
♪ WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE JUST
FIGURED OUT BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ BECAUSE WE'RE REALLY SMART!
BLUE!
LET'S GO PAINT A HOUSE
IN YOUR PICTURE!
[ barking]
LET'S SEE, BLUE.
WOW.
WHAT A GREAT PICTURE
OF A HOUSE.
LOOKS KIND OF LIKE
OUR HOUSE.
HEY, IT'S THE PAINT DROPS.
REMEMBER HOW WE MIXED
COLORS?
RED...
AND YELLOW...
Both:
MAKE ORANGE!
WHOA.
AND IT'S
THE FELT FRIENDS
AND THE SAILBOAT
WE MADE WITH THEM.
OH, AND IT'S
THAT LITTLE CHICK.
HI.
HEY, THIS PICTURE
MIGHT TELL A STORY.
YEAH... LIKE THE ONES
IN THE MUSEUM.
WHAT STORY
DO YOU THINK IT TELLS?
YEAH.
HEY, THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR ALL YOUR HELP TODAY.
♪ NOW IT'S TIME FOR SO LONG
♪ BUT WE'LL SING
JUST ONE MORE SONG ♪
♪ THANKS FOR DOING YOUR PART
♪ YOU SURE ARE SMART
♪ YOU KNOW, WITH ME AND YOU
♪ AND MY DOG, BLUE
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING
♪ THAT WE WANT TO DO.
BYE-BYE.
SEE YOU LATER. BYE.
COME AGAIN. BYE-BYE.
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING
THAT WE WANT TO DO.♪
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING.♪