HI, OUT THERE!
IT'S ME, STEVE.
HAVE YOU SEEN BLUE, MY PUPPY?
THERE SHE IS!
COME ON IN.
HI.
OH, HI.
COME ON IN.
I'M LOOKING FOR BLUE.
SHE'S BEEN ACTING
KIND OF DIFFERENT TODAY.
WILL YOU HELP ME?
OH, GOOD.
COME ON.
BLUE?
THERE'S BLUE!
YOU SEE BLUE?
WHERE IS SHE?
SHE'S RIGHT THERE.
BLUE?
BLUE, WHAT ARE
YOU DOING UNDER HERE?
HEY, BLUE'S KIND OF
SHAKING A LITTLE BIT.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
DO YOU THINK
BLUE'S COLD?
NO!
NO?
HEY, DO YOU THINK
BLUE'S SCARED?
YEAH.
BLUE, WHAT ARE
YOU AFRAID OF?
OH!
OH, THAT'S A GOOD IDEA.
WE'LL PLAY "BLUE'S CLUES"
TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT BLUE'S AFRAID OF.
♪ WE ARE GONNA PLAY
"BLUE'S CLUES" ♪
♪ AND THAT'LL
REALLY HELP BLUE. ♪
YEAH.
NOW, REMEMBER, BLUE'S PAW PRINTS
WILL BE ON THE CLUES--
BLUE'S CLUES.
RIGHT, WE BETTER
CLEAN THIS... THIS...
DID YOU DO THAT?
WELL, IF YOU DIDN'T DO IT
AND I DIDN'T DO IT, THEN...
WHOA!
THAT'S KIND OF SPOOKY.
WELL, DO YOU KNOW WHAT
WE NEED FOR BLUE'S CLUES?
OUR...
NOTEBOOK!
NOTEBOOK, RIGHT.
COME ON.
I JUST LOVE
BLUE'S CLUES.
OOH, HERE IT IS.
YOU KNOW, I CAN TELL I'M REALLY
GOING TO NEED YOUR HELP TODAY
FIGURING OUT
WHAT BLUE IS AFRAID OF.
WILL YOU HELP ME?
YOU WILL?
GREAT.
OKAY, SO, WE GOT TO FIND A...
PAW PRINT!
RIGHT, BECAUSE
THAT'S THE FIRST...
CLUE!
YEAH, THEN WE PUT IT
IN OUR NOTEBOOK...
♪ 'CAUSE THEY'RE BLUE'S CLUES,
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
BLUE'S CLUES!
♪ WE GOT TO FIND
ANOTHER PAW PRINT ♪
♪ THAT'S THE SECOND CLUE
♪ WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
'CAUSE THEY'RE WHOSE CLUES? ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES.
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WE GOT TO FIND THE LAST PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE THIRD CLUE ♪
♪ WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK
♪ 'CAUSE THEY'RE BLUE'S CLUES,
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO.
♪ SIT DOWN
IN OUR THINKING CHAIR ♪
♪ AND THINK
♪ THINK
♪ THINK.
♪ 'CAUSE WHEN WE USE OUR MINDS,
TAKE A STEP AT A TIME ♪
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING...
♪ THAT WE WANT TO DO.
OKAY, READY?
LET'S GO HELP BLUE.
DID YOU SEE WHICH WAY SHE WENT?
BLUE WENT THAT WAY.
OH, RIGHT, THIS WAY.
THANKS.
LET'S GO FIND
BLUE'S CLUES TOGETHER.
♪ WE ARE LOOKING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WONDER WHERE THEY ARE.
HMM!
A CLUE, A CLUE!
WHAT WAS THAT?
A CLUE!
A CLUE?
THIS FEATHER IS A CLUE
TO WHAT BLUE'S AFRAID OF.
WOW!
WE HAVE OUR FIRST CLUE.
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
NOTEBOOK.
WE NEED OUR HANDY-DANDY,
SUPERDUPER NOTEBOOK.
OKAY, A FEATHER.
WE HAVE A LONG LINE
AND THEN SOME SHORT LINES
COMING OUT OVER HERE
AND THAT MAKES A FEATHER.
SO, WHAT COULD BLUE
BE AFRAID OF?
THIS FEATHER?
NAH.
IT MUST BE SOMETHING
WITH THIS FEATHER-- YEAH!
WONDER WHAT IT COULD BE.
I THINK WE NEED
TO FIND TWO MORE BLUE'S CLU...
THERE'S BLUE.
LET'S GO SEE WHAT SHE'S UP TO.
OH, PAIL, LOOK
AT THAT BIG SHADOW!
OH, OH! WHAT DO
YOU THINK IT IS?
BLAH, BLAH, BLAH!
JUST KIDDING.
IT'S ME, STEVE.
BLAH!
LOOK, MY SHADOW
DOES WHAT I DO.
BLAH!
AH, LOOK!
WHAT IS THAT
A SHADOW OF?
DO YOU KNOW?
WHAT IS THAT A SHADOW OF?
A TREE!
Both:
OH!
:
IT'S... WOW!
YOU ARE SO GOOD.
THAT'S JUST
A SHADOW OF A TREE--
WITH A LITTLE
BIRD'S NEST, EVEN.
THAT'S NOT SCARY.
YEAH, SEE
THE BIRD'S NEST?
LOOK!
LITTLE BIRD.
OH, LOOK!
LOOK!
WHAT IS THAT
A SHADOW OF?
WHAT IS THAT A SHADOW OF?
A BIRDBATH!
Both:
OH!
HEY, WOW!
YOU ARE
SO GOOD AT THIS.
IT'S JUST A SHADOW
OF A BIRDBATH.
THAT'S NOT SCARY EITHER.
ARE YOU READY?
LET'S GO LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
A CLUE, A CLUE.
DID YOU SAY
WHAT I THINK YOU SAID?
A CLUE?
RIGHT HERE IN THE GARDEN?
THE CLUE?
OUR SECOND CLUE.
BUT WHAT IS IT?
A SHADOW!
OH, A SHADOW, RIGHT.
BUT A SHADOW OF WHAT?
IT'S GONE!
OOH!
WELL, WE BETTER HURRY UP
AND WRITE THIS CLUE DOWN
IN OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK.
NOTEBOOK, RIGHT.
OKAY, SO... THIS... SHADOW.
CURVE UP HERE.
SORT OF BUMPY AT THE TOP.
A CURVE DOWN HERE.
A WAVY LINE ON THE BOTTOM.
WE HAVE THIS SHADOW.
HMM.
SO, WE NEED TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT BLUE IS AFRAID OF.
WHAT WAS OUR FIRST CLUE?
A FEATHER.
RIGHT-- A FEATHER.
AND NOW WE HAVE THIS SHADOW.
HMM.
FEATHERS AND THIS SHADOW.
WHAT COULD BLUE BE AFRAID OF
WITH FEATHERS AND THIS SHADOW?
FEATHERS AND THIS SHADOW?
I THINK WE NEED TO FIND
OUR LAST BLUE'S CLUE.
DO YOU HEAR THAT?
SOUNDS LIKE IT'S COMING FROM...
THE KITCHEN.
LET'S GO.
Both:
ALLO!
HI, MR. SALT
AND MRS. PEPPER.
HAVE YOU SEEN BLUE?
YES, SHE'S
RIGHT HERE.
HEY, BLUE!
STEVE, STEVE!
WE JUST GOT
OUR PICTURES BACK.
WANT TO SEE?
LET'S SHOW STEVE!
DO YOU WANT TO SEE
MR. SALT AND MRS.
PEPPER'S PICTURES?
YEAH! THIS IS GOING
TO BE SO MUCH FUN.
AND THEN WE CAN LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
UH, OKAY,
HERE'S ONE.
OH, IT'S
FANTASTIC, REALLY.
OH, LOOK, STEVE.
IT'S FANTAS...
WHAT IS THIS?
STEVE, CAN YOU TELL
WHAT THIS PICTURE IS OF?
I THINK I GOT
A LITTLE TOO CLOSE.
OH, WELL THAT'S
A... WHOA!
DO YOU KNOW WHAT
THAT'S A PICTURE OF?
UH, HOW ABOUT BREAD?
IS IT A PICTURE
OF BREAD?
BREAD?
NO.
HOW ABOUT
A GRAHAM CRACKER?
YEAH!
YEAH, THAT'S IT.
OH, RIGHT! LOOK!
All:
OOH! AH!
I THINK I GOT A LITTLE
CLOSE FOR THIS ONE, TOO.
:
WHAT IS THIS ONE?
UH, STEVE, DO YOU
KNOW WHAT THIS IS
A PICTURE OF?
WHOA! UH, WHOOSH!
UH, IT'S A...
DO YOU KNOW WHAT
THIS IS A PICTURE OF?
MMM, HOW ABOUT
PURPLE GRAPES?
DO YOU THINK
IT'S A PICTURE
OF PURPLE GRAPES?
NO!
IS IT A PICTURE
OF CHOCOLATE?
CHOCOLATE?
NO!
NO. HMM.
HOW ABOUT A RAISIN?
A RAISIN?
YEAH.
A RAISIN!
THAT'S IT!
A RAISIN.
NOW I REMEMBER.
LOOK, SEE?
OH, THIS ONE.
THIS ONE...
IS MAGNIFIQUE.
THIS ONE,
IT'S MAGNI...
OH, MY!
WHAT COULD THIS
PICTURE POSSIBLY BE?
OKAY, OKAY,
DON'T YOU WORRY.
WE'LL... WE'LL FIGURE
THIS ONE OUT, TOO.
WOW!
DO YOU KNOW WHAT
THIS IS A PICTURE OF?
HOW ABOUT BROCCOLI?
BROCCOLI?
IS IT A PICTURE
OF BROCCOLI?
NO.
WELL, HOW ABOUT CELERY?
CELERY?
DO YOU THINK IT'S
A PICTURE OF CELERY?
YES!
YEAH?
OH, YEAH! RIGHT!
IT ISCELERY.
OH, CELERY.
BUT OF COURSE!
WATCH!
THANK YOU, STEVE.
YEAH, THANK YOU.
WELL, YOU'RE WELCOME.
WOW! THOSE PICTURES
WERE KIND OF SPOOKY.
I MEAN, THEY WERE
ALL JUST SO...
CLOSE.
CLOSE, YES, CLOSE.
THAT'S THE WORD
I WAS LOOKING FOR.
GOOD WORK
WITH THOSE EYES.
♪ MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME,
MAIL TIME! ♪
♪ MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME!
THE MAIL'S HERE!
LET'S GO!
♪ HERE'S THE MAIL,
IT NEVER FAILS ♪
♪ IT MAKES ME WANT
TO WAG MY TAIL ♪
♪ WHEN IT COMES,
I WANT TO WAIL, "MAIL!" ♪
MAIL'S HERE,
MAIL'S IN.
KNOCK, KNOCK.
WHO'S THERE?
BOO.
BOO WHO?
DON'T CRY.
I BROUGHT YOU
A LETTER!
THANKS.
YOU'RE WELCOME!
OH! BOO-HOO,
'CAUSE I WAS CRYING, SEE?
GET IT?
:
THAT'S PRETTY FUNNY.
WE JUST GOT A LETTER.
♪ WE JUST GOT A LETTER
♪ WONDER WHO IT'S FROM.
LOOK, IT'S A LETTER
FROM OUR FRIENDS.
All:
HI, STEVE!
Girl:
WE'RE MAKING
SHADOW PUPPETS.
YOU SEE HOW MANY SHADOWS
YOU CAN MAKE AGAINST A WALL.
A MONSTER.
YOU TAKE YOUR HANDS
AND YOU, LIKE,
TWIST THEM TOGETHER
SO THAT YOUR PALMS
ARE FACING YOU
AND THEN YOU TWIST
YOUR THUMBS AROUND
AND THEN YOU START WAIVING
YOUR HANDS.
AND THAT MAKES A BUTTERFLY.
BYE, STEVE!
BYE.
YEAH.
KIND OF SCARY, HUH?
OH, COME ON, BLUE.
WE'LL FIGURE OUT
WHAT YOU'RE AFRAID OF, TOO.
OH, IT'S A GHOST.
A GHOST?
:
OH!
♪ BLUE SKIDDOO...
♪ SKIDDOO...
YEAH, BLUE, I KNOW.
THAT PICTURE DOES LOOK
KIND OF SPOOKY.
HEY, LET'S JUMP IN
TOGETHER.
♪ BLUE SKIDDOO,
LET'S GO TOGETHER. ♪
WOW.
LOOK AT THIS HOUSE!
HAVE YOU SEEN
THAT LITTLE GHOST?
:
RIGHT THERE.
OH, HELLO,
LITTLE GHOST.
HI, MY NAME
IS BOO.
BOO?
YOU SCARED ME.
DID... DID YOU
HEAR THAT, TOO?
THAT'S WHY I NEED
YOUR HELP.
LOTS OF NOISES
AND THE NOISES
SCARE ME.
WILL YOU HELP FIGURE OUT
WHAT THE NOISES ARE?
YOU WILL? GOOD.
UM, WE CAN HELP
FIGURE OUT
WHAT THE NOISES ARE
SO THEY WON'T BE
SO SCARY.
SO, WHAT DO
YOU THINK
THAT MYSTERIOUS
SOUND IS?
FOOTSTEPS.
F-F-FOOTSTEPS?
OKAY, BOO.
LET'S SEE IF WE CAN
FIND THOSE FOOTSTEPS.
I THINK IT'S COMING
FROM OVER THERE.
WHAT IS IT?
I CAN'T LOOK.
OH, LOOK! PHEW!
IT'S JUST MY KITTEN
MAKING THOSE SOUNDS.
OH, IT'S JUST LITTLE
KITTEN FOOTSTEPS.
SEE? NOTHING TO BE
FRIGHTENED OF, BOO.
UH-OH.
WHAT WAS THAT?
HMM, I THINK WE'RE GOING
TO NEED YOUR HELP AGAIN.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT THAT SOUND IS?
THUNDER!
TH-TH-TH-THUNDER?
OKAY, LET'S GO SEE WHERE
THAT THUNDER IS COMING FROM.
OH, I SEE.
IT'S THUNDERING
OUTSIDE.
SEE, IT'S JUST A NOISE.
NOTHING TO BE
SPOOKED ABOUT, BOO.
UH-OH.
UM, DO YOU KNOW
WHAT THAT MYSTERIOUS SOUND IS?
POTS AND PANS!
P-P-POTS AND P-PANS?
Man:
BOO...
LUNCH IS READY.
OH, IT'S MY DAD
MAKING ME LUNCH
IN THE KITCHEN
WITH HIS POTS
AND PANS.
GOT TO GO, BYE!
Boo:
THANKS.
OH, YOU'RE WELCOME... BOO.
OH, WE STILL HAVE TO FIND
OUR LAST CLUE.
LET'S GO.
IT'S JUST THE PHONE.
HELLO?
Whoo.
WHO IS THIS?
Whoo!
NO, I'M... I'M ASKING YOUWHO.
A CLUE, A CLUE!
WHO?
Whoo, whoo!
I'LL BE WITH YOU
IN JUST ONE SECOND.
I'M JUST TRYING
TO FIGURE OUT WHO...
NO, IT'S A CLUE!
A CLUE? YOU SEE A CLUE?
Whoo, whoo.
OH, I SEE A CLUE, TOO.
IT'S THIS SOUND.
WHAT IS THIS SOUND?
Whoo, whoo.
WHOO, WHOO.
WHOO, WHOO, HUH!
Whoo.
OKAY, WE KNOW WHAT TO DO.
PUT IT IN OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK.
HMM, OKAY.
THE SOUND IS KIND OF LIKE THIS.
LOTS OF CIRCLES, LIKE "Os".
AND WE HAVE "WHOO"
AS OUR THIRD CLUE.
YOU KNOW WHAT THAT MEANS?
WE'RE READY FOR OUR...
THINKING CHAIR!
THINKING CHAIR.
COME ON.
OKAY, NOW THAT WE'RE IN
OUR THINKING CHAIR, LET'S THINK.
ALL RIGHT.
SO, WE NEED
TO FIGURE OUT WHAT...
WHAT BLUE IS AFRAID OF.
AND OUR CLUES ARE A FEATHER...
THIS SHADOW...
AND THIS SOUND: WHOO, WHOO.
HMM, SO WHAT COULD
BLUE BE AFRAID OF
THAT HAS FEATHERS, THIS SHADOW
AND MAKES THE SOUND
"WHOO, WHOO?"
WELL, MAYBE...
MAYBE BLUE'S AFRAID
OF A SHADOW-DANCING FEATHER.
WHOO, WHOO.
NO.
NO, THAT'S NOT SCARY.
WELL, WHAT COULD BLUE
BE AFRAID OF THAT HAS FEATHERS
A SHADOW THAT LOOKS LIKE THIS
AND MAKES THE SOUND
"WHOO, WHOO"?
WELL, A BIRD HAS FEATHERS.
BUT WHAT KIND OF BIRD...
AN OWL!
AN OWL?
AN OWL.
THAT'S IT!
THAT'S BRILLIANT.
AN OWL HAS FEATHERS
AND ITS SHADOW LOOKS LIKE THIS
AND AN OWL MAKES THE SOUND
"WHOO, WHOO."
WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES.
♪ WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ BECAUSE WE'RE REALLY BRAVE!
SO, BLUE, WE FIGURED OUT
WHAT YOU'RE AFRAID OF.
IT'S AN OWL.
THAT'S ALL IT IS.
OH, OKAY, LET'S GO SEE.
HEY, YOU SEE THAT, BLUE?
IT'S THE OWL'S SHADOW
WITH THE EARS AND EVERYTHING.
WHOO, WHOO.
YOU HEAR THAT?
THE OWL'S CALLING
TO YOU, BLUE.
WHOO, WHOO.
PROBABLY WANTS
TO SAY HI.
OH, LOOK,
THE OWL'S FEATHERS.
THAT WAS A CLUE.
BLUE, I'D LIKE
TO INTRODUCE YOU
TO MR. OWL.
MR. OWL,
THIS IS BLUE.
WHOO. HELLO, BLUE.
WHOO.
OH, LOOK.
IT'S MR. SALT
AND MRS. PEPPER.
REMEMBER WHAT WE
DID WITH THEM?
THE PICTURE.
RIGHT.
OH, NO, DON'T
GET TOO... CLOSE.
NEVER FEAR--
SHOVEL AND PAIL
ARE HERE.
WE WANTED TO SEE
THE OWL'S SHADOW.
OH, LOOK...
IT'S BOO!
SO, DID WE ALL MEET
BLUE'S NEW FRIEND,
THE OWL?
All:
HELLO.
WHOO, WHOO.
AND LOOK, BLUE'S
NOT AFRAID ANYMORE.
GOOD JOB.
OH, IT'S TIME.
HEY, THANKS SO MUCH
FOR ALL YOUR HELP TODAY.
♪ NOW IT'S TIME FOR SO LONG
♪ BUT WE'LL SING
JUST ONE MORE SONG ♪
♪ THANKS FOR DOING YOUR PART
♪ YOU SURE ARE SMART
♪ YOU KNOW, WITH ME AND YOU
♪ AND MY DOG, BLUE
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING
♪ THAT WE WANT TO DO.
BYE-BYE! SEE YOU LATER.
BYE.
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING
THAT WE WANT TO DO.♪
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING...♪