HI, OUT THERE!
IT'S ME, STEVE.
HAVE YOU SEEN BLUE, MY PUPPY?
THERE SHE IS!
COME ON IN.
HI.
OH, HELLO.
COME ON IN.
WE'RE WORKING IN THE GARDEN.
WHEW.
OH...
WHICH WAY DID BLUE GO?
THIS WAY?
NO, THAT WAY.
OH, THIS WAY.
THANKS.
LET'S GO FIND HER.
♪ WE ARE GOING
TO THE GARDEN ♪
♪ WE ARE GOING TO THE GARDEN
♪ WE ARE GOING TO THE GARDEN,
TO DO OUR PLANTING WORK, YEAH. ♪
OH, HELLO, SHOVEL.
HELLO, PAIL.
HI, STEVE.
SO, HAVE YOU
SEEN BLUE?
Both:
SHE JUST HELPED
US DIG A HOLE.
UNDER THE PILE OF DIRT.
HEH.
THERE YOU ARE.
WHAT'S WRONG, BLUE?
DO YOU NEED SOMETHING?
OH.
YOU NEED TO WATER THE FLOWERS.
OKAY.
I'LL TURN ON THE WATER.
YOU DON'T NEED
TO WATER THE FLOWERS.
WELL... WHAT DO
YOU NEED TO DO?
OH... OKAY!
WE'LL PLAY "BLUE'S CLUES"!
THAT'S A GREAT IDEA!
I LOVE "BLUE'S CLUES."
♪ WE ARE GONNA PLAY
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ 'CAUSE IT'S A REALLY FUN GAME,
YEAH! ♪
NOW, REMEMBER, BLUE'S PAW PRINTS
WILL BE ON THE CLUES:
BLUE'S CLUES.
OH, I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE THINKING.
WE SHOULD PROBABLY
CLEAN UP FIRST, RIGHT?
OKAY.
NICE AND PRETTY.
I'M READY.
LET'S GO.
OOPS.
I FORGOT.
WE SHOULD PROBABLY
CLEAN THIS UP, TOO.
HEY, WAIT.
YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED
FOR BLUE'S CLUES?
WE NEED OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK!
NOTEBOOK, RIGHT.
COME ON.
BLUE'S CLUES!
I'M SO EXCITED!
OH... HERE IT IS.
HEY, I THINK I'M REALLY
GOING TO NEED YOUR HELP TODAY
FIGURING OUT WHAT BLUE NEEDS.
WILL YOU HELP ME?
YOU WILL?
OH, GOOD.
♪ WE GOT TO FIND THE PAW PRINT,
THAT'S THE FIRST CLUE ♪
♪ WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND NOW WHAT DO WE DO? ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE SECOND CLUE ♪
♪ WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
NOW WHAT DO WE DO? ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE THIRD CLUE ♪
♪ PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND, WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WELL, WE SIT DOWN
IN OUR THINKING CHAIR ♪
♪ AND THINK, THINK, THINK
♪ 'CAUSE WHEN WE USE OUR MINDS,
TAKE A STEP AT A TIME ♪
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING...
♪ THAT WE WANT TO DO.
COME ON.
DID YOU SEE A CLUE?
WHERE?
BEHIND YOU!
WHERE'S THE CLUE?
I CAN'T FIND IT.
HURRY, BEHIND YOU.
QUICK.
OH...
IT'S A... CLUE?
IT IS A CLUE.
YOU KNOW HOW YOU CAN TELL
IT'S A CLUE?
BECAUSE OF THE PAW PRINTS ON IT.
IT'S, IT'S...
BUBBLES.
HEY, YOU KNOW
WHAT WE NEED TO DO NOW?
WRITE IT DOWN
IN OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK!
NOTEBOOK.
JUST DRAW A CIRCLE.
BUBBLE, BUBBLE...
AND BUBBLE.
HMM.
SO, WE NEED TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT BLUE NEEDS.
OUR FIRST CLUE IS BUBBLES.
I WONDER WHAT SHE NEEDS TO DO
WITH BUBBLES.
BLOW BUBBLES?
COUNT THE BUBBLES?
OOPS.
HMM.
WELL, I THINK WE NEED TO LOOK
FOR MORE CLUES
TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT SHE NEEDS TO DO.
Mr. Salt:
STEVE.
Mrs. Pepper:
THAT SOUNDS LIKE OUR FRIENDS.
MR. SALT
AND MRS. PEPPER.
HELLO, MR. SALT
HI, STEVE.
HELLO,
STEVE.
WE NEED
YOUR HELP.
HOW CAN WE HELP YOU?
WE'RE MAKING A FRUIT SALAD
TO HAVE WITH LUNCH.
WE NEED TO WASH
THE FRUIT
BEFORE WE EAT IT.
Both:
WILL YOU HELP FIND THE FRUIT
WE NEED TO WASH?
DO YOU THINK
WE CAN HELP?
OKAY, GREAT.
WE'LL HELP FIND
THE FRUIT TO WASH
AND THEN WE'LL LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
GREAT.
FIRST WE NEED
TO FIND THE FRUIT
THAT IS NEXT
TO THE FRUIT
THAT HAS LEAVES.
LEAVES.
HMM.
WHICH FRUIT HAS LEAVES?
THAT ONE.
IT'S A PINEAPPLE.
OH.
OH, THE PINEAPPLE HAS LEAVES
ON TOP OF IT, SEE?
UM, NOW, WHICH FRUIT
IS NEXT TO IT?
RIGHT THERE.
AN ORANGE.
Mr. Salt:
FANTASTIC!
NOW WE NEED TO FIND THE FRUIT
THAT IS FARTHEST AWAY
FROM THE FRUIT
WITH THE MOST
SEEDS.
CAN YOU FIND THE FRUIT
THAT'S FARTHEST AWAY
FROM THE FRUIT
WITH THE MOST SEEDS?
THAT ONE.
IT'S RIGHT THERE.
OH.
OH, THE WATERMELON IS FARTHEST
AWAY FROM THE STRAWBERRY
THE FRUIT WITH THE MOST SEEDS.
♪ WE HAVE THE MOST SEEDS,
WE HAVE THE MOST SEEDS. ♪
GREAT!GREAT!
NOW WE NEED
TO FIND THE FRUIT
IN BETWEEN A FRUIT
WITH A LEAF
AND A FRUIT
WITH A STEM.
CAN YOU FIND A FRUIT
IN BETWEEN THE FRUIT
WITH A LEAF
AND A FRUIT WITH A STEM?
THAT ONE.
WHAT, THIS ONE?
THE KIWI?
KIWI!
GREAT JOB.
NOW WE CAN LOOK FOR MORE...
...BLUE'S CLUES
SO I DON'T GET SPLASHED ANYMORE.
♪ MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME,
MAIL TIME ♪
♪ MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME!
HEY, BLUE, THE MAIL'S HERE.
♪ HERE'S THE MAIL,
IT NEVER FAILS ♪
♪ IT MAKES ME WANT
TO WAG MY TAIL ♪
♪ WHEN IT COMES,
I WANT TO WAIL, "MAIL!" ♪
MAIL'S HERE,
MAIL'S HERE.
I GOT ONE
FOR YOU
'CAUSE THAT'S
ME, MAIL.
HELLO, MAILBOX.
HI, STEVE.
HAVE I GOT
A LETTER
FOR YOU.
THANK YOU.
♪ YOU'RE
WELCOME. ♪
WE JUST GOT A LETTER.
♪ WE JUST GOT A LETTER
♪ WONDER WHO IT'S FROM?
OOH, IT'S A LETTER
FROM MY FRIENDS.
Both: HI, STEVE.
WE'RE BRUSHING OUR TEETH.
I DO SIDE TO SIDE...
AND UP AND DOWN.
I BRUSH MY TONGUE, TOO.
THEY'RE ALL CLEAN, SEE?
BYE, STEVE.
BYE.
MMM... TINGLY.
HEY, WE BETTER GET BACK
TO FINDING BLUE'S CLUES.
WHERE DID BLUE GO, ANYWAY?
OH.
THAT WAS MY SOCK.
OH, NO.
MY LAUNDRY
IS ALL OVER THE PLACE.
NO, LAUNDRY,NOT A CLUE.
OH.... OH!
DID YOU SEE A CLUE?
YES!
WHERE?
BEHIND YOU.
OH, OH, OH, OH.
IT'S A CLUE!
A CLUE!
IT'S A...
A TOWEL.
WELL, THIS TOWEL
IS ONE OF BLUE'S CLUES.
YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED,
OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK.
ALL RIGHT.
SO, LET'S DRAW OUR SECOND CLUE.
A TOWEL.
OKAY.
A LINE HERE.
WAVY LINE.
AND WE HAVE A TOWEL.
HMM.
SO WHAT DOES BLUE NEED?
OUR FIRST CLUE WAS...
BUBBLES.
BUBBLES, RIGHT.
AND NOW OUR SECOND CLUE
IS A TOWEL.
HMM.
SO WHAT DOES BLUE NEED TO DO
WITH BUBBLES AND A TOWEL?
HMM...
WE'RE GOING TO NEED
TO FIND ONE MORE CLUE.
DON'T YOU THINK?
HMM... BUBBLES AND A TOWEL.
YUP, YOU SAID IT.
WE MADE A MESS.
WELL, LET'S CLEAN THIS UP.
AND THEN WE CAN LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
LOOK.
IT'S WASHER,
OUR WASHING MACHINE.
HELLO, WASHER.
HI, STEVE, HI, BLUE.
WE REALLY NEED
TO SORT THESE CLOTHES.
YEAH, AND CLOTHES GO...
OH.
AND HERE COMES IRONING BOARD.
AND DRESSER.
HUDDLE UP.
HERE'S THE PLAN.
I'LL TAKE THE
STAINED CLOTHES
AND WASH THEM.
THEN THE STAIN
WILL COME OUT.
Ironing Board:
GIVE ME THE WRINKLED CLOTHES
AND I'LL IRON THEM.
THEN THEY WON'T
BE WRINKLED.
AND I'LL PUT ALL
THE CLEAN STUFF AWAY.
THEN WE WON'T
HAVE A MESS.
LET'S GO.
FALL IN.
WILL YOU HELP US?
GREAT.
Steve:
WHERE DO THESE PANTS GO?
NO.
IN THE DRESSER.
Dresser:
CLEAN AND UNWRINKLED PANTS
ARE READY TO BE PUT AWAY.
GREAT JOB.
AND WHERE DO WE PUT
THIS T-SHIRT?
NO.
YES!
Ironing Board:
JUST HOW I LIKE THEM, WRINKLED.
GOOD JOB!
UH...
HOW ABOUT THIS SHIRT?
NO.
YES!
LOVE THOSE
STAINED CLOTHES.
FANTASTIC,
NOW ALL THE CLOTHES ARE SORTED.
THANK YOU FOR GIVING US
ALL OUR CLOTHES.
WELL, YOU'RE WELCOME.
WOW.
YOU WERE GREAT.
THANKS FOR HELPING.
NOW WE CAN GO LOOK...
OKAY, WHERE IS ALL THIS WATER
COMING FROM?
OVER HERE.
WHO WAS THAT?
SPLASHING, SPLASHING, SPLASHING.
A LOT OF SPLASHING.
HMM, WHERE IS THAT VOICE
COMING FROM?
Starfish:
ME!
HELLO, STARFISH.
HI, STEVE.
HI, BLUE.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
WILL YOU HELP ME?
OF COURSE WE'LL HELP YOU.
YOU READY TO HELP STARFISH?
♪ BLUE SKIDDOO, WE CAN, TOO!
WOW.
WHAT A BEAUTIFUL BEACH.
HI, STEVE.
HI, BLUE.
HELLO, STARFISH.
HOW CAN WE HELP YOU?
CAN YOU HELP ME
FIND THE OCEAN?
I NEED TO WASH
ALL THIS SAND OFF
IN THE OCEAN
BUT I CAN'T FIND IT.
WILL YOU HELP ME?
CAN YOU HELP STARFISH
FIND THE OCEAN?
OKAY, GREAT.
LET'S GO.
Starfish:
OH, NO, WHICH WAY DO WE GO?
HMM, WHICH WAY
SHOULD THEY GO?
THAT WAY!
OH, THAT WAY?
TO THE LEFT?
OKAY.
Starfish:
OH, NO.
WHICH WAY DO WE GO?
NOW WHICH WAY
SHOULD THEY GO?
DOWN.
YEAH, DOWN.
OH, THAT WAY, GOING DOWN.
OKAY.
Starfish:
OKAY, WE'LL GO DOWN.
OH, NO, WHICH WAY DO WE GO?
WHICH WAY SHOULD
THEY GO NOW?
THAT WAY.
GO THAT WAY.
OH, THAT WAY,
TO THE RIGHT.
OKAY.
Starfish:
OKAY, WE'LL GO TO THE RIGHT.
HEY.
THE OCEAN!
WE FOUND THE OCEAN!
YEAH.
YOU WERE RIGHT,
YOU FOUND THE EXIT.
EXCELLENT.
OOH.
I'M CLEAN!
THANKS FOR HELPING ME.
GREAT. NOW WE CAN LOOK
FOR OUR LAST BLUE'S CLUE
TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT BLUE NEEDS TO DO.
THANKS, STEVE.
BYE.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE BACK.
NOW WE GOT TO FIND
ONE MORE CLUE.
A CLUE.
WHAT WAS THAT?
CLUE?
DID YOU SEE A CLUE?
WHERE'S THE CLUE?
IT'S OUR FRIEND,
SLIPPERY SOAP.
HE'S A BAR OF SOAP.
HI, SLIPPERY.
HI, STEVE.
I WAS DREAMING THAT BLUE
CAME UP TO ME AND THEN...
A CLUE!
A CLUE.
YOU'RE A CLUE, SLIPPERY.
YOU'RE ONE OF BLUE'S CLUES.
I'M A CLUE, I'M A CLUE!
AND WHAT DO WE DO
WITH OUR CLUES?
NOTEBOOK!
WE'LL DRAW IN
OUR SUPER-DUPER,
HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK!
NOTEBOOK.
I'M SO PROUD.
ALL RIGHT, SLIPPERY.
HOLD STILL FOR A MINUTE.
A CURVE HERE.
A CURVE THERE.
THERE.
AND THERE.
HAH.
PRETTY GOOD LIKENESS.
NOW, WE HAVE OUR THIRD CLUE,
SLIPPERY SOAP.
A BAR OF SOAP.
HEY, HEY, WE HAVE
ALL THREE CLUES.
YOU KNOW WHAT IT'S TIME FOR?
THINKING CHAIR!
RIGHT, IT'S TIME FOR OUR...
THINKING CHAIR.
COME ON.
NOW THAT WE'RE IN
OUR THINKING CHAIR...
LET'S THINK.
NOW, WE NEED TO THINK
ABOUT WHAT BLUE NEEDS TO DO.
HMM.
OUR CLUES ARE BUBBLES...
A TOWEL...
AND...
SOAP.
HMM.
NOW WHAT WOULD BLUE NEED TO DO
WITH BUBBLES, A TOWEL AND SOAP?
OH, WELL, DOES SHE NEED
TO PUT THE BUBBLES
BETWEEN THE TOWEL AND THE SOAP
AND, AND MAKE A BUBBLE SANDWICH?
NO.
WELL, WHAT WOULD YOU DO
WITH BUBBLES, A TOWEL AND SOAP?
A BATH!
BATH?
BATH!
THAT'S IT!
OF COURSE!
BLUE NEEDS TO TAKE A BATH.
SHE'S DIRTY, SO SHE NEEDS
TO TAKE A BATH, WITH BUBBLES
AND USE SOAP TO CLEAN HERSELF
AND DRY HERSELF OFF
WITH A TOWEL.
WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES!
♪ WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE JUST FIGURED
OUT BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ BECAUSE WE'RE REALLY SMART.
BLUE, I'M GOING TO GET
A TOWEL, SOAP
AND GET YOUR BUBBLE BATH READY.
HEY... WOW.
LOOK AT ALL THESE BUBBLES.
HEY, LOOK WHO'S HERE.
IT'S MR. SALT AND MRS. PEPPER.
REMEMBER HOW WE HELPED THEM
FIND THE FRUITS TO WASH?
Salt and Pepper:
CAREFUL!
OH, LOOK, IT'S WASHER.
LEAVE YOUR CLOTHES FOR ME,
SO I CAN GIVE THEM A BATH.
OH, HELLO, STARFISH.
REMEMBER WHERE WE MET HER?
THE OCEAN.
RIGHT, AT THE OCEAN.
OH, HEY, SLIPPERY.
HEY, MR. SALT
AND MRS. PEPPER
WATCH OVER THESE GUYS
FOR A SECOND.
BATH TIME.
HEY, THANKS SO MUCH
FOR ALL YOUR HELP TODAY.
♪ NOW IT'S TIME
FOR SO LONG ♪
♪ BUT WE'LL SING
JUST ONE MORE SONG ♪
♪ THANKS FOR DOING YOUR PART
♪ YOU SURE ARE SMART
♪ YOU KNOW, WITH ME AND YOU
♪ AND MY DOG, BLUE
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING
♪ THAT WE WANT TO DO.
BYE-BYE.
SEE YOU LATER.
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING
THAT WE WANT TO DO!♪
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING!♪