HI, OUT THERE!
IT'S ME, STEVE.
HAVE YOU SEEN BLUE, MY PUPPY?
THERE SHE IS!
COME ON IN.
[ barking...]
HI.
WE'RE PUTTING BLUE'S TOYS AWAY.
[ barking]
OH... WILL YOU HELP US?
YOU WILL?
WELL, THANK YOU.
THAT'S VERY NICE OF YOU.
COME ON.
WELL, BLUE,
IT LOOKS LIKE
YOU'RE DONE
PUTTING YOUR TOYS AWAY.
[ barks]
WHAT WAS THAT?
A BALL.
OH, YOU SEE ANOTHER TOY?
WHERE?
BEHIND YOU.
[ barks]
GOOD WORK, BLUE.
THANKS.
WELL... WE JUST HAD
CLEANUP TIME.
WHAT TIME IS IT NOW?
HMM...
HEY, BLUE, DON'T WE ALWAYS
DO SOMETHING EVERY DAY
RIGHT AFTER CLEANUP TIME?
[ barks "mm-hmm"]
OH, OKAY!
WE'LL PLAY "BLUE'S CLUES"
TO FIGURE OUT WHAT TIME IT IS.
I LOVE "BLUE'S CLUES."
♪ WE ARE GOING TO PLAY
BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ 'CAUSE IT'S
A REALLY FUN GAME, YEAH! ♪
ARE YOU READY?
OOH, REMEMBER--
BLUE'S PAW PRINTS WILL BE
ON THE CLUES: BLUE'S CLUES.
OH... WELL, SINCE
WE JUST HAD CLEANUP TIME
GUESS WE BETTER
CLEAN THIS UP, TOO.
THERE WE GO,
MAKE IT ALL NICE AND CLEAN.
[ both sneeze]
OH!
YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED
FOR BLUE'S CLUES:
OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK!
RIGHT, NOTEBOOK.
COME ON.
BLUE'S CLUES,
I'M SO EXCITED.
OH... HERE IT IS.
HEY, YOU KNOW, I CAN TELL I'M
REALLY GOING TO NEED YOUR HELP
FIGURING OUT WHAT IT'S TIME FOR.
WILL YOU HELP ME?
YOU WILL?
GREAT!
♪ WE GOT TO FIND A PAW PRINT,
THAT'S THE FIRST CLUE ♪
♪ WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND NOW WHAT DO WE DO? ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE SECOND CLUE ♪
♪ WE PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
NOW WHAT DO WE DO? ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WE GOT TO FIND ANOTHER PAW
PRINT, THAT'S THE THIRD CLUE ♪
♪ PUT IT IN OUR NOTEBOOK,
AND, WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO ♪
♪ BLUE'S CLUES, BLUE'S CLUES
♪ BLUE'S CLUES!♪
♪ WELL, WE SIT DOWN
IN OUR THINKING CHAIR ♪
♪ AND THINK, THINK, THINK
♪ 'CAUSE WHEN WE USE OUR MINDS,
TAKE A STEP AT A TIME ♪
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING...
[ barks]
♪ THAT WE WANT TO DO.
BLUE!
BLUE?
DID YOU SEE
WHICH WAY BLUE WENT?
THAT WAY.
OKAY.
♪ WE ARE LOOKING
FOR BLUE'S CLUES ♪
♪ WE ARE
LOOKING FOR BLUE'S CLUES... ♪
A CLUE!
OH.
OH, A CLUE!
WHERE?
BEHIND YOU.
OH, OH, IT'S A CLUE!
IT'S A BLANKET.
YOU KNOW HOW YOU CAN TELL
THIS BLANKET IS A CLUE?
IT'S GOT BLUE'S PAW PRINTS
ALL OVER IT!
HEY, HEY,
WE NEED OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK.
OKAY, WE'VE GOT
A LINE ON THE TOP.
TWO CURVY LINES
FOR THE SIDES.
AND THE DOTS.
AND THERE IS THE BLANKET.
SO, A BLANKET.
HMM.
WHAT DO YOU THINK IT'S TIME FOR?
IS IT TIME FOR BLUE
TO HIDE UNDER THE BLANKET?
NO.
WELL, I THINK WE'LL HAVE TO
KEEP AN EYE OUT
FOR TWO MORE BLUE'S CLUES.
DO YOU HEAR SOMETHING?
TICKITY, TOCK,
TICKITY, TOCK...
TICKITY TOCK.
IT MUST BE OUR FRIEND,
[ tick-tocking...]
IT IS OUR FRIEND
TICKITY TOCK.
YOU KNOW,
SHE'S AN ALARM CLOCK.
HELLO, TICKITY TOCK!
[ gasps]
I AM SO SORRY,
TICKITY TOCK.
I DIDN'T REALIZE
YOU WERE SLEEPING.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT,
STEVE.
WELL, IT LOOKS LIKE
SOME OF YOUR PIECES FLEW OFF.
YES, CAN YOU HELP ME
PUT THEM BACK ON?
CAN YOU HELP FIND TICKITY TOCK'S
PIECES AND PUT THEM BACK ON?
YOU WILL?
YES, TICKITY TOCK,
I THINK WE CAN DO THAT.
OH, NO! THEY'RE MIXED UP
WITH ALL THOSE OTHER
THINGS IN THE DRAWER!
CAN YOU HELP BLUE FIND
TICKITY TOCK'S HANDS FIRST?
I NEED THEM TO POINT OUT
WHAT TIME IT IS, STEVE.
[ barks]
NO.
YES.
MY HANDS!
BUT NOW I HAVE NOTHING
TO POINT AT TO TELL THE TIME.
CAN YOU HELP FIND
WHAT TICKITY TOCK POINTS AT
TO TELL THE TIME?
[ barks]
NO.
NO!
[ barks]
YES!
[ barking]
MY NUMBERS, THEY'RE ALL HERE!
THANKS,
BUT I DON'T HEAR ANYTHING.
I NEED SOMETHING
TO MAKE NOISE WITH.
CAN YOU HELP FIND WHAT
TICKITY TOCK MAKES NOISE WITH?
[ barks]
NO!
YES!
YEAH, THE ALARM BELL.
[ bells ringing]
I'VE GOT MY HANDS,
AND ALL 12 NUMBERS TO POINT AT.
ONE, TWO, THREE
FOUR, FIVE,
SIX, SEVEN, EIGHT
NINE, TEN,
ELEVEN, TWELVE!
I'VE GOT MY ALARM BELLS.
THANKS FOR PUTTING ME
BACK TOGETHER.
WELL, YOU'RE WELCOME,
TICKITY TOCK.
YOU DID A GREAT JOB.
AND THANKS, BL...
BLUE?
I THINK BLUE'S
GONE TO THE CLOSET.
OH, THANKS, TICKITY TOCK.
BLUE? BLUE?
[ barks]
OH!
HEY, BLUE.
[ barks "hello"]
OOH... LOOKS LIKE WE DIDN'T
FINISH CLEANUP TIME AFTER ALL.
SO, LET'S CLEAN THIS UP
AND THEN WE CAN LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES
AND FIGURE OUT
WHAT TIME IT IS.
HEY...
LOOKS LIKE SOMETHING'S MISSING
FROM THAT HANGER.
WELL, WHAT DO YOU THINK
IT COULD BE?
WELL, LET'S SEE.
WE HAVE STEVE'S PAJAMAS,
STEVE'S PAJAMAS, STEVE'S PAJAMAS
AND BLUE'S PAJAMAS,
BLUE'S PAJAMAS AND...
WHAT COMES NEXT?
[ barks]
BLUE'S PAJAMAS.
COOL.
BLUE'S PAJAMAS
BELONG THERE.
HEY, LOOKS LIKE
SOME SHOES ARE MISSING.
DO YOU SEE WHICH ONES?
WELL, LET'S SEE.
WE HAVE STEVE'S BOOTS,
STEVE'S SNEAKERS,
STEVE'S SLIPPERS...
AND WE HAVE BLUE'S BOOTS
AND... WHAT COMES NEXT?
[ barks]
BLUE'S SNEAKERS.
GOOD WORK.
WELL... LOOKS LIKE
EVERYTHING IS IN PLACE.
DON'T FORGET US!
SORRY.
[ barks]
YOU KNOW, YOU'RE RIGHT.
I DON'T THINK WE'RE DONE YET.
LOOKS LIKE ONE OF BLUE'S
BEDTIME TOYS IS MISSING.
WHAT'S SUPPOSED
TO GO NEXT?
WELL, LET'S SEE.
WE HAVE STUFFED ANIMAL, DOLL...
STUFFED ANIMAL, DOLL...
WHAT'S SUPPOSED TO GO NEXT?
BEAR.
BEAR STUFFED ANIMAL.
WHAT? OH!
YOU THINK IT'S
THE BEAR STUFFED ANIMAL.
HMM...
[ bear squeaks]
OH!
THANKS.
YOU KNOW, YOU REALLY
ARE VERY GOOD AT THIS.
HEY, LET'S GO LOOK
FOR MORE BLUE'S CLUES
SO WE CAN FIND OUT WHAT
COMES AFTER CLEANUP TIME.
RIGHT, BLUE?
BLUE?
A CLUE!
WHAT?
YOU SEE A CLUE?
WHERE?
RIGHT BEHIND THE BOOKS.
[ book humming]
WHERE?
[ book humming and laughing]
[ chuckles, clears throat]
IT'S A BOOK.
IT'S A CLUE!
WE NEED OUR HANDY-DANDY...
NOTEBOOK.
DRAW A COUPLE OF LINES
FOR THE SIDES...
A RECTANGLE...
AND LINES FOR THE PAGES...
AND NOW WE HAVE...
A BOOK!
HMM.
BLUE'S CLUES ARE GOING TO
TELL US WHAT IT IS TIME FOR.
OUR FIRST CLUE WAS...
A BLANKET.
OH, A BLANKET, RIGHT.
AND NOW WE HAVE A... BOOK.
AND WE NEED TO KNOW
WHAT TIME IT IS.
WELL, WHAT DOES BLUE WANT
WITH A BLANKET AND A BOOK?
OH, IS IT BLANKET AND BOOK TIME?
NO!
WELL, I THINK WE NEED
TO LOOK FOR ONE MORE BLUE'S CLUE
TO FIND OUT WHAT TIME IT IS.
BUT WE GOT TO FIND BLUE FIRST.
HMM... I THOUGHT
I HEARD BLUE IN THERE.
RIGHT THERE!
HA!
♪ MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME,
MAIL TIME! ♪
♪ MAIL TIME, MAIL TIME!
THE MAIL'S HERE!
♪ HERE'S THE MAIL,
IT NEVER FAILS ♪
♪ IT MAKES ME WANT
TO WAG MY TAIL ♪
♪ WHEN IT COMES,
I WANT TO WAIL, "MAIL!" ♪
[ barks]
MAIL'S HERE, MAIL'S IN.
DON'T MISS IT--
IT'S THE MAIL!
THANK YOU, MAILBOX.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
WE JUST GOT A LETTER.
♪ WE JUST GOT A LETTER
♪ WE JUST
GOT A LETTER ♪
♪ WE JUST GOT A LETTER
♪ I WONDER WHO IT'S FROM.
HMM...
HI, STEVE.
OH, IT'S FROM OUR FRIENDS.
THESE ARE
MY FAVORITE TIMES OF THE DAY.
MUSIC TIME.
I CAN BANG REALLY HARD.
I LOVE PLAY TIME.
I HAVE APPLE JUICE.
I CAN OPEN IT ALL BY MYSELF.
LUNCH TIME!
THOSE ARE MY FAVORITE TIMES,
BYE.
THANKS, EVERYBODY.
I LOVE ALL THOSE TIMES,
DON'T YOU?
HEY, YOU KNOW,
WE STILL HAVE TO FIND OUT
WHAT IT'S TIME FOR RIGHT NOW
SO KEEP AN EYE OUT
FOR OUR LAST BLUE'S CLUE
SO WE CAN...
[ bird hooting]
WHAT IS THAT SOUND?
[ animal chattering]
HEY, BLUE, WHERE'S THAT SOUND
COMING FROM?
[ barking
"Blue Skiddoo"]
WOW, DID YOU SEE THAT?
THERE GOES BLUE!
♪ BLUE SKIDDOO, WE CAN, TOO.
WHOA.
WHOA...
WE'RE IN THE JUNGLE.
THE MIGHTY JUNGLE.
COOL...
OH...
HELLO, LION PRINCE.
HEY, STEVE.
WHAT'S UP?
YOU HAVE TO HELP ME.
I THINK THREE
OF THE ANIMALS
ARE HIDING
[ whispers]:
EVEN THOUGH THEY KNOW
WHAT TIME IT IS.
HOW COULD WE HELP?
IF WE MAKE
THE SAME NOISE
THE ANIMALS MAKE
THEY'LL COME OUT.
WILL YOU HELP
THE LION PRINCE?
YOU WILL? COOL.
UH, YES, SIR,
MR. LION PRINCE, SIR.
WE CAN HELP YOU FIND
THE ANIMALS.
WAIT. LOOK
INTO THE JUNGLE
AND LISTEN
FOR THEIR SOUNDS.
[ frog croaking]
CAN YOU MAKE THE SAME NOISE
AS THE ANIMAL?
RIBBIT, RIBBIT...
[ frog croaking]
HEY, I THINK
IT'S WORKING.
LOUDER. CAN YOU MAKE
THE SOUNDS LOUDER?
THEN THE ANIMAL
WILL COME OUT.
RIBBIT, RIBBIT...
DO YOU SEE THEM? WHICH ONE
OF THE ANIMALS IS IT?
THE FROG!
WHERE?
[ frog croaking]
OH! A FROG!
OH, GREAT.
WE FOUND YOU.
OUTSTANDING!
BUT WE HAVE TWO MORE
ANIMALS TO FIND.
[ barks]
OOH, I THINK BLUE
HEARS ANOTHER ANIMAL.
COME ON.
[ elephant trumpets]
DO YOU HEAR THAT?
CAN YOU MAKE
THE SAME NOISE
AS HER?
[ elephant trumpets]
[ trumpeting]
HEY, YOU ARE
SO GOOD AT THIS.
DO YOU SEE HER?
[ elephant trumpets]
CAN YOU SEE
WHICH ANIMAL
IT IS?
A ELEPHANT.
AN ELEPHANT?
YEAH.
WHERE? WHERE?
[ trumpets]
OH! OH, IT IS
AN ELEPHANT.
ELEPHANT,
WE FOUND YOU.
MAGNIFICENT!
ONLY ONE MORE ANIMAL
LEFT TO FIND.
[ monkey chattering]
CAN YOU MAKE THE NOISE
OF THE ANIMAL?
OOH-OOH...
OOH-OOH, AH-AH.
OOH-OOH, AH-AH-AH.
HEY, HEY, THAT'S GREAT.
I THINK IT'S WORKING.
LOUDER!
AH-AH! AH-AH!
OOH-OOH-OOH...
DO YOU SEE HIM?
WHICH ONE OF THE ANIMALS
IS IT?
A MONKEY!
A MONKEY?
WHERE?
[ monkey chattering]
IN THE TREE!
OH, OH, IT IS A MONKEY!
MONKEY!
WE FOUND YOU!
[ chattering]
THANKS FOR HELPING ME
FIND ALL THE ANIMALS.
HEY, NO PROBLEM,
LION PRINCE.
GREAT JOB.
[ rhythmic croaking,
trumpeting, chattering]
♪ RIBBIT, [ trumpets],
OOH-OOH-AH-AH-AH-AH ♪
♪ RIBBIT,
[ trumpets],
OOH-OOH-AH-AH-AH-AH ♪
COME ON, DO IT WITH ME.
IT'S KIND OF FUN.
♪ RIBBIT, [ trumpets],
OOH-OOH-AH-AH-AH-AH ♪
♪ RIBBIT,
[ trumpets],
OOH-OOH-AH-AH-AH-AH. ♪
HEY, YOU KNOW, WE STILL HAVE
TO FIND OUR LAST CLUE
SO WE CAN FIGURE OUT
WHAT TIME IT IS IN OUR HOUSE.
COME ON.
[ humming "Blue Skiddoo"]
OOH, OOH, AH, AH, AH, AH.... AH.
WOW.
WHAT A JUMP.
WHAT?
A CLUE!
OH... OH!
YOU SEE A CLUE?
YOU SEE ANOTHER BLUE'S CLUE?
WHERE?
BEHIND YOU.
OVER THERE.
OH, RIGHT.
THANKS.
BLUE'S PAW PRINTS
ARE ON THIS PILLOW.
IT'S ANOTHER CLUE.
IT'S OUR THIRD BLUE'S CLUE.
YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED?
OUR HANDY-DANDY NOTEBOOK!
OKAY...
A CURVY LINE ON THIS SIDE...
AROUND THE BOTTOM...
TO THE TOP...
OVAL SHAPE HERE...
AND WE HAVE A PILLOW.
A PILLOW!
HEY...
HEY, WHEN WE HAVE ALL THREE
CLUES, WE'RE READY FOR OUR...
THINKING CHAIR!
AHA.
HERE WE ARE,
IN THE THINKING CHAIR.
LET'S THINK.
OKAY, SO... WE NEED TO FIGURE
OUT WHAT TIME IT IS FOR BLUE.
BLUE'S CLUES ARE A...
A BLANKET.
BLANKET.
A...
BOOK.
BOOK, RIGHT.
AND A PILLOW.
HMM.
AND WE NEED TO KNOW
WHAT TIME IT IS.
OH, OH, OH!
IS, IS IT TIME FOR BLUE
TO WRAP THE PILLOW IN A BLANKET
AND READ IT A STORY?
NO!
[ barking]
OKAY.
WELL, WELL, WHAT TIME IS IT
WHEN YOU HAVE A BOOK,
A BLANKET AND A PILLOW?
NAP TIME!
NAP, NAP! YES!
IT'S BLUE'S NAP TIME!
SHE WANTS A PILLOW
TO REST HER HEAD ON
SHE WANTS A BLANKET
TO KEEP HER WARM
AND SHE WANTS ME
TO READ HER A STORY
TO HELP HER GET TO SLEEP.
HEY, WE JUST FIGURED OUT
BLUE'S CLUES!
[ lullaby]:
♪ WE HAVE JUST FIGURED OUT
♪ THAT BLUE... [ Blue yawns]
WANTS HER NAP NOW ♪
♪ YES, THE CLUES
TOLD US THAT... ♪
[ yawning]:
♪ BLUE WANTS TO NAP.
[ barks]
HEY, BLUE!
WE NEED TO GET
YOUR PILLOW
AND YOUR BLANKET
AND YOUR FAVORITE BOOK!
[ barking...]
HEY, BLUE, I SEE YOU'VE GOT
YOUR PILLOW AND YOUR BLANKET.
LET'S SIT DOWN
AND READ YOUR FAVORITE STORY.
HEY, IT'S TICKITY TOCK.
I CAN TELL YOU
WHAT TIME IT IS.
IT'S BLUE'S NAP TIME.
WHAT A COINCIDENCE,
TICKITY TOCK...
WE JUST
FIGURED THAT OUT, TOO.
YOU KNOW, WE'RE JUST ABOUT
TO READ A NAP-TIME STORY BOOK.
[ frog croaking]
UH-OH.
[ elephant trumpeting,
monkey chattering]
WHAT'S THAT NOISE?
[ rhythmic croaking,
trumpeting, chattering]
IT'S THE JUNGLE ANIMALS!
WELL, COME ON IN!
PULL UP A CARPET.
WE'RE ABOUT TO READ
A NAP-TIME STORY BOOK.
[ clears throat]
IT'S CALLED A PUPPY'S DAY.
[ Blue oohing,
monkey chattering]
"ONCE UPON A TIME,
THERE WAS A LITTLE PUPPY
WHO WANTED TO TAKE A NAP.
"BUT, SHE COULDN'T GET ANYONE
TO FIGURE OUT WHAT SHE WANTED
SO... SHE RAN AROUND THE HOUSE
LEAVING CLUES."
HMM...
THIS SOUNDS FAMILIAR.
"THE PUPPY LEFT A CLUE
ON A BLANKET.
ON A BOOK.
AND THEN SHE LEFT A CLUE
ON A PILLOW."
HEY, WAIT A MINUTE.
THIS IS THE STORY
OF WHAT HAPPENED TODAY.
I BET YOU KNOW
WHAT COMES NEXT, DON'T YOU?
YEAH.
"AND THEN WE FIGURED OUT THAT
IT WAS THE PUPPY'S NAP TIME."
THE END.
[ all snoring...]
GOOD BOOK.
[ snoring continues...]
[ quietly ]:
IT LOOKS LIKE EVERYONE
IS SLEEPING.
YOU KNOW, YOU'VE BEEN
SUCH A BIG HELP TODAY.
[ quietly:]
♪ NOW IT'S TIME FOR SO LONG
♪ BUT WE'LL SING
JUST ONE MORE SONG ♪
♪ THANKS FOR DOING YOUR PART
♪ YOU SURE ARE SMART
♪ YOU KNOW, WITH ME AND YOU
♪ AND MY DOG, BLUE
[ yawning]:
♪ WE CAN DO ANYTHING
♪ THAT WE WANT TO DO.
[ yawning]:
SHH...
[ barks softly]