Use the free code JOINNOW at
www.playships.eu
This is a story from long ago,
when the great mammoths
still roamed our lands.
It's the story
of my two brothers and me.
When the three of us were young,
we were taught
that the world is full of magic.
The source of this magic
is the ever-changing lights
that dance across the sky.
The shaman woman of our village
told us that these lights
are the spirits of our ancestors,
and that they have the power
to make changes in our world.
Small things become big.
Winter turns to spring.
One thing always changes
into another.
But the greatest change I ever saw
was that of my brother,
a boy who desperately
wanted to be a man.
- Get down.
- What?
Get down! Get down!
Kenai.
Never try to milk a caribou.
No. No, don't. No. Come on, don't. No.
Hey. Will you two knock it off?
That's all right.
After today, he won't treat me like that.
Right, the big manhood ceremony.
Doesn't matter what the spirits say,
you'll always be our baby brother.
- Well, wait till I get my totem.
- Baby brother.
Hey, I said knock it off.
The quicker we get these fish,
the faster we get to your ceremony.
Let's all just try and get along
for a few hours. Okay, Denahi?
- Whatever you say.
- Okay, Ken...
So, what are we waiting for?
When the Earth was young
and the air was sweet
And the mountains kissed the sky
In the great beyond
With its many paths
Man and nature lived side by side
In this wilderness of danger and beauty
Lived three brothers bonded by love
Their hearts full ofjoy
They ask now for guidance
Reaching out to the skies up above
Great spirits of all who lived before
Take our hands and lead us
Fill our hearts and souls
with all you know
Show us that in your eyes
We are all the same
Brothers to each other
in this world we remain
Truly brothers all the same
Give us wisdom to pass to each other
And give us strength so we understand
That the things we do
The choices we make
Give direction to all life's plans
To look and wonder
at all we've been given
In a world that's not always as it seems
Every corner we turn
Only leads to another
A journey ends but another begins
Great spirits of all who lived before
Take our hands and lead us
Fill our hearts and souls
with all you know
Show us that in your eyes
We are all the same
Brothers to each other
in this world we remain
Truly brothers all the same
- Kenai's back.
- Kenai.
Kenai, are you excited
about getting your spirit rock today?
It's not a rock. It'll be my totem.
I'll probably get a sabre-tooth tiger
for bravery,
or strength, or greatness.
- Something that fits me.
- A mammoth for your fat head?
- Make sure you get that basket tied up.
- Don't worry.
No stupid bear
is gonna get near this fish.
Just tie it up.
- She's back. Tanana's back.
- Come on.
- Come on, Kenai, let's go.
Tanana's got your rock. Come on.
Great spirits of all who lived before
Take our hands and lead us
Fill our hearts and souls
with all you know
Show us that in your eyes
We are all the same
Brothers to each other
in this world we remain
Truly brothers all the same
Brothers all the same
Nana.
- Hey, Nana.
- Well, hello there, sweetheart.
What a big girl.
When each of us comes of age,
the great spirits reveal to us a totem
that helps guide us through our lives.
Some of us use courage to guide us.
Others patience.
And some of us beauty.
Kenai.
- You nervous?
- Excited.
You should be. It's a good one.
Kenai, I have been to the mountain
where the lights touch the earth,
and the great spirits
have revealed to me your totem.
To become a man, your actions
must be guided by one thing.
Your totem is...
Love.
- What?
- Yes, love.
The bear of love?
A love that connects
and unites all living things.
- Who wants to trade?
- There is no trading.
Oh, Kenai,
love is the most precious of totems.
It reveals itself in unexpected ways.
Let love guide your actions,
then one day you'll be a man,
and we'll place your mark
next to those of our ancestors.
There he is.
Come here, lover boy.
- Leave me alone.
- Kenai, wait.
- I'm sorry.
- What?
Your totem, I think it's really great.
- You do?
- Yeah. And I made you something.
Really?
Now when you skip around
loving everybody,
you'll smell so sweet.
Well, isn't this nice?
Instead of fighting,
you're giving each other flowers.
Yeah, isn't it lovely?
He's so in touch with his totem already.
Hey, dog breath,
go take care of the fish.
Sure. Kenai loves me, he loves me not.
Kenai loves me, he loves me not.
Kenai loves me, he loves...
- Kenai.
- Someday I'm gonna just...
- He's just such a...
- Hey, bonehead.
Just because his totem is wisdom
doesn't mean he's wise.
- I mean, look at him.
- Kenai loves me, he loves me not.
- Hi, Denahi.
- Hi.
Let go!
Yeah, the spirits messed up
on both of our totems.
I felt the same way
when Tanana gave me mine.
- Get out of here.
- No, really.
I said, "The eagle of guidance?
What does that mean?"
But now that I'm older,
I know it's about being a leader
and keeping an eye on you two.
I just want to get my handprint
on that wall.
Just be patient, Kenai.
When you live by your totem, you will.
- Really?
- Guarantee it.
But come on, the bear of love?
I mean, a bear doesn't love anyone.
They don't think. They don't feel.
I mean, they're...
- They're thieves.
- You didn't tie it up, did you?
You should get the totem of pinheads.
Knock it off.
- We'll just make another basket.
- We?
Oh, no. It took me two weeks
to make that basket.
Get lover boy to do it.
He's the one always messing things up.
- Typical Kenai.
- All right, I'll go get your basket.
Kenai, wait. Kenai!
What?
Kenai!
- Where'd he go?
- If we're lucky, far away.
Kenai!
- Kenai.
- Sitka, no, you gotta get out of here.
- What?
- The bear. Behind you.
Hey, bear, come on. Over here.
Come on, bear, come this way.
Denahi!
- Hold on.
- Pull.
Sitka. Sitka!
Sitka.
Come on!
- Sitka!
Sitka. Sitka!
- Sitka?
- Sitka, where are you?
Kenai.
No.
Sitka!
Denahi, let's find him!
Sitka.
Sitka, where are you? Sitka!
- You ready?
- For what?
For going after the bear.
I know what you're feeling,
but killing that bear is wrong.
Wrong? Our brother is dead
and it's because of that monster.
I don't blame the bear, Kenai.
- I see.
- Killing the bear won't make you a man.
Now you're trying to be wise.
I'm trying to follow my totem.
Why can't you?
You really think love
has anything to do with being a man?
A man wouldn't just sit here
and do nothing.
Kenai. Don't upset the spirits.
Spirits. Thanks for your wisdom.
I've got to stop him.
You left too soon, Sitka.
Your brothers need your guidance.
Kenai.
What?
Sitka.
No.
I don't blame the bear, Kenai.
A man wouldn't just sit here
and do nothing.
So, Kenai,
you've decided to join the living.
That's quite a bump you've got.
That must have been one heck of a ride
down the rapids.
Tanana?
Nana, you won't believe this.
I was at the top of this rock,
and all of a sudden...
Kenai, honey.
I don't speak bear.
No.
No, no! No!
All right! All right! All right!
Would you settle down? Settle!
Kenai! Kenai...
Kenai. Kenai. This isn't going to work.
Kenai, listen to me. Sitka did this.
Strange. Spirits don't usually
make these kind of changes.
Oh, my, my, my, my.
Sitka must have something really big
planned for you. Yep, yep.
You are going to get
a whole new perspective on things.
Do you see in black and white
or colour?
Hey. Listen to me.
You got yourself into this mess.
If you want to change,
take it up with your brother's spirit.
You'll find him on the mountain
where the lights touch the earth.
He'll help you make up
for what you've done wrong.
But I didn't do anything wrong.
Tanana? Tanana!
Wait. I didn't do anything wrong.
- I don't even know how to get there.
- What happened to them?
- I don't know.
- They were here. Now they're gone.
Yeah, that's pretty weird.
So you're telling me you didn't eat them
and you have no idea where they are?
Hey, hey, you. You just talked.
Just back away, real slow-like.
- How did you do that?
- I knew you had them.
Are we there yet?
Don't make me
turn this formation around.
Hey. Wait. Come back.
I'm trying to find where the lights...
- What's he getting worked up about?
- Maybe the goose pooped on him?
He's looking over here.
Let's beat it. This way.
- No, this way.
- Thank you very much.
- Just stay still and...
- Hey, you two!
Head down.
I think he's seen us. Now what?
- Act like we're not here.
- We're not here.
- What are you doing?
- You said to...
- Don't say anything.
- Okay.
- I said, "Don't say anything."
- Excuse me.
- Don't eat us.
- You won't like us, eh? We're gamey.
Yeah. Eat hoof-for-brains over there.
- Pine-cone breath.
- Crusty tail.
- Twig legs.
- Big nose.
- Sorry.
- You went too far that time.
- Okay, I'm sorry.
- Guys.
- Yours is bigger than mine.
- I'm not eating anybody.
- That's mighty decent of you, eh.
- My name's Rutt.
- This is my brother Tuke.
- How's it going, Bear?
- Don't call me that.
- Sorry...
- Mr Bear?
- I mean, I'm not a bear. I hate bears.
- Well, gee, you're one big beaver.
- No kidding, eh?
Do either of you know
where the lights touch the earth?
No. No. Sorry, bear... Beaver.
I'm not a beaver, I'm a bear...
No, I mean, I'm not a bear.
- I'm a man.
- Excuse me.
I was transformed into a bear.
Magically. I was lifted into the sky
by my brother.
- Crazy.
- Gesundheit.
No. Fruitcake.
- Are you okay?
- No. That bear. Over there.
- He's crazy.
- I am not crazy.
Whoever said you were?
We understand.
- You do?
- Yeah, yeah.
You see, we're not moose either.
- We're not?
- No.
We're like squirrels. Yeah.
Yeah. Beauty, eh?
Well, he's actually the squirrel.
I'm more of a purebred wolverine.
Look at these cuspids.
- Give him a little room.
- Why am I talking to moose?
- No, we're squirrels, eh.
- Wolverine.
I'll find it myself.
- I wouldn't go that way.
- Why not, eh?
Well, there was a reason.
- You brought it up.
- I'm trying to...
- So, you think of it yet?
- Well, no, but it's driving me nuts.
Hey. Is the coast clear?
- What?
- Are there any hunters around?
- No.
- Good!
You didn't see the trap?
I saw it from a mile away.
You must be pretty embarrassed.
Don't worry.
I won't tell anyone.
- What?
- You need to get down. Let me help.
Oh, wait.
- Hold still.
- Just... Stop that.
If you just...
- Stop it!
- It's no use.
The only way to get down
is to chew your own foot off.
I don't need some stupid bear's help.
I just need the stick.
- Okay, here.
- No, I'll do it myself.
Put it back. No, where you found it.
To the left. By the little rock.
- Here?
- Yes.
Okay.
Boy, that tree is strong, huh?
You know, when I was little,
I was really into climbing trees.
All kinds of trees.
I climbed pine trees, oaks, cedars,
maples, birch trees, willow trees...
My eyes were watering
and my tongue was swollen.
From that moment on,
I was more careful about what I lick.
See? It's all about using your head.
That was funny. Do it again.
- Don't you have someplace to go?
- Yeah, the salmon run.
How about this?
I get you down, then we go together.
- Deal?
- Yeah, okay, fine.
If you can magically get me down,
I'll go with you to this...
- Salmon run.
- Whatever. But if you can't...
You turn around, walk away,
and never come back, ever.
- You swear?
- Yeah.
- Pinkie swear?
- Yeah, sure, fine, pinkie swear.
But this is a human trap
and you're just a dumb little bear.
There's no way
you're going to be able...
Okay, so I'm thinking
we travel by day and sleep by night.
My bedtime is an hour after sunset...
Run!
Yeah, good riddance.
Denahi.
Denahi, you found me.
You wouldn't believe
what a nightmare this has been.
Denahi? It's me. Kenai.
Is he gone?
I think he was going...
Hello. I can't breathe.
- Why is he chasing me?
- That's what they do.
- But it's not like him.
- Lucky for him, he didn't find us
'cause when I get in a fight,
I go all crazy
and I'm a raging ball of brown fur.
I mean, I don't want to brag or nothing,
but I got some moves.
- Really?
- Yep. This first one, well...
It's just a little thing
I like to call "The Slasher."
And this one I like to call
"Flying Fury of Death."
- He's coming back.
- Where?
Typical.
Yeah, well,
the next time we run into that hunter...
There is no "we."
I'm not taking you to any salmon run.
What? But you pinkie swore.
Yeah, well, things change.
See you, kid.
Wait...
The truth is,
I got separated from my mom.
And now, with this hunter around...
- Kid, I got my own problems.
- Come on. Please.
Can't we just go together?
There's a lot of bears and a ton of fish,
and every night we watch the lights
touch the mountain. Last year...
- Wait, wait. What did you say?
- Lots of bears and fish.
No. You know
where the lights touch the earth?
Yeah! The top of the mountain
right by the salmon run.
- You're kidding me.
- No, no, they're practically next door.
Come on, I'll show you. It'll be great.
I promise to help you escape
from every trap you walk into.
I'm not going to walk into any more...
- Traps.
- Come on. What do you say?
Sure you can take me
to where the lights touch the earth?
Yeah, no problem.
- If you slow me down...
- I won't, I promise.
All right, we leave first thing tomorrow.
And keep all that cuddly bear stuff
to a minimum, okay, kid?
My name's not "kid." It's Koda.
What's your name?
- Good day.
- How's it going, eh?
Beauty. So we got a lot to get done
today. You want to get started?
- Yeah. Just give me one sec, eh?
- Okay.
- Just help me crack this.
- All right.
- You ready now?
- Almost.
Just want to do "dog facing forward."
- Come on.
- Good. Okay.
And go.
This a nice patch here.
Don't go near this patch here.
Something went here.
Skinny. Fat. Skinny. Fat.
Hey, I've got a mountain to get to.
Come on, kid.
I told you before. My name's Koda.
Say it with me. Ko... Da.
Sure your mom didn't ditch you,
Ko-duh?
- Rutt.
- Go away, I'm eating twigs.
- You're breaking my concentration.
We should start running, like now!
I can't. I'm still digesting. I'll get cramps.
- He's after us!
- Come on, little brother.
Cramp!
If you really want to know
how me and my mom got separated...
I was saving this story
for the salmon run, but I'll tell you.
It was probably the fifth or sixth
most coldest day in my entire life.
- Sounds good. You should save it.
- You think so?
Yeah. For your friends.
- Well, I have this other story.
- Tell you what.
- How about no talking?
- Okay.
- Then I'll sing.
- No, no, no.
Tell everybody I'm on my way
Will you stop it?
New friends and new places to see
Come on, quit it.
Koda, stop singing.
Yes, I'm on my way
And there's nowhere else
that I'd rather be
Tell everybody I'm on my way
And I'm loving every step I take
With the sun beating down
Yes, I'm on my way
And I can't keep this smile off my face
'Cause there's nothing like
seeing each other again
No matter what the distance between
And the stories that we tell
will make you smile
Oh, it really lifts my heart
So tell them all I'm on my way
New friends and new places to see
And to sleep under the stars
Who could ask for more?
With the moon keeping watch over me
Not the snow, not the rain
can change my mind
The sun will come out, wait and see
And the feeling of the wind in your face
Can lift your heart, whoa
There's nowhere I would rather be
'Cause I'm on my way now
Well and true
I'm on my way now
Hey, hold on, eh?
Wait up.
- How's it going, bear boy?
- And smallish bear.
I didn't know you had a little brother.
He's cute.
- Actually, he's...
- There was this hunter following us.
We was thinking if we could
maybe just hang out with you guys.
- Just hang out.
- Yeah, it'd be fun.
- If the hunter was going to catch up...
- Then you'd eat him.
- That's what we was thinking.
- We lost the hunter at the glacier.
You don't think he'll follow those?
- They are quite nice.
- I've got an idea.
Okay, this is really weird.
- I'm driving.
- When can I have a turn?
It's not as easy as it looks.
Just watch what I do.
Let's get a back seat or something.
I look like you hunted me.
Tell everybody I'm on my way
Hey, come on.
And I just can't wait to be there
Blue skies ahead
Yes, I'm on my way
Nothing but good times to share
So tell everybody I'm on my way
And I just can't wait to be home
With the sun beating down
Yes, I'm on my way
With nothing but good times to show
I'm on my way
Yes, I'm on my way
Beauty, eh?
Okay, here's how I remember it.
The snow is white, it's all right.
Yellow or green, it's just not clean.
I learned that one the hard way.
That reminds me. Last year at the
salmon run my friend Bucky dared me.
But I'd heard of a cub
who stuck his tongue to an iceberg.
Then he started to float away.
To save him
they had to rip off his tongue,
so now he hath to talk like thith
all the time and...
Do you ever stop talking?
Look. The night rainbow.
- You can see the spirits from here.
- You know about the great spirits?
Yeah, my grandma's up there,
and my granddad.
Mom says the spirits make
all the magical changes in the world.
Like how the leaves change colour,
or the moon changes shapes,
- or tadpoles change into frogs.
- Yeah, I get it.
You know, for a change, maybe
they could just leave things alone.
- What do you mean?
- My brother's a spirit.
If it wasn't for him, I...
I wouldn't be here.
You have a brother up there?
- What happened to him?
- He was killed by a...
By a monster.
What's your brother's name?
Sitka.
Thanks, Sitka. If it weren't for you,
I would have never met Kenai.
I always wanted a brother.
So, you want to play "I spy"?
- All right. I'll go first.
- Okay.
I spy something green.
Tree?
- My turn?
- Yeah.
Okay, I spy something tall.
- Tree.
- Okay.
I spy something with bark.
Tree?
Okay, I spy something...
- A vertical log.
- Tree.
- Okay, I spy something...
- My turn.
- Tree.
- No, I...
- It counts.
- I didn't even spy anything.
Okay. Tree.
Let's play something else.
Koda. Come on.
- Koda, wake up.
- Two more months, Mom.
So, where are we?
Well, which way?
- I think it's that way.
- You think, or you know?
That way?
Why wasn't I turned
into a homing pigeon?
- Come on.
- Hey, riding mammoths was your idea.
Thanks for the ride, guys. See you.
Lucky for you,
I've been lost worse than this.
- Last summer, I was with Bucky...
- Enough with the stories.
I don't care about the time
you and Binky found
the world's biggest pine cone ever.
First of all, his name's Bucky, not Binky.
Second, it wasn't a pine cone,
it was a pine nut.
And it was huge.
Even bigger than your fat head.
Our big guardian bear is leaving, eh?
Yeah. We'd better follow him. Come on.
- Can you swing your leg...
- I can't get off.
Me, neither. Okay, you guys...
I guess we'll just catch up
with those guys later, eh?
- Good trip, eh?
- Beauty.
You know, I was thinking now
might be a good time for me to drive.
Just relax and enjoy the ride.
Yeah. Okay.
I'm sorry we're lost, okay?
- Even though it's your fault.
- My fault?
That's it.
Just remember, if it weren't for me,
you'd be hanging upside down.
Better than being stuck nowhere
with you and your blabbering mouth.
"I'm lost. I can't find my mommy.
Will you take me to the salmon run?"
- Why don't you just grow up?
- Fine. I'll go on my own then.
- Fine. Go ahead.
- Fine.
Koda?
Those monsters are really scary.
Especially with those sticks.
Come on, let's go.
So, you recognise anything yet?
Or maybe you can't see past
my fat head.
So, do you really think
I have a fat head?
Well, if you hunched your shoulders
a little it wouldn't seem so big.
You mean like this?
Or like this?
How about this?
Oh, my, that was good.
Maybe they can give us directions.
- That clears up the sinuses.
- Oh, it does.
Okay, okay, hit me again.
I think she's looking.
- Hello, sweetie.
- Yes, she's checking me out, all right.
- Hey, baby.
- No, come on, you nitwit.
Are you out of your head?
She's looking at me.
Like she's looking at your ugly mug?
Come on.
Excuse me, miss. It's go-time, baby.
You want to go? Bring it on.
- Horns up.
- Hold on.
- Excuse me.
- What do you want?
- What is that?
- Just a minute, bear.
Hey, shut up.
No, you shut up.
Hey, will you shut up?
Just shut up.
Their horns are screwed on too tight.
Wait a second.
- I know this place.
- You do?
Yeah. The salmon run's not far.
We just have to go through here.
What?
Hey, you sure you know
where you're going?
Yeah, yeah, follow me.
Koda?
Where are you?
- Don't do that.
- Scared you, didn't I?
There's scared,
and then there's surprised.
And you were both.
Nice try. You got a little spit right there.
- Kenai!
- You're not getting me this time.
No, look out.
No.
Come on.
Kenai.
Kenai, where are you?
Left. Left. No, the other left.
Kenai!
No!
What are you doing?
We got to get out of here.
Why do they hate us, Kenai?
- We're bears.
- So?
So, you know how they are.
They're killers.
Wait a minute, who's the killers?
- Bears.
- What? Which bears?
I'm not like that, and you're not like that.
Well, obviously not all bears.
I mean, you're okay.
Most bears will look for any excuse
to attack a human.
But, Kenai, he attacked us.
You're just a cub.
When you're older, you'll understand.
Fish! Fish! Fish!
We made it. We're here.
- Come on!
- What? Koda.
- Fish! Fish! Fish!
- Hey. Get away from me.
Get away from me. Go on.
Hey, you're stirring up the water, dude.
Yeah, try not to scare off
the fish there, buddy.
Tug.
Hey, Koda. Come here.
Look at you.
- Have you seen my mom yet?
- No, as a matter of fact I haven't.
- Me and my friend Kenai beat her.
- He's with you?
Hi.
I've never seen you at the run before.
- Where are you from?
- Well, I...
There's the mountain,
just like I promised.
The lights touch the top every night.
Gonna be harder getting up there
than riding those mammoths.
- Mammoths?
- Are you kidding?
- That's weird.
- Yeah.
He does weird stuff.
Like the way he drinks water with a leaf.
He never sharpens his claws on a tree.
He's never hibernated before...
Koda. Koda.
Can I talk to you for a second?
Excuse us.
He's kind ofjumpy, isn't he?
Okay. Okay.
Koda, I...
- I got to get going.
- Well, when you come back...
I won't be coming back.
What? Why not?
Because... Well, it's hard to...
- You're leaving?
- No.
Well, I mean, yes.
Well, it's just that I...
- I don't belong here.
- Don't belong?
Every bear belongs here.
Come on, buddy.
Everyone's invited
Let's have some fun!
This is how we live
We're all here for each other
Happy to give
All we have, we share
And all of us, we care
So come on
Welcome to our family time
Welcome to our brotherly time
We're happy giving and taking
to the friends we're making
There's nothing we won't do
Welcome to our family time
Welcome to our happy-to-be time
This is our festival
You know that best of all
We're here to share it all
There's a bond between us
nobody can explain
It's a celebration of life
And seeing friends again
I'd be there for you
I know you'd be there for me, too
- So come on
- Welcome to our family time
Welcome to our brotherly time
This is our festival
You know, and best of all
We're here to share it all
Remembering love once departed
Someone dear to your heart
Finding love, planning a future
Telling stories
and laughing with friends
Precious moments you'll never forget
This has to be the most beautiful
The most peaceful place
I've ever been to
It's nothing like I've ever seen before
When I think how far I've come
I can't believe it
Yet I see it
And then I see family
I see the way we used to be
- Come on
- Welcome to our family time
Welcome to our brotherly time
We're happy giving and taking
to the friends that we're making
There's nothing we won't do
Welcome to our family time
Welcome to our happy-to-be time
This is our festival
You know, and best of all
You're here to share it
We're here to share it all
All right, settle down, everyone.
Settle down. Hey.
Don't throw your fish bones there.
Somebody could choke on that.
Look, okay, I'll go first.
Okay, let's see. The most interesting
thing that happened to me this year.
I know, I know, I know! Listen to this.
It was when I knocked down that tree
that was blocking the view
from my cave.
Now I got a family of chipmunks
staying in my place.
Yeah.
All right, everybody,
let me see some paws in the air.
- Who's gonna be next? Come on.
- Tug. I got one.
Watch me. Hey, gotcha.
This year I lost my dear husband Edgar.
Quit telling everyone I'm dead!
Sometimes I can still hear his voice.
I'm getting the next one.
Oh, yeah.
- This is it. I got it. I got...
- I guess it's our turn.
This is the year
I met the most gorgeous...
No, you're gorgeous.
- You're gorgeous-er.
- Get a cave.
If only Edgar was alive...
I told you, woman, I'm right here!
- I love you, buttercup.
- This has got to be it.
- Here you go, Koda.
- You gotta tell it, Kenai.
- What?
- Yes. You caught it, you tell it.
Didn't you play when you were a cub?
Come on, Keno.
Okay, all right already. All right.
- You want to know what I did this year?
- Yes.
I went on the longest, hardest, most
exhausting journey I've ever been on
with the biggest pain in the neck
I've ever met.
What do you expect
from a little brother?
Okay, buddy, your turn.
- Let's hear it, Koda.
- Okay, okay, here we go.
This year I watched my mom
in a life-and-death struggle
battling the most fiercest creature ever.
- Who's next?
- What?
Wait a minute. I think we all want
to hear the rest of that one, Koda.
I thought you might say that. Let's see.
It was probably the fifth or sixth
most coldest day in my entire life.
Me and Mom were eating fish,
having a great time.
All of a sudden she pushes me into
the bushes and tells me to be real quiet.
She says, "I smell something."
So I started sniffing.
There's something in the woods
running towards us,
getting closer and closer.
And then, out of the trees,
jumps a hunter.
And now there's nowhere for Mom to go.
The monster has her backed up
against this giant glacier.
The monster attacks,
but Mom's too quick for him.
And before he can do it again, she
stands up real big and yells, "Go away."
Kenai.
Mom smells more of them.
There's a whole pack
coming right at us.
Sitka, no. The bear. Behind you.
She runs to stop them
before they get to me.
They're all around her,
poking her with sticks.
- Sitka.
- The whole thing broke and fell off.
There was ice everywhere.
She couldn't hold her breath
any longer, and pow.
She bursts out of the water.
I've never been so scared in my life.
- I'm going after the bear.
- Koda?
- Sitka wouldn't want it.
- Sitka's not here
because of that monster.
Fell off a glacier?
I've never seen anything like that.
Can you imagine?
Kenai. What's the matter, Kenai?
- What happened next?
- Was she okay?
Hey, Kenai, what's wrong?
Where you going?
She got out of the water okay.
That's how we got separated.
Right after that I met Kenai.
Kenai?
Scared you again, huh?
- Yeah.
- Where have you been?
- You look horrible.
- Koda...
My mom says when
you eat too much fish, just lie down.
There's something I...
You know that story
you told me last night?
- Yeah.
- Well, I have a story to tell you.
Really? What's it about?
Well, it's kind of about a man,
and kind of about a bear.
But mostly it's about a monster.
A monster who did something so bad...
Everywhere I turn I hurt someone
But there's nothing I can say
to change the things I've done
I'd do anything within my power
I'd give everything I've got
But the path I seek
is hidden from me now
Koda, I did something very wrong.
Brother bear, I let you down
I don't like this story.
You trusted me, believed in me
and I let you down
Your mother's not coming.
Of all the things I hid from you
I cannot hide the shame
And I pray someone
No. No!
Something will come
to take away the pain
There's no way out
Of this dark place
No, no future
I know I can't be free
But I can't see another way
And I can't face another day
Koda? Koda?
Koda!
Koda, I wish I could...
If there was just some way...
I'd give anything if...
If I could just...
I'm sorry, Koda.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry, Kenai.
I don't know what I'm doing any more.
I need help.
Sitka.
Look, I am sorry.
If I was driving
this never would have happened.
- You never let me do nothing.
- Trample off. I said sorry. Let it go.
I can't believe you totalled a mammoth.
- That mountain came out of nowhere.
- I cannot accept your apology.
- It was in my blind spot...
- Look. It's that little cub.
- Something's bugging him.
- What's wrong, smallish bear?
Nothing. I'm fine.
Good. Where were we? Oh, yeah.
You're a big, selfish, reckless hoofer.
- What?
- I'm fed up with it.
- From now on, he's my new brother.
- You can't do that.
Sorry, you've been replaced
with my dear brother...
What's your name again?
I don't want any more brothers.
- See? He's had enough of you, too.
- I promise I'll change.
Trample off. You won't.
Being a brother means nothing to you.
- Of course it does.
- Like what?
What about when your hooves
froze in the pond?
- Who sat with you all winter, eh?
- You did.
Who showed you
where the good grazing is?
The really tender stuff
all covered in dew.
Now, why do you think I did that, eh?
Because I...
Because I love... dew.
Excuse me?
I don't believe I heard what you said.
I said, "I love dew."
I love dew, too.
Hey, I can change.
- Go away.
- Come on, I can change.
- Go away, don't touch me.
- I can change.
Hey. No.
Not there, that's the spot.
Like, we'll see you later, smallish bear.
Yeah, good day.
You know what this calls for?
A pile of delicious barley and amber
weed on a cool bed of malted hops.
I like it.
Sitka! Sitka, are you there?
Sitka?
Please. Please, Sitka.
I don't know what else to do.
Sitka.
Denahi.
Sitka, hurry, change me back.
Where are you, Sitka?
Denahi.
Denahi, please.
Koda.
No!
Leave him alone.
Koda!
Kenai?
Sitka?
Koda, don't be afraid. It's me.
He needs me.
You know, he did look better as a bear.
But, Denahi...
It's all right, Kenai.
No matter what you choose,
you'll always be my little brother.
Did I say little?
Kenai.
My brother Kenai went on to live
with Koda and the other bears.
He taught me
that love is very powerful.
And I passed on the wisdom
of his story to our people.
The story of a boy who became a man
by becoming a bear.
Great spirits of all who lived before
Take our hands and lead us
Fill our hearts and souls
with all you know
Show us that in your eyes
We are all the same
Brothers to each other
in this world we remain
Truly brothers all the same
Brothers all the same
So, like, what are you doing there,
smallish bear?
I'm practising my moves.
Want to see one?
Sure. This ought to be good?
Listen to me. I was a man
that was changed into a bear.
No beaver. Man into bear. That's it.
Yeah, so, before that
you was probably like a goat?
- What about a water buffalo?
- No, he's a rabbit.
Look at his ears and furry feet.
Watch out for the rabbit, eh.
No way, eh.
Okay, now, everyone, take a big inhale.
And then on...
On the exhale,
shift into salutation to the sun.
No, you shut up.
- How you doing over there, Koda?
- Pretty good.
In accordance with all federal
and state wildlife regulations,
no fish were harmed
during the making of this film.
No! He's gonna eat me!
Cut. Cut.
Somebody, help me.
Help me. Somebody.
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/33fp7
Help other users to choose the best subtitles