I'm telling you, something's missing.
But Tim, when it comes to deserts, we've got
everything under the sun.
Sorry, DA, it just doesn't say "desert" yet.
Are you kidding? It screams "desert." We've
got sand. We've got gravel.
We've got desert plants like cacti, creosote
bushes, ocotillo.
We've got the desert's harsh conditions.
Hot, blazing sun
Dry, blinding dust storms.
Tim's right. There is something missing!
As I always say, Arnold, it never hurts to be
prepared.
That's funny, Ms. Frizzle, that's exactly what l
was thinking.
I know! I know! Desert animals! That's
what's missing!
Ms. Frizzle, our diorama will never be
complete without desert animals!
Dynamic deduction, Phoebe!
These should do for now.
Now? It's later I'm worried about.
Thank you, Ms. Frizzle. Here you go, little
guy....
According to my research, that's a kangaroo
rat. And that's a gila monster.
Isn't it cute?!
Only Phoebe would think a Gila monster is
cute.
And there's more...Tortoise...beetle...
scorpion...jackrabbit...roadrunner...
Hey, Liz, what's up with you?
And you know what this is? A baby coyote!
Phoebe, are you sure all these animals live in
the desert?
Think about it. The desert is really hot.
The sun beats down all day long. Beat. Beat.
Beat.
And there's nowhere for the animals to go to
escape the heat...heat... heat!
But...
Not only is it hot, but there's hardly any food in
the desert!
So any animal that shows its face...gets
EATEN by a bigger one!
STOP!
And that's not all.
It isn't?
The worst part? There's almost NO WATER
in the desert.
No water?
Uh-uh. No shelter. No food. No water.
In no time at all, all your cute little animals are
buzzard bait.
SCARClTY is the name of the game, Pheebs.
Scar-ci-ty.
He's right, Phoebe. There's not much food,
water, or shelter in the desert.
We've got to DO something!
Yeah!
What can we do? What can we do?
What can WE do?
Well, at my old school, we'd take a stand!
Form a committee!!
Go on a field trip!?
Arnold? Are you serious?
He's right! SADS to the rescue!
SADS?
Students Against Desert Scarcity!
To the Desert!
Ms. Frizzle? Yes Arnold?
For once, I'm prepared.... Regulation Desert
gear...
As outlined in Chapter 7 of my new Field Trip
Survival Guide....
Ms. Frizzle, do your worst!
I'll do my best, Arnold!
Well, are you guys coming,
or do I have to save these desert animals all
by myself? To the bus!
Follow that Phoebe!
Hey Arnold, so what d'you have in that
knapsack anyway.
A little sunblock, snake bite kit, a few dozen
Malloblasters...
What?! No football!?
Carlos, we are NOT going to the desert to
have FUN!
We're not? The desert is full of surprises,
Phoebe.
And this bus is so slow! Can't we go any
faster, Ms Frizzle?
Every second we waste means those poor
little animals are out there suffering.
That's one way of looking at it, Phoebe! Okay
bus! Do your stuff!
All right!
Way to go!!
Are we there yet?
Chill, Phoebe. We only just took off.
We're flying over mountains. Didn't you say
"Students Against DESERT Scarcity"?
Yeah, and mountains have PLENTY of shelter,
food and water.
Ms. Frizzle! We must be going the wrong
way!
Wrong way? Why, Phoebe. If it weren't for
the mountains, there wouldn't be a desert.
What do mountains have to do with the
desert?
Haven't you guys ever heard of a rain shadow?
No...
Some deserts are made by what's called the
rain shadow effect.
When warm moist air rises over the
mountains...
its water vapor condenses into rain or snow.
The mountains catch all the moisture,
so the air reaching the other side is dry as a
desert.
Look out below!!
It's not fair! Why should the mountains get all
the water!
If you keep asking questions, Phoebe. You'll
find an answer!
Oh, and there's the perfect parking spot! Hold
on tight!
Field Trip Tip Number 63, "ln the event of a
rapid loss of altitude
you may want to put on a parachute." Liz, my
parachute.
That's not a paraCHUTE, that's a
pair-a-SHOES!
Look at this place!
Whew! The Thermoprobe reads 1 07 degrees
Fahrenheit! That's HOT!
How can anything live here?
Is it just me? Or does this look like the "Final"
field trip.
Come along, class. We're here to experience
the desert!
Take chances! Make mistakes! Get dusty!
Field Trip Tip Number 87...Not a problem!
Come on, you guys. Students Against Desert
Scarcity, remember?
We've got work to do!
Desert Scarcity? What about Dessert
Scarcity? I'm hungry!
Hey, Arnold, where are those Malloblasters?
I'm afraid they've melted.
How can you even think about eating
when all these poor little animals are suffering
from hunger?!
The only poor little animals I see...are US!
There's one!
Why that's a collared lizard!
And that's a funny-looking bird!
That, Keesha, is a fine example of a hungry
roadrunner chasing a delicious lizard to eat!
Come on! We have to protect that lizard!
At my old school, lizards never ran on their
hind legs!
Quick, everyone, back in the bus!
Phoebe. What are we doing??
How would you like to be a lizard being
chased by a hungry roadrunner?
A situation worth exploration, Phoebe!
Wow, cool, we're shrinking
As I always say...'when the going gets hungry,
the hungry get going.'
Bad oh bad oh bad bad bad.
And getting worse! It's gaining on us!
I hate field trips where we get eaten!
Any minute now, we're going to know what it
feels like to be EATEN!
Field Trip Tip Number 107:. To avoid being
eaten become inedible.
WHAT's THAT MEAN?!!
Class? Do I hear a suggestion to avoid
digestion?
According to my research, Arnold,
it means we ought to become something that's
not very appetizing.
On the button, DA! One inedible horned lizard
coming up!
Phew! Close one!
Well, first-hand experience tells us
roadrunners don't like lizards with spikes!
Would you?
So, the little animals here have special ways
to avoid getting eaten
Iike running fast or being prickly...
Phoebe, that's right!
Which means they don't need your help,
Pheebs.
Are you sure about that? Life is tough in the
desert.
Don't we know it! It's too hot to chase after
animals!
Or to be chased! Phew! I'm burning up!
Exactly! And somewhere out there is a poor
little animal which is burning up, too!
Now come on, we've got to find it and help it!
Stop the bus, please.
Everybody out!
Not again.
Single file, class.
I'm hot!
I'm tired!
I'm hungry!
I'm prepared.
Phoebe, we've been looking and looking...and
we haven't found anymore animals.
None, Phoebe. And I'm burning up!
Me too!
You're hot! What about that poor little
jackrabbit?!
See? It's sitting there with the sun beating
down on its head! And it's wearing a fur coat.
Field Trip Tip Number 1 58
when the sun is beating down on your head,
put on a hat. Got that covered.
Thanks, Arnold!
Hey!!
Here little jack rabbit. This will keep you from
getting too hot...a nice hat to shade your--
Phoebe
Arnold! Now how will that jackrabbit keep
cool?
Well...
EAR-conditioning, Phoebe!
EAR-conditioning! Good one, Ms Frizzle!
Thanks, Carlos
Carlos! How can you joke at a time like this?
According to my research, it's not a joke,
Phoebe!
You know how a car radiator cools off hot
water from the engine...
some desert animals have big ears which do
the same thing.
When their warm blood moves through their
big ears, it gets cooled off in the same way!
Stay cool.
Come on, Pheebs, just admit it.
The lizards don't need your help and neither
do the jackrabbits.
Okay. So the jackrabbit has a way to keep
itself cool. But what about that!
That is a desert tortoise! You don't usually see
them out in the heat like this.
See? An animal in need! Come on! We've
got to help it!
We do?
Carlos, don't be so selfish
How would you like to be a tortoise roasting in
the hot desert sun?
I wish you hadn't said that...
As I always say, there's more than one way to
beat the heat!
Oh, no!
So THlS is what it's like to be a desert
tortoise!
Where are we?
In a tortoise burrow. An underground shelter.
It's A LOT cooler down here.
Ah! Good observation, Keesha!
Yes! Another animal that can keep cool
without your help, Pheebolino!
But Carlos! I just thought of something!
Maybe the reason we didn't see any animals is
because they all burned up before we got here!
I knew it! We're too late!
What's happening?
Class, the bus is now on automatic turtle!
We're being pushed by another desert
tortoise!
Are we still in the desert?
Wow, what happened?
The sun went down and the desert has totally
changed!
Oh Carlos look! How sweet, eleven, twelve,
thirteen, fourteen...
Hey! We weren't too late! The reason we
didn't see any animals is
because they were just waiting for the sun to
go down!
50 degrees Fahrenheit! You don't have any
sweaters in that knapsack, do you Arnold?
Once the sun goes down, the air cools off.
Field Trip Tip Number 257:.
To beat the heat do like most desert
animals...come out only at night.
There you have it, Phoebe. Another way
desert animals help themselves!
It's okay, Phoebe. There's nothing wrong with
being wrong.
As I always say, 'Make mistakes. Make
mistakes. Make mistakes.'
It's the best way to learn something.
But, let's face it - Students Against Desert
Scarcity is a bust.
Okay, Carlos. Okay. You don't have to rub it
in
I might have made a mistake about that lizard.
And I might have made a mistake about the
jack rabbit.
And I even might have made a mistake about
the tortoise.
But there's one thing I know I'm not wrong
about...
How much you wish you'd stayed home today?
No. How much everything here on the desert
needs water!!
You're telling me!
Thanks, Ralphie.
Phoebe!
Well, if no one's going to help me give water
to all these poor little animals..
I'll just do it MYSELF!
Phoebe! Where are you going?
I said I was going to give these poor animals
water, and I'm going to...
Phoebe, I know this may sound crazy, but hear
me out.
Okay, Carlos - I'm listening.
These animals didn't need your protection
from being eaten
or from burning up in the sun, right?
Right...
They can cope. Right?
Well, maybe they don't need your water,
either.
Carlos, HOW CAN YOU SAY THAT??
You KNOW there's no water in the desert.
You said so yourself. Rain
shadow...remember?
But look at them. They couldn't live without
water.
And they are definitely alive. They must get it
somehow.
Okay, then, if you're so smart, tell me HOW!
Come on, Carlos, take chances, get messy,
make MlSTAKES.
I...I don't know.
Exactly. Maybe people like me come out here
and give the animals water.
Maybe people like me keep these animals
alive.
Hey, at least save the water for the animals...
What are you talking about?
Didn't you just splash me?
Is that... rain??
Everyone back on the bus!
Rain?
In the desert?
It doesn't rain here very often class, but...
as I always say, not very often is a long way
from never!
And the desert is a long way from needing my
water...
And we're a long way from the bus. Come on,
Phoebe!
Doesn't it feel GREAT? NOW we're talking
WATER.
It's amazing. We went from absolutely no
water to....FLOOOD!
Good morning, class! Everything's right as
rain!
Where are we?
What happened to the desert?
Is this a dream?
No, Phoebe, it's the desert after a rainstorm.
Everything's changed. There's so much
activity.
What happened to all the scarcity? Look at all
these plants and animals.
Desert life never ceases to amaze me!
Do you see what I see? Flower power!
It's as if they were waiting for enough water to
bloom.
There are shrimp in this puddle!
Shrimp? In the desert??
Ah huh and pigs too, look!
Actually that's a peccary, a desert relative of
pigs.
And this cactus is full of water!
According to my observations, this piece of
cactus is juicy on the inside
and waxy on the outside.
Hey...maybe that waxy stuff keeps the water in.
As I always say, when it pours, the desert
stores.
You know, Phoebe. You were right.
The desert does need water.
And the animals need protection from being
eaten and from the heat.
Yeah but Carlos, you were right too.
They don't need us to help them. They're
already equipped to live here.
That's right, Phoebe.
Everything that lives here has adaptations to
help cope with life in the desert.
Come along, class! Back to the bus.
You mean soaking up water as quickly as
possible is an adaptation?
Absolutely correct!
And having spikes is an adaptation...
...that helps keep you off the menu.
And burrowing under the sand
and having big ears is an adaptation for
beating the heat.
Yes! All the things that live here have
adaptations for survival.
It makes so much sense, doesn't it?
Field Trip Tip Number 999. For those without
desert adaptations
always travel with a teacher with frizzy
red-hair.
Well, I have to say, except for the part where
we almost got eaten...
...and the part where we almost burned up in
the sun...
and the part where we almost drowned in a
flood...
...my field trip manual was REALLY helpful.
So glad you enjoyed it, Arnold.
Well, now that I know that all these plants
and animals have adaptations to help them
cope with living in the desert,
that gives me some time to save something
else.
Phoebe, I don't think this is a...
I tell you, we've got to DO something!
Phoebe! We just DlD something!
A whole bunch of somethings!
But this time it really is an animal in need.
We'll call ourselves SASH!
SASH?
Students Assisting Sleepy Heads!
CARLOS!!
He obviously has no adaptations to cope with
desert field trips!
According to my research, Phoebe,
hibernation lS an adaptation!
As I always say, if you can't take the heat, get
out of the desert!
Is it the magic school bus?
stay tune with us and be a smart kid
Are you sure the Producer wanted this fake
cactus, Liz?
I better go...
Me? At my old school, kids NEVER answered
the phone. Hello...?
Is this the Magic School Bus?
Yes, but...
Good, because you see I'm starting up a new
group...
Save Our Kangaroo Rats...and I want Phoebe
to be president.
You do? I mean that's nice of you to say
but kangaroo rats don't need to be saved.
You mean, they have adaptations which make
it possible for them to live in the desert, too?
Right. For instance, they may never take a
drink in their entire lives.
They can get all the water they need from the
seeds and plants they eat.
Well, do they have an adaptation to help them
cope with the short nights?
Short nights?
Yeah, watching that show you'd think that night
time lasted about five seconds.
Oh, well, we were a little short on time...
Ah-ha!
But just a little! We wanted to show how
desert animals come out at night.
It's an adaptation, you know!
Okay, speaking of "adaptations,"
I don't know of ANY plant that grows from a
seed the instant it rains.
Look, when you have a lot of information to
cover in a half hour,
you don't have time to wait for seeds to grow
into plants!
But they do grow very quickly in the desert.
Did you want to see the desert in full bloom
after the rain or not?
Of course I did...And did you know that cactus
needles are really leaves?
Is that an adaptation?
Yes! Unlike leaves, needles don't lose any
water!
And you know what else? Not all deserts are
hot..
Even places that are very cold are called
deserts if they don't get enough rain.
Fascinating! Well, thanks for calling.
Wait! One more question! Do you actually
know Phoebe?
Yes. In fact--
Could you do me a favor? Just tell her I think
she's the greatest. Goodbye!
Maybe I should answer the phone more
often...
THE END