_
♫ Little Shop
Little Shop of Horrors. ♫
♫ Little Shop,
Little Shop of Terror. ♫
♫ Call a cop.
Little Shop of Horrors. ♫
♫ No, oh, oh, no-oh! ♫
♫ Little Shop
Little Shop of Horrors. ♫
♫ Bop she-bop,
Little Shop of Terror. ♫
♫ Watch 'em drop.
Little Shop of Horrors. ♫
♫ No, oh, oh, no-oh! ♫
♫ Shing-a-ling, what a creepy
thing to be happening. ♫
♫ Look out! Look out! Look out! ♫
♫ Shang-a-lang, feel the
Sturm und Drang in the air. ♫
♫ Sha la la and stop right where
you are, don't you move a thing. ♫
♫ You better... ♫
♫ You'd better, telling you
you'd better tell your mama. ♫
♫ Something's gonna get her,
she'd better, everybody better, beware! ♫
♫ Here it comes, baby. ♫
♫ Tell those bums, baby. ♫
♫ No, oh, oh, no-oh! ♫
♫ Hit the dirt, baby. ♫
♫ Red alert, baby. ♫
♫ No, oh, oh, no-oh! ♫
♫ Alley Oop, haul it off the stoop,
I'm warning you. ♫
♫ Look out! Look out! Look out! ♫
♫ Run away, child, you're
gonna pay if you fail. ♫
♫ Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! ♫
♫ Look around, look who's coming down,
down the street for you. ♫
♫ You bet 'cha, you bet 'cha,
you bet your butt, you better ♫
♫ best believe it
something's come to get 'cha. ♫
♫ You better, better watch
your back and your tail. ♫
♫ Come-a, come-a, come-a. ♫
♫ Little Shop
Little Shop of Horrors. ♫
♫ Bop-she-bop
You'll never stop the terror. ♫
♫ Little Shop
Little Shop of Horrors. ♫
♫ No, oh, oh, no-oh! ♫
Seymour, what's going on down there?
Very little, Mr. Mushnik!
...till the weekend.
And at his press conference today,
President Kennedy fielded questions
concerning last Thursday's
total eclipse of the sun,
an unprecedented astrological
phenomenon which has baffled the nation.
Ah! So! She finally
decides to come to work!
Uh, good morning, Mr. Mushnik.
What morning? It's almost closing time.
Not that we had a customer.
Seymour, what in the name of
God is going on down there?
Audrey, would you go down
and see what he's...
Audrey! Audrey, where
did you get that shiner?
Uh... a shiner?
Audrey, that greasy boyfriend of
yours is beating up on you again?
No! I know it's none of my business,
but I'm beginning to think
he's maybe not such a nice boy.
I got these pots
unloaded for you, Mr...
Seymour, look what you've
done to the inventory!
- Don't yell at Seymour, Mr. Mushnik.
- Hi, Audrey.
You look radiant today.
- Is that new eye make-up?
- Oh!
I'll help him clean it up
before any of the customers get here.
That should give you plenty of time.
Oh, God, what an existence I got!
Misfit employees, bums on the sidewalk,
business is lousy,
my life is a living hell!
Hey, you! Urchins!
Shoo! Shoo! Shoo!
Move! Move!
Move! Go away!
No loitering!
Man, I wasn't loitering.
Were you, Crystal?
Not me, Ronette.
Were you, Chiffon?
You ought to be in school!
Yeah, but we on a split shift.
Right, we went to school
until fifth grade, then we split.
So? How do you intend
to better yourselves?
"Better ourselves?" You heard what he said?
"Better ourselves?"
Mister, when you're from Skid Row,
ain't no such thing.
♫ Alarm goes off at 7:00 ♫
♫ and you start uptown. ♫
♫ You put in your eight hours ♫
♫ for the powers that
have always been. ♫
Sing it, child.
♫ Till it's 5:00 p.m. ♫
♫ Then you go. ♫
♫ Downtown where the
folks are broke. ♫
♫ You go downtown
where your life's a joke. ♫
where you buy your token ♫
♫ and you go ♫
♫ home to Skid Row. ♫
♫ Home to Skid Row. ♫
♫ Yes, you go ♫
♫ Downtown, where the
cabs don't stop. ♫
♫ Downtown, where
the food is slop. ♫
♫ Downtown where the
hopheads flop in the snow, ♫
♫ down on Skid Row. ♫
♫ Uptown, you cater
to a million jerks. ♫
♫ Uptown, you're messengers
and mailroom clerks. ♫
♫ eating all your lunches
at the hotdog carts. ♫
♫ The bosses take your money
then they break your hearts. ♫
♫ Uptown you cater to
a million whores. ♫
♫ Disinfect terrazzo
on their bathroom floors. ♫
♫ Your jobs are really menial,. ♫
♫ you make no bread
and then at 5 o'clock you head ♫
♫ by subway ♫
♫ Downtown, where
the guys are drips. ♫
they rip your slips. ♫
♫ Downtown, where
relationships are no-go. ♫
♫ Down on Skid Row. ♫
♫ Down on Skid Row.
Down on Skid Row. ♫
Down on Skid... ♫
♫ Down on Skid Row.
Down on Skid Row. ♫
♫ Poor, all my life,
I've always been poor. ♫
♫ I keep asking God what I'm for. ♫
♫ And he tells me,
"Gee, I'm not sure." ♫
♫ "Sweep that floor, kid". ♫
♫ Oh! ♫
♫ I started life as an orphan,
a child of the street, ♫
♫ here on Skid Row. ♫
♫ He took me in, gave me shelter, a bed,
a crust of bread and a job. ♫
♫ Treats me like dirt,
calls me a slob, which I am. ♫
♫ So I live ♫
♫ - Downtown.
- That's your home address. - You live ♫
- When your life's a mess. - You live ♫
♫ - Downtown.
- Where depression's just status quo, ♫
♫ down on Skid Row. ♫
♫ Someone show me a way
to get outta here. ♫
♫ 'Cause I constantly pray
I'll get outta here. ♫
♫ Please, won't somebody say
♫ Someone give me my shot
or I'll rot here. ♫
♫ Downtown...
Show me how and I will. ♫
♫ I'll get out of here, ♫
♫ Downtown...
I'll start climbing uphill. ♫
♫ And get outta here. ♫
♫ Downtown...
Someone tell me I still could get outta here. ♫
♫ Someone tell Lady Luck
that I'm stuck here. ♫
♫ Downtown...
Gee, it sure would be swell to get outta here. ♫
Bid the gutter farewell and get outta here. ♫
♫ Downtown...
I'd move heaven and hell to get outta Skid. ♫
I'd do, I don't know what to get outta of Skid. ♫
♫ Downtown...
But a hell of a lot to get outta Skid. ♫
People tell me there's not a way outta Skid. ♫
♫ Downtown...
But believe me, I've got to get outta Skid Row! ♫
Six o'clock and we
haven't sold so much as a fern!
All right! That's it! Forget it!
Don't bother coming in tomorrow.
- But, you don't mean...
- You can't.
Wha... wha... what don't I mean?
I'm through! Forget it! Kaput!
- You can't.
- Kaput! Extinct!
I'm closing this God and
customer forsaken place.
Mr. Mushnik, forgive me for saying so,
sir, but has it ever occurred to you
that maybe what the firm needs is
to move in a new direction?
What Seymour's trying to say is...
Seymour, why don't you
run downstairs and bring up
that strange and interesting new
plant you've been working on?
You see, Mr. Mushnik,
Some of those exotic
plants Seymour's been
tinkering around with...
are really unusual.
And we thought that maybe some of
those strange and interesting new plants
prominently displayed and...
and advertised, would attract business.
I'm afraid it isn't
feeling very well today.
There, now, isn't that bizarre?
At least.
What kind of a weirdo
plant is that, Seymour?
I don't know.
I think it's some kind of flytrap,
but I haven't been able to identify it
in any of my books.
I gave it my own name though,
I call it an Audrey II.
- After me?
- I hope you don't mind.
You see, sir, if you were to put a...
a strange and interesting plant like this
here in... in the window,
then... then maybe...
Maybe what? Maybe what?
Do you have any idea
how ridiculous you sound?
Just because you put a strange and interesting
plant in the window people don't suddenly...
Excuse me, I couldn't help noticing
that strange and interesting plant.
- What is it?
- It's an Audrey II.
I've never seen anything like it before.
- No one has.
- Where did you get it?
Well...
Do you remember that total
eclipse of the sun about a week ago?
♫ Da do. ♫
I was walking in the wholesale
flower district that day.
♫ Shoop da do. ♫
And I passed by this place
where this old Chinese man...
♫ Chang da do. ♫
He sometimes sells me
weird and exotic cuttings.
♫ Snip da do. ♫
'Cause he knows, you see, that,
well, strange plants are my hobby.
♫ Da da da da da da do. ♫
He didn't have anything
unusual there that day.
♫ Do da do. ♫
So I was just about to,
you know, walk on by...
♫ Oop, for you, sha shu do do do. ♫
when suddenly and without
warning, there was this...
♫ total eclipse of the sun. ♫
It got very dark.
And there was this strange humming
sound, like something from another world.
♫ Da do. ♫
And when the light came back, this
weird plant was just sitting there.
♫ Oop see do. ♫
Just, ya know, stuck
in a... among the zinnias.
♫ Audrey II. ♫
I coulda sworn it hadn't
been there before...
but the old Chinese man
sold it to me anyway...
for $1.95.
♫ Sha la la la la la do. ♫
Well, that's an unusual story,
and a fascinating plant.
Oh, while I'm here,
I might as well take $50 worth of roses.
$50! Wooo!
- Can you break a hundred?
- A hundred? Ah! No!
Well, then I'll just have to
take twice as many, won't I?
- Twice as many?
- Twice as many? - Twice as many!
Twice as many.
That plant in the window,
it's simply amazing!
wherever did you get it?
- Look, there it is, Marge.
- Oh, my gosh, it's peculiar.
Thank You!
Thank you very much, sir!
Thank you!
Thank you! Come again!
Come and look at the
weirdo plant some more!
It's just going to get
bigger and more interesting.
Just don't stand there! Quick, quick!
Put the plant back in the...
Oh, what did you call it?
Audrey II.
Well, put that Audrey II back in the
window where passersby can see it.
Oh, my god!
I never thought this could happen!
Oh, my children,
I'm taking us all out to dinner tonight!
Oh! I'd love to, Mr.
Mushnik, but I have a date.
With that same old nogoodnik?
I'm tellin' you, Audrey, you don't need
a date with him, you need major medical.
He's a rebel, Mr. Mushnik,
but he... he makes good money.
Besides...
he's the only fella I got.
Enjoy dinner.
Goodnight, Seymour.
Goodnight... Audrey.
Poor girl.
Are we still going out?
You're not going anywhere, Krelborn!
You're staying right here
and taking care of that sick plant!
I told you it's been giving me trouble.
The Audrey II is not a healthy girl.
Strictly between us,
neither is the Audrey I.
If I only knew what breed it was.
Who cares what breed it is?
Look what it's done for business.
- I know.
- So, work Seymour.
Nurse this plant back to
health, I'm counting on you.
- I know.
- You do?
- I do.
- So fix. Good night.
♫ Oo sha la la la do,
wa wa. ♫
Well, Twoey, I don't know
what else I can do for ya.
Are you sickly, little plant,
or are you just plain stubborn?
What is it you want?
What is it you need?
♫ I've given you sunshine
I've given you dirt. ♫
♫ You've given me nothing
but heartache and hurt. ♫
♫ I'm begging you sweetly
I'm down on my knees. ♫
♫ Oh, please, grow for me. ♫
♫ I've given you plant food
and water to sip. ♫
♫ I've given you potash,
you've given me zip. ♫
♫ Oh, God, how I mist you,
oh, Pod, how you tease. ♫
♫ Now please, grow for me. ♫
♫ I've given you southern exposure
to get you to thrive. ♫
♫ I've pinched you back hard
like I'm supposed ta. ♫
♫ You're barely alive. ♫
♫ I've tried you at levels of
moisture, from desert to mud. ♫
♫ I've given you grow lights
and mineral supplements. ♫
♫ What do you want from me?
Blood? ♫
Oh! Damn roses!
Damn thorns!
♫ I've given you sunlight,
I've given you rain. ♫
♫ Looks like you're not happy ♫
♫ 'less I open a vein. ♫
♫ I'll give you a few drops, ♫
♫ if that'll appease. ♫
♫ Oh, please... ♫
♫ Oh, oh, oh... please... ♫
♫ grow for me! ♫
W-S-K-I-D.
Skid Row Radio.
You're listening to radio station
WSKID, home of the hits.
And in just a few minutes we'll be
bringing you Wink Wilkensen's Weird World,
the show that talks to wonderful people
who bring in their weird things.
But first, the weather.
Thank you very much, Tom. The weather today will
be partly cloudy with a chance of rain.
Sorry about that. The high temperature
will be in the low 50s tonight, so,
get out those electric blankets, and
tomorrow we'll start off with
some morning haze and clouds.
- Uh, excuse me. I was told to come...
- Yeah, you're next.
High tomorrow should be in the low 70s
with the low in the high 60s.
In the suburbs, the sun should be
out through most of the day...
except for some cloudy
patches towards the evening,
but I don't think
that'll affect your barbecue.
The barometer reading
should be 21 point 6.
And the wind will be at about...
I'd say 12 miles per hour.
So, watch it out there on those boats.
The sun will be rising tomorrow
at about 7:17 am...
and it should be setting
around 6:29 p.m., but...
check me if I'm wrong.
The cold front is moving in
from the southwest,
but it should brighten up by noon.
The weekend should be mild, and for
you Average Mean Temperature fans,
the average mean temperature
for the season,
69 degrees, not too bad.
Thank you, and back to you.
You're listening to radio station WSKID.
And now, Wink Wilkensen's Weird World,
with your host, Wink Wilkensen.
Hi everybody! It's Weird Wink
Wilkensen, laughin' and scratchin' at ya.
How's everybody doin' today? I got a little
bit of a stiff neck. Let me just fix this up.
Oooh!
That feels a lot better!
Well, I got a great show for you today
with some wonderful weird stuff!
What are you doing here?
Wah...! You...! Please, lady, no, put your
clothes back on! It's Wink... you can't do this to me!
I mean, what if your
husband were to walk in?
I'm right here, Wink,
I'm sorry, I love your show...
but I've got to kill you both
with this machine gun.
Oh! You got me!
Oh, oh, oh, I feel...
I feel so very weird!
Okay, our first guest today is a young man
you probably read about in the newspapers,
a young man by the name of... uh...
Seymour Krelborn,
is that correct?
Who has discovered a new breed of
plant life hitherto unknown on this planet.
Let me play you down
to your seat, Seymour.
Hello, Seymour!
Um...
Hello, Wink.
Hey, I wish you folks
at home could see this.
Seymour, where did you get
such a weird plant?
Well, you remember that total
eclipse of the sun about a week ago?
♫ Da ooh! ♫
And thus we conclude our interview with
Seymour Krelborn, the young botanical...
Mind if I call you a genius?
Gosh, no!
The genius who had discovered
this most amazing, unidentified plant.
Uh... I'd like to remind our listeners
that the Audrey II is on display
exclusively at
Mushnik's Skid Row Florists.
- Am I late? Did I miss it?
- Mushnik's.
And, so, until next week...
- The address!
- This is Wilkinson saying so long...
- Six days a week...
I said, "Mention the address!"
♫ W.S.K.I.D. ♫
♫ Skid Row Radio. ♫
Oh, well. It's still good advertising.
Seymour's first radio broadcast.
I wanted to hear it so bad.
I tried to be on time, but...
- Don't tell me, you got tied up?
- No, just handcuffed a little.
Girl! Hey, girl!
I don't know who this mess is you been hangin'
out with, but he is hazardous to your health.
Oh, that's for sure,
but I can't leave him.
- Why not?
- Oh, he'd get angry.
And if he does this when he likes me,
imagine what he'd do if he ever got mad.
So, dump the chump,
get another guy and let him protect you.
How about the little
jerk with the glasses?
- Seymour?
- That him.
Oh, we're just friends.
I don't even deserve a desperate, sweet,
considerate, suddenly successful guy like Seymour.
That poor child suffers
from low self-image.
- You got a point.
- She got a problem.
♫ I know Seymour's the greatest, ♫
♫ but I'm dating a semi-sadist. ♫
♫ So I got a black eye
and my arm's in a cast. ♫
♫ Still that Seymour's a cutie. ♫
♫ Well, if not, he's
got inner beauty. ♫
♫ And I dream of a place ♫
♫ where we could
be together at last. ♫
♫ A matchbox of our own. ♫
♫ A fence of real chain-link. ♫
♫ A grill out on the patio. ♫
♫ Disposal in the sink. ♫
♫ A washer and a dryer. ♫
♫ And an ironing machine. ♫
♫ In a tract house
that we share. ♫
♫ Somewhere that's green. ♫
♫ He rakes and trims the grass. ♫
♫ He loves to mow and weed. ♫
♫ I cook like Betty Crocker ♫
♫ and I look like
Donna Reed. ♫
♫ There's plastic on the furniture ♫
♫ to keep it neat and clean, ♫
♫ in the Pine-Sol scented air. ♫
♫ Somewhere that's green. ♫
♫ Between our frozen dinner ♫
♫ and our bedtime, 9:15 ♫
♫ we snuggle watching Lucy ♫
♫ on our big, enormous
12-inch screen. ♫
♫ I'm... ♫
♫  his December bride. ♫
♫ He's father, he knows best. ♫
♫ The kids play Howdy Doody ♫
♫ as the sun sets in the west. ♫
♫ A picture out of Better Homes
and Gardens magazine. ♫
♫ Far from Skid Row ♫
♫ I dream we'll go. ♫
♫ Somewhere... that's... ♫
♫ green. ♫
♫ Ya ya ya ya,
ya ya ya. ♫
♫ Poor Seymour pushed a broom.
Nothing in his news but gloom and doom. ♫
♫ Then he lit a fuse and give him room.
He started an explosion, holy cow. ♫
♫ That thing went bang kerboom
and he's having some fun now. ♫
♫ Now! ♫
♫ Some fun now.
Hot damn! ♫
♫ - Ain't he having some fun now? ♫
- Yes, ma'am
♫ - He's having some fun now.
- Oh boy! ♫
♫ Ain't he having some fun now? ♫
Now!
♫ Some fun now!
Sho' 'nough. ♫
♫ Ain't he havin' some fun now
Hot stuff. ♫
♫ He's a-havin' some fun now.
Oh boy! ♫
♫ Ain't he havin' some fun now?
Now! ♫
♫ Some fun now!
Good God, good God! ♫
♫ He's havin' some fun now?
Oh boy, oh boy. ♫
♫ Yes, he's havin' some fun now
Oh boy. ♫
♫ Ain't he havin' some fun now! ♫
♫ Some fun now. ♫
Excuse me, excuse me.
Hello? Hello?
Yes, yes, yes, yes, Mrs. Shiva.
- No, Mrs. Shiva.
- I'd like to pay for these.
Right away, Mrs. Shiva.
Seymour!
Seymour!!
Did you send out the
order for Mrs. Shiva?
Mrs. Shiva? I forgot!
You forgot?
You forgot!!
Do you hear this, God? He forgot!
Are you listening, customers?
He forgot!
Audrey, quick! We've got to do
an emergency arrangement.
Birthday? Wedding? Baby?
- Funeral.
- Get me the lilies.
Mr. Mushnik's real mad at me,
Audrey, I keep forgettin' things.
Scissors. You got a lot on your mind.
Mind? What mind? The Shivas are
our most important funereal account.
A big, enormous family,
they're dropping off like flies!
Sometimes I think Mr.
Mushnik's too hard on you.
- Glue.
- Well, that's okay,
- after all, I owe him everything.
- Glitter.
He took me out of the Skid Row Home
for Boys when I was just a little tike,
gave me a warm place to stay,
floors to sweep, toilets to clean,
and every other Sunday off.
You know, I... I think you ought
to raise your expectations, Seymour.
Now that you're getting successful, I mean.
It's clear you suffer
from a low self-image,
and it's high time
you get it fixed.
Why don't you go out and...
and do something nice for yourself like.
buy some new clothes?
Well, I'm a very
bad shopper, Audrey.
I don't have good taste, like you.
Oh... uh...
but I could help you pick things out.
- You could?
- Sure.
You'd go shopping with me?
Sure.
You'd be seen with me in a public
place like a department store?
Sure.
Tonight?
Oh, I can't tonight,
I got a date.
Again, this date?
Some date.
A date gives you a corsage,
not a multiple fracture.
I'm tellin' you, Audrey,
he's not a good, clean kind of boy.
He's a professional.
What kind of a professional rides a
motorcycle and wears a black leather jacket?
♫ When I was younger,
just a bad little kid, ♫
♫ my mama noticed
funny things I did, ♫
♫ like shooting puppies
with a BB gun. ♫
♫ I'd poison guppies
and when I was done, ♫
♫ I'd find a pussycat
and bash in its head. ♫
♫ That's when my mama said, ♫
♫ What did she say? ♫
♫ She said,
"My boy, I think someday" ♫
♫ "you'll find a way to make your
natural tendencies pay." ♫
♫ - "You'll be a dentist."
- You'll be a dentist. ♫
♫ "You have a talent for
causing things pain." ♫
♫ - Pain
- "Son, be a dentist," ♫
♫ Be a dentist. ♫
♫ "People will pay you to be inhumane." ♫
♫ Inhumane. ♫
♫ "Your temperament's
wrong for the priesthood," ♫
♫ "and teaching would
suit you still less." ♫
♫ - "Son, be a dentist."
- Son, be a dentist. ♫
♫ - "You'll be a success."
- You'll be a success. ♫
♫ Here he is, folks,
the leader of the plaque. ♫
♫ Watch him suck up that gas.
Oh, my God! ♫
♫ He is a dentist and he'll
never ever be any good. ♫
♫ Who wants their teeth done
by the Marquis de Sade? ♫
Oh, that hurts!
Wait, I'm not numb.
Oh, shut up.
Open wide, here I come!
♫ - I am your dentist.
- I am your dentist. ♫
♫ And I enjoy the
career that I picked. ♫
♫ - I am your dentist,
- I am your dentist. ♫
♫ and I get off on the pain I inflict. ♫
♫ I thrill when I drill a bicuspid. ♫
♫ Bicuspid. ♫
♫ It's swell, though they tell me
I'm maladjusted. ♫
♫ Maladjusted. ♫
♫ And though it may cause
my patients distress, ♫
♫ - No, no, no!
- Distress. ♫
♫ somewhere, somewhere
in heaven above me, ♫
♫ I know, I know that
my mama's proud of me. ♫
Oh, Mama!
♫ - 'Cause I'm a dentist,
- Dentist. ♫
♫ and a success. ♫
♫ Say, "Aaah". ♫
Aagh.
Aggh!
♫ Say, "Aaah" ♫
Aggghh!!
♫ Now spit! ♫
Excuse me, sir,
you can't go in there right now.
Relax. You want
some nitrous oxide?
Suit yourself.
We're closed.
Oh, it's all right, Seymour,
this is my date, my boyfriend.
And Seymour, Orin Scrivello,
D.D.S.
Hey! I know you! Sure!
I saw you on the news.
I even know your name.
Now, let's see, it's uh... Cecil.
No, no, no, it's uh...
Cedric.
- No.
- Give me a chance.
It's uh...
- Simon?
- It is Seymour!
- Somebody talkin' to you?
- Oh, no. Excuse me.
- Excuse me, what?
- Excuse me... Doctor.
That's betta.
I know! Sure!
You're the plant guy, right?
Hey, that means it
must be in there, huh?
Well! That is incredible!
- What do you call that thing?
- Audrey II.
Cute name, it's catchy.
Nice plant, big.
Uh, shouldn't we be leaving now?
You're quite the little
chatterbox tonight, ain't ya?
- I'm sorry.
- Sorry, what?
I'm sorry, Doctor.
Doctor. Sorry, Doctor.
You gotta train 'em, huh, stud?
Listen, here's my card,
you ever need a root canal or
anything like that, give me a buzz, ya hear?
Now, I'm serious,
it's on the house.
Audrey!
- You got the handcuffs?
- They're right in my bag.
You ought to see the
way he treats her, Twoey.
She deserves a prince,
not a sadistic creep like him.
The man's a total disgrace
to the dental profession.
I don't know what's
going on, sometimes.
Seems like the whole
world's goin' crazy.
At least we got each other, right?
I'm gonna turn in, Twoey.
I'll see you in the mornin'.
Oh, boy, here we go again.
Come on,
I haven't got much left.
Just give me a few days to heal, okay?
Then we'll start again on the left hand and...
Feed me.
I beg your pardon?
Twoey, you talked! You opened
your trap, you said... and you said...
Feed me, Krelborn!
Feed me now!
- I can't!
- I'm starvin'!
Look, maybe I can squeeze a
little more out of this one.
- More! More! More! More!
- There isn't any more!
What do you want me to do?
Slit my wrists?
Oh, boy!
Look, I got an idea.
I'm gonna go down to Schmedrick's and
pick you up some nice chopped sirloin.
- Must be blood.
- Twoey, that's disgusting.
- Must be fresh.
- I don't want to hear this.
♫ Feed me. ♫
Does it have to be human?
Does it have to be mine?
♫ Feed me. ♫
Where am I supposed to get it?
♫ Feed me, Seymour, ♫
♫ feed me all night long. ♫
♫ That's right, boy. ♫
♫ You can do it. ♫
♫ Feed me, Seymour, ♫
♫ feed me all night long. ♫
♫ 'Cause if you feed me, Seymour, ♫
♫ I can grow up big and strong. ♫
You eat blood, Audrey II,
let's face it.
How am I supposed to keep
on feeding you, kill people?
I'll make it worth your while.
What?
You think this is all coincidence, baby?
The sudden success around here?
The press coverage?
Look, you're a plant,
an inanimate object.
Does this look inanimate to you, punk?
If I can talk and I can move,
who's to say I can't do anything I want?
- Like what?
- Like deliver, pal.
Like see you get everything
your sacred, greasy heart desires.
♫ Would you like a Cadillac car? ♫
♫ Or a guest shot on Jack Paar? ♫
♫ How about a date with Hedy Lamarr?
You're gonna get it, if you want it, baby. ♫
♫ How'd you like to be a big wheel? ♫
♫ Dining out for every meal? ♫
♫ I'm the plant that can make it all real. ♫
♫ You're gonna get it. ♫
♫ I'm your genie, I'm your friend,
I'm your willing slave. ♫
♫ Take a chance,
feed me and ♫
♫ you know the kind of eats
and red-hot treats, ♫
♫ the kind of sticky, licky sweets I crave. ♫
♫ Come on, Seymour, don't be a putz. ♫
♫ Trust me, and your life
will surely rival King Tut's. ♫
♫ Show a little initiative, boy, work
up some guts and you'll get it. ♫
♫ I don't know. ♫
Come on, boy!
Lighten up.
♫ I have so... ♫
♫ so many strong... ♫
♫ reservations. ♫
Tell it to the Marines.
♫ Should I go... ♫
♫ and perform... ♫
♫ mutilations? ♫
♫ You didn't have nothing
till you met me. ♫
♫ Come on, kid,
what will it be? ♫
♫ Money? Girls? ♫
♫ One particular girl? ♫
♫ How about that Audrey? ♫
♫ Think it over. ♫
♫ There must be
someone you can 86. ♫
♫ Real quiet like and
get me some lunch! ♫
♫ Think about a
room at the Ritz, ♫
♫ wrapped in velvet,
covered in glitz. ♫
♫ A little nookie gonna clean
up those zits, and you'll get it. ♫
♫ Gee, I'd like a Harley machine
tooling around like I was James Dean. ♫
♫ Making all the guys on
the corner turn green. ♫
♫ So, get it!
Woo woo woo. ♫
♫ If you want to be profound,
if you really got to justify, ♫
♫ take a breath and look around. ♫
♫ A lot of folks deserve to die. ♫
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
That's not a very nice thing to say.
- But it's true, isn't it?
- No.
I don't know anyone who deserves to get
chopped up and fed to a hungry plant!
♫ Sure you do. ♫
Stupid woman! Christ!
What a frigging scatterbrain!
I'm sorry, Doctor!
- Falls off the motorcycle!
- I'm clumsy, Doctor. I'm clumsy, Doctor.
Messes my hair!
Get the door open, you little slut!
I'm trying, Doctor.
Get the Vitalis.
Quick! The Vitalis!
- I'm out of it!
- What?!
♫ If you want a rationale
it isn't very hard to see. ♫
♫ No, no, no. ♫
♫ Stop and think it over, pal. ♫
♫ The guy sure looks like
plant food to me. ♫
♫ The guy sure looks
like plant food to me. ♫
♫ He's so nasty treating her rough. ♫
♫ Smacking her around
and always talking so tough. ♫
♫ You need blood
and he's got more than enough. ♫
♫ I need blood
♫ You/I need blood
and he's got more than enough. ♫
♫ So go get it! ♫
Hey! Does that mean
they're finished? My turn?
Sit!
What happened? What did
he do? Tell me everything!
Well, they have to do
that to remove the jaw.
Ah! Consider yourself
very, very lucky.
- Next!
- It's me, Arthur Denton! I'm next!
Nurse!
Does... that have an appointment?
Ask it, I'm off duty.
I've been saving all month for this.
I think I need a root canal.
I'm sure I need a long,
slow root canal.
Let's go.
- I have a history of dental problems.
- Shut up!
Yes, Doctor.
I went to a terrible dentist on Wednesday,
who was recommended to me by...
somebody that I saw Monday...
who's the brother of a man
that I usually see Sundays.
And their mother actually taught
them everything they know.
She's incredibly gifted, and quite elderly and a
lot of people think she shouldn't be working, but...
I go to her because I'm just
incredibly devoted to her strength.
She can't really see who you are, but she
knows... she knows the sound of your voice.
And if you tell her
where it is, the problem,
she eventually works her way back and
she finds the trouble and she does it.
I wish I had that stamina,
'cause I can only go so long.
That's how I want to be.
I don't ever want to have to be just...
- Comfy?
- Yes, Doctor.
I remember the first time
I went to a dentist.
I thought, "Gosh, what a neat
job! If only I were a dentist."
The dentist I went
to had the greatest car.
He had a Corvette. I thought,
"My gosh, everybody calls him ' Doctor'
and he's not really a doctor."
Oh, my God!
Only I got out of there okay, and then,
and then, ya know, after it was all finished...
they gave me a candy bar. I
thought, "This is what I get, a candy bar?"
This is what you do, you go through a
little thing you get chocolate out of it.
For getting to work with incredible professionals,
using incredibly, incredibly wonderful equipment...
- and that's...
- Let's look at that mouth.
- Say, "Aaah".
- Aaaaah!
Aaah! Candy bar!
Oh! Candy bar! Candy bar!
Oh, that's great! C'mon!
Gosh! Oh, God! Do it again!
Oh, God! Doctor! Whoo!
Yeah! Oh! Great!
Oh! You are something special!
You are something special!
C'mon! C'mon! C'mon!
Thank you!
Oh! Yeah! Yeah! Thank you!
Oh, my god! It's your
professionalism that I respect.
Oh, God! Don't stop, doc!
Don't stop! Come on! More!
Yeah! Yeah, come on! Yeah!
What do you want? Say, "Please"!
Aah, aah, aah..
Unh-unh, unh-unh, unh-unh.
Great! Oh!
I'm going to get a candy bar!
Ah! C'mon!
Oh, yeah!
Yeah, oh!
Wow!
Oh, yeah!
Oh, yes!
-Yes!
- Yeah.
Get out!
- What's wrong?
- Get out of here!
Whatsa matter?
Go on! Get out of here!
Right this way.
I'm gonna tell each and
every one of my friends
about you and they're
gonna hear about...
Just get it!
- What's this?
- Oops.
Ha-ha-ha.
Sorry.
Goddamn sicko!
Let me ask you something,
does this thing scare you?
Yes.
Would you like if I
took this thing and
- made straight for your goddamn incisors?
- No.
- It'd hurt, right?
- Mn-hm.
- You'd scream, right?
- Mm-hm.
Well, get your ass in there!
- Say, don't I know you?
- Yeah, Seymour Krelborn, we met yesterday.
Oh, your mouth's a mess, kid.
That wisdom tooth. We'll just rip
that little bugger right out of there.
- Now, what do you say?
- No, let me...
There's always time for
dental hygiene, Seymour.
You ever seen the results
of a neglected mouth?
Look, Seymour.
This could happen to you.
Unless I take immediate action!
- Uh, what's that?
- A drill.
- It's rusty!
- It's an antique.
They don't make them like this anymore.
Sturdy...
heavy...
dull.
I'm going to want some gas for this.
Oh, thank god,
I thought you wouldn't use any.
The gas isn't for you,
Seymour, It's for me.
You see, I want to really enjoy this.
In fact, I'm going to use
my special gas mask!
I find a little giggle gas before I
begin increases my pleasure enormously.
Here we go!
Oh, Seymour, I'm flying!
The things I'm going
to do to that mouth!
What the hell's that?
A gun?
The kid's got a goddamn revolver!
Oh, Jesus,
I'm in trouble now, huh?
Oh, wait till I turn this gas off.
Uh-oh.
Oh, give me a hand,
would ya? Huh?
No, I guess you wouldn't, would ya?
You see, Seymour, I could asphyx...
Asphyx...
What'd I ever do to you?
- Nothing, it's what you did to her.
- Her who?
Oh, her.
Shh! Go away.
- Um! Chop it up.
- What?
- Feed me!
- Okay, okay.
Oh, brother.
Gimme, gimme, gimme,
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Audrey, what'd they say to you?
- Oh, who?
- The police.
- Oh, uh, nothing.
Audrey, talk to me,
tell me what they said.
It's Orin, they say
he's disappeared!
- The... the police, they told you that?
- They suspect foul play.
They do?
His receptionist, this morning
she found the place a shambles.
Gas masks everywhere.
Things all over the floor.
They think...
I can't even think
about what they think.
Audrey?
Don't cry, Audrey.
Would it be so terrible if
something had happened to him?
Seymour, what a thing to say!
Well, would it?
It wouldn't be terrible at all...
it'd be a miracle.
Not to mention all the money I'd
save on Epsom salts and Ace bandages.
You see?
But I'd still feel guilty,
I mean...
if he met with foul play or
some terrible accident of some kind,
it'd be partly my
fault just because...
secretly I wished it.
Audrey, don't you waste another
minute thinking about that creep!
There's a lot of guys that'd...
give anything to go out with you.
- Nice guys.
- I don't deserve a nice guy, Seymour.
- That's not true.
- You don't know the half of it!
I've led a terrible life.
I deserved a...
a creep like Orin Scrivello, D.D.S.
You know where I met him?
- In The Gutter.
- The Gutter?
The Gutter, it's a nightspot.
I worked there on my nights off
when we weren't making much money.
I'd put on...
cheap and tasteless outfits,
not nice ones like this.
Low and nasty apparel.
Audrey, that's all behind you now,
you got nothing to be ashamed of.
You're a very nice person.
I always knew you were.
Underneath the bruises and the
handcuffs, you know what I saw?
A girl I respected.
I still do.
♫ Lift up your head. ♫
♫ Wash off your mascara. ♫
♫ Here, take my Kleenex
wipe that lipstick away. ♫
♫ Show me your face, ♫
♫ clean as the morning. ♫
♫ I know things were bad, ♫
♫ but now they're okay. ♫
♫ Suddenly Seymour ♫
♫ is standing beside you. ♫
♫ You don't need no make-up. ♫
♫ Don't have to pretend. ♫
♫ Suddenly Seymour ♫
♫ is here to provide you ♫
♫ sweet understanding. ♫
♫ Seymour's your friend. ♫
♫ Nobody ever treated me kindly. ♫
♫ Daddy left early. ♫
♫ Mama was poor. ♫
♫ I'd meet a man
and I'd follow him blindly. ♫
♫ He'd snap his fingers at me, ♫
♫ I'd say, "Sure". ♫
♫ Suddenly Seymour ♫
♫ is standing beside me. ♫
♫ He don't give me orders. ♫
♫ He don't condescend. ♫
♫ Suddenly Seymour ♫
♫ is here to provide me ♫
♫ sweet understanding. ♫
♫ Seymour's my friend.
Tell me this feeling ♫
♫ will last 'til forever. ♫
♫ Tell me the bad times
are clean washed away. ♫
♫ Please understand that
it's still strange and frightening ♫
♫ for losers like I've been.
It's so hard to save. ♫
♫ Suddenly Seymour. ♫
♫ He purified me. ♫
♫ He purified you. ♫
♫ Suddenly Seymour ♫
♫ Suddenly Seymour. ♫
♫ showed me I can. ♫
♫ - Yes, she can!
- Yes, he can! ♫
♫ - Learn how to be more.
- Be more. ♫
♫ - The girl that's inside me.
- The girl that's inside you. ♫
♫ - With sweet understanding.
- With sweet understanding. ♫
♫ - Seymour's your man.
- Seymour's your man. ♫
You love her madly,
don't you, schmuck?
Mr. Mushnik, you scared me.
I... I...
I scared him?
After what I seen, I scared him?
Do you think I didn't know, huh?
Oh, I knew.
I knew you lay down here,
on your pathetic little cot
and dream about her.
But I didn't know the
lengths to which you'd go
the depths to which you'd sink!
What depths? What sink?
What are you talking about?
Little red dots all
over the linoleum.
Little red spots on
the concrete outside.
I'm talking blood, Krelborn.
I'm talking under my own roof.
An axe murderer!
♫ He's got your number now. ♫
I saw everything.
♫ He knows just
what you've done. ♫
Everything you did
to her boyfriend.
♫ You've got no
place to hide. ♫
I saw you chopping him.
♫ You've got nowhere to run. ♫
It's true. I chopped him up,
but I didn't kill him!
♫ He knows your
life of crime. ♫
Tell it to the police.
♫ I think it's suppertime! ♫
♫ Come on, come on. ♫
♫ Think about all those offers. ♫
♫ Your future with Audrey. ♫
♫ Come on, come on. ♫
♫ Ain't no time to turn squeamish. ♫
♫ Come on. ♫
♫ I swear on all my spores ♫
♫ when he's gone
the world will be yours. ♫
♫ Yours, yes yes, yes. ♫
♫ Come on. Come on. Come on. ♫
♫ Come on. Come on. ♫
♫ It's suppertime. ♫
You know, Krelborn,
it kills me doing this, but...
considering you're almost
like a son to me, I'm thinking...
maybe we don't have
to go to the police.
- We don't?
- I'm thinking...
what if I kept my mouth shut and
gave you a one-way ticket outta town?
You'd do that, sir?
You could lay low for a
while, say 30, 40 years.
- Meanwhile, I would keep the plant.
- The plant?
Of course, you'd have to teach me
how to take care of it while you're away.
Give me your secret gardening tips.
But then, if you'd rather hang...
♫ Come on. Come on. ♫
What do I have to do?
Just feed it.
Just feed it what?
♫ Suppertime. ♫
♫ Come on. Come on. ♫
- Minerals.
- Yes.
♫ Come on. Come on. ♫
Thursdays, you should give it water.
- What else?
♫ - Come on. Come on. ♫
♫ It's suppertime. ♫
But whatever you do...
Yes?
♫ It's suppertime. ♫
- Whatever you do...
- Yeah?
- What the hell is...
- Sir!
Wait! Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
I said, "Wait!"
Wait!
♫ It's suppertime. ♫
Seymour Krelborn!
So, finally, we meet you! What an
occasion! Let's toast it. Up yours. Christ!
- Canapé?
- Cigarette?
Let's talk turkey. Sign here.
- We'll book you on lecturing tours.
- Yes, darling.
We're sending photographers Thursday.
So get the plant ready
and wear a clean shirt.
- Just sign this release.
- Need a pen?
Aren't you thrilled?
It's the cover of Life magazine!
Dessert?
I'm telling you, son,
it's a cinch to get ratings.
- The title is Marvin's.
- The concept is mine.
The first weekly
gardening show on a network!
- And you're gonna host it, you lucky kid.
- Sign! - Sign! - Sign!
♫ They say the meek shall inherit.
You know the Book doesn't lie. ♫
♫ It's not a question of merit,
it's not demand and supply. ♫
♫ They say the meek
are gonna get it. ♫
♫ You know the meek are gonna get
what's coming to them. ♫
Oh, my God!
And here he is himself,
Mr. Seymour Krelborn!
Mr. Krelborn, we'll
have so many questions
that the American people in our
television audience have for you.
Come over here and tell our viewers
at home, and elsewhere,
about this particularly
amazing agricultural phenomenon,
a phenomenon, I might
add, that has made you one of
the most talked about plant
scientists in the country.
Cut!
What the hell's going on, what
happened to the goddamned greenery?
- It just needs to be fed.
- So feed it.
I can't feed it, not now.
Then I'll feed it.
Where do you keep the plant food?
It doesn't eat plant food,
and I can't feed it now.
Why don't you leave
me alone? All a ya.
Just go away. Leave me alone.
Get out of here. Go away. Leave me alone!
Go away! Leave me alone!
Everybody go away! Leave me alone!
Seymour!
You're hysterical.
I know, I'm sorry.
What am I gonna do?
I never should've started, but I did.
Now, if I don't feed it, it'll die.
I'll lose her, I'll lose everything.
- Seymour, who are you talking to?
- Oh, huh? Nobody.
You're acting funny. It wasn't
nice throwing those people out.
Those men said Seymour Krelborn's
Gardening Tips is sure to be a very big TV show.
- I know, I'm sorry, I feel terrible.
- Well, you shouldn't.
They're coming back tomorrow and
they're bringing you a great big check.
- They are?
- I wish you were enjoying your success.
- They said they're coming back with money?
- Tomorrow.
Then we could afford to get
out of here, couldn't we?
Uh, whadya mean?
That's it, after tomorrow
we could leave here together.
Together?
If you'll have me.
Audrey, will you have me?
- Uh, whadya mean?
- Marry me, Audrey.
- Oh, Seymour, this is so sudden.
- Well, will ya?
Sure.
Then that's it!
We'll go get married right now.
Oh, Seymour!
Then tomorrow we'll come back,
I'll be on television, get the money
and then we'll live
happily ever after.
Oh, Audrey, I'll give you a
wonderful life with no plants, I promise.
- No plants at all.
- You're talking peculiar again, Seymour.
We'll start tonight, we'll
go to City Hall, get married,
and spend the night
somewhere it's safe, some nice hotel.
- Oh, Seymour.
- Oh, Audrey.
Oh, I gotta get ready!
Hurry, hurry!
Feed me.
Under no circumstances.
I will not, so stop asking.
Feed me!
No! No more!
I can't take living with the guilt.
Tough titty.
Watch your language.
Aw, cut the crap,
bring on the meat.
Okay, okay.
I'll bring you meat, I'll run down to the
corner, pick you up some nice ground round.
- How about that?
- Don't do me no favors!
- Look!
- Hmm?
It's my last offer, yes or no?
You sure do drive a hard bargain.
Done! Fine! Great!
Don't think you're getting dessert!
- Hello.
- ♫ Hey, little lady, hello. ♫
Who... who is this?
♫ You're looking cute as can be. ♫
Is this someone I know?
♫ You're looking mighty sweet. ♫
Seymour!
♫ No, it ain't
Seymour, this is me! ♫
Oh, my God!
- I don't believe it.
- Believe it, baby, it talks.
Am I dreaming this?
No, and you ain't in Kansas, neither.
Something is very wrong here.
I need... need me some
water in the worst way.
Look at my branches.
I'm drying up.
I'm a goner, honey!
♫ Come on and give me a drink. ♫
I don't know if I should.
♫ Hey, little lady, be nice. ♫
Do you talk to Seymour like this?
♫ Sure do. I'll drink it straight. ♫
Your leaves are dry.
♫ Don't need no glass or no ice. ♫
I'll get the can.
♫ Don't need no twist of lime. ♫
Here we go.
♫ And now it's suppertime! ♫
Oh, relax, doll,
it'll be easy.
Get offa her! Get off!
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
Audrey! Audrey!
Yes, I... I'm okay.
I'm sorry, Audrey, I'm just so
sorry, I never meant to hurt you.
I never meant to hurt anybody.
It's just that somehow it makes
things happen, terrible things.
Oh, I guess I shoulda stopped
when I found out what it lived on, but...
it was so cute and harmless and...
we started doing business and
making money and you liked me and...
Seymour, do you really think
I liked you because of that?
I liked you from the day
I came to work here.
You mean, you'd still like
me even if I wasn't famous?
I'd still love you, Seymour.
Really?
All I ever wanted... was you...
and a sweet little house.
Oh, Audrey, you're the most
wonderful person that ever lived.
We're gonna get that little house and
everything'll be okay somehow, you'll see.
♫ Suddenly Seymour ♫
♫ is standing beside you. ♫
♫ - showed me I can.
- Yes, you can... ♫
'Scuse me, 'scuse me,
pardon me, beg your pardon.
If you two kids would just
stop singing for a moment
I've got something
I wanna discuss with ya.
Now, which one of you
is Seymour Krelborn?
- I am.
- Oh, it's a pleasure.
Boy, has your phone been busy!
I've been trying to reach you for weeks.
Patrick Martin, Licensing and Marketing,
World Botanical Enterprises.
Son, kid, boy, are we gonna
make a fortune together!
- He's not interested.
- Oh, he will be.
Ya see, me and the guys at the home
office have been following this plant o'yours,
and we've come up with
one incredible idea.
We're very proud of it.
Picture this.
We take leaf cuttings,
develop little Audrey IIs...
and sell them to florist
shops across the nation.
Why, pretty soon every household
in America could have one.
Every household in America!
For starters, kid.
Why this thing could go...
worldwide!
- Worldwide?
Think of it, boy,
Audrey IIs everywhere!
Why, with the right advertising, this
thing could be bigger than Hula-Hoops.
Bigger than Hula-Hoops?
What do you say, Seymour?
We have a deal?
No! Keep your contract.
Nobody's touching that plant, ya hear?
Hey, hey!
We're offering a lot of money.
Forget the money! Keep the
money and get outta here! Go on!
- What are you, nuts?
- Yeah, I'm nuts.
- Get outta here!
- Hey, hey, now c'mon!
Go on! Get outta here!
You're a loser! Go on!
Go on, get out!
Look, I'll come back when
you're in a better mood.
- Go on! Get outta here, now!
- All right.
Audrey, you thinkin' what I'm thinkin'?
I think so.
He'll keep eatin', he'll keep
eatin' until there's nothing left.
We gotta stop it, Seymour!
We got to!
No... I've got to.
- I end this once and for all.
- Seymour.
- Bust that pod wide open.
- Wait! I'm coming with you.
No, it's me that got us into
this, I'm the one to get us out.
Wait for me, Audrey.
This is between me
and the vegetable.
Every household in America!
Thousands of you, eating!
That's what you had in
mind all along, isn't it?
No shit, Sherlock!
We're not talking about one hungry plant
here, we're talking about world conquest!
And I want to thank you!
You're not gonna get away
with this, your kind never does!
I don't care what it takes,
only one of us gets out of here alive!
♫ Better wait a minute. ♫
♫ You better hold the phone. ♫
♫ Better mind your manners,
better change your tone. ♫
♫ Don't you threaten me, son,
you got a lot of gall. ♫
♫ We're gonna do things my way, ♫
♫ or we won't do things at all. ♫
Ira!
♫ You in trouble now. ♫
Yes she damn!
♫ You don't know what
you're messin' with. ♫
♫ You got no idea. ♫
♫ You don't know what you're lookin' at
when you're lookin' here. ♫
♫ You don't know what you're up against.
No, no way, no how. ♫
♫ You don't know what
you're messin' with. ♫
♫ But I'm gonna tell you now. ♫
♫ - Now. -Now. - Now. - Now. ♫
♫ Get this straight! I'm just a mean,
green mother from outer space. ♫
♫ - And I'm bad.
- Mean, green, bad. ♫
Outer space?
♫ I'm just a mean, green mother from outer
space, and it looks like you've been had. ♫
♫ I'm a just mean, green mother
from outer space. ♫
♫ So get off my back. ♫
♫ Get out of my face. ♫
♫ 'Cause I'm mean and green. ♫
♫ And I am bad. ♫
♫ Want to save your skin, boy? ♫
♫ You want to save your hide? ♫
♫ You want to see tomorrow? ♫
♫ You better step aside. ♫
♫ You better take a tip, boy. ♫
♫ You want some good advice? ♫
♫ You better take it easy
'cause you're walkin' on thin ice. ♫
♫ You don't know what you're
dealin' with, no, you never did. ♫
♫ You don't know what you're lookin' at,
but that's tough titty, kid. ♫
♫ The lion don't sleep tonight
and if you pull his tail he roars. ♫
♫ You say that ain't fair,
you say that ain't nice. ♫
♫ You know what I say?
"Up yours!" ♫
♫ - Up. - Up. - Up. - Up. - Up. ♫
♫ Watch me now! ♫
♫ I'm just a mean, green mother
from outer space. ♫
♫ - And I'm bad.
- Mean, green, bad. ♫
♫ I'm just a mean, green mother,
a real disgrace. ♫
♫ And you got me fighting mad. ♫
♫ I'm just a mean, green mother
from outer space, ♫
♫ I'm gonna trash your ass,
gonna rock this place. ♫
♫ I'm mean and green. ♫
♫ And I am bad! ♫
♫ Ya know, I don't come
from no black lagoon. ♫
♫ I'm from past the
stars, beyond the moon. ♫
♫ You can keep the "Thing",
keep the "It". ♫
♫ Keep the creatures
they don't mean shit. ♫
All right, that does it!
♫ I got killer buds,
a power stem. ♫
♫ Nasty thorns and I'm using
them, so, better move it out. ♫
♫ Nature calls, you got the
point, I'm gonna bust your balls. ♫
♫ - Ah. -Ah. - Ah. -Ah. ♫
♫ I'm mean and green. ♫
♫ And  I... ♫
♫ am... ♫
♫ bad. ♫
Bye-bye, Seymour!
Oh, shit!
♫ Little Shop
Little Shop of Horror. ♫
Little Shop of Terror. ♫
♫ Call a cop
Little Shop of Horrors. ♫
♫ No, oh, oh, no-oh! ♫
♫ Little Shop
Little Shop of Horrors. ♫
♫ Bop she-bop,
Little Shop of Terror. ♫
♫ Watch 'em drop
Little Shop of Horrors. ♫
♫ No, oh, oh, no-oh! ♫
♫ Shing-a-ling what a creepy
thing to be happening. ♫
♫ Look out! Look out! Look out! ♫
♫ Shang-a-lang feel the
Sturm und Drang in the air. ♫
♫ Stop right where you are
don't move a thing. ♫
♫ You better... ♫
♫ You'd better, telling you, you'd better
tell your mama. ♫
♫ Something's gonna get her
she'd better, everybody better, beware! ♫
♫ Come-a, come- a, come-a. ♫
♫ Little Shop, Little
Shop of Horrors. ♫
♫ Never stop, never
stop the terror. ♫
stop the horror. ♫
♫ No, oh, oh, no, oh,
oh, no, oh, oh, no! ♫
♫ When I was younger,
just a bad little kid, ♫
♫ my mama noticed
funny things I did, ♫
♫ like shooting puppies
with a BB gun. ♫
♫ I'd poison guppies
and when I was done, ♫
♫ I'd find a pussycat
and bash in its head. ♫
♫ That's when my mama said, ♫
♫ What did she say? ♫
♫ She said,
"My boy, I think someday" ♫
♫ What'd she say? ♫
♫ Just say it! ♫
♫ "You'll be a dentist". ♫
♫ "You have a talent for
causing things pain." ♫
♫ "Son, be a dentist," ♫
♫ "People will pay you to be inhumane." ♫
♫ "Your temperament's wrong
for the priesthood," ♫
♫ "and teaching would
suit you still less." ♫
♫ "Son, be a dentist." ♫
♫ "You'll be a success." ♫
♫ Here he is, folks,
the leader of the plaque. ♫
♫ Watch him suck up that gas.
Oh, my God! ♫
♫ He's a dentist and he'll
never ever be any good. ♫
♫ Who wants their teeth done
by the Marquis de Sade? ♫
That hurts! Wait, I'm not numb.
Aah, shut up. Open wide, here I come!
♫ I am your dentist. ♫
♫ And I enjoy the
career that I picked. ♫
♫ I am your dentist, ♫
♫ and I get off on
the pain I inflict. ♫
You'll love it.
♫ I thrill when I drill a bicuspid. ♫
♫ It's swell, though they tell me
I'm maladjusted. ♫
♫ And though it may cause
my patients distress, ♫
♫ somewhere, somewhere
in heaven above me, ♫
♫ I know... I know that my
mama's proud of me. ♫
Oh, Mama!
♫ 'Cause I'm a dentist, ♫
♫ and a success. ♫
♫ Say, "Aaah" ♫
Oh.
♫ Say, "Aaah". ♫
♫ Say, "Aaah" ♫
Aaah!
♫ Now spit! ♫
♫ If you want a rationale, ♫
♫ It isn't very hard to see. ♫
♫ No, No, No... ♫
♫ Stop and think it over, pal. ♫
♫ The guy sure looks
like plant food to me! ♫
♫ He's so nasty
treatin' her rough! ♫
♫ Smackin' her around,
and always talkin' so tough! ♫
♫ You need blood and he's
got more than enough! ♫
♫ I need blood and he's
♫ (You/I) need blood and he's
got more than enough...! ♫
So, Go Get It!
♫ La la la la,
la la la. ♫
♫ Ya ya ya ya,
ya ya ya. ♫
♫ Poor Seymour
pushed a broom, ♫
♫ nothing in his news
but gloom and doom. ♫
♫ Then he lit a fuse,
and give him room. ♫
♫ He started an explosion.
Holy cow! ♫
♫ That thing went bang ka-boom.
And he's havin' some fun now. ♫
♫ Some fun now! My word!
Hope he's havin' some fun now? ♫
♫ Sure did! He's a-havin'
some fun now. Oh boy! ♫
♫ Ain't he havin' some fun now? ♫
♫ Now! ♫
♫ Some fun now! Come and see him!
Ain't he havin' some fun now? ♫
♫ Yes, Ma'am!
He's a-havin' some fun now. ♫
♫ Oh boy!
Ain't he havin' some fun now? ♫
♫ - Suddenly Seymour.
- Suddenly Seymour. ♫
♫ - He purified you.
- He purified you. ♫
♫ - Suddenly Seymour.
- Suddenly Seymour. ♫
♫ - Showed me I can.
- Yes, you can. ♫
♫ - Learn how to be more.
- The girl that's inside me/you. ♫
♫ - With sweet understanding.
- With sweet understanding. ♫
♫ - With sweet understanding. ♫
♫ Seymour's your man. ♫