Seat belts, everyone!
Please let this be a normal field trip!
With the Frizz, no way!
Aaaaw!
♪ Cruising on down Main Street, ♪
♪ You're relaxed and feeling good! ♪
Yeah!
♪ Next thing that you know you're seein' ♪
Wah ha ha hoo!
Octopus in the neighborhood!
♪ Surfin' on a sound wave, ♪
♪ Swingin' through the stars! ♪
♪ Take a left at your intestine! ♪
♪ Take your second right past Mars! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Navigate a nostril! ♪ Achoo!
♪ Climb on the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Spank a plankton, too! ♪
Take that!
♪ On our Magic School Bus, ♪
♪ Raft a river of lava! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Such a fine thing to do! ♪
Woah!
♪ So strap your bones right to the seat! ♪
♪Come on in and don't be shy! ♪
Come on.
♪ Just to make your day complete, ♪
♪ You might get baked into a pie! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Step inside, it's a wild ride! ♪
Come on!
♪ Ride on the Magic School Bus! ♪