Seat belts, everyone!
Please let this be a normal field trip!
With the Frizz, no way!
Aaaaw!
♪ Cruising on down Main Street, ♪
♪ You're relaxed and feeling good! ♪
Yeah!
♪ Next thing that you know you're seein' ♪
Wah ha ha hoo!
Octopus in the neighborhood!
♪ Surfin' on a sound wave, ♪
♪ Swingin' through the stars! ♪
♪ Take a left at your intestine! ♪
♪ Take your second right past Mars! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Navigate a nostril! ♪ Achoo!
♪ Climb on the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Spank a plankton, too! ♪
Take that!
♪ On our Magic School Bus, ♪
♪ Raft a river of lava! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Such a fine thing to do! ♪
Woah!
♪ So strap your bones right to the seat! ♪
♪Come on in and don't be shy! ♪
Come on.
♪ Just to make your day complete, ♪
♪ You might get baked into a pie! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Step inside, it's a wild ride! ♪
Come on!
♪ Ride on the Magic School Bus! ♪
Pass me that one next, Pheobe!
OK, Ralphie.
It's going to be a model
of the solar system.
Neat, huh, Janet?
Uh, I hate to tell you, cousin Arnold,
but when my class built one,
The sun was so huge, we
had to hang it from the flagpole.
And you had all nine planets?
That's right, Keisha.
Mercury, Venus, Earth, Mars,
Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, Neptune, Pluto.
My class already started the solar system.
I bet you your class didn't learn
about the aliens that live on the planets.
For your information, Ralphie Earth
is the only planet that can support life
As far as we know.
And how far do you know?
Really far, because I got
straight A's on all my tests.
And this proves it.
If you already know so much, Janet,
why did you come to visit our class?
Because Arnold told me all
about your "field trips," A-Dorothy Ann
What did he say?
That they were and I
quote: "highly unusual."
And you know what I said?
Prove it.
She's really nice,
Once you get to know her.
Good morning, class.
Have you all met Arnold's cousin?
Janet?
Yes, Ms. Frizzle.
My teacher doesn't dress like that.
That's nothing. Sometimes the Frizz
looks totally outrageous.
Well, since we're lucky
enough to have a guest today,
I'd say it's a perfect
time for a... Field trip!
Hey cuz', now's your chance to prove it.
I wonder where we're going today.
Inside a rotten log, been there,
To the bottom of the ocean, done that.
We're going to the planetarium?
Hardly unusual, Arnold.
The Frizz taking us on a normal field trip?
Believe me, that's unusual.
Hmm, hmm, hmm.  How odd.
Closed today.
Closed?
Hmm, well, looks like we'll
just have to go back to school.
Oh, no!
Some field trip, Arnold.
You know what?
My teacher would have called ahead.
Because my teacher planned ahead.
My teacher never makes a mistake.
My teacher is a zillion times better than-
Nobody is better than Ms. Frizzle.
Oh, yeah?
Prove it.
Stop the bus!
Yes, Arnold?
Isn't there... You know,
someplace else you could take us?
You mean another planetarium?
Well, sort of, but bigger.
Bigger?
You know the big one.
Oh, oh, Arnold.
Why didn't I think of that?
T-minus five and counting.
Four, three, two, one, blastoff!
What's happening?
A field trip!
Janet: Into outer space, highly unusual.
Welcome to outer space, class.
The only planetarium open 24
hours a day, seven days a week.
And how are all my astronauts doing?
We're weightless!
We're in trouble!
No, Arnold. We're in orbit around the Earth.
Hmm, let's see now. We are just about there.
Wonderful! Let the tour begin!
We're coming up to the sun.
Look how huge it is!
Class, are you all wearing your special,
heavy-duty sunblock 8,000 sun goggles?
I wonder how many Earths will fit in the sun.
Over a million!
Hold onto your goggles. Yeehaw!
Now class, we've traveled
from Earth around the sun.
And now we are on our way to-
Janet: Mercury, the closest planet to the sun.
When I tell my class,
they're going to be so jealous.
Wow! We're landing!
Of course.
Arnold: Told you Janet.
We hardly weigh anything
compared to my old planet Earth.
I wonder if that means there's
less gravity pulling on us here.
Exactly, Keisha.
Good thinking.
Come along, class.
Follow the bouncing lizard.
This way, please.
Bet I can jump higher than you, Dorothy Ann!
You're on!
I won first place in my
class jumping contest.
Here's my blue ribbon to prove it.
Wait till I tell my class I won the
jumping contest on Mercury too.
But you know what they're going to say?
What?
Prove it.
How on Earth?
I mean, how am I going
to prove I was on Mercury?
Man, the aliens on Mercury
sure make big footprints.
Nothing can live on Mercury, Ralphie.
It's too hot and dry during the day.
And according to my research,
way below freezing at night.
And day or night,
there's no air,
Which makes it extremely
difficult  to breathe.
Well, something had
to make tracks this big.
Something did, Ralphie, a meteorite.
Hmm,
Meteorites are pieces of stone or
iron that fall from space.
Come along, class!
If the ones that hit the
planet are called meteorites,
What do you call the ones that miss?
What?
Meteor-wroooooongs!
Wow!
Janet, what are you doing?
Hey, watch it!
Eureka! My very own meteorite!
When I show this to my
class, it'll prove I was on Mercury.
Oh, Janet.
Wahoo!
We are now approaching Venus,
this second planet from the sun.
I can't wait, I can't wait, I can't wait!
Cool, Venus has clouds, just like Earth.
Wow, what a view.
Uh, I think I'll go... sit down now.
Come along, class!
Hey!
I feel like I weigh the
same here as I do on Earth.
That's because Venus
is about the same size of Earth,
And has about the same gravity.
Come on, Arnold.
Check out those weird clouds.
Oh, good, a little rain will
cool the place down!
Except that's not rainwater
in those clouds, Wanda.
It's sulfuric acid.
Sulfuric acid?
Mm-hmm.
It's a deadly poison.
Oh, we're perfectly safe!
As long as we keep our space suits on.
I like rocks, but... this is ridiculous.
Do you have to have all of these?
Absolutely, if this doesn't prove
I was on Venus, nothing will.
We're now passing through the
orbit of the third planet, which is Earth.
Look, it's so beautiful.
And there's air we can breathe,
And it's not too hot, or not too cold.
The only one that supports life.
And coming up is Mars.
The fourth planet, right, Ms. Frizzle?
Very good, Janet!
Ooh, you certainly do know your planets.
I got straight A's on all my reports.
We know, we know, enough already!
Oh, here we are, class!
Take a look at Mars!
How marvelous!
It looks like the whole place is rusting.
No wonder it's called the Red Planet!
As you can see, the soil here is
colored by red dust, which has iron in it.
Look at those cliffs of ice!
Ice climbing anyone?
Wow, right.
No thanks. Too cold.
Too slippery.
Too right. Who wants to waste time
climbing up an old ice cap anyway?
Come on, cuz', we've got lots to do.
Maybe I should have stayed home today.
We've made it to the top!
I wonder if Mars could
have been another Earth.
If it had water, and wasn't so cold.
Maybe. But as I always say,
Mars is the best place for ice cream.
Ice cream? Where?
Here. I screaaaaaam!
Let’s goooo!
I screeeeeam!
Uh!
That's the last ice block.
Great! Now for some red dust.
On Earth, I had simple little chores:
Emptying wastebaskets, feeding the
fish, clearing the table.
Oof!
The only thing is, we've been to
Mercury, Venus, and Mars so far.
And we haven't seen
a single...
Alien!
Tell it we surrender!
Hi, guys. Which way's the bus?
Arnold!
I knew it was him the whole time.
Mars ice and dust, enough
to prove we were on Mars.
Uh, no need to thank me.
I don't think there's much
chance of that, Janet.
Look! A flying potato!
Huh?
That's no potato.
It's an asteroid, Ralphie.
A hunk of space rock.
Smaller than a moon,
but bigger than a meteorite.
It's part of the asteroid belt,
A ring of asteroids which divides our solar
system into the inner and outer planets.
Janet: An asteroid!
I gotta have it!
Please, it'll only take me a second!
Watch out!
What was that?
What happened?
What's going on?
Don't worry, class.
Just an unexpected orbital interruption.
Let's just see where we are, shall we?
The map!
It's gone!
We're lost in space!
Class: We're lost in space!
Use the free code JOINNOW at
www.playships.eu
As I always say, there's nothing
a good space mechanic can't fix.
Wrench!
Wires!
An asteroid.
I mean... Wires!
Screwdriver!
An asteroid! Perfect proof!
Ms. Frizzle, we've
got half of the map now.
Good. One more adjustment.
Miss Frizzle? Miss Frizzle!
Keep your claw on that button, Liz.
Up, up, and away!
Um, bad news!
Janet, we're not only lost in space,
We're lost in space without a teacher!
What are we gonna do? What are
we gonna do? What are we gonna do?
Ms. Frizzle to class! Ms.
Frizzle to class! Come in!
No reason to panic. I'd never leave you.
I'm right here. I'll give you a hint.
I'm headed for one of the outer planets.
But that's a half of the
map that we don't have.
Oh, good!
You can fill it in as you go along.
You've got a navigator who
knows the neighborhood.
We do?
Of course. Janet.
I wonder if Miss Frizzle's down there.
Ralph, which planet is that?
One of the gas giants!
What is that red blotch?
It's a storm. Thousands of miles wide.
And the only planet with a
big red spot is Jupiter.
Jupiter, the fifth planet.
Wow! Thanks, Janet! Way to go!
Now if I could just get some of that red
spot, it would prove I've been to Jupiter!
Miss Frizzle to bus!
Miss Frizzle to bus! Over!
Jupiter is the largest planet,
but don't worry, Carlos.
Because I'm not on it.
Then where are you?
I've got to have some of that red spot!
We're out of control!
Janet!
Pull up! Pull up!
It's all yours, Ralphie.
Whoa!
Janet!
Chill out, guys. If you've been to
Jupiter, you've got to have proof.
Right?
I knew I should have stayed home today.
Ms. Frizzle to class!
Ms. Frizzle to class! Come in, please!
Miss Frizzle! Janet almost got us-
I got them some of Jupiter's red spot.
Did you say red hot?
You're not even warm yet.
The outer planet I'm
on is very cold and dark.
The colder you get, the
warmer you'll be to finding me.
Oh great, now it's a riddle.
Off we go again!
Hey look! Another planet!
It's beautiful!
Where are we?
It's gotta be Saturn.
If there's no other gas
giant with such beautiful rings.
Saturn! The sixth planet!
Well, it must be cold down there because
Saturn is pretty far away from the sun.
But Miss Frizzle said cold and dark.
It could be very, very dark on Saturn.
Oh no, you don't.
You just want to grab more stuff.
Hey, I'm just trying to help.
If you want to play "Let's Find
Miss Frizzle Without a Map,"
For the rest of your
life, that's fine with me.
Janet's right. Miss Frizzle could be on Saturn.
Couldn't she?
Okay, Arnold, but it's your job to
keep your crazy cousin under control.
Miss Frizzle to bus! Miss Frizzle to bus! Over!
Ah, Liz and I can't wait to show you
all the stars we can see out here.
Oh, it's so beautiful!
Come back! What about a hint?
She just gave us a hint, Ralphie!
She did?
Yeah!
She can see the stars!
Which means she can't be on Saturn.
She could never see the stars
through all those storms and clouds.
Planet number seven, coming up!
That must be Uranus!
You could tell by its tilted faint grey
rings and its blue-green gases.
See, cuz', Uranus doesn't do a
thing for me so you can get off me.
Okay?
Sorry, Janet, but I have
to stay on top of the situation.
The Frizz couldn't see the stars
through those clouds either.
No way she's on Uranus!
To the next planet.
Wait!
I need proof!
And we need Miss Frizzle.
Step on it, Wanda.
Hey, watch it!
Neptune!
Please, we gotta stop at Neptune!
It's my favorite planet!
The eighth planet.
Neptune.
Looks like another planet
surrounded by gases.
And it's blue.
Oh, my favorite color!
Forget it, Janet.
Miss Frizzle couldn't see
the stars from down there.
Go Wanda!
No!
Now where do we go?
She's not on Jupiter, Saturn.
Uranus, or Neptune.
That means there's only one planet left!
Which one?
I'll tell you.
After Arnold gets off of-
Aaaah!
Right, listen carefully.
Miss Frizzle is on the
farthest planet from the Sun.
Pluto.
To Pluto!
Pluto is cold and dark all right!
And clear, they've got to be here.
Look!
There they are!
Yay!
Good work, class.
I knew you find us!
Right, Liz?
Sure can see the stars from here.
I wonder where the Sun is.
See that tiny star over there?
Uh-huh.
Well, that's it.
That's the Sun?!
Mmm-hmm!
No wonder Pluto's so cold and dark!
Look how far away the Sun is!
So, the colder we got, the
warmer we got finding you.
It was a good hint if I do say so myself.
I got enough stuff for all of
us to prove we made it to Pluto.
Huh?
Well, what are you waiting for?
Let's go!
Are you kidding?
There's no room in there.
All right, be that way.
There's no way I'm going
home without my stuff!
There's no way I'm going home without you.
It's proof!
Nobody will believe me without it.
I'll believe you.
They'll believe you.
Janet, you want proof?
I'll give you proof.
Here's proof of what will happen to you
if you stay here with your stuff.
Arnold, no!
Oh, cuz'!
Back to Earth!
And step on it!
Ah, ah, choo!
Thanks, Janet.
Arnold, it's the least I can do.
If it weren't for you, I'd still
be on Pluto with all my stuff.
I don't need to prove anything.
That was the most amazing field trip ever!
You know it, I know it.
If no one else believes
me, that's their problem.
Right on! Way to go, Janet!
You said it.
Ahchoo!
Attention all students!
We've just learned that scientists have made their
first contact with an alien from outer space.
An alien?
Wow.
Ralphie was right!
Oh my.
The alien, claiming to be from Pluto, has
called to complain about a pile of litter
That was recently dumped on his planet.
Ralphie!
As I always say, class,
you're out of this world.
Is this the Magic School Bus?
Magic School Bus?
I want the Magic School Bus!
Hello, Magic School Bus.
Don't you mean The Twilight Zone?
That show had more
science fiction than fact!
Well, we realize a school bus
would make a lousy spacecraft.
I'll give you that one, but only because
you'll call it a magic school bus.
But there's no way any spacecraft
could visit all nine planets in a day.
Well, if we did it in real time, you would
be a grown up by the time we got to Pluto.
Speaking of Pluto, scientists don't
really know what its surface is like.
You're right, but until one of your kids
grows up to be an astronomer or an astronaut
And figures out what Pluto
is like, we have to guess.
Also, Pluto right now isn't
the ninth planet from the Sun.
Until 1999, it's temporarily
inside Neptune's orbit.
Right again.
What about those funny looking sun goggles?
I happen to know you should
never look directly at the Sun.
Hurts your eyes.
You're one bright kid.
So how come some of the time the
kids were floating around in the bus?
Well, when the bus was coasting with the rocket
engines off, they were weightless, like astronauts.
Oh yeah, so how come they were
able to walk around in the bus sometime?
Well, uh, would you believe an artificial
gravity geoscopic infabulator?
No way.
Okay, you got me. We just fudged it.
And I don't think I didn't notice that you had
all the planets lined up in a neat little row.
Oh, that.
Well, it's true that planets are
very rarely all lined up like that.
Yeah, like almost never.
But it's so much easier to keep
track of them all that way!
You wouldn't want us to have
forgotten one, would you?
And another thing,
If an astronaut ever does make to Pluto,
she'd better not take her helmet off.
You think they'd end up
with more than a cold, huh?
She'd end up a block of ice or worse,
Which reminds me why I called in the first place.
Yes?
I'm still waiting for someone to
get that pile of litter off my planet.
♪ Surfing on a sound wave, ♪
♪ Swinging through the stars, ♪
♪ Take a left at your intestine, ♪
♪ Take your second right past Mars! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Navigate a nostril! ♪
Achoo!
♪ Climb on the Magic School Bus ♪
♪ Spank a planton too. ♪
Take that!
♪ On our Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Raft a river of lava! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus ♪
♪ Such a fine thing to do, ♪
Woah!
♪ So strap your bones right to the seat! ♪
♪ Come on in and don't be shy, ♪
♪ Just to make your day complete, ♪
♪ You might get baked into a pie! ♪
♪ On The Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Step inside, it's a wilder ride! ♪
Come on!
♪  Ride on The Magic School Bus! ♪