Bees! We want bees!
Put it over here!
Hold it everybody, hold it!
lt's JUST a science fair.
Just a science fair?
Too bad we can't use last year solar powered
juggling machine.
Nice try, Ralphie, but it doesn't fit with this
year's theme...animals that live together.
And l quote from the entry form...
''Some animals live alone, but some live and
work together in groups, called communities.''
Watch your back! Heads up! Comin' through!
l'm escorting an important visitor to our
classroom.
Make way for...
Hello, class!
Ms. Frizzle! You almost stepped on our
visitor.
Oh, my!
WHAT visitor?
My friend, the ant!
Look at her go! lsn't she amazing? l wonder
where she's headed...
Don't worry, little ant. Wherever you're going,
l'll make sure you get there.
No time for ANTics, Keesha. We've got to
pick a project for the science fair.
Ah, the passion of science.
Now Liz, do you have any idea where l put that
camera?
There it is.
My ant? Where's my ant?
Keesha, YOUR ant is eating MY
Mallow-Blaster!
So that's why she came in here! She was
looking for food!
Don't worry little ant, Arnold's more than happy
to share his Mallow-Blaster.
Keesha, are you going to baby-sit that ant all
day, or...
Hey! Maybe we could do something about my
ant for the science fair!
According to my research, where you find one
ant there's usually more.
That's right, Dorothy Ann. Ants live together in
nests.
But what could we do with ants? A mural? A
model?
Careful with that camera, Liz.
At my old school, lizards weren't allowed to
make movies.
That's it! We'll make a MOVlE!
She's a natural star!
l can see it all now...we'll call it ''Travels with
my Ant.''
A movie about an ant...
You know something? That's not a bad idea...
No, it's a good idea! A GREAT idea!
Yes!! Let's make a movie!
l'll write it! lt'll be all about an ant with a long
nose called elephANT! Get it?
CARLOS!!
Can l help write it too?
You can write it together.
What about us?
You can all be lN it, and play ants!
What are my lines?
Who's the star?
My ant, of course!
lf you're going to direct this movie, Keesha,
you might need this.
Me direct it? But l thought you--
lt was your idea.
Oh wow? Oh boy! l'm the director! The
whole films depends on me!
As l always say, Keesha...ACTlON!
How could she do that?
Ms. Frizzle, you could do the costumes.
Thank you, Carlos.
Okay now, people, this is...
Keesha...?
ln a minute, Phoebe.
This is what l want you to do.
Follow that camera lizard!
Great Liz! A little tighter.
ANTS! But which one's mine?
Look at them all! Where are they going?
Guys. Can we go back in now? l just know
it's going to rain.
Not until l find my ant, Arnold! She's my star
and now l lost her.
According to my research
your star's been telling the other ants in its
nest about Arnold's Mallow- Blaster.
Excellent observation, Dorothy Ann.
Ants don't actually talk to each other, but they
do communicate.
l got it! lt's a Western
starring an ant that rounds up food, see, and
then tells the rest of the ants where it is.
That's good, Ralphie! That's good! We'll call
it ''Food Dude.''
Excellent Carlos. An ant whose job it is to find
food is a forager ant.
Food dude is a wonderful name for Keesha's
ant.
Ms. Frizzle? Are we going on a field trip?
Very observANT, Arnold!
ObservANT! l like it, l like it a lot!
ls that her? ls that my ant?
l don't think so, Keesha.
Director to bus, please. Director to bus.
Oh, bad. Oh bad, bad, bad!
Ms. Frizzle, we've lost her! We've lost our
star!
l can't do a movie without a star!
Right you are, Keesha! She's one in a million!
Seatbelts, everyone! Here we go!
Again!
But we're shrinking!
l feel like we're on the inside of a mini
Mallow-Blaster...
We are!
Hey! We're being foraged!
l thought we were going to play ants - not food.
l knew l should've stayed home today...
Giant potato chip being foraged straight
ahead.
So, uh, Keesha? ls the movie going to star a
forager ant?
And are WE going to co-star as the food?
Ms. Frizzle, l'm really sorry
but l don't think this movie should star a
forager ant.
Got that, Carlos? Not about a forager ant...
Why not? That's what your ant is!
l know, Carlos, but l've been thinking.
l want more drama - more excitement!
l wish you hadn't said that...
Where are we?
An anthill!
Ms. Frizzle! We're on location! This is
perfect!
We'll meet the ants, up close and personal!
Now l'll find my star!
Okay, people! This movie is my
responsibility...
so l will check out the anthill and then tell you
what to do next!
Come on, Liz!
RUN!!!!
Good opening sequence, Keesha! lt really
grabbed me! Did you get it, Liz?
What's with those gigantic ants? Who let
them on the set?
We're on location, Keesha. Remember?
They look like they're guarding the nest or
something. Don't they, Carlos?
Cool! Keesha, the movie could star a guard
ant!
l don't know Ralphie...
Come on Keesha. We can call it ''The
Guardfather''.
Perfect for the wide screen with stereo sound
and...
And smell-o-vision!
Smell-o-vision?
Guard ants use their antennae to smell if
we're friend or foe.
They are smelling us.
Precisely, Tim. Ants don't understand words,
but they do understand smells.
They're checking to see if we smell like them.
Yeah, they want to know if we're wearing the
same deodorANT!
CARLOS!
No, no! lt's a great joke! lt's going in...
Ants don't wear deodorant, Carlos.
But their bodies do make scented chemicals
called pheromones.
Pheromones?
Pheromones!
lt tickles! What is this stuff?
Well, class, we now smell like these ants.
We do?
Uh huh! And now the guard ants will let us into
the nest.
As l always say, when visiting a nest, smell
like the rest!
l smell like an ant - just what l always wanted.
Really, Ralphie? Me too!
Oh boy!
One good smell deserves another!
Excuse me!
That tickles!
Cool!
Come on, Liz. We've got to get in there and
find our star!
Wait for us!
OK Phoebe, what do we have so far?
Well, this movie is NOT about a forager ant or
a guard ant.
So, what lS it about, Keesha? We can't write
this script without a star!
Let me think...
Don't worry, everybody - it's all part of the
creative process -- she's thinking of a story.
Check it out!!!
Where are they going?
Man, it must be rush hour.
Look, Keesha, a cast of thousands.
OKAY! Places everyone.
Where do you want us, Keesha?
What about make-up, Keesha? l don't look
anything like these ants!
And what's the plot, Keesha? Who's the star?
l'm working on it! l'm working on it!
Who knew so many ants would audition?
Um, Keesha? Maybe it would help if we
worked with the ants - got to know them better.
We're not going inside an ant are we?
No, Arnold. But Phoebe's right.
Understanding begins with observation.
Good idea, Phoeb! Method acting! l love it!
Okay, everyone! SEE the ant, FEEL the ant,
BE the ant! ACTlON!
This ant's rubbing its head.
And this one's licking itself.
That's it, Arnold, BE the ant.
But l did this today already...in the shower.
Hey, maybe the ants are cleaning themselves.
Tim, your logic is spotless.
Yuck! These 2 are kissing.
Keesha, l've got it! The movie's a
Rome-ANTS! Get it? RomANCE!
CARLOS!
These ants aren't kissing at all.
Yeah, it looks like that ant is giving the other
ant something.
Oh sure, give it back to me AFTER you've
chewed it.
What is it?
Mallow-blaster. l recognize it in any form.
So these ants are passing FOOD around!
Cool! A food-passing ant would make a great
star! Think of the story!
l have, Carlos, and it doesn't work.
One day, an ant passed food to another ant.
lt just doesn't feel complete somehow...
Come on, Keesha - we need a star!
Hey, the star could be the presidANT. Get it?
PresidANT?
CARLOS! STOP!
l know we need a star, Carlos! l just haven't
seen the right aaaaaa...!
Everyone, Stay with your partner!
Help!
Not so fast!
Keep shooting, Liz!
After those ants, people! lt's a great chase
scene!
Wait a minute - what's in here?
AND...Chase scene. Take 1 !
Hey! Where are you guys going?
What are they carrying?
They're like little worms!
Cut! No worms! This movie is about an ANT!
Why do you keep giving things to ME? Do l
look like an ant?
l don't know, Arnold, but you look like you're
holding a baby.
Maybe it lS a baby...a baby ant!
Well done, Phoebe! They're baby ants, all
right.
When they hatched from eggs, they're called
larvae.
That's it! ''Larvae: The Beginning''.
But who ever heard of a movie about larvae?
l don't know, Keesha. l think it has potential.
l think it's cute.
But all they do is wiggle! There's no drama!
No action!
The ants are moving the larvae around. How's
that for action?
And WHY are they moving them? How's that
for mystery?
Hey, l bet they're trying to keep the larvae
WARM!
Exactly, Tim.
Nurse ants move the young around the nest to
keep them the right temperature.
My aunt's a nurse!
l've got it! l've got it! We could call it
FlorANTS Nightingale!
Cut!!!
Now what, Keesha?
lt's a really good idea and everything
but somehow it isn't enough. Where's the
danger? The intrigue?
Hey, WHAT are those things??
Hey, wait! Wait!! l didn't say ACTlON!
People! People! What are you doing?
Pupae! These things are called Pupae.
Come on, pupae, l mean people! Look at it!
Do you really want to make a movie starring a
PUPAE!
Pupa, actually, only one is called a pupa.
Pupae is plural.
Pupae, Pupa, whatever!
Pretty exciting story if you ask me. lt would
make a great documANTary.
Documentary? No way, Carlos!
Mr. Cud's class did a documentary last year
on cows, remember?
Just to keep you up to date, Keesha,
we're NOT doing a movie about a forager ant,
a guard ant, a nurse ant, a larva or a pupa.
Keesha! There aren't any ants left!
Well then, how about an egg?
Oh no! An egg! That's even worse.
Um, Ms. Frizzle. Where do ant eggs come
from anyway?
Good question, Phoebe! The eggs came from
the queen.
The queen? Ms. Frizzle! You're a genius!
Carlos, the queen is the perfect star!!! Think of
the story - a royal exclusive!
You're right! lt's gold!
Come on, what are we waiting for? Let's go!
Which way?
lt's the creative process again...
thataway!
Excuse me, Ms Director? ls water supposed
to be coming through the walls like that?
After the tunnel caves in, you will see some of
the most amazing ant activity yet!
Did you say, After the tunnel caves in...?
All right, class! Duck and cover!
And...CUT! Okay people, don't panic. l'll have
you out of here in....Whoa!
Look at these ants go!
They're repairing the nest! Like construction
workers.
Right, Tim. That's their job. They're builder
ants.
Keesha! We have GOT to do this movie about
a builder ant!
Look at the action! The drama! The
excitement!
Yeah, but which builder ant, Tim?
Well...just pick one.
The queen is the star. Know why? Because
there is only one.
But...
Trust me on this. l'm the director, remember?
To the queen!
This must be it, Keesha! Are you excited?
You bet, Phoebe! This movie is going to have
everything -
action, drama, excitement - and most of all a
REAL STAR!
Quick! Quick! Go in and bow to the queen!
Ask her who her agent is, the queen is very
importANT.
Maybe so, but where is she?
Why there she is! The biggest one.
lsn't she wonderful!
That's the queen?
That's the queen!
But she's not doing anything!
My kind of job!
Of course she is! She's doing a lot! lsn't she,
Ms. Frizzle?
Absolutely, Keesha! The queen is the only one
who lays the eggs!
The queen laid an egg. The end.
Not much of a movie, Keesha!
Sure it is! We start in close on the queen...
Then we pull back and...
No way, Keesha. This may be the queen, but
she's no star.
So what is it about? Keesha.
Nothing!
l give up!
Oh, great. lt's still raining. lt figures!
No, thank you. l'd rather walk! l deserve to get
wet!
Oh bad. Oh bad, bad, bad...
What made me think l could direct a movie?
Now l've wrecked the science fair for everyone.
Keesha?
Too bad l'm such a rotten director.
But you're not!
l am! l almost wiped out my whole class
and there's still no movie - no story - no star!
But what about the queen?
What kind of star just sits there and lays
eggs?
But if it weren't for her eggs, there wouldn't be
any ants.
So! lf it weren't for the ants that brought her
food, there wouldn't be a queen.
l see what you mean.
And if it weren't for the forager ants, there
wouldn't be food for anybody.
And if it weren't for the builder ants, there
wouldn't be a nest.
And if it weren't for the guard ants, the nest
would be attacked.
Yeah, there isn't only one star. More like they
all are.
Phoebe! That's it!
lt's really about ALL the ants!
All the ants...and how they work together!
Keesha! You're right!
Of course l'm right, because l'm the director,
come on!
Hey, where's everyone going? We've got a
movie to make about ants!
Without a star? Forget it.
l said ants, not ant!
There isn't one star in an anthill! All the ants
are stars!
Yeah! Every ant has a job to do to keep the
nest going!
...just like WE each have a job to do to make
this movie.
Forget the movie...MUD SLlDE
Everyone on the bus!
Hey! What about the ants!?!
As l always say...ACTlON!
Thanks, Ms. Frizzle!
CUT! We've got to save the ants!
How?
The magnifying glass! We'll block the
entrance!
Wanda, Ralphie, Carlos, Phoebe!
Grab that end!
DA, Arnold, Tim, Ms. Frizzle! And ...LlFT!
Keesha, it's great! A survival movie!
Yeah, and we'll call it, ''A River Almost Ran
Through lt''!!!
Finally, the nest was saved, the rain stopped,
and the sun came out!
The end!
That was amazing! How did you do it?
l didn't do a thing! lt was Keesha's idea.
Yes, but l couldn't have done it without
Phoebe!
And l couldn't have done it without...Without
Arnold!
And l couldn't have done it without Dorothy
Ann!
And l couldn't have done it without Carlos!
And l couldn't have done it without Wanda.
Her part was truly significANT! Get it?
CARLOS!!
And l couldn't have done it without Tim!
And l couldn't have done it without Ralphie!
And l couldn't have done it without Ms. Frizzle!
And l couldn't have done it without... the
school bus.
But none of us could have done it without the
inspiration of... ..the ANTS!
As l always say, it's easy if you've got talANT!!!
Ms. Frizzle!
ls it the magic school bus?
stay tune with us and be a smart kid
Okay Liz, l promise
l'll let everyone know how much work you did
on that movie.
Just let me take this call, okay?
Hi, you work on the Magic School Bus show,
right?
You bet. l am the producer.
One of them.
l know for a fact there are thousands of ants in
an ant colony
but in your show l only counted 137.
l guess you must be an accountANT. Get it...?
Oh boy, now l know who's responsible for all
the terrible puns.
Well actually, you're right, there are thousands
of ants in one colony
but we couldn't afford to hire that many extras.
And they're also thousands of different
SPEClES of ants.
You only showed one kind of ant.
Right again. There are about 10,000 different
kinds of ants,
more than all other social insects put together.
And you didn't say a thing about the fact that
all the ants we saw were female.
Yes, we feel quite repentANT about that.
Almost every ant in a colony is female.
The only thing the few males that are around
do is mate with the queen. Anything else?
Yes. Ants use pheromones for more than
telling friend from foe.
lt's how they communicate where food is, or if
the nest needs repairing -
they smell pheromones like we hear words!
You know, kid, l have to say, you're pretty darn
smart.
Actually, l'm brillyANT! Gotcha!
One more call, and that's it. Promise.
Hello, magic school bus?
This is the Oscar Awards committee returning
your call.
Yes, l just had a question about the rules.
ln the category of best camerawork, is it
possible to nominate a lizard?
THE END