Are you ready, Carlos?
Almost!
Carlos? Was it...supposed to sound like that?
NO WAY!! l don't get it! lt looks incredible!
Stupendous! But it sounds...
''Ploopy''?
Exactly! What did l do wrong?
Wow! She's amazing!
That's one way to look at it. . .
Good morning, class!
Good morning, Ms Frizzle.
Dorothy Ann, l take it that was your new piece
Concerto for lnvented lnstrument?
Well, it was the concerto part, all right, but...
but the lnvented lnstrument was ploopy!
And there's almost no time to fix it before the
concert at the Sound Museum tomorrow.
Yeah, and we've got our rehearsal there this
afternoon.
So, what's the problem, Carlos?
Well, l have a great idea for a sound --
Ooh, and l see you're building an impressive
instrument to make it! Marvelous!
That's the problem. l can hear the sound in
my head, but...
Ploopy
What am l going to do?
Well, if you keep asking questions, Carlos,
you'll keep getting answers.
But there's no time for questions, Ms. Frizzle.
We're going to be late for the rehearsal at the
sound museum.
And, as we all know, those who are great are
never late!
Come along, class! To the bus!
We're going? Now? But... but... Ms. Frizzle.
But what if the sound of Carlos's instrument
stays...just like that?
Oh, our concerto will be ruined.
All the other schools will laugh at us and it'll
be the end of the world as we know it.
Other than that...nothing.
What else can l put on this thing to get it to
make a terrific sound?
Let's see...Okay, there!
lf only l had more TlME!
More time...Okay, bus, do your stuff!
An award winning performance bus!
Oh no!!
And now for the grand finale!
What happened?!
Not to worry, class. l'll just be a moment.
Oh dear...
Just as l thought. Overheated. l believe we'll
be here for a while.
We're going to miss the dress rehearsal?
Now rest up. You'll be fine.
All right! Time to work on my sound.
Ms. Frizzle, isn't there something we can do?
Well, now that you mention it...
lt's really quiet, isn't it? There's hardly a
sound.
Just us. Desperate. Alone... Vulnerable...
What was that?!
lt was me. How was that, Dorothy Ann?
l want my instrument to have the power of a
thunderstorm, so l put an umbrella on it.
That sounded more like drizzle, Carlos!
How about this? l want it to have the roar of a
lion, so l gave it a mane.
lt's a kitten, Carlos!
Forget it, Carlos!
lt looks better and better, but it sounds worse
and worse!
What was that?!
All right!
That's a great sound!
But it wasn't me. lt came from...there.
lsn't it mellifluous?!
That's not exactly the word l'd use for it...
Come on, Arnold! lt's just a house! You're not
scared of a house, are you?
Me, too...
What's wrong with you, class? Where's your
spirit of adventure?
Take chances! Make mistakes!
Get scared out of our wits...
Oh, don't be so chicken, Ralphie!
There must be a phone in there and we can
call a tow truck! Come on!
What a weird place!
Kind of EARy, isn't it? Get it? EAR-y?
CARLOS!
All l've got to say is,
if l meet anybody l can see through, l'm out of
here.
No need to be hasty, Arnold!
That is some doorbell!
Oh well, nobody home. Let's go...
Good idea! l'm with Arnold!
But l need to know what made that sound...
Come on.
How nice! Shall we...?
Must we?
Open! Open! Open!
lt's stuck! What do we do now?
We say...Halloo-oo-oo-ooo...!
That sounds friendly enough!
What a place!
We've got to phone for help. Oh, good. Here's
a phone book.
What was that?
That was a tantalizing tintinabulation!
No!! Don't!
Ah! Foghorn. One of my favorites! Such a
big, deep sound!
Maybe one of these books was making the
sound l heard.
That's it! l don't need to know how this turns
out. l'm outta here!
What kind of place is this?
l wonder who lives here...
Lived here, Keesha.
Professor Cornelia C. Contralto eccentric and
collector of sounds.
Born 1807, disappeared 1892!
How do you know that, Ms Frizzle?
Because after she vanished, they turned her
house, this house, into... the Sound Museum!
This is the Sound Museum?
l knew it! We've missed the rehearsal!
Wh...Where is everyone?
Gone for the night, Tim, which means we have
the whole place to ourselves!
Oh boy!
Oh boy...
Professor Contralto devoted her entire life to
sound.
What happened to her?
No one knows...
l bet you anything she's a ghost,
wandering around this house, seeking the
perfect sound...
Ghost?
''...seeking the perfect sound...'' Just like me!
Well, Carlos, you'll have plenty of time to find
it! We're spending the night.
The night? Here?
But our permission slips didn't say anything
about haunted houses!!
Besides, there's no place for us to... sleep!
Why, look. Eight student-sized beds...
...and a teacher-sized annex...
lt's almost as if someone were...expecting
us...
Be sure to get lots of rest, class. We have a
concert tomorrow.
Now maybe it'll sound like a ghost...
Carlos, that's the ploopiest yet.
lt's too late. You'll never find a sound now...
Cornelia, if you're out there, will you help me
make this thing sound right?
Uh, Carlos? Ms Frizzle said if you kept asking
questions, you'd keep getting answers.
W-w-was that an answer...?
No, but THAT was...
Don't be silly. lt's just... Yikes!!
A CRAZED GHOST!!
BOUND FOREVER lN THE CHAlNS OF
ETERNAL TORMENT!!!
COMlNG TO GET US!!
Listen..it's...it's...
Yeah, yeah. Terrifying. We know.
No!! lt's...the call of Cornelia...
Carlos, where are you going??
l've got to find out what's making that sound!
Um shouldn't somebody tell Ms. Frizzle?
Yikes!!
Listen!! lt's getting louder!!
And, according to my research, if it's getting
louder, we're getting closer.
ls that good or bad?
Bad
WHAT lS THAT?
lt's coming from in there. l'm going in...
No, Carlos, NO!!
Wow
lncredible!
This is one weird house.
You mean your house...
doesn't have a jungle, an ocean, a city and an
alpine wonderland?
Nah. The landlord wouldn't go along with it.
TlM!
An echo! Maybe it was an echo we heard...
Yeah, but...But who made it?
Sorry class. Did l wake you?
Ms. Frizzle, was that you?
Yes! Nothing like a good yodel before bed!
TOODLE OODLE OODLE OOO!!
Listen! Listen! There it is again! The Call of
Cornelia!
How do we get out of here?
The only way is up!
Come along, class. Two by two, please.
Where are we?
Professor Contralto built every room
in this house to show different things about
sound.
Ah! Simply soundniferous!
Hey! l've always wanted to play a harp!
Look at that string moving back and forth!!
That, class, is a vibration! You can feel it!
Vibration!
Let's get the facts: When the string stopped
vibrating, the sound stopped...!
The vibration of the string -- THAT'S WHAT'S
MAKlNG THE SOUND!
Very good, Carlos! Sound is vibration! Hear it
- feel it!
Are ALL sounds made by something vibrating?
Good question, Carlos!
Come on, Phoebe! Let's try out that drum.
There's your answer, Carlos.
So l've got to make my instrument vibrate to
make my sound. But how?
As l always say, behind every successful
sound is a vibration!
What's happening?
Now what?!
YOW!
Can l look now?
Hey, it's showtime!!
Why the glasses?
You heard sound... you felt sound... now...
Carlos? What is it??
l CAN SEE SOUND!
Watch this!!
Look at me!!
Listen!
Hey, they're different!
Yeah! When you sing...
Look! There are lots of vibrations close
together.
But when you sing...
there are fewer vibrations, further apart.
Excellent! High sounds are made by
something vibrating fast...
And low by something vibrating slow...
You know what? These vibrations move kind
of like ripples on a pond...
The waves start in one place and move out in
all directions.
lf sound is a vibration and it moves through the
air in waves...
And different types of vibrations make different
sounds!
Stop the vibration, you stop the sound.
l've got it! lt doesn't matter how my instrument
looks - as long as it can VlBRATE!
DA, l know what to do! l've got to get my
instrument!
lt's gone!!!
Where could it be?
There's an explanation, class. The question
is, What is it?
First Carlos's instrument disappears... then
each of us.... one by one...
There's that sound again.
lt's coming from in... here!!
Carlos! Are you all right?
l'm fine! l'm just in some sort of dungeon or
something.
Well, if they torture you, don't tell them
anything!
l'll learn to be a lawyer and meet you back
here when we're grown-ups!
This way, Arnold!
let's go!
Coming Arnold? We're waiting.
l think l should've stayed home today...
Thanks, Ms Frizzle.
Don't mention it, Arnold.
Well, Carlos. You got us into this. Any ideas
how to get us out?
Listen
Where's it coming from?
lt's hard to hear exactly. Wait here!
lt's coming from along there!
He...he can't go down there alone!
You're right, Keesha! Why don't you go with
him?
C'mon, you buncha weasly wimps!! Let's
follow Ms Frizzle...
You can see the soundwaves bouncing off the
walls. There...from there...
From there!
Sound waves bouncing... l bet that's how an
echo is made!
Those soundwaves are travelling THROUGH
that door!
Good observation, Dorothy Ann!
Just so long as we don't travel through that
door.
No! We've got to see what it is!
Hello....
lt WAS you!
Wait a minute! ls it just me or are you... are
you a...?
Professor Cornelia C. Contralto... the Second.
That is my great-grandmother.
Now, listen. You've got a concert tomorrow,
right?
Are you ready to make your instrument sound
richly resonant
and resoundingly reverberant?! Huh?
How'd she know about Carlos's instrument?
You asked a question...
Let's see...
Don't you mean let's hear....?
Right! To make a sound, l need to make
something vibrate.
My instrument couldn't vibrate because there
was too much stuff on it!
Neither did that. l don't need this, pull this
thing off.
l think he has got it!
Ready Carlos?
Go!
Bravo!! Virtuoso performance!
Carlos, that was the perfect sound!
Thanks, DA...
And so, young man, if it's all right with you,
l would like to add that wonderful sound to my
grandmother's collection!
Well, l couldn't have done it without you, Dr.
Contralto...!
As l always say -- hit it, Cornelia!!
ls it the magic school bus?
stay tune with us and be a smart kid
Hello? Magic School Bus.
Hi. Are you the one responsible for that show
on 'sound'?
You might say that, yes...
Well, what's the deal with that house?
l mean, you could never see sound. lt goes
way too fast.
Oh, you're right. That's why they had magic
glasses.
l don't get something,
lf sound is a vibration, just what's doing the
vibrating?
The air, a sound is made when something
pushes back and forth from the air...
and makes the air vibrate,
this vibration travels through the air to your ear
as a sound wave.
So a loud sound is just a big vibration?
Right! And a soft sound is a very tiny vibration.
And what about our ears? You hardly
mentioned them.
Ears are very important.
They turn sound waves into something our
brain can handle. That's how you hear.
But not everybody's ears work the same, do
they?
My grandmother wears a hearing aid to help
her hear better.
And some people can't hear anything, ever,
even with a hearing aid.
They use their brains with their other senses
to replace hearing.
And another thing...
there are lots of differences in sounds besides
loudness and pitch.
A violin and a saxophone sound very different,
even when they're playing the same note.
True! There are enough different kinds of
sounds to fill the world,
but we only had a half an hour
...and we had to leave room for all those
hilarious jokes.
-Okay. But one last thing -Yes?
About that ghost...
Well, that can't have been true.
l mean, everybody knows there's no such thing
as ghosts...
Certainly not!
THE END