Seat belts, everyone!
Please let this be a normal field trip!
With the Frizz, no way!
Aaaaw!
♪ Cruising on down Main Street, ♪
♪ You're relaxed and feeling good! ♪
Yeah!
♪ Next thing that you know you're seein' ♪
Wah ha ha hoo!
Octopus in the neighborhood!
♪ Surfin' on a sound wave, ♪
♪ Swingin' through the stars! ♪
♪ Take a left at your intestine! ♪
♪ Take your second right past Mars! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Navigate a nostril! ♪ Achoo!
♪ Climb on the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Spank a plankton, too! ♪
Take that!
♪ On our Magic School Bus, ♪
♪ Raft a river of lava! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Such a fine thing to do! ♪
Woah!
♪ So strap your bones right to the seat! ♪
♪Come on in and don't be shy! ♪
Come on.
♪ Just to make your day complete, ♪
♪ You might get baked into a pie! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Step inside, it's a wild ride! ♪
Come on!
♪ Ride on the Magic School Bus! ♪
I told 'em I'd have an
idea for Broadcast Day.
So I'll have an idea for Broadcast Day.
Why don't I have an idea for Broadcast Day?
Mom: Ralphie!
Get up, Ralphie!
You're going to be late for school!
Oh, no!
Ralphie, what are you doing?
Our class is broadcasting two
hours of live television today,
And I said I'd have a show for them to do.
And I don't.
Yet.
But I will.
No, you won't.
What?
It's my opinion as your mother,
and as a doctor that you have a fever,
Which means you are sick, which
means you are going back to bed.
But Mom!
No buts about it, Ralphie.
I'm sure your class can do
Broadcast Day without you.
We can't do it without him!
And we go on in an hour!
Where is he?
I'll get it!
I was wondering what you got to.
Hello?
Yes, Dr. Tennelli.
Dr. Tennelli!
That's Ralphie's mom!
Uh-huh, yes, I see, huh?
Uh-huh.
Yes?
He's sick? Oh, poor Ralphie.
Why aren't I surprised?
Of course he must stay in bed.
What?
In bed?
What about Broadcast Day?
Yes, Dr. Tennelli.
Thank you for calling.
Bye-bye.
Is Ralphie staying home from
school today, Ms. Frizzle?
Yes, I'm afraid so, Arnold.
What are we gonna do? What are we
gonna do? What are we gonna do?
Why we're taking school to him, of course!
To the bus!
Are we doing broadcast day
from Ralphie's room, Ms. Frizzle?
What better place to take chances?
Make mistakes!
And it sure is messy!
Ms. Frizzle, are you sure
this visit isn't a field trip?
What do you think, Arnold?
Arnold: I think Ralphie shouldn't
have stayed home today.
How can anything that smells like
grape shoe polish help my body get well?
It will if you take one
teaspoon three times a day.
And don't forget to
shake well before using.
Like this?
Ah-ha! Even your jokes are sick.
Open.
No!
Oh boy!
I feel great!
Mom, you are a miracle doctor.
Can I go to school now?
Forget it, Ralphie.
I've gotta go see another patient.
But Grampa's downstairs if you need anything.
I'll check in later!
If I get an idea, I’ll still
have time to phone it in.
That's it! A phone in!
Huh?
Hi, we're here!
Hello!
Ralphie, we're here!
I must be hallucinating.
Maybe I'm sicker than I thought.
Hi, Ralphie!
How you doing?
Uh-oh!
Gee, you look terrible.
Don't worry, I'll have you
camera-ready in no time.
Is it just me?
Or is my entire class standing in my room?
Aren't you glad to see us?
We came to do Broadcast Day.
Really? What a great idea!
Now and then I do have them, Ralphie.
Speaking of great ideas, what’s yours, Ralphie?
Mine? Oh, you mean for Broadcast Day?
Oh, you’d better take it easy, Ralphie.
Your body is telling you to slow down
But, Ms. Frizzle, I can’t!
We have a show to do!
What does my body know anyway?
Oh, it knows a lot about the detection
and rejection of infection, Ralphie.
Whoa!
Inside you, at this moment, there
is action, excitement and adventure!
Exactly what we need for our show.
So, what's your idea, Ralphie?
Oh, well, um...
Oh, what's going on with my body anyway?
Oh, that's an excellent question, Ralphie!
Class, everyone back to the bus!
Huh?
But Ms. Frizzle, we just got here.
Mm-hmm.
Single file pl-
Wait!
Where are you going?
You can't go on a field trip now!
And I can't do broadcast day all by myself.
I'm sick.
Huh?
Wait a minute!
What's going on?
It was your idea, Ralfi.
We're here to get the inside story!
Inside story?
Inside what?
What about Broadcast Day?
Think, Ralphie!
Where is all the action right now?
The action?
Liz! What are you doing?
Hang on a second.
The action is all inside me.
What a great idea!
Broadcast Day could be about
what's going on inside me!
Exxon and Ralfi?
Rrrrrrolllll tape!
This is FNN.
Good afternoon. I'm Ralphie.
And this is the Frizzle News Network.
Welcome to our live, on-the-scene coverage of
a natural disaster of major proportions.
My poor sick body.
Over to you, Keisha.
Thanks, Ralphie.
One disturbing question
remains unanswered at this hour.
What's making Ralphie sick?
The FNN news team hopes to find out.
And to do that, they will go
straight to the troubled zone.
My sore throat.
Seat belts, everyone.
Ralphie say, "Ah!"
Cool.
I've never seen that
from the outside before.
The FNN news team is
nearing the disaster area.
In a moment, we will have live footage.
Ralphie: See anything yet?
Woah!
Ah, get a shot of those vocal cords, class.
Look how red and swollen his throat is.
No wonder it hurts.
The question is, why is it red and swollen?
And why does it-
Class: Yow!
Hey, where'd they go?
Where's the bus?
Huh?
Ralphie, did you have to cough?
Sorry.
I couldn't help it.
At this rate, we'll never get the
inside story of what's making Ralphie sick.
We've got to find another way in.
Mm-hmm.
It's not as easy for us or germs to
get inside the body as you might think.
Yeah, skin pretty much covers it.
How are you gonna get the
inside story if you can't get inside?
Wait a second.
I've got it!
Look at this!
Is it just me?
Or does this say this way in?
It's a shortcut.
Get it?
Shortcut?
Carlos! Yuck!
Excellent observation, Carlos.
Seat belts, everyone!
Wow!
You saw him first on FNN News.
Hey, you guys!
The whole world wants to know.
Now that you found a way in,
how are you gonna get to my throat?
Ralphie's right!
We're all the way down at the knee.
Hmm, let's see if I can
put you in the picture.
As I always say, for every
trip, there's a road map.
That's Ralphie's bloodstream!
Could we travel through his
bloodstream to get to his throat?
Absolutely, Dorothy Ann!
♪  We'll take the trans-Ralphie highway system. ♪
And here we go!
Wa-hoo!
This is Ralphie for FN News.
My entire class has just
dived deep into my cut!
And it doesn't even hurt!
What are those?
Those are tiny, tiny blood vessels.
They're all part of the bloodstream.
Eeny, meeny, miney, moeeee!
♪ Red River Flowing ♪
Head north, Miss Frizzle!
Yee haw!
Woah!
Is that my blood?
But I thought blood was red!
That stuff is clear.
That's right, Ralphie.
The liquid part of the blood is clear.
So what are those red things?
Are they what make blood look red?
Scintillating surmise, Ralfi.
According to my research,
they're called red blood cells.
And the white ones are white blood cells.
But what are those jaggedy things?
Those are platelets.
They help the body heal scrapes and cuts.
But we still don't know
what's making me feel sick.
And boy do I feel sick.
Mom: Ralphie!
I'm home!
Quick, hide, Liz!
Sweetheart.
Feelin' any better?
Yeah!
Fine, great!
It, um, looks as if you've been busy.
Just, uh, er, game I was playing!
So, Mom, I think I'll get some sleep now.
Hey,
What's that you're watching?
What? This? It's um, nothing.
Just some movie.
You wouldn't like it.
Oh, I don't know about that.
It's remarkably realistic.
Look, red blood cells.
And those look exactly
like white blood cells.
Nah, are you kidding?
Those are just cheap special effects.
Look, you can even see the wires.
We're here!
We are?
We're in Ralphie's throat?
There are a lot more
white blood cells here.
Where are they going?
Looks like they're after something.
Follow the white blood cells.
Sorry, Ralphie. What did you say?
Me? Did I say something?
Look, that truck thing is
following the white blood cells
Through the blood vessel wall to
the place where the infection is.
Yes! They're getting the inside story!
Whoo!
Ah, now that we're inside
Ralphie's throat tissue,
Time for some on-the-spot reporting!
Up close and personal.
Keisha, Carlos, camera one.
The trick here is not to make eye contact.
Phoebe and, uh, Arnold, you take camera two.
I'm the one who should
have stayed home today.
Way to go, guys. Take chances.
Get messy. Get out there.
Get the story.
Just don't mention my name, okay?
Ralphie, are you talking to yourself?
Not exactly, mom.
And now, over to Keisha and
Carlos live from the throat.
Ralphie, that little girl looks
just like your friend Wanda.
Who, her? No, no, no. Wanda's much shorter.
Carlos here, we're out here in the throat
tissue trying to find out what's going on and-
Hey!
What's that?
Look at that, folks!
Whoa!
Have we got us some action here!
Those yellow-green balls
are destroying that wall.
What are those green things?
Those are bacterial cells.
They're actually not unlike the
bacteria that are making you sick.
That's bacteria, and it's making me sick?
This just in, folks. That's
bacteria, and it's making Ralphie sick.
And according to my
research, bacteria are germs.
Once inside our bodies, they can make us sick.
Ralphie has a bacterial infection!
This is it!
The inside story!
Bacteria invade throat!
Is it just me? Or did they say Ralphie?
No, no. It says here this
shows about a guy named Alfie.
Ix-nay on my ame-nay.
The bacteria from Ralphie's
throat infection are everywhere!
And they're destroying his throat cells!
Look! Look! Here comes some white blood cells!
Whoa!
Wow!
It's throwing stuff at the bacteria!
That...that was incredible!
That white blood cell
just ate those bacteria!
That huge battle is going on inside me?
I mean inside Alfie.
This battle is raging! Who's going to win?
No wonder I'm sick.
Arnold here, on
location with the infection.
I'm going to try to get an exclusive
interview with these two bacteria.
I mean, four bacteria.
I mean, eight bacteria?
Hey guys! They're multiplying!
Help!
Bad news, guys.
The bacteria from the
infection are multiplying faster
Than the white blood cells can gobble them up!
We're losing!
Let's get out of here!
How could my body lose?
Ralphie, are you alright?
I don't think you should be watching this.
No!
I mean, please don't turn it off, Mom.
I want to see how it ends.
I'll tape it for us downstairs.
But you don't understand!
What I understand is that your
body needs to save its strength
So it can use its energy
to battle those bacteria.
You have to rest, sweetheart.
It's not just me, Ralphie.
Any good doctor knows the
best cure is complete rest.
Over to me, Dorothy Ann.
Right now, the white
blood cells are losing!
Certainly looks that way, Dorothy Ann.
They need help. They need backup support.
Ralphie, did you hear me?!
Where's our backup support?
Backup support.
Where do I get that?
Not to worry, Ralphie.
It's already on its way.
Cue the medicine!
Is that the medicine Mom gave me earlier?
It sure is, Ralphie.
Look what it's doing!
It's destroying more bacteria.
The medicine is giving the
white blood cells another chance.
And they're throwing out
even more of those stick things.
Oh, those stick things are antibodies.
The white blood cells use
them to mark the bacteria.
The...
I hope this doesn't mean
what I think it means.
Oh no!
Ralphie's antibodies have
marked the bus as bacteria!
We're not bacteria,
We're Ralphie's friends!
But his white blood cells
are doing such a good job,
They now recognize us as enemies too.
Enemies?
But we know what white
blood cells do to enemies.
That's right, Arnold.
They'll try to destroy us.
Destroy us?!
Ah, the wonder of the human body.
Ralphie! Do something!
Ralphie! You've gotta help us!
Ralphie! Help!
Ralphie!
Oh, don't worry, class.
In order to destroy us, Ralphie's
white blood cells will have to catch us first.
But we've got to get
out of Ralphie's throat.
Good thinking, Keisha.
When the spot is tight, hang a right!
Broadcast Day! The story!
Where is everybody?
Ms. Frizzle here with an
update on the Ralphie story.
To escape the white blood cells,
we left Ralphie’s throat
And are now heading up
his nasopharyngeal passages.
The what?
According to my
research, that means...
His nose?
We're up Ralphie's nose?
Ew!
That's the inside of my nose?
Weird.
Achoo!
Bless you.
Of course, there's no telling how
long we'll have to stay here.
Or how long we can stay here.
Liz, I'm trying to think here.
I get it. I've got to sneeze them out!
But I don't feel like sneezing.
Ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, achoo!
Wheeeeee!
Second floor, boy socks, woo!
Going up!
All right,
Way to go, Ralphie!
Yeah!
This is Keisha still reporting
to you live for FNN.
We are now back in Ralphie's room.
So, Ralphie, what do you have to
say about today's amazing adventure?
Well, I'm sorry that my
body made such a mess of it.
Wait a minute.
Do you really think
your body's been working against you?
Sure.
And against you, too.
You almost didn't get in. Remember?
Only because your body's built to
keep out things like a bunch of germs.
Or a bus full of kids.
And my throat is so sore I can barely talk.
Only because your body is sending
extra blood there to help fight the infection.
Okay, but what about when you almost
got gobbled up by my white blood cells?
Only because your body
thought we were bacteria.
Your body was only trying to protect you.
I guess you're right. My body
was just trying to get rid of germs.
Like you!
Come along, class.
Good old body.
Hmm, so that's the inside
story, isn't it, Miss Frizzle?
That's the inside story, Ralphie.
Pretty amazing, don't you think?
Well, we may have won the battle,
class, but he's still fighting the war.
Hey, guys, how's this for a concept?
Inside Ralphie, the series!
Week one, he gets a charlie horse,
Week two, tennis elbow,
Week three, the final episode, athelete's foot!
Is this the Magic School Bus?
Magic School Bus?
I want the Magic School Bus!
Sorry, Liz, but I can't hear a thing.
Liz, your heart sounds like a telephone.
Hello.
Hello. Is this the Magic School Bus?
Yes, and you're talking to the producer.
Can I help you?
Yeah, what were those kids doing visiting Ralphie
when he was so sick and tired?
Oh, well don't worry, he wasn't infectious.
But thanks for calling. Bye.
Hello, Magic School Bus.
You know, Ralphie shouldn't
go around picking scabs.
If the Magic School Bus
got in, so could germs.
A good point.
Bandages, like skin, are there
to keep germs out of your body.
Bacteria aren't the only
things it can make you sick.
There are viruses, parasites, fungi, and...
Right, and some sickness
isn't caused by infection,
But by the body's own systems not working right.
Thanks for calling. Bye.
Whoo!
Hello, Magic School Bus.
Well, I think that somebody should
say that medicine can be dangerous.
And kids should never take
medicines without an adult in charge.
You just did, thank you.
Um, did Ralphie ever get better?
He sure did. His body did a great
job of getting rid of all those germs,
and he got just as
healthy as he was before.
And they should also say that your
body's always trying to be healthy.
You're absolutely right, and
there's a lot you can do to help it out.
I know.
Like eating properly, getting
enough sleep, and exercising.
Getting all your shots is
another way to keep healthy.
Shots help your body be prepared
for some of the really tough germs.
I don't like getting shots.
They sometimes hurt.
Me neither.
But I also don't like getting sick, and I'd
rather get a shot now than get sick later.
Me too, I guess.
Hey, does Miss Frizzle ever get sick?
No way!
She takes good care of herself, gets
all of her shots, and she's magic.
♪ Surfing on a sound wave, ♪
♪ Swinging through the stars, ♪
♪ Take a left at your intestine, ♪
♪ Take your second right past Mars! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Navigate a nostril! ♪
Achoo!
♪ Climb on the Magic School Bus ♪
♪ Spank a planton too. ♪
Take that!
♪ On our Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Raft a river of lava! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus ♪
♪ Such a fine thing to do, ♪
Woah!
♪ So strap your bones right to the seat! ♪
♪ Come on in and don't be shy, ♪
♪ Just to make your day complete, ♪
♪ You might get baked into a pie! ♪
♪ On The Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Step inside, it's a wilder ride! ♪
Come on!
♪  Ride on The Magic School Bus! ♪