Okay. This is it. Tie game.
Bottom of the ninth. Bases loaded.
All you gotta do is slam the ball over the left
field fence...
and win the seventh game of the World
Series!
Ral...phie! Ral...phie! Ral...phie!
Ralphie! Ralphie! Wake up! Ralphie, you're
up.
Oh right, Keesha. l knew that.
Hey, Wanda! Where's home plate?
There isn't one, Ralphie. Just pretend.
Pretend?? Me??!!
But l'll have nothing to slide into when l hit a
home run!
You'll have nothing to hit, if you don't let me
pitch.
Oh, all right. l'll pretend...
Hey you guys! Check this out!
l just found out the coolest thing!
Psst, Liz. Come here.
Dorothy Ann! Not now! l'm one swing away
from hitting my way into the record books.
But you've got to see this! lt'll change your
lives!!
Whatever it is, it can't be more important than
our baseball game.
l just finished this book! ''A Child's Garden of
Physics!
l'm really happy for you DA.
We can't wait to hear the book report.
But right now, l've got a game-winning homer
to hit...
So if you could just get off the field.
But Ralphie! You don't understand!
This book's all about what gets things moving,
and what makes them stop!
Forces! Friction! Pushes! Pulls!
Forces?
Friction?
Pushes?
Pulls?
And as l always say, where there's physics,
there's a field trip!
Listen! A force is just a push or a pull.
lf you're going to FORCE us to listen to this...
You're being kinda PUSHY, don't you think?
No, no, l'm talking about REAL force. Picture
this...
There's this big red sled sitting in the snow
not going anywhere. But if somebody comes
along and gives it a push
Who?
lt doesn't matter, Arnold. lf somebody comes
and--
l need to know so l can complete my mental
picture.
Yeah, me too!
Okay, okay. How about--
Napoleon!
Fine. lf Napoleon comes along and gives the
sled a push,
it'll move! That's a force!
And it'll keep moving on the slippery snow until
something stops it...
Like the entire British army?
No, like...some dirt!
Things rubbing together cause a force called
FRlCTlON.
The sled stops because of the friction of the
dirt against the runners.
Friction slows down and stops nearly every
motion on earth!
You stopped our game to tell us THAT?
lsn't that cool!
Let us know when they make the movie, okay
DA!
Very funny, you guys..
Well, l think friction is fascinating!
Well l think it's...hey...
Dorothy Ann! Wait!
You know, that book does sound sort of cool..
lt is! And look at this, Ralphie!!
Page 97!
Hey! lt's a baseball field!
But it would be impossible to play normal
baseball there! There's no friction!
You know, Dorothy Ann, this is one amazing
book.
Flat. Sturdy. White and the right size.
Gee, D.A...d'you think maybe l
could...BORROW it??
Sure! But you have to promise to take care of
it!!
A scout's honor.
You're up, Ralphie.
Thanks, D.A.!
All aboard!
Now? But... but, Ms. Frizzle
we're in the middle of the most important
competition in the history of sports.
Just a delay of game, Ralphie.
Delay of game? What for?
Field trip delay! lt's time to explore the
unknown!
Be adventurous, brave and bold!
Let's go!
Field trip!?
Just so long as we don't get blasted, roasted,
toasted, or eaten...l'm happy!!
Don't worry, Arnold. That's not until next
week.
Today we're going to a baseball game!
All right!
This is so cool!
A baseball game? That's not new or different
or exciting...
What!?!
Let's go someplace REALLY unusual...
like that place l showed you, Ralphie!
You know. Page 97? Show them...!
yeah...well, uh...
Ralphie! How could you?
Well...you know, it was the right size
and with the white cover and all, it made a
great home plate...
Hey, it's not like l RUlNED it!
Please, Ms. Frizzle, can we get my book
before we go?
No occasion for agitation, Dorothy Ann.
We'll not only get your book, we'll keep
Ralphie happy, too...
We will?
Bus, do your stuff!
Time to hit the books!
Let me get the facts. Are we where l think we
are?
Yes! Yes! We are.
At my old school, the librarian never let us
drive in our books.
Ms Frizzle!! Stop here! Please!
Page 97!
lt's the page l was talking about! lt's all about
a World Without Friction!!
lt looks like the world of baseball to me! Come
on.
Ralphie, watch out! The ground on that field's
got NO FRlCTlON!
l can't stop...!
Wow! lt's Ralphie the runaway pinball!
Yep, there's no stopping him now.
Without friction, how ARE we going to stop
him?!
What would happen if something smashed
into him?
Right, a force pushing the other way!!
But what can we use? The only forces we can
control in there are...
...us!!
Take me out of the friction, where things just
slow to a stop...
This way class.
Something tells me l should have stayed home
today.
Oh no, what should l do now!?
l wonder what would happen if l tried to run...
Not a good idea!!
Oh boy, is this ever weird.
l can't...walk...l need something to push
against...
like the friction of my feet against the ground!!
These feet were made for friction!
Forget walking, l just want to stand up.
How about a force to get you going Dorothy
Ann?! Like a...push?
Never fear, Ralphie!! A PUSH to the rescue!!
There. l saved you.
Saved me?? l was having a blast!!
Hey, DA, looks like Ralphie gave you the push
off!
That's the last time l save HlM! Whoo!
Whew...that was close...
Look on the bright side, Arnold. No friction, no
grass stains.
Okay, hit it Liz!
Now what??
Hello, sports fans! Welcome to the All Frizzle
Friction Free Baseball Classic!
And what a beautifully frictionless day it is!
Ms Frizzle, where did you learn to announce
like that?
You'd be surprised what teachers do during
the summer break...
but lets talk about the game, D.A.
Oh yes. Well, folks, believe it or not,
we're coming to you live from inside my
textbook!!
Our playing field today is slipperyer than ice
and slicker than spit.
The ground out there has NO, we repeat, NO
FRlCTlON!
Yessiree baseball fans,
this could very well be this week's Game of the
Century!
On the mound is Wanda, one of the most
outstanding pitcher in the class..
and master of the famed Bubblegum Ball...!
You ready for this, Ralphie?
Try me!
First up is Ralphie, the most fearsome
four-foot hitter in the league!
And there's the pitch!
And look at that, folks!! The force Wanda used
really got that ball going!
and her pushed her way backwards!
lt's a swing and a miss!
Sorry, Ms. Frizzle.
a serious catcher-teacher hip check!!
What is going on here?
Another pitch...this one looks good..
A hot grounder down the third base line!
But, Dorothy Ann, what do you think has
happened to our batter...?
This isn't fu-uh-uh-unny!
He's spinning off to first!
Yes! Yes! Ralphie is going for the double with
a spin-on-it!
Oh dear...!
Just look at that ball go folks!!
That's what happens when there's no friction
from the ground to slow it down!!
And look at Ralphie go!
Oh no! Double play!
Okay, l'll play second.
lt's all yours!
Coming through...!
Then again, maybe l'll back Tim up in center.
Look out!
ls this baseball or BASHBALL?
Holy cow! Where have all the infielders
gone??
Whoa-oh-oh-oh-oh my sto-om-a-a-ach!
Comin' home!!
And what a throw!! lt's going to be close!!
Will Ralphie remember that no friction means
NO SLOWlNG DOWN!?!
Missed me!
ls it just me, or are we going to collllliiiiiiiide!
Do l look like home plate?
lf you're home plate, l must be...SAFE!
l guess baseball isn't exactly field trip
material--
The lack-of-friction was the big pain!!
Pain?? l can't believe you failed to see the
wonder
of a World Without Friction!
l'd trade all the wonder in the world for box
seats--
which we might've had if it weren't been for
your goofy book!!
Ms Frizzle?
Yes, Dorothy Ann?
l think we better call this game ''Too Lack of
Friction''.
Game!! Hiddit' again Liz.
Grab on, class!!
Oh yeah??
Yeah!!
Well sez you!!
Sez you!!
Yeah!!
All right! lt's the All Frizzle Friction Free
TUG-A-WAR!
Then again...maybe not.
Very good, Wanda!
A PUSH is ONE force that can get us moving.
What's the opposite?
A pull?
A PULL!!!
Right.
This is more like it.
Thanks bus.
Wait a sec...where is everybody??
Grab on, you guys.
Pull! Pull! Pull!
Wow, you were right D.A. We had no idea
friction did so much!!
Dorothy Ann, could l borrow that book when
Ralphie's done with it?
C'n l, too?
Then me!!
Wait a sec! No one GETS the book until we
get OUT of it!!
He's got a point.
l guess so.
To the bus!
ls everyone seated?
Yes, Ms Frizzle.
Then let's book it!!
Uh oh, what was that?
At my old school, we only pressed FLOWERS
in our books.
Any suggestions class?
Better gun it, Ms. Frizzle...
Excellent idea, Wanda!
Oh no!! The cover of the book is pushing down
on the bus
too hard for the wheels to push us out!!!
What???
WE'RE STU UH UH UH UH...UH UH UCK!!!
l can't believe this!! We're stuck in Dorothy
Ann's book!!
What'll happen to us if we can't get out?
Guess we'll be food for the BOOKworms.
CARLOS!
This is serious!
l know, a real HEAVY situation.
As l always say, those who are book bound
should take a look around!
Stay on the same page, please!
Step on it, Liz!
There's not enough friction down here to push
the bus out!
There's too much friction up here!
Okay, okay, where do we stand?
Somewhere between page 96 and 97.
CARLOS!
Hey, just trying to lighten things up.
Lighten things up, that's it!
We climb up on the roof and PUSH UP on the
book!
Let me get the facts. You're saying we should
hold up the book
get in the bus and drive away?
Yes!
How?
Good question, Arnold. Anyone have an
answer?
DA, this is ALL YOUR FAULT!!
Ralphie, you're a genius!
Look! The letters peel off the page! l HAVE A
PLAN!!
We split into two teams, right?
Right
Ralphie's team goes on the roof and pushes
up on the book...
...while my team piles letters up under here to
hold the book up
long enough for us to get out!
Like this.
Exactly.
Let's do it!
Let-'er rip!
Carlos, take a letter!
Excellent plan. But why doesn't YOUR team
push up on the book
while MY team piles the letters? Okay? Okay!
Not okay!
Yes okay!
Not!
Um, D.A...what is it again that makes
everything stop??
Friction...
And if there's a lot of it you can't really get
anywhere, right, Ralphie?
Yes...
Well, l think there's a little too MUCH friction
between you two.
So if we're ever going to get out of this book...
We'd better get rid of the friction between us.
Sorry.
No, l'm sorry.
Well, l'm even sorrier.
No l'm sorrier...
And l'm sorrier than both of you.
Ok, let's do it!
C'mon, we gotta make it!
Almost there, we need some more words.
Out of the book, and through the words, back
to class we go...
An open and shut case!
CARLOS!
Hang on, Ralphie. Remember what happened
last time you jumped out of the bus like that...
Never fear, there's friction HERE!
Good old friction!
Hey there, friction fans!
Welcome to the All Frizzle
Complete-With-Friction Baseball Classic!!
Yessirree, it's a bee-yootiful day here at
Frizzle Field
and have we got a game for you!!
The first up is our very own Dorothy Ann.
l tell you, Keesha, if she hits the BALL as hard
as she hits the BOOKS
waaattch out!
Ohh! A tremendous hit, deep into center!
Holy Cow! She exerted some kinda force on
that ball!!
BUT can the left fielder, Carlos
get to that ball and apply HlS force to stop it?
No he can't!! What a shot, folks!!
But lucky for Carlos, the friction of the ball
against the grass has slowed it to a stop!!
What WOULD we do without friction, folks?
C'mon.
And D.A. finds a friend in friction as she slides
home!
The big question! ls she safe or out!?!
l don't know, Keesha, l can't make out the
plate!!!
That's funny... neither can l...
Where is it??
l think it's over there!
DA was right...this book is GREAT!!
As l always say, Ralphie, never judge a book
by its cover.
ls it the magic school bus?
stay tune with us and be a smart kid
Hey, Liz. Another day, another----caller.
Now WHO could that be?
Hello? magic school bus's producer speaking.
Hi, you know that textbook the bus and the
kids went inside?
Wonderful book, isn't it?
Yeah, l'd like to know where l can get a copy.
So you can visit a world without friction?
Right. l already checked the library.
Where did you look?
ln the non-friction section, of course.
Actually, you can find non-friction anywhere.
But here on earth, l thought friction was the
only game in town.
lt is, but you'd be surprised how many ways
we can give friction the slip.
You mean, like sliding down a slide?
Yes, very little friction, but lots of fun.
Or playing shuffleboard.
Oh wait, of course.
lce skating. She shoots! She scores!
Snow skiing?
and more skiing.
Snow swimming.
Skate boarding.
Oh! And don't forget, log rolling.
Very non-frictional.
So friction is all around us, but sometimes
there's just less of it.
Exactly
And sometimes a lack of friction can surprise
you.
Yes, l suppose it could surprise
Yoooooooowhhaaaaaa!!
Thanks! Non-friction is my favorite.
Sometimes working on this show is stranger
than friction.
THE END