Seat belts, everyone!
Please let this be a normal field trip!
With the Frizz, no way!
Aaaaw!
♪ Cruising on down Main Street, ♪
♪ You're relaxed and feeling good! ♪
Yeah!
♪ Next thing that you know you're seein' ♪
Wah ha ha hoo!
Octopus in the neighborhood!
♪ Surfin' on a sound wave, ♪
♪ Swingin' through the stars! ♪
♪ Take a left at your intestine! ♪
♪ Take your second right past Mars! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Navigate a nostril! ♪ Achoo!
♪ Climb on the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Spank a plankton, too! ♪
Take that!
♪ On our Magic School Bus, ♪
♪ Raft a river of lava! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Such a fine thing to do! ♪
Woah!
♪ So strap your bones right to the seat! ♪
♪ Come on in and don't be shy! ♪
Come on.
♪ Just to make your day complete, ♪
♪ You might get baked into a pie! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Step inside, it's a wild ride! ♪
Come on!
♪ Ride on the Magic School Bus! ♪
Hey, Ralphie, wait for me!
Wanda, I can't move.
Push!
Whoa!
Oof!
Yes!
How's it goin', Liz?
Aren't you psyched?
The Frizz is taking us to the beach today.
Don't forget!
We can't go until after our reports.
Then let's keep the reports short, D. A.
Yup, where there's a will, there's a way!
We brought sand and a crab shell for
our two beach things to go together report.
Didn't we, Carlos?
Whoa! A humongous wave at ten o' clock!
See?
Crabs dig in the sand.
So crabs and sand go together.
Wipeoutl!
What did you bring, Ralphie?
Uh…
Hello, everyone.
Hi, you guys.
Phoebe, Phoebe, did
you bring the dune grass?
Ralphie, have I ever let you down?
Did you bring the sun?
Actually, I couldn't fit it in my
knapsack, but I did bring this.
The sun, in all its glory.
At my old school, we weren't
allowed to bring the sun to class.
How about you, Tim?
Check it out.
A stunning portrait of a rock
to go with Wanda's mussel.
You did bring the
mussel, didn't you, Wanda?
Ta-da!
One mussel to go with Tim's rock.
I named him Gussel the Mussel.
Gus for short.
Who's Gus for short?
Hi, Keisha.
Gus is the mussel I brought for the
two beach things that go together report.
See?
Oh, no.
Oh, help. Oh, bad.
Oh, bad, bad.
Oh, bad, bad, bad, bad, bad, bad, bad, bad, bad.
Something wrong?
I totally forgot about the report.
You did?
You didn't bring anything?
Just my swimsuit and a towel.
And a tuna fish sandwich.
Uh-oh.
What's wrong with that?
I love tuna sandwiches.
Listen, don't panic yet.
Who's your partner?
Arnold.
Don't worry.
Arnold likes reports.
He probably did the whole thing himself.
Where is Arnold anyway?
Arnold?
Hi, guys.
Yuck!
What happened to your shoe?
I was running.
And I sort of stepped into
the pond near our house.
And you were running
because you were in a hurry
Because you couldn't wait
to show me what you did
For our two beach things
that go together report, right?
Ugh!
I knew I forgot something!
You mean you didn't bring anything either?
Just my bathing suit and a towel.
And the scum on your shoe!
Scum and a tuna fish sandwich.
D. A., why didn't we think of that?
But do scum and a tuna
fish sandwich go together?
Hey, maybe they do.
Think, think, think, think, think, think.
No.
Oh great.
Not only do I get slimed by pond scum,
But I forget my report!
I knew I should have stayed home today.
Hey!
We can't just give up, Arnold.
We have to work with what we got.
But Keisha!
Oh, good morning, class!
Good morning, Miss Frizzle!
We have an exciting day ahead of us.
Haven't we?
Hang 10, you guys!
Maybe she'll forget the reports.
And the first thing on the agenda is your
two beach things that go together reports.
Then again, maybe she won't.
Hmm, let's start with, um, Ralphie and Phoebe.
Phew.
Why the sun and dune grass go together!
By us!
All rights reserved.
Dune grass, like other plants,
Uses the energy from the sun
to make its own food.
No sun? No dune grass.
No sun? No nothing!
Oh, Keisha and Arnold,
why don't you go next?
Yes, well, uh...
We brought this, um, nutritious
tuna fish sandwich.
And this delightful green scum.
You did?
Why that is absolutely fantastic!
It is?!
So tell us what the connection
is between delightful green scum
And a nutritious tuna fish sandwich.
Um, uh, they both
have... um... adjectives?
Oh dear, hold that thought.
It's time to go to the beach.
Oh, but don't worry. We'll finish
your reports when we get back.
Line up by the door please.
Saved by the bell.
Yeah, I never thought I'd
be glad to go on a field trip.
Oh, for once, a nice
peaceful day at the beach.
Forget it, Arnold.
Everyone else will have a wonderful
time, but we've got work to do.
Now concentrate.
How does your scum go with my sandwich?
You know class, this trip just might
give you the answer you're looking for.
I wonder if she knows we don't know.
She knows everything.
Frizzle: Well, not exactly everything.
It's your job as scientists
to look for connections.
Connections?
You mean how things go together?
Exactly.
We're here, everybody out.
There's dune grass with
the sun beaming down on it.
And here's a rock.
Covered with Gus' family!
Look at them all!
It's a regular... mussel beach.
Carlos!
And here's a crab burrowing into the sand.
Look up there.
That's a gull, isn't it?
I wonder what it's doing.
Wow!
It just ate that crab!
Um, the beach air is making me hungry.
Hmm.
Everyone else's reports seem so obvious.
Arnold, you're eating our report!
Oh, sorry.
I forgot.
Arnold, we've got to figure out the connection
between my sandwich and your scum.
Ready to explore this environment?
In a bit more depth?
Huh?
Now?
But we just got here.
Uh-oh.
I'm getting that old
field trip feeling again.
Come on, Arnold.
I know we can figure it out if we try.
Seat belts, everyone!
H2O , here we go!
Mmm, how refreshing!
♪ Anchors away, my class, ♪
♪ Anchors away! ♪
Think, Arnold, think!
I can't!
I hate it when my socks get wet.
Can I have my shoe back?
No way.
We need it for our report.
Ooh, look!
There's some seaweed!
What are those?
They're beautiful.
Those are sea urchins, Tim.
They eat seaweed.
And sea otters eat them!
Do you really
think they... Otter?
Bad Carlos.
Hmm.
Are you looking, Arnold?
What do you see down there?
Well, I'm trying hard
to look for connections.
Just as you said, but I can't
see past all that... Green stuff.
Yuck, it's going all scummy.
Did you say scummy?
That's it!
Look, Keisha, scum!
Excellent observation, Arnold.
This scum is called phytoplankton.
Phytoplankton?
Phytoplankton!
Yes, little tiny plants.
Wait a second.
Does that mean the scum on Arnold's
shoe is some kind of phytoplankton?
Ah! Care to try my marvelous
mega magnifier, mayhaps?
Sea scum.
Shoe scum.
Not exactly the same, but not far off.
What do you think, Keisha?
Should we take a closer look?
Sure. Why not?
Keisha, you don't
know what you're saying.
I know that tone of voice.
It means something
weird is going to happen.
Wahoo!
Uh, did we just shrink?
We did.
We are now as tiny as phytoplankton.
And that's seriously tiny.
Class, you will notice that
the buses equipping each of us
With a specially designed
underwater breathing mask.
So, get messy!
Make mistakes!
Get out there and explore!
Wanda: I'll go first.
This is so cool!
Arnold: And so wet.
Wow.
And remember, look for connections.
Got it.
I don't get it.
How are we supposed
to find a tuna fish sandwich,
In the middle of the ocean when
we're the size of phytoplankton?
Who knows?
Maybe there's teeny, tiny
phytoplankton-operated sandwich stands.
And to think that when we're big,
all this just looks like green scum.
Amazing, isn't it?
Arnold, what are you doing?
Who, me?
Arnold.
We have to figure out what all this
has got to do with my tuna fish sandwich.
And we have to figure it out now.
Hey, Keisha!
Look at me!
Is it my imagination
or do they look hungry?
It's not just you, Ralphie.
These bigger creatures
are eating the phytoplankton.
So, as I always say, it's
better to be in the bus...
Whoa!
Than to be in something else.
Ah, nature never ceases to amaze me.
Phew, we were nearly lunch at first sight.
Just your average day
at the beach with the Frizz.
Okay, bus.
Do your stuff!
Congratulations!
We are now the size of zooplankton.
Zooplankton?
I wonder if that's what
just tried to eat us.
Very good, Keisha.
Zooplankton eat phytoplankton.
Zooplankton are tiny
animals that live in the water.
This way, class, we've got to take chances.
Get messy!
Get eaten.
And don't forget to look for connections.
But Miss Frizzle, this is a big ocean.
I'll never find a connection between
scum and a tuna fish sandwich.
Of course you will, Keisha.
Stay with your partner.
But,
Mmm.
Hey, Keisha, we thought
phytoplankton looked weird,
Get a load of these guys!
They are not guys, Carlos.
They're zooplankton.
There don't seem to be as many of
them as there were of the phytoplankton.
Good observation, Tim.
What else do you notice?
Anyone?
Those giant things.
Very good, Phoebe.
Those giant things are anchovies.
They're a kind of fish.
Anchovies?
You mean the salty things my dad puts on
his pizza when he doesn't want me to eat it?
You may not like anchovies,
Ralphie, but they might like you.
I wonder if that's because
we're the size of zooplankton.
Keisha's right, class.
As you can see, anchovies eat zooplankton.
Can anyone guess where this is leading?
To lunch?
Precisely.
All right, everyone.
Back in the bus.
Ready, bus?
Wee!
Well done.
We are now the size of an anchovy.
I suggest we stay in the
bus while we have our lunch.
But there's so much to see out there!
Oh, excellent observation, Wanda.
At my old school, we always had to stay
in the bus if we ate lunch in the ocean.
Since we can't eat our report, do
you want some organic potato chips?
No, thanks.
I had some phytoplankton earlier.
You did?
Listen, Arnold. Time is running out.
And we don't have our report yet.
Scum.
Tuna fish sandwich.
What's in a tuna fish sandwich anyway?
Mayonnaise, tuna fish.
Maybe a little vinegar,
some chopped celery.
Did you say tuna fish?
Um, yeah.
Arnold, you may accidentally be a genius.
What does a tuna fish look like?
I don't know.
I never saw one without mayonnaise.
D.A., quick.
There's got to be a picture of a
tuna fish in one of your books.
Here, an albacore tuna.
I got it. I got the connection!
What eats phytoplankton? Zooplankton!
And what eats zooplankton?
Little fish like anchovies!
And what eats little fish like anchovies?
Well?
Tuna fish!
AAAAAAAAAAAAH!
Arnold: I knew I should’ve stayed home today.
Class, we are now inside an albacore tuna.
Cheer up, Arnold.
We’re off the hook.
We know how your scum and
my tuna fish sandwich are connected!
Ugh, you know,
It’s a tuna-eat-scum world out there.
No, no, no, listen!
Tuna don’t eat scum.
Scum gets eaten by zooplankton, which get eaten
by little fish like anchovies, which get eaten by tuna!
Our report’s in the bag!
The bag’s in a tuna’s tummy.
Who knows what you call
something that’s connected?
Linked together.
You mean like a chain?
Oh! Very good, Tim!
Tuna are linked to phytoplankton
by what they eat.
Tuna and phytoplankton belong
to the same food chain!
Food chain?
A chain of food? I could get into that!
Me too!
Phytoplankton, zooplankton, fish, and people too!
We’re all in a food chain.
Scum, this fish, and you!
Humans are usually at the
very top of the food chain.
But for once, we’re actually inside it!
Hmm,
We are also in the perfect position
to study a tuna’s digestive system.
What?
Now?
Miss Frizzle, do you think we
can go back to school now?
Arnold and I need to do our report!
Well, if you insist.
I guess we could leave the tuna’s
digestive system for another day.
Whoo, way to go!
Close one.
Hmm.
Yes, very good!
Okay class, take your seats!
Here we go!
Class: Help!
Yow!
Nope.
Already have a bus.
Look out!
Look out! Whoa!
This is it, Ralphie.
The wave of our dreams!
When we get back to the classroom,
we will discuss our observations!
Surf’s up!
Arnold, do you observe what I observe?
She’s hanging 10!
There really is more to Ms.
Frizzle than meets the eye!
So to wrap up our report, allow us to show
you the artwork we’ve commissioned.
An original tale.
Here we have our recent experience.
The ocean food chain.
It works like this:
Scum, or phytoplankton, are eaten by zooplankton,
Which are eaten by small fish like anchovies,
Which are eaten by big fish, like tuna!
It’s so e-fish-cient!
Carlos!
And this, class, is a land food chain.
Yeah, a mouse eats grass seeds,
A snake eats the mouse,
And the hawk eats the snake!
The hawk is at the top of this food chain.
What’s at the bottom? Hmm?
Grass!
So, what’s at the bottom of the ocean food chain?
I think,
Phytoplankton!
And what do phytoplankton and
grass have in common?
You step on them both.
Arnold!
They’re both plants!
Hey wait a minute.
Do food chains begin with plants?
Yes, they do!
Each and every one of them!
Yay!
Well, if scum and a tuna fish
sandwich are connected,
I guess just about everything
must be connected somehow, huh?
Hey, where’s my shoe?
Nature never ceases to amaze me.
As I always say, if the shoe is clean,
Wear it.
Is this the Magic School Bus?
Magic School Bus?
I want the Magic School Bus!
Hello.
Hi, is this Big Al’s Total Pigout Emporium?
I’d like to order a toasted Big Al special with-
Whoa, wait a second, wrong number,
this is the Magic School Bus show.
No way! I was just watching it!
That’s why I was so hungry!
Maybe you can clear up a few things for me.
I’ll try.
People are on top of the food chain, right?
Except I don’t eat just tuna,
I eat lots of things!
So am I on top of lots of food chains?
You are.
What do you call a lot of chains put together?
A pile?
Am I at the top of the food pile?
Actually a lot of different chains mixed
together are called a food web.
I get it!
So if things are connected in a chain,
What if something happens to
one part of the chain?
Well, it will make something happen
to everything else in the chain.
It’s all connected.
OK, but you know, it’s not true that
all the food chains start with plants.
I read about some plants and animals living deep
in the ocean that get their energy from chemicals.
Yes, but,
They’re weird.
Weird?! You say they’re weird,
Since when does a tuna eat a school bus?
They could if the bus was small enough
and looked like a delicious anchovy
Yes, but you and I both know
school buses don’t shrink.
And they don’t go in the ocean.
Magic school buses do.
Being magic can make all the difference.
And Miss Frizzle must be magic.
Why do you say that?
'Cause somehow she can hang 10 between
math lessons and report marking!
I guess you’re right.
Uh, thanks for calling, bye.
Why, thank you Liz, this looks de-
Rats.
♪ Surfing on a sound wave, ♪
♪ Swinging through the stars, ♪
♪ Take a left at your intestine, ♪
♪ Take your second right past Mars! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Navigate a nostril! ♪
Achoo!
♪ Climb on the Magic School Bus ♪
♪ Spank a planton too. ♪
Take that!
♪ On our Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Raft a river of lava! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus ♪
♪ Such a fine thing to do, ♪
Woah!
♪ So strap your bones right to the seat! ♪
♪ Come on in and don't be shy, ♪
♪ Just to make your day complete, ♪
♪ You might get baked into a pie! ♪
♪ On The Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Step inside, it's a wilder ride! ♪
Come on!
♪  Ride on The Magic School Bus! ♪