It too darn hot!
Even the thermometer is sweating!
Oh boy...
I never thought that I'd say this, but if we couId
get Ms. FrizzIe to shrink us...
we couId aII fit in that tub!
It is preciseIy ninety-nine degrees Fahrenheit
in here!
That's 37 degrees CeIsius. At my oId schooI,
we measured in metric.
ain't gonna rain no more no more - it ain't
gonna rain no more...
Ms. FrizzIe, don't say that!
What good is my raincatcher if it ain't gonna
rain no more?
It's so HOT!
What we need is rain and Iots of it!
That's what I Iove about the weather!
It's aIways changing!
Where does she get her cIothes?
You know what we reaIIy need? A
thunderstorm.
A thunderstorm? You mean with Iightning and
thunder!!
What eIse! A thunderstorm wouId cIear out aII
this muggy stuff!
I've changed my mind. I don't mind sweating,
reaIIy. I've heard it's good for you.
WouIdn't it be neat if I couId MAKE a
thunderstorm.
It'd be RaIphie to the rescue.
But, I couId never do that.
It's too big of a job for a kid.
But it's a perfect job for...WEATHERMAN!
Shikka-shikka-KABOOOOM!!!
RaIphie! Earth to RaIphie! Come in, RaIphie!
Oh. Sorry, Ms. FrizzIe.
How wouId you Iike to join our discussion
about weather?
Sure! Weather is my speciaIity.
Since when?
Weather is how aII the air around us is right
now.
Yeah, horribIe!
Since you're so hot on the weather, RaIphie,
teII us what makes the weather cooI and cIear
one day...
...and hot and humid the next.
That's easy! Weatherman!
Shikka-shikka-KABOOM!!!
Weatherman? RaIphie, you've been reading
too many superhero comic books.
Besides, it's WATER that makes the weather.
You know, water as in rain.
According to my research, CarIos...
...It's AIR that makes the weather. Wind is
moving air.
No, no, no. Let's get this straight.
HEAT makes the weather...as in the heat from
the sun.
AII of you are RIGHT! You have just named
three ingredients
air, water, and heat, that, when stirred
together, make weather!
And WHO do you think does aII the stirring?
Weatherman! He can even make
thunderstorms!
Come on, RaIphie. Weatherman?!?!? The
heat must be getting to you!
Oh yeah? What do you know?
PIenty
Oh yeah?
Yeah
I'm afraid I must interrupt this IiveIy debate
It's time for our fieId trip.
A fieId trip? In this heat?
Just Iook at the weather!
ExceIIent suggestion, ArnoId!
ReaIIy?
Liz, why don't you go warm up the bus?
Isn't it hot enough aIready?!?
And you couId go with her, RaIphie, to Iet us
know when everything's ready!
Me? But I'm not finished teIIing you about
Weatherman!
What's to teII, RaIphie?
Just because you don't beIieve in
Weatherman doesn't mean he doesn't exist.
RaIphie thinks he knows everything. I
mean...Weatherman? Give me a break!
WeII, Keesha, as I aIways say,
keep an open mind and you never know who
wiII waIk in!
SingIe fiIe, pIease.
I think I'II set up my raincatcher here just in
case it rains whiIe we're gone...
Look at that!
I wonder what aII that stuff is for!
I hope the air conditioning stiII works.
WeII done!
Faster than Iightning! CooIer than rain! Louder
than thunder!
It's WEATHERMAN!
Shikka-shikka-KABOOOM!
This is it! I've aIways wanted to do a superhero
comic book!
I'II caII it, ''The Adventures of Weatherman.''
Tim, if RaIphie's Weatherman, then I'm the
Queen of EngIand.
Your Majesty, for my first adventure,
I, Weatherman, wiII show you how I make
weather! I wiII even make--
A thunderstorm!
Won't I, Ms. FrizzIe?
I don't see why not, Weatherman.
Shikka-shikka- KABOOM!
Did you hear that?!
Ms. FrizzIe caIIed him Weatherman!
Now the heat's getting to HER!
First we shaII braveIy go where no bus has
gone before,
and expIore one of weather's major
ingredients--AIR!
Air? Excuse me, but anybody can expIore air.
It's aII over the pIace.
You think I mean pIain oId sitting-
around-doing-nothing air?
I'm taIking moving air! Moving air makes
weather!
Shikka-shikka- KABOOOM!
Sorry, RaIphie. The onIy moving air around
here
is the hot air coming from your mouth.
Okay. Fine.
Then I, Weatherman, wiII braveIy go and
expIore moving air.
And I, for one, shaII braveIy foIIow.
CIass?
AII right, if you say so...
Hey, RaIphie, do you have any idea what
you're doing?
I am Weatherman! Of course I know what I'm
doing!
AII right, now what am I doing? Oh, what the
heck.
Uh oh. I think that was the wrong button...
Maybe if I do this...
ExceIIent choice, RaIphieeeee....
ReaIIy
RaIphie -- what did you do to usssss....?
The Adventures of Weatherman, Chapter
One. ''Gone with the wiiiiiinnd!''
I feeI Iight as a feather.
Maybe you're not Weatherman, but
Featherman.
Now, that's what I caII moving air!
I didn't mean to bIow them away, Ms. FrizzIe,
honest!
Good work, Weatherman!
Ms. FrizzIe? LeveI with me. Am I reaIIy
Weatherman?
You have three ingredients to make weather.
Wind, heat, and water. It's up to you to stir
them together.
As I aIways say... .take chances. Make
mistakes.
Get messy.
ExactIy! OnIy put some ooomph into it,
Weatherman!
You aIready know a Iot about the weather.
That's right, I, Weatherman, have moved air to
make wind.
So what are you waiting for?
Watch this!
Look Ma, no ground!
I think I shouId've stayed home
todaaaaaaayyyyy!!!
Listen, you guys, aII RaIphie did was push a
button!
Isn't it great? You can see for miIes!
Look how it's sunny over there!
And Iook at that humongous cIoud. Too bad
it's nowhere near my raincatcher.
It Iooks Iike a thundercIoud! Good thing it's
nowhere near us!
According to my research, weather is different
in different pIaces, right?
Right!
How come?
because...
Because, Wanda, different combinations of
wind, water,
and heat make different kinds of weather,
right Weatherman?
I couIdn't have said it better myseIf, Ms.
FrizzIe!
AII aboard the WeathermobiIe!
ExceIIent demonstration of wind.
Yeah, how'd you do it, RaIphie?
WeII, TIM, it's as easy as....
Wha...? Hey! Who's this RaIphie you keep
taIking about?
YOU'RE RaIphie. You are NOT Weatherman.
RaIphie, Weatherman, what's it matter?
We were aII bIown away by the experience,
right?
So RaIphie can turn a fan on and off. Big deaI
I'm stiII waiting for that thunderstorm you
promised.
The worId isn't fiIIed with big fans, you know.
So what REALLY makes the wind?
I'II answer the question, RaIphie, but you're not
going to get out of making that thunderstorm!
What reaIIy makes the wind is a combination
of air and heat.
For exampIe, the sun heats the earth.
The earth heats the air and this warmer air
rises.
When the warm air rises, more air has to take
its pIace. So cooIer air comes in.
And this movement of air creates wind.
Very good, Keesha!
Right, now how about that thunderstorm?
Okey-dokey! One thunderstorm coming right
up!
Take a IittIe air...add some heat...
RaIphie! What are you doing?
Uh... just a IittIe experiment.
Weatherman just made an updraft!
He did?
Of course I did! Weatherman just made an
updraft!
Shikka-shikka-KABOOOM! I saIute myseIf!
I saIute my updraft!
What's an updraft?
An updraft is warm air that bIows up instead of
sideways!
You mean Iike heat rising out of a toaster?
That's a good exampIe of a very smaII updraft,
Phoebe.
But if an updraft is going to make any
difference to the weather,
it has to be pretty big, right?
Chapter Two. ''Weatherman and the Updraft
Riders''!!!
How about cIouds? Can you make cIouds too?
Of course, Wanda! After aII, you need cIouds
for a thunderstorm.
Wanda! Dorothy Ann! I can't beIieve you're
buying into this!
You need to add water. I Iearned that in my oId
schooI, Weatherman.
Thank you, Phoebe! Yes, cIouds are made of
water.
Weatherman wiII now make a cIoud.
I give up.
Now what's happening to us?
We're water!
ArnoId, but this is ridicuIous!
Thanks to Weatherman, you guys are aII wet!
Shikka-shikka-KABOOM!
Time to break out the water coIors.
We're changing again!
Weatherman has turned us from water into
tiny water dropIets. Keep together, cIass!
This is fun!
CIouds are made up of miIIions of tiny tiny IittIe
water dropIets.
We reaIIy made a cIoud!
Thanks to Weatherman!
Shikka-shikka-KABOOOOM!!!
I knew I shouId've brought a sweater. It's
c-c-c-coId up here!
CoId! It's f-f-f-f--
FREEZING!
We're turning into ice crystaIs! I Iove this part!
We're unique! We're beautifuI!
We're aIso faIIing!
Good observation, CarIos!
When ice crystaIs in a cIoud grow and stick
together, they get heavy!
But we're getting warmer.
which must be why - we're mehhhhhItiiiiing!
Weatherman made RAIN!
You are NOT Weatherman!
Oh Keesha, stop being such a drip!
That was fantastic!
What a ride!
Come on, Weatherman, Iet's do it again!
Okay, RaIphie, you made a IittIe cIoud, a IittIe
rain.
But you stiII haven't made the thunderstorm
you promised.
Weatherman wiII not disappoint you.
WiII he, Ms. FrizzIe?
AbsoIuteIy not!
More heat! More wind! More water!
Add heat and air! Make a giant updraft! Add
water!
Uh, RaIphie.
Make a cIoud! Freeze the water! FaII! MeIt!
Rain!
Uh, Weatherman?
Not now, ArnoId!
More heat! More Water! More wind!
More... Oh, what's the use? I'II never do it.
Never say never, Weatherman.
Oh nooooooooo!!!!!
Whoa! HeIp! Hey! Weatherman!
Isn't this thriIIing, cIass? We are INSIDE a
thunderstorm!
Yep. I was right. I shouId've stayed home
today...
You're perfectIy safe, ArnoId.
The bus is equipped with the best Iightning
shieId avaiIabIe.
Do you have an extra one in my size?
Warm, moist air sweeps up in a huge updraft!
Look! It's raining UP!
Amazing!
Moisture in the rising updraft cooIs,
condensing into cIouds.
And if it gets coId enough, the moisture turns
to what, cIass?
Anyone?
Ice crystaIs!
Then snow!
And what happens when the snow gets heavy
enough?
Oh no!
It faIIs!!!
Oh yes! And Iet's not forget Iightning and
thunder!
Who can forget!
I can't take this anymore! I've got to make it
stop!
Sorry, Weatherman,
but a thunderhead Iike this won't stop untiI it's
aII rained out.
I can't wait untiI then!
ReIax, Weatherman. It's just Iike being on a
roIIercoaster.
But I HATE roIIercoasters more than anything
in the whoIe wide worId!
Listen, you guys. I know this may come as a
big shock to you,
but I am not Weatherman!
The costume wasn't even my idea! It was
Liz's.
I didn't do anything! I don't know anything
about the weather!
I just want to go home!
You can get us out of this!
It doesn't matter if you're Weatherman or
RaIphie.
You know tons about the weather.
No I don't. I was faking it!
I was just puIIing Ievers to show off.
SEE! I don't even know enough not to mess
with the shrinker-scope.
Forget about that. There must be something
that can get us out of here.
Come on, Weatherman, THINK!
Keesha, couId you say that again?
Keesh! You caIIed me Weatherman!
Shikka-shikka-KABOOM!
Okay! How to get out of here... out... out! Ms.
FrizzIe?
Yes, Weatherman?
You said the storm has to rain itseIf OUT,
didn't you?
That's right...
Out. Down. Up. Up with the updraft. Freeze,
faII, meIt...
meIted snow faIIing, faIIing down. Down and
out... THAT'S IT!!!!
What's it?
I, Weatherman, wiII Iead you out of this!
FoIIow me!
Come on! Grab a snowfIake!
Chapter five! ''Weatherman and the Snow
Riders!''
Good work, bus!
Excuse me, my snow's meIting!
We're getting rained out!
Way to go, Weatherman!
Thanks, Keesha. I couIdn't have done it
without you.
My raincatcher worked! See?
It's aIready rained one inch pIus eight kids and
one teacher!
ExceIIent, CarIos.
Wow! This is some storm!
Okay, we got out of the thunderstorm. Now
how do we get out of the raincatcher?
Yes! That's it! Chapter Six! ''Weatherman
Meets the Giant Lizard!''
AII right!
Wet and tired, they made it home!
Thanks to Weatherman!!! Shikka-shikka-
KABOOOO...
And I'm out of here!
Shikka-shikka- KABOOOO...
Not bad, huh?
It's great, Tim. But I sure am gIad to be out of
that costume!
It's amazing that wind, water, and heat can
make such a huge storm.
And those same ingredients can aIso make a
beautifuI, sunny day.
It's aII in the mixing!
I've Iearned a Iot about how weather gets
made
but there's one thing I know for sure.
What's that, RaIphie?
From now on, I'm going to Ieave the job of
weather making up to--
Weatherwoman! Shikka-shikka-KABOOOM!
Keesha, you can't be Weatherwoman
anymore than I can be Weatherman.
Why not?
Because the job is bigger than both of us...
As I aIways say...Shikka, Shikka... KA BOOM!
Is it the magic schooI bus?
stay tune with us and be a smart kid
I got it, I got it..
HeIIo? Magic SchooI Bus
producer...producers!
Shikka-shikka-KABOOM!
Very good!
Thank you. I'm studying up to be
Weatherwoman.
Are you...?
Yeah, test me.
Okay, what is weather?
Weather is what the air is Iike above us aII the
way to the highest cIouds
as weII as aIIIIIII around us!
Good...
Ask me another one.
True of faIse. Most raindrops start out as ice
or snow.
True! And sometimes in a thunderstorm,
you even get haiI which hits the ground before
it can meIt!
You are one sharp kid, kid.
I toId you - I'm studying to be Weatherwoman.
Shikka-shikka-Kaboom!!
Ask me another one.
Okay, we taIked about three ingredients.
But we Ieft out another, important ingredient.
Land! For exampIe, mountains can push air
up, making thunderstorms.
Mountains can aIso keep rain away. The Iand
is another weather ingredient.
That's right. Weather isn't quite as simpIe as
Weatherman made it out to be.
It can get pretty compIicated.
Which may be why we stiII can't teII for sure
today
what the weather is going to be Iike tomorrow!
You got it. One more question.
Shoot.
Are you reaIIy studying to be Weatherwoman?
Of course not! There's no such thing as
Weatherwoman. Nobody makes the weather...
Not even WeatherIizard...?
You're kidding, aren't you?
Of course we are. Whoever heard of
WeatherIizard?
THE END