Let's see...the plangdabber's connected to the
dinplonker...
the blagblatter's connected to the katiebator...
This always happens.
The shrinker-scope breaks the second the
warranty runs out...
Oh bus!
What am l going to do with you?
Okay. Ready for a rehearsal?
She's gonna love it!!
A one and a two...
SURPRlSE!
Yes!
Something's missing...l know it...
My chemistry experiment. lt's almost done.
Your homework?? At a time like this??
l'm mixing three things together - water, sand
and cement...
to get something new...concrete!!
That's what missing...
Cake!!!!
l can't believe it!! We forgot the cake!!
How can we throw a birthday party for Ms.
Frizzle, without a cake!!
What a disaster
Oh well...
Good morning, class.
Good morning, Ms. Frizzle.
Oh. l see you've heard the news.
l'm disappointed too. The bus is acting
up...so...today's field trip is cancelled.
Oh no!! Not the chemistry trip!!
That's okay, Ms. Frizzle. We'll get over it.
lt was all arranged.
We were going to the bakery...
Bakery...
A bakery?? What's that got to do with
chemistry??
Baking is chemistry, Ralphie. lt's like my
cement experiment--
mixing parts together to make something new,
only tastier...
A bakery is really just a small chemical plant.
Except it's a plant where they make...cakes!!!
Gee, Ms. Frizzle, you know
we've all been looking forward to this
chemistry field trip for months...
We have??
Oh yeah. We have.
And, well...l don't think any of us
would think our education was complete
without a trip to a bak---...ah, chemical plant...
Why...Carlos...
Does everyone feel this way?
Well, l'm not one to stand in the way of taking
chances,
making mistakes, and getting messy!!
Bus problems or no bus problems, To the
bakery!!
Yessss!!!
Oh, no.
Now, bus, that wasn't so difficult, was it?
Maybe it was...
Great. How're we supposed to get a cake
when we're this size???
And how're we supposed to even get in
there??
Can't let a tiny bit shrinkage spoil our fun, now
can we Liz?
Well, l guess that answers my question...
Bus. Bus.
Yes, honey. We're going to take the bus
home.
All gone.
Maybe it's a problem with the iotascope. Or
perhaps the enormomometer...
Liz. Not one of these cakes is chocolate! And
that's her favorite.
Besides...we're too small to buy one anyway.
What'll we do?
Well...we could make one...
Are you serious??
Get real!
All right!! A full-scale chemistry experiment!!
But how will we do it without Ms. Frizzle
seeing?
We'll just have to get her out of the bakery...
But a teacher never abandons her bus.
Ms Frizzle?...You know how the
shrinker-scope is acting up?
Could be the shrinker-scope. Might also be the
mesmerglobber. But yes, Carlos?
Well, there's this a great auto parts store right
next door, see, and...
Carlos, what a good idea!
lt worked...!
Liz, you're in charge!
You're joking!?
See you laterrrrrrrrrrrrr...
Bye, bye.
C'mon, liz, let's go.
Blistering bagels!! Moths?? ln my kitchen??!!
Quick! Set 'er down over there, Liz!!
Where did it go???
l'll be back, l shall returrnnn...
Phew! That was close!
Come on, we have work to do!
We are about to combine a few parts into a
magnificent new whole:
the finest birthday cake ever!!...
Okay! The first thing we have to do is gather
and measure the ingredients...
Ralphie: get two eggs! Tim and Wanda: a cup
of sugar and lots of flour!
Liz: a teaspoon each of salt and cream of
tartar!
Keesha: milk and lots of it!
Phoebe: butter! Arnold: baking soda.
And Dorothy Ann, you guard the door
and make sure Ms. Frizzle doesn't come back
too soon!!
Now what about me? Guess l'm stuck getting
the chocolate!
EGGS-actly the ingredient l was looking for.
And-a one. A-two. Aaaaaand...THREE!
l am the King of Soda!!
Arnold!! Youyouyouyou....
You what, D.A...?
You amazing chemist!!! You look at that stuff
fizz!!
The vinegar spilled into the baking soda.
l wonder what would happen if l used this...
Perfect
Mmmm, definitely sugar - my favorite
ingredient!
This won't be easy.
Thanks, Ralphie!
Oh, Phoebe, at your old school you were never
such a butterfingers!
Gotcha.
Now, we've got all the ingredients to make a
cake except the eggs. Where's Ralphie?
TOUCHDOWN!
Yes!!
Amazing!! Now what happens if l mix a LOT of
vinegar with a little bit of baking soda?
You don't know 'til you try, Dorothy Ann!!
Ms. Frizzle...you're, uh...back!!
Unfortunately, the mechanic over there doesn't
know a dwangflommer from a plonthoister.
So l'd thought l'd pop back and see how
everyone's doing...
say, Ms. Frizzle. How'd you like to help me
with a little experiment...?
Excellent idea.
A little bit more... keep going...
Man!! This is tough when you're half the size
of a hot dog!!
Could be worse, Arnold...
l don't see how...
Now l do...
Oh noooooooooo, we shrunk...
Man-o-man-o-man-o-man...
What to do, what to do...
Look at us!
l guess this is what happens when you travel
with faulty equipment.
Wait!! l've got an idea!! Be right back!!
Swell. Now what do we do?
Hey! Look at this!
Wow! Where'd you find those great building
blocks?
These aren't building blocks..Catch!
Hey, this is salt!
Hey, everybody! l found a DlAMOND! Check
out the glimmering surface...
Here's another diamond!
And another one!
We're going to be RlCH!
Not rich--sweet! This is SUGAR!
So this is what sugar looks like close up.
See how the sides make a pattern.
Things that looked alike when we were
big..look different now that we're small!
Let's go you guys! We gotta finish it before the
baker catches us!
Some salt.
Here comes some sugar.
Shimmerin' shortbreads!
Now, some flour.
We can't use this flour--it's got something in it!
No it doesn't. This is what flour looks like
close up.
Even flour is made up of different parts.
l...l couldn't have seen what l thought l
saw...Holy hotdog bun!!
Now that's what l call flour power!
And now for the best ingredient of them all!
Chocolate! Yummy!
Hey!! Mixing in the chocolate makes it a new
colour!
Sure it does, Keesha.
but check out how you can still see which bits
are chocolate and which ones aren't!!
Now we need the wet stuff! Hang on,
everyone!
At least milk still looks like milk.
Sufferin' sweetrolls!! lt must be those blasted
moths!!
Operator?? Get me Smug Bug Pest Control!!
And hurry!!
And now for a real eggs-periment! Eggs away!
Yes!! Pouring the milk, that's correct!!
And now they're...carrying eggs.
Whaddyou mean you've never seen that
behaviour in moths before??
Oh yeah? Well, same to you!!
Salt, sugar, flour, cream of tartar, milk, butter,
eggs, chocolate...aaaaaand....
baking soda! Hit it, Liz!
So...Ms. Frizzle...
is this amazing chemistry or what???
You bet, D.A...
But maybe l should check on the rest of the
class now...
Oh no!! The Friz is back!!
Come on, come on, come on, DA!! Think of
something!!
Come on, come on, come on, DA. Think!
Hey!! Ms. Frizzle! What would happen
if l put a whole bunch of baking soda into a
bottle with the vinegar??
There's only one way to find out!!
What a mess!
lt's a chemical reaction
The balloon!
and a real beauty, too!
No kidding!!
Baking soda and vinegar mixed together made
something new.
A gas that pushes out the sides of the balloon!
Just like filling a tire with air!!
Dorothy Ann! That reminds me!!
The bus needs new tires!! l wonder how much
that'll be?
l better go check, thanks for reminding me!!
Yesss!! Way to go DA!!
No, l am not crazy.
Perhaps my establishment just happens to
attract a higher breed of moth, that's all!!
lf you want anything done right, you have to do
it yourself...
Now, the next step is to mix all the ingredients
together.
Whew! That's gonna take some monster
beaters!
Good idea, Ralphie!
EGG BEATERS!
Everything's getting mixed together.
Yeah, and one more ingredient's getting
added.
What's that?
Air!! The beaters are forcing AlR into the mix.
All the parts are combining into one new thing.
lt's called cake batter!
But if Ms. Frizzle asks, it's --
CHEMlSTRY!!
Cooks and chemists are a lot alike. Both
measure out ingredients...
and mix them together..to make something
new!
The only difference is... l get to taste mine!
Hear that???
He's gonna see us??
Yummy. But when did l make this??
Maybe...that moth...
l am going crazy...
What's happening?
Why is it suddenly getting so hot?
Maybe it's because the floor is on fire.
l am pleased to announce the addition of the
last ingredient - HEAT!
Carlos! Do you mean to say...
Yes! WE'RE lN THE OVEN! And that
means...
...WE'RE GETTlNG BAKED!!
Help!!!
Wait a second here.
lf my facts are straight--we're stuck in a cake
baking in an intensely hot oven!!!
At my old school, we never got baked...except
that time the air conditioning went...
We're toast...!!
Well, technically no, but you've got the right
idea...
is it just me...or is that the Tin Man from ''The
Wizard of Oz''??
Maybe we should ask Toto, here...
Phew! Warm one today.
MS. FRlZZLE?
Feels like somebody forgot to put up the
heat-shield.
Much better!
Oh, good.
Thanks, Ms. Frizzle.
As l always say, if you can't stand the heat --
get out of the oven.
Yeah, but how?
Hey, look! The batter's moving!
According to my research, the baking soda is
making bubbles!!
Whoa! Now what?
The batter's not the only thing getting pushed
around...!
What's that noise?
lt's steam!
Excellent observations! lt's so hot that the
water in the batter is vaporizing,
making more and bigger bubbles.
The batter is starting to look kind of solid.
The cake, it's done!
Ah, the sweet smell of parts combining into a
new and magnificent whole!
Now...l wonder if the baker is making this cake
with a special customer in mind...
Oh no. We're going to have our cake and be
EATEN too!
No digressions for indigestion, Arnold. We
just...
Oh well, as l always say, the more mixup
things are, the better the solution.
We're doomed!
Wait!! l've got it! ls there any baking soda left?
Plenty...
Vinegar?
Hmmm. Red, tarragon, or regular white??
Uhhh...regular white is fine...
What are you doing DA?
Yeah. we gotta get outta here!
Well, Baking soda plus vinegar equals...
...the gas pressure we need to push us out of
here!
Dorothy Ann, you are one brilliant chemist!
Gee, thanks.
Come on you guys, hurry.
Yesss
Hooray!
We made it!
We're out!
And stay out!!!
Finally!! All fixed. Who'd've guessed?? lt was
the hinkleblammenjammenflappe--
Surprise!!!!
Why...class...this is wonderful...l don't know
what to say...
That's not all, Ms. Frizzle...we still have the big
finale!!
A big finale?? What could that be??
Ready, Arnold...?
You bet...
Class!! Where did you ever get such a lovely
cake...??
You wouldn't believe us if we told you...
The baker just gave it to us...said it was
ruined...something about a moth...
But, frankly, we didn't believe him...
As l always say: chemistry, it's a piece o'
cake!!
ls it the magic school bus?
stay tune with us and be a smart kid
Finally!! All my baking!! Done for the day!!
Wow. ls this the bakery where they filmed that
'Magic Schoolbus' show?
Yes, yes of course!! l was brilliant in it!!
A remarkable tenor, that's whatthe Frizzle
Opera Review said...
Those look good.
l bet you a donut l can tell you some crucial
information missing from the show...
What?? lmpossible!! You insult me!! You're
on...
lt was--
WAlT!! Was it that Dorothy Ann is a little
young to be doing those experiments??
Not really. Ms. Frizzle was there,
and everyone knows you need a grown-up
around
when you're doing chemistry experiments. And
she was wearing goggles.
Ha!! Then l'll bet you two donuts...
Sure!! lt was--
--WAlT!! Was it that some people think
chemicals are bad for them?
No - some chemicals are good. lt depends on
what you use them for.
Okay...three donuts, then...
Okay!! lt was--
WAlT!! Was it though we said things are
made out of parts
we never said what the parts are made of???
No. l already knew they're made of smaller
parts called atoms.
And atoms are made of even smaller parts.
And so on and so on. lt was--
WAlT!!
Maybe you think things like salt
and sugar don't really look like building blocks
and diamonds.
They do under a microscope... l love looking
through microscopes.
l think you're bluffing. l'll bet you every donut in
this store you
you can't tell me what information was
missing...
You never said how old Ms. Frizzle is...
Leapin' ladyfingers!!...
THE END