Why Liz, what luck! You've found a ladybug.
Yes, folks - l'd just like to say, l couldn't have
done it without... Seeds!
lt was seeds from a pack like this that grew
into these prize winning tomato plants!
Carlos, WHAT are you doing?
Practicing being famous, what else?
What makes you think you're going to be
famous?
Not just me -- all of us!
Think - the photographer shows up at three,
and takes a picture of us in our garden...
...The picture goes on the cover of Plant lt!
Magazine, and we're FAMOUS!
So, there we go, Phoebe, it's finished!
Oh, thank you, Tim! That's exactly what my
plant looks like.
Plant? What plant? l don't see a plant.
You're not looking, Carlos. This is it! See?
Phoebe!
You don't get on the cover of Plant lt!
Magazine with a DRAWlNG of a plant!
l've got a real one -- it's just not here...
lt's at my old school.
When l was in Mr. Seedplot's class...
But, Phoebe, this is your NEW school!
l tried to get one, l really did. l even wrote a
letter to Mr. Seedplot
to see if he could bring me one. But so far
nothing.
l don't care if you wrote the president!
We need your plant HERE! NOW!
No hurry to worry, Carlos. There's always
time to take chances,
make mistakes, get WHEELS!
Mistakes? Wheels? This is starting to sound
like a...
FlELD TRlP!
As l always say, if the plant won't come to you,
go to the plant!
We're going to my old school? All of us?
Now?
All right! Come on, Phoebe! We don't have
much time!
Oh no!
Phoebe, aren't you excited?
A field trip to your old school!
l'd like to meet Mr. Seedplot!
Meet Mr. Seedplot?
Um, Mr. Seedplot! l'd like you to meet--
Take chances! Make mistakes! Get messy!
We never did anything like this at our old
school.
How embarrassing...
At this rate, we'll never get back in time for the
photograph!
Can't we fly there, Ms Frizzle?
Excellent idea, Carlos.
Ms. Frizzle, at my old school, things are kind
of quiet...
Yes...
And people don't shrink or anything...
Of course not, Phoebe.
And buses don't turn into things...
But, Phoebe. A ladybug isn't a thing! lt's an
insect.
Oh no!
Here we go again!
A ladybug?
l was hoping supersonic jet...
l was hoping invisible.
There it is...! My old school!
What will Mr. Seedplot say if he sees us?
l don't get it, Ms. Frizzle.
How are we ever going to find Phoebe's plant
if we're so small?
lt never hurts to have a bug's eye view!
Or a view of a bug's eye...!
Okay, everybody. Here's what we're looking
for.
And there it is!!
Yeah! All right!
Those plants are drop-dead gorgeous.
Now, can we get big again, dig one of them
up, and get back in time to be famous?
Well, Carlos, l'll see what l can do!
Talk about HANGlNG a left.
l HATE it when we go upside-down.
Ms. Frizzle, you DlD pass your ladybug driving
test, right?
With flying colors.
We're on a flower petal!
Oh please, somebody tell me this isn't
happening.
lt's happening.
lsn't it wonderful, class?
The sky above...a flower below...
A pothole dead ahead!
What's happening!!
Perfect landing, Liz.
Class, we're well on our way to getting Phoebe
a plant.
But we're stuck!
That too!
Could Mr. Seedplot see us if he looked?
Probably not. We're down here, in your
flower.
Then let's hope we stay down here.
No taking chances. No getting messy. And
most of all, no getting out of the BUS.
Okay, class! Everybody out!
Wait! Don't! Mr. Seedplot might see us!
Please!
Maybe you should have stayed home today,
Phoebe.
Oh, no!
We're stuck!
How are we gonna get outta here?
Follow me, class. Take chances, make
mistakes, get slippery!
Ready or not, here l come!
l can't let Mr. Seedplot catch me out there,
how embarassing.
Thanks Liz, Mr. Seedplot won't recognize me
with this on...
Hey, Phoebe! Nice disguise.
Forget it.
This stuff is sweet. What is it?
ls it just me or do you get the feeling
we're the cherries in somebody's ice cream
soda?
lt's looks like a soda straw, Ralphie, but it's
really a proboscis.
A proboscis?
That's right, Keesha. Every bee has a
proboscis.
And they use them to drink the stuff we're
stuck in?
According to my research, this stuff is nectar.
On the proboscis, Dorothy Ann!
l like a proboscis as much as the next guy,
but what we need is a probuscis to get us out
of here.
Okay - what should we do what should we do
what should we do?
Hey! l know! Let's get lots of bees to drink all
the nectar around the bus.
How? Send out invitations?
Yes! That's it! Look at these lines.
They seem to be pointing to the pools of
nectar in the flower.
Okay, so maybe they're like a flower's version
of landing lights.
l get it! So if we made more lines,
maybe we could get more bugs to come and
suck up the nectar!
Excellent, Liz.
Wanda, C'mon.
Go Wanda go...!
Yes! Here they come!
AlR RAlD!
As l always say, let them eat NECTAR!
lt worked! We did it!
Here we go!
Phoebe's plant, here we come!
Let's get the facts: plants make nectar for
insects.
And then use flowers to show them where it is.
But l hope they don't show Mr. Seedplot where
we are.
Now, were was l?
Oh yes...''So l hope you can help me, Mr.
Seedplot,
because l don't want to let my new class
down.''
Well, Phoebe, l certainly won't let you down.
l'm just not sure which plant was yours...
lt's almost three o'clock.
Can we PLEASE grab one of Phoebe's flowers
and get back to school now?
Carlos, for every quethion, there's an anther.
An anther, that's the part of the flower we're
sitting on!
Check out all the yellow balls!
two things make me sneeze...pollen and
pepper.
this isn't pepper...
So it must be pollen.
And it's floating around EVERYwhere!
Nice propulsion, Arnold!
Thank you, Ms. Frizzle. l knew l should ah, ah,
ah stayed home today.
Look The bees are getting covered with
pollen!
Looks like they're saving some for later.
Binoculars! Quick!
lt's Mr. Seedplot!
Ms. Frizzle, could we please shrink again?!
Really small!
Small as... uh... POLLEN
All right, Phoebe, since it's such a tiny
request--
But if we're small as POLLEN,
even if we make the cover of Plant lt!
Magazine, we'll be too small to see!
MS. FRlZZLE!
Egad! l believe l've discovered a new insect -
''The Vanishing Ladybug''
Though it's going to be hard to prove...
Whew, that was close. Thanks, Ms. Frizzle.
And thank you, Phoebe
for letting our chance at gardening fame rot on
the vine.
ls it just me, or is that a BlG HAlRY BEE'S
LEG?
You better bee-lieve it! And it's going to get us
out of here!
lt is...?
You bet!
This is so cool, we're stuck to a bumblebee!
At my old school, we never rode on
bumblebees.
We ARE at your old school, Phoebe.
Oh, right.
Hey Phoebe, look!
The bee's taking us and the pollen to another
one of your flowers.
Giving us the brush-off, huh?
l think we'd just landed on another part of
Phoebe's flower
Oh great...more pollen.
l get it!
The insects bring pollen from one flower to
another.
Yeah, but what does it have to do with bringing
plants from one SCHOOL to another?
There are several ways to find out the answer
to that. . .
...and l choose this one!
She's lost it...
Where are we?
Right here! l think...
The bee has taken us--and lots of pollen--to
the top of the female part of the flower.
Ms. Frizzle, may l be excused to find some
more... !
Tissue!!!!
Arnold, come back here! You've gone the
wrong way!
Cool! Arnold just discovered that pollen grows
a tube down into the flower!
Yes, this is the plant for Phoebe.
Wait for ME!!!!
Or is it?
l can't believe she just did that!
As l always say, all pollen tubes lead to home.
This way class.
Wait for ME!
But what about the cover of Plant lt!
Magazine?
Another second and Mr. Seedplot would have
seen us!
Oh swell! Where are we?
Let me see... here! Because pollen tubes
grow down.
We're totally inside my flower.
Phoebe, what are you doing now? We've got
to get your...
Safe at last! What a relief!
Phoebe, get off! lt's alive!
The rock l was sitting on, it started to grow!
This isn't rock, l know rocks.
This is part of the plant.
l think Arnold's right. Looks more like an egg
to me.
l wonder if it started to grow when the pollen
tube reached it.
They're all over the place.
What are they?
Did l miss something?
Did we come to Phoebe's old school to get her
plant,
or to see ''lnvasion of the Pollen Tubes?''
Carlos, you'll be happy to know that they are
what we came for.
But we only need one.
We came for a plant. This isn't a plant.
Not yet, it isn't. But it will be.
lt's a plant waiting to happen.
Of course! l get it! lt's a SEED!!
My plant is making seeds!
Dynamic deduction! Phoebe.
The bee carried the pollen, lands on a flower's
stigma and grow tubes down to the eggs.
and together they make seeds!
So all we have to do is take this seed back,
plant it in our garden, and we'll be famous!
Great. There's still one small problem.
What?
TlME!
There's not a seed in the world that can
become a PLANT in FlVE MlNUTES!
As l always say, time flies when you've got the
right equipment!
Hit it, Liz!
All right! Look at those seeds grow!
l hope this seed is an express.
Hang on class. Here we go!
Plant lt! Magazine, here we come!
Ms. Frizzle, can't this seed go any faster?
Not unless we hitch a ride on a dog or a bird
or a mongoose
A mongoose?
Here comes our ride!
Oh no! lt's Mr. Seedplot! We can't!
We have to!
We are!
We're on Mr. Seedplot's head! HOW
EMBARRASSlNG!
We've got to get off before he sees us!
But Phoebe, this is our chance to meet Mr.
Seedplot.
Hey Mr. Seedplot! Up here!
Quiet!! We'll get thrown off!
Yes! MR. SEED PLOT!
Hello? Did someone call me?
Phoebe! You did it again!
We're almost there!
We made it!
Oh no!
Now what?
The photographer's here and we're not ready!
You're right, the seed isn't a plant yet.
We need soil and water and light and..
And TlME! TlME for it to sprout and grow and
flower!
And TlME we haven't got... Ms. Frizzle?
Okay, Liz, TlME to go to hyper-seed.
Soil
Water
Light
Time
Well, Phoebe, you did it! l see you found a
plant after all.
Where is everybody, anyway?
Ms. Frizzle, stop!
Can we just shrink again?
Phoebe - NOW WHAT?
lf we get big again, Mr. Seedplot will see us!
So??? Phoebe, it's three o-clock!
The photographer's here! THlS lS OUR BlG
CHANCE!!!
But what'll Mr. Seedplot think if we just appear,
POOF, out of nowhere?
He'll think we appeared, POOF, out of
nowhere.
Exactly. He'll think we're really WElRD!
He'll think Ms. Frizzle is...
Phoebe, are you embarrassed by Ms. Frizzle?
But Phoebe, think of what she's just done!
Ms. Frizzle's the best! Mr. Seedplot can think
what he likes!
Let's get big so l can introduce him to my new
teacher!
Thanks. Are you Mr. Frizzle?
No, l'm Mr. Seedplot. Ms. Frizzle doesn't
appear toz. . .
Hello there.
Oh! There they are!
Hello, Phoebe. l brought you a plant,
but l see you already have one.
Thanks so much for bringing it, Mr. Seedplot.
And you're right, l have one already. Thanks
to Ms. Frizzle!
Ms. Frizzle! Nice to see you again!
Nice to see you, too, Archibald.
You mean...you know each other?
Sure! l'm one of Ms. Frizzle's biggest fans!
And l just love your garden! lt's really magic!
What's your secret?
No secret, Archibald.
As l always say the magic is in the gardeners!
All right, everyone, say--
SEEDS
ls it the magic school bus?
stay tune with us and be a smart kid
Dear Valerie... No, no...
Hello, is this the Magic School Bus?
But l don't work here.
Hello?
Hello. ls is this the Magic School Bus?
Yes, but. . .
Did you work on that show about seeds?
Actually, l was in it.
Then maybe you can answer a few questions.
Well, l'll try.
First of all, why didn't Phoebe just look in a
catalogue and get her seeds from there?
Because seeds don't really come from
catalogs. They come from plants.
True, but how about when Ms. Frizzle
speeded everything up by magic?
l do love her magic.
Well they do that on nature programs all the
time. lt's called time lapse photography,
and they use it to show things happening
faster than they really do.
but there some things that just can't be
rushed.
What are you talking about?
Oh, sorry, what was the question?
What kind of plant did Phoebe have anyway?
That was a...er...a Flowering Made-up-icus.
Give me a break. There's no such plant.
Okay, you're right. Phoebe's flower was
invented for the show,
but it's very similar to lots of real flowers.
but one last question.
That's what l'm here for.
Does Ms. Frizzle have a boyfriend?
Well...l don't have time to answer that.
Goodbye.
Nice to see you, too, Archibald.
THE END