Seat belts, everyone!
Please let this be a normal field trip!
With the Frizz, no way!
Aaaaw!
♪ Cruising on down Main Street, ♪
♪ You're relaxed and feeling good! ♪
Yeah!
♪ Next thing that you know you're seein' ♪
Wah ha ha hoo!
Octopus in the neighborhood!
♪ Surfin' on a sound wave, ♪
♪ Swingin' through the stars! ♪
♪ Take a left at your intestine! ♪
♪ Take your second right past Mars! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Navigate a nostril! ♪ Achoo!
♪ Climb on the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Spank a plankton, too! ♪
Take that!
♪ On our Magic School Bus, ♪
♪ Raft a river of lava! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Such a fine thing to do! ♪
Woah!
♪ So strap your bones right to the seat! ♪
♪Come on in and don't be shy! ♪
Come on.
♪ Just to make your day complete, ♪
♪ You might get baked into a pie! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Step inside, it's a wild ride! ♪
Come on!
♪ Ride on the Magic School Bus! ♪
Eeew!
Is that some kind of rot or what?
That is one rotten orange, Ralphie.
It's so disgusting, it
could win the contest.
Ah, the smell of decomposing orange.
Oh, delectable.
So what's my score, Tim?
Do I win the most disgusting,
grossest rot contest ever?
Two nose holds and a faint.
Good one, Ralphie.
Woohoohoo!
Definitely disgusting.
Let's see,
Yup, this should do it.
Next!
How about this, Tim?
It fell behind the counter
when I was still at my old school.
Eww, Phoebe!
That banana's so rotten, it's mush.
Score?
That's three nose holds.
Congratulations.
Next!
Wait until you see this!
Wanda, what is in there?
I don't know, Carlos.
Nobody knows.
It's been in the fridge since I was four.
Just beautiful.
You're not gonna open it are you?
Of course she is.
Come on, class.
Don't you wanna see
what rip-roaring rot's inside?
Here goes.
Oh!
Yuck!
Score, please.
Three faints.
Very good, Wanda.
We've got us a winner!
And to congratulate you on winning
the most disgusting rot contest,
I have a little prize.
Oh, Wanda, it's a baby tree.
Miss Frizzle, I really
like it and everything,
But it's not really rotten, is it?
It's so... alive.
That's right, Keisha.
It's very alive.
And so is rot.
It is?
Mmm-hmm.
Well Wanda, what would
you like to do with your prize?
Um... I guess
I'd like to plant it.
And I know just the spot.
You know that old lot
near my house, on Decatur?
An excellent place for a new tree.
To the bus!
Two by two, please.
Now Wanda, you really wanna put
your nice tree in that ugly old lot?
Correct.
But it's filled with lots of dead stuff.
Rotting logs, tree stumps,
That's the point, Carlos.
We could make that lot beautiful.
Just clear out all the dead stuff
and plant my lovely green tree.
Think how great this
tree will look when it's big.
It could be a little park, and
we could call it Wanda World.
No, wait, no, wait, no, wait.
Why not do something really cool with it?
What about a theme park?
Yeah, cool.
Theme park?
Now wait a minute.
Yes, and the theme could be Rot.
What?
And we'll call it Rotland.
Yeah!
Oh, interesting notion.
Any other thoughts?
I know, I know.
Let's build a restaurant.
Yeah, a fast food joint.
I hate to say this, but restaurants
and theme parks mean litter.
Garbage everywhere.
Think of the environment.
Hmm,
So let's build a recycling center.
A what?
Oh, no.
That's a great idea, Phoebe.
No, it's not.
Hey, there's the lot!
Miss Frizzle, I'm going
to go out and have a look.
Certainly, Wanda.
Take chances!
Get messy!
Make mistakes!
Woohoo! This is more than I thought.
There's a lot of stuff to get rid of.
Hey guys!
A tunnel of rot!
Specials for veggies!
Junk sculpture!
Hello, excuse me, I have an announcement.
We need help.
Huh?
Larry's Log Away.
The log removal service
that won't leave you stumped.
Perfect.
Oh, I can't wait to see their faces when
I get this place all cleaned up.
Hello.
Oh, hi, is this Larry's Log Away?
You got him.
Right, I have a job for you.
We need to get rid of
some useless dead log.
Sure, I can do that. Where is it?
A lot on Decatur.
Ooh, how about if I come now?
Yeah, that will be just great!
Listen, the theme park
could have a slime ride.
Forget it.
This neighborhood needs a restaurant.
We can argue about what
to do after the lot is clear.
Hold it!
Why not just leave
this place the way it is?
Arnold, why do you always want to leave
things alone instead of doing something?
I have this theory that if you leave nature alone,
It'll get along just fine.
Forget your theories, Arnold.
That rotten log has to go.
It's dead. It's useless.
I mean, look at it!
And that, Wanda, is exactly what we shall do.
Seat belts, everyone.
Wanda, now look what you've done.
The Frizz is going to...
No, no way.
This puzzle...
You're not going to...
We really shouldn't.
We can't!
Whoa!
Too late, Wanda.
Keep strong.
Oh no, not now.
What did I do? What did I do?!
But Miss Frizzle, we've got to get out of here.
Now!
Where are we going?
We're going to find out what Wanda
brought us to do with life, Wanda.
But do we have to find out now?
Okay, class.
Everybody out!
Take chances. Make mistakes. Get messy.
Wahoo!
Yeah, make mistakes. My specialty.
Wow!
A dead log sure looks different
when you're no bigger than a bug.
And the bugs are different too, right Liz?
Wow! Look at that!
Rot! Life!
Okay, let's go back now.
Lighten up, Wan.
Last one up's a centipede!
No! Wait!
Please, don't go up there!
We've got to gooooooo!
What's that?
That, class, is a chipmunk.
Hi!
Wanda? Where are you?
I'm over here!
Ah, thanks, Miss Fizzle.
Ah, Don't mention it, Wanda.
Wow! It's another world up here!
Whoa!
The perfect look for Rotland!
But we can't do anything
until we take this log away.
So let's get big again and get out of here.
Hey! Where do you think this goes?
It goes down, Ralphie.
Okay now, us, we want to go home.
Single file, class.
Our rotten field trip has only just begun.
Not if I have anything to say about it.
Hey, everyone!
Uh, there's a great log in my backyard!
Why don't we go there for our field trip?
I'll serve cookies and milk.
Wanda, we're here,
Because you pointed to this
log and said, and I quote,
"Just look at it!"
Remember?
I took a chance. I made a mistake.
So how do I stop it from
getting really messy?
No sign of Larry the Log Away guy?
Huh?
Yikes!
Whoa!
Really have to get out of here!
What's that sound?
Oh, don't worry class.
Woodpeckers only eat bugs.
Wow!
There are hundreds of tunnels down here.
How about a tunnel tour in Rotland?
Grreat idea, D.A.!
Forget Wanda World, let's build Rotland
and I say, "Start right away!"
Let's go!
Hey! Look at that!
It's coming this way!
Look out!
Well done class.
You found a Bessie bug,
One of the animals which made all these tunnels.
Great!
Here's a bus! We can go now.
A Bessie bus?
Now I've seen everything.
This place keeps getting
more and more amazing!
Uck!
What's this stuff?
Those are part of the mushrooms
we saw on the outside of the log.
Some mushrooms grow on dead wood.
Underneath the mushroom caps, a tangle
of tiny threads grows throughout the wood.
These threads eat the
wood and help rot the log.
Hey!
This thread effect could be good
for the haunted house in Rotland.
He's back!
You did say just bugs?
Right, Miss Frizzle?
Yes, Ralphie.
Phew! That was close!
Who would have known a
dead log could be so alive?
Right, Miss Frizzle?
I'm sorry, but I don't think we should stay in a
place where we might become somebody's lunch.
I told you we should have
left well enough alone.
And I'm telling you, we have to
get out of here before...
Wahoo!
Miss Frizzle?
Too cool!
Come on!
No, D.A., let go!
Wait!
Whoa!
I bet you never thought an amoeboid
plasmodium ecould be so much fun!
A what?
A slime mold.
It's another living
thing living off the log.
Think of it, D.A.
The stunningly stupendous, super
slime slide found exclusively at...
Shh!
Rotland.
No, Carlos.
Found naturally in a dead log.
Which is stunningly
stupendous just the way it is.
Right!
Wait!
What about taking this log away?
Sorry, Wanda.
We've changed our minds.
Hey, hey, Carlos, D.A.
Welcome to the Leave It As It Is Club.
Okay then, it's settled.
We'll do the restaurant instead.
Now let's go!
What was that?
Hey, wait! You're going the wrong way!
It gets worse and worse.
Lunchtime class!
All right!
Nothing like a rotten log that's catered!
So what will it be?
Log nuggets, wood dumplings, pureed bark?
Huh?
Um, I hate to be
picky, Ms. Frizzle, but,
Do you have anything
in the way of food?
But the log is food, Ralphie.
That's the beauty of it.
All these creatures use
the log for food and energy.
Fine, fine.
So let's just get out of here
and open our restaurant.
Right, Ralphie?
Whoa.
Not only does stuff eats the log,
But stuff eats the stuff that eats the log.
Yeah.
Everywhere you look
around here, it's lunchtime.
You know something, Keisha?
This place is already a restaurant.
What?
Sorry, Wanda, but we don't
want to clear it away anymore.
Yes!
Two more for the Keep
The Log The Way It Is Club.
Okay, so no Rotland, no restaurant.
So let's get big and argue some more!
Why argue?
Five out of eight kids say we
shouldn't take this log away.
One more chance to
get everybody out of here.
Phoebe, Tim!
This reminds me of the
mush my banana turned into.
The process of decomposition
breaks everything down!
Be it wood, banana, or bug.
Phoebe!
Phoebe, Tim, I can honestly
say that your recycling center idea
Is the best ever in
the history of the earth.
Really?
You bet.
So please, please tell Ms. Frizzle that you
want to get big to recycle this log, please?
But it's already being recycled, Wanda,
As food for fungi and bugs.
As a place for mosses and lichens to grow.
And as a home for all sorts of creatures.
Okay, okay, but all these creatures
leave a lot of litter, don't they?
You know bug plops, so the
quicker we clear it out-
Wait!
The bug plops are being used too.
Natural recycling.
I'm sorry, but that is gross.
Oh, it's not gross, Wanda.
It's another addition to decomposition.
Ooh, I give up.
Okay, it's not gross,
it's perfect, I love it.
Now let's just get out of here!
Hey everyone, over here!
Now what?
Look! Beautiful, rich soil.
Perfect for your tree, Wanda.
Now will you join the
Leave It As It Is Club?
I don't believe it.
♪ An old dead log, sitting on your lawn. ♪
♪  It's ugly, it's awful and you want it gone. ♪
♪  Well that log you got, it's not a lot. ♪
♪ 'Cause it's got rotten, that says a lot. ♪
♪  It's breaking on down,
are you wondering how? ♪
♪  Well, fungus and bugs, they
use them for chow. ♪
♪  It's rained on by rain, snowed on by snow, ♪
♪  We're standing to soil so
new things can grow. ♪
♪  It's cool, it's renewal. ♪
♪ Ask Miss Frizzle, that log's
just fine the way it izzle. ♪
This place is fine, just the way it is.
All right, I see it now!
There's absolutely no
reason to take this log away.
Except one,
Yeah, Wanda, which one's that?
Larry.
Who's Larry?
Ah!
Let's get out of here!
This way, class.
What's that?!
Stay with your partners.
Wanda, is there something you'd like to tell us?
I'm sorry, really I am.
I didn't know when I
called Larry, but I know now.
Why do I always have to do something
when I should just leave well enough alone?
Frizzle: Sometimes action has a
certain attraction, Wanda.
And now is one of those times!
I got it!
Good idea!
Hey! Help!
Put these on. And hurry!
You have got to be joking.
You want us to wear these things?
Do you have a better idea?
Seat belts, everyone!
Here we go!
Larry! Larry!
Who's that?
Hmm.
What on earth do you think
you're doing, Lawrence?
I am uh...
I'm from the Organization
of Log Gremlins, local 119.
You are?
And frankly, the OLG doesn't like people coming
along and unnecessarily shaking things up.
Tell me, Larry, what do you
see when you look around here?
Well, I see a routine rot removal.
Well, look again!
See that dead log?
Did you know it's a theme park, a restaurant, a
recycling center, and Wanda World all rotted into one?
You wouldn't believe how
many creatures live in there!
And you know what else?
Huh. No.
What else?
They are nature's rot squad, Larry.
Rot is a wonderful thing
and necessary thing.
Rot is nature recycling itself,
creating the new friendly OLG.
Whoa!
I get it.
Is there a hidden camera
around here someplace?
Come on, you guys.
Face it, Lawrence.
Removing this log is an
imposition on decomposition.
I had no idea rotting logs had
such eloquent spokesgremlins.
But how come I never heard them before?
Yow.
Oh boy, I probably shouldn't
be operating heavy machinery.
That gremlin idea was a
stroke of genius, Wanda.
Thanks, Arnold.
But I'll tell you something.
From now on, I'm gonna
leave well enough alone.
Wanda, what should we do? What
should we do? What should we do?
Come on, Arnold.
Everybody, back on the bus.
What?
Um, do you two have any particular plans for that?
Odiferous collection of rot.
Rot is an important part of nature.
Right?
Right.
And one of its uses is to
provide food for other living things.
So, who's up for a picnic?
Yuck!
But Wanda, Arnold, that's disgusting.
Not if you're my tree.
Yum, yum, compost.
As I always say, it doesn't
have to be delicious to be nutritious.
Is this the Magic School Bus?
Magic School Bus?
I want the Magic School Bus!
Ugh, Liz, you can't bring that in here!
Hello, hello.
Hello, Magic School Bus.
Hi. Are you responsible for that
show I just saw on decomposition?
Get that a-
Why do you ask?
Because it was rotten!
No kidding.
No, wait, I was kidding.
I've got to tell you, I've seen
some rotten things in my time,
But they're not always
filled with bugs and fungus.
Um, well that's because a lot of rot
is caused by things too small to see.
We wanted to shrink down to the
size of bacteria, but Arnold wouldn't go.
Is there anything that doesn't rot?
Not if it was once alive.
Plants, animals, bacteria, they
all decompose after they die.
Even the rotters eventually rot.
Okay, so tell me this.
There's a fallen log across
the street from my house.
That's been there since last summer.
When is it gonna rot?
It's already decomposing,
but rot can take a long time.
Years even.
But it will eventually return to the
soil, just like the log in the show.
Like I said, almost everything rots.
Yeah, how come you almost totally
ignored one of my favorite creatures?
I did, which one?
The earthworm.
Funny you should say that.
Earthworms should not be ignored.
Never.
Earthworms are very good at
eating and plowing and improving soil.
Then that's what they should be left to do.
You know, I was thinking,
what if there were no rot?
If nothing rotted, ever.
Then the soil wouldn't get back
the nutrients that plants need to grow.
Most plants would die and the Earth
would become barren like a desert.
And you know what?
What?
There are no such things as log gremlins.
Depends on whom you talk to.
Hahaha!
♪ Surfing on a sound wave, ♪
♪ Swinging through the stars, ♪
♪ Take a left at your intestine, ♪
♪ Take your second right past Mars! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Navigate a nostril! ♪
Achoo!
♪ Climb on the Magic School Bus ♪
♪ Spank a planton too. ♪
Take that!
♪ On our Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Raft a river of lava! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus ♪
♪ Such a fine thing to do, ♪
Woah!
♪ So strap your bones right to the seat! ♪
♪ Come on in and don't be shy, ♪
♪ Just to make your day complete, ♪
♪ You might get baked into a pie! ♪
♪ On The Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Step inside, it's a wilder ride! ♪
Come on!
♪  Ride on The Magic School Bus! ♪