[Bus beeps]
Seat belts, everyone!
Please let this be a normal field trip!
With the Frizz, no way!
Aaaaw!
♪ Cruising on down Main Street, ♪
♪ You're relaxed and feeling good! ♪
Yeah!
♪ Next thing that you know you're seein' ♪
Wah ha ha hoo!
Octopus in the neighborhood!
♪ Surfin' on a sound wave, ♪
♪ Swingin' through the stars! ♪
♪ Take a left at your intestine! ♪
♪ Take your second right past Mars! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Navigate a nostril! ♪ Achoo!
♪ Climb on the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Spank a plankton, too! ♪
Take that!
♪ On our Magic School Bus, ♪
♪ Raft a river of lava! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Such a fine thing to do! ♪
Woah!
♪ So strap your bones right to the seat! ♪
♪Come on in and don't be shy! ♪
Come on.
♪ Just to make your day complete, ♪
♪ You might get baked into a pie! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Step inside, it's a wild ride! ♪
Come on!
♪ Ride on the Magic School Bus! ♪
[Bus beeps]
[Music]
D. A.: Arnold, that's brilliant!
It is?
Yeah, Ms. Frizzle said to bring in
something to help answer the question,
What happens to the food we eat?
Oh, right!
What did I bring?
Your own mouth!
Chewing!
It's the first step in...
In digestion.
Yeah, yeah, we know, Dorothy Ann.
But my buddy Arnold
here is not chewing food,
He's chewing gum.
Gum?
Yep, been chewing for
two hours and 24 minutes.
Only six hours and 46 minutes to go before
he breaks the school gum chewing record.
But, Wanda...
What's chewing gum got to do with digestion?
Nothing, but the first one to break the gum
chewing record wins two free tickets to...
Action...Mountain!
The wildest, scariest, best
scream-your-lungs-out ride in the world!
The ride of my dreams!
Let's get the facts.
Arnold wants to go on the fastest, the scariest,
the best scream-your-lungs-out ride in the world?
You feel all right, Arnold?
Actually, my ticket's up for grabs.
I'm just helping Wanda out.
I would have done the chewing
myself, but I got a new filling.
See?
Ah!
[Ms. Frizzle groans]
[Mrs. Frizzle continues groaning]
Oh, good morning, class.
One digestive system coming up.
Eee ya!
[Whimsical Sound Effects]
Now that's more like it!
Was that in the lesson plan?
As I always say, no guts, no digestion.
Well, as I always say,
No chewing, no free tickets.
Come on, Arnold, chew!
Chew, Arnold!
Um, Wanda?
I think I, uh, uh, swallowed it.
Very funny, Arnold.
You're kidding, right?
Say ah!
Ahhhh!
Arnold, how could you?
Wanda, I-
We were going to
ride Action Mountain together!
You didn't do it on purpose, did you?
No, no, it was an accident, really.
I'm sorry, Wanda.
I told you, breaking
records made me nervous.
I told you I've never
won anything in my life.
Never say never, Arnold.
Arnold: I told you you should've
picked someone else!
Oh, hey, Arnold, it's okay.
I mean, it's only a ride.
And that's the end of that.
Actually, Wanda, it's only the beginning.
Of what?
Our next field trip.
Field trip!
Field trip.
Miss Frizzle, I'd really love
to go on a field trip, but-
But I've got this weird feeling.
I mean, I already ruined Wanda's day.
What if I ruin everybody else's?
Well, Arnold, I do need a
volunteer to stay behind.
Stay behind?
Come on, go!
Me! Me! Pick me!
Oh, thank you, Arnold.
Alright!
Wait a minute.
This is too good to be true.
What's the catch?
Meet your substitute teacher.
Liz?
Oh, could be worse.
(Ominously) See you very soon, Arnold.
One field trip for them,
One bag of Cheezie Weezies for me.
Frizzle: Mmm.
Our timing should be just about right.
I don't get it.
I thought we were supposed to answer the
question about what happens to the food we eat.
Yeah, where are we going?
Not far, class, not far at all.
Here we go!
[Magical Sounds Effects]
Arnold: Mmm-mmm!
[Music]
Whoops!
Whoa!
Where are we?
Ralphie: Check out the pink pavement!
The walls are drippy.
You know what, Miss Frizzle?
At my old school, we turn
back in this kind of weather.
What are those humongo white things?
Whoa!
If you ask me, they're
humongo bus crushers.
Actually, Ralphie, they're more
like humongo food crushers.
Wait.
If that's food,
We're either on the weirdest
cutting board in the world,
Or in somebody's mouth!
(All) Eww!
Bingo.
But not just anybody's mouth.
Look familiar?
Arnold?!?
Boy, it's kind of empty in here.
I wonder where they went.
Well, wherever they are,
They don't have me to slow them down anymore.
Hmm.
Ah, nothing like Cheezie
Weezies with a green olive chaser!
So the first thing that happens to the
food when it gets digested,
Is the teeth cut and grind
it into smaller pieces.
At my old school, we were
never allowed to be digested.
Never say never, Phoebe.
But according to my research...
After chewing comes swallowing!
I call it "Action Arnold."
The wildest, scariest, best
scream-your-lungs-out ride in the world!
Woohoo!
[Class screaming]
[Music]
Ms. Frizzle: Class,
welcome to the esophagus.
Carlos: The asparagus?
(D.A. laughs) No, Carlos, the esophagus.
It's where your food
goes after you swallow.
Ha ah!
Miss Frizzle.
What are you doing?
Time to let Arnold's digestive
system do the driving.
Cool.
It's like we're driving through a
tunnel, but the tunnel's driving US!
Hey Arnold, how 'bout a push?
I wonder if this is what it feels like to
get squeezed out of a tube of toothpaste.
Yeah, but I get the feeling we're not
gonna end up on Arnold's toothbrush.
Huh?
Oh, right, you are Tim.
The esophagus connects
them out to the-
Anyone?
I don't know how much
more of this I can stomach.
Ms. Frizzle: Excellent, Ralphie!
The stomach is the next step in digestion.
And it's a real doozie!
[Class screaming]
In just a few moments we'll
be landing in Arnold's stomach.
Thank you for flying Digestion Airways.
Now that's what I call a belly flop.
[Laughter]
Olive eating.
Now that's a school record I could go for.
Thanks.
Wanda would be so impressed.
Oh, Arnold!
Hey, why not?
Ah, oof!
The all school record book.
Olive eating.
978?!
Ok, it doesn't have to be olives.
(dejected) Oh, there have to be other
records waiting to be broken.
(Ms. Frizzle-deep voice) Yo ho ho
and a stomach of slop.
Check out the pink cliffs of Arnold!
Ralphie, that's his stomach wall.
Rock, dead ahead!
I bet this is what the pilgrims felt like
before they crashed into Plymouth Rock.
Forget the pilgrims, the walls are moving!
[Screams]
Hard aport, class!
[All gasp]
Phoebe: I know Arnold likes rocks, but do
you really think he'd swallow one?
Wanda: That's no rock,
That's Arnold's gum!
Phew, that was close.
Is it just me or do you get the feeling
there's more out there than just food and water?
Whatever it is, it's eating the bus.
[Cracking]
Oh, nothing to worry about,
just a little stomach acid.
Stomach acid?!
Here at United Digestion, we
believe in breaking things down.
We start with the raw material of the food.
Put it in the mouth and use the
finest teeth in the world to tear, grind,
And crush it into pieces
small enough to swallow.
Then the food gets pushed down the
esophagus line into Stomach Central!
Where we add acids and other chemicals to
break the food down and dissolve it into a liquid.
And that's only half of what
we do here at United Digestion.
Man, when it comes to digestion,
Arnold doesn't mess around.
You haven't seen anything yet.
You mean there's... more?
Mmm hmm
All right, Arnold!
If this doesn't impress her, nothing will.
How many more to go, Liz?
One more and I break the school record
for pens stuffed into a pocket protector.
[Screaming]
What's that?
Poor Arnold looks like he's
got a hole in his stomach.
Not a hole, Keisha, a valve.
The doorway to his small intestine!
Yeah, well, he just swallowed the gum.
Hey, why hasn't the gum been digested?
A few things are too tough
to be broken up and dissolved.
Like... school buses.
Right?
There's only one way to find out.
Here we go!
[Class screaming]
Where are we?
It looks like Scuba World.
Welcome to the small intestine,
the next step in digestion.
I don't get it.
The food's been dissolved,
digested, whatever.
What else is left to do?
As I always say, Ralphie,
digested is not delivered.
Anyone for a dip?
Go swimming in Arnold's digestive juice?
Not me, no way.
How was I supposed to know
she'd have digestive juice scuba gear?
Isn't this the coolest?
Hey, there's the gum!
I'll be right back.
Hey, look at this!
The dissolved food is disappearing
into these... rubber cactus type things.
They're called villi.
Cool!
They're soaking up the food like a sponge.
But where did it go?
Here at United Digestion,
what we digest, we deliver.
As the villi in the small intestine
soak up the nutrients in the food,
The nutrients are transferred
into the bloodstream.
And the bloodstream delivers
the nutrients to all parts of the body.
Because here at United Digestion,
we believe in turning food into fuel.
I get it.
The bloodstream is like a pizza
delivery service, only it delivers energy.
Speaking of energy, where's Wanda?
[Wanda Screaming]
Wanda!
[Brahm's Lullaby]
[Lullaby continues]
[Arnold snoring]
Huh? Did I do it?
Two minutes and four seconds.
How can I break the school napping
record if my stomach keeps waking me up?
Where could she be?
I don't see her anywhere.
Wanda!
Where are you?
We've been through the entire
small intestine, and no sign of her.
[Wanda screaming]
There she is!
Ah!
Ah, she went into the large intestine.
The large intestine?
You mean there's more?
What's that?
Just Arnold's leftovers.
Watch out!
[Bus beeps]
Whoa!
Boy, what a ride!
Talk about action!
[overlapping sounds of disgust]
Man, if the small
intestine was Scuba World,
The large intestine is...
Smell World.
At least it's a lot drier in here.
Yeah.
But where's Wanda?
Wait a minute.
This should work.
Wanda, if you can hear this, give a shout!
Wanda: Ah!
Let's go!
All right!
The further we go, the drier it gets.
It looks like the walls are
sucking up all the water.
That's the large intestine for you.
It removes the water from the leftovers.
So we have to find Wanda
before she gets dried into a raisin.
A raisin?
Cool.
Ralphie!
Um, not cool at all.
Terrible, actually, hehe!
Yikes!
[Screaming]
[Gasps]
Wanda! Don't!
[Wanda screaming]
Gotcha!
All right, Carlos!
You saved her.
Saved me?
I was having a blast!
Arnold's digestive system is the wildest,
scariest, scream-your-lungs-out ride in the world!
And it's not over yet.
We've done the mouth.
We've done the esophagus, the stomach,
the small intestine, the large intestine.
What could be next?
The extra large intestine?
No.
We just have to join the rest of
the waste products and finish the trip.
What?!
Wait a minute.
According to my research,
the waste products go...
uh-uh!
No way!
At my old school, we were never
allowed to end up in the toilet.
Anyone have a better idea?
We could go back to the
mouth and ride it again!
Wanda!
She's right.
We could go back the way we came.
I've been keeping track.
And the digestive system is just
one long tube divided into parts.
We started off in the mouth, got
squeezed down the esophagus,
Landed in the stomach, got
pushed into the small intestine,
And wound up here in the large intestine.
And since we don't want to go out
here, all we have to do is go backwards.
We could go back up the large intestine,
back to the small intestine,
into the stomach, back up the esophagus,
and burst triumphantly out the mouth.
It won't be easy.
You're right, Tim.
Digestion pushes everything down.
We'll have to fight our way back.
We might never make it.
Never say never, Miss Frizzle.
[Laughing]
How can I break the
record for eating lunch,
If I can't find my lunch?
Hmm. I wonder if there's any rules
about it having to be my lunch.
A chocolate Malo Blaster.
Ms. Frizzle: ♪ She'll be coming around the
mountain when she comes. ♪
Yee Haw!
Full speed ahead!
This is insane.
Consider the alternative.
You know, biking is my favorite sport.
Ms. Frizzle: Now!
Ah, so much for the easy part.
The easy part?!
Yeah.
Remember all the muscle power
that pushed us down the esophagus?
Oh!
And it's almost noon.
If Arnold eats lunch, there's going to
be tons of food raining down on us!
If I eat Ralphie's lunch and break
the lunch eating record real fast,
Wanda will think I'm the best
thing since velcro shoe fasteners.
But then Ralphie will be
steamed at me for eternity.
What are we going to do? What are we
going to do? What are we going to do?
Wanda, what are we going to do?
[Juices Bubbling]
I've got it!
But if I don't eat something, I'll
wither away to nothing.
I know!
I could eat Ralphie's lunch and think
up a good excuse on a full stomach.
Ghostly voice: Arnold!
What?
I've heard my stomach
growl before, but... talk?
Voice: Arnold!
Are you about to eat
Ralphie's Malo Blaster?
Uh, no.
I mean, yes!
Eee!
Wait a second!
Who is this?
This is your conscience, Arnold.
(Echoing) You know you
shouldn't eat Ralphie's Malo Blaster
Besides, you're not even hungry.
Not hungry?
I could eat a....
You just think you're hungry.
What you really are is thirsty.
I am?
Trust me, you are.
Now there's a nice bottle of
seltzer in Wanda's lunch bag.
That's what you really want.
Uh...ok.
I guess.
Hey!
How come it's ok to drink Wanda's seltzer,
But it's not ok to eat
Ralphie's malo blaster?
Because Wanda's a far kinder and more generous
human being than Ralphie when it comes to sharing.
Then how come when she has a
Malo Blaster, she hogs it all to herself?
Look!
I'm your conscience, alright?
Just do what I say and drink the seltzer.
Now!
Time me.
Way to go, Arnold!
Now let's rock the bus to
create a giant gas bubble!
[Class grunts with effort]
It's working! It's working!
Now what?
[Burp]
Did I break the seltzer-chugging record?
I'll never break a record.
(Sadly) I'll never win anything.
I'll never even get to eat lunch.
Ms. Frizzle: Did someone say lunch?
[Clears Throat] Congratulations, Arnold.
Huh?
You just broke the record for
being the best field trip ever!
Wha- What?
And giving me the ride of my dreams!
You mean I was the field trip?
Yep.
But where exactly did you go?
You went inside?
[Laughter]
Miss Frizzle, no matter what,
I'll never miss another field trip.
Never, ever, ever, ever!
Wonderful, Arnold.
[Dinosaur Roaring]
Um.. starting right after the next one.
[Laughter]
[Reciever Clicks, Phone Dials]
[Phones Continue Dialing]
Is this the Magic School Bus?
Magic School Bus?
[Overlapping Voices] Magic School Bus?
I want the Magic School Bus!
[Cheery Music, Phone Rings]
Producer: Magic School Bus?
Just a minute, please.
Hold on.
Be right with you.
Magic School Bus?
For a show on science, there
sure are of busload of mistakes.
You think so?
I mean, they just zip
through the digestive system.
Nobody's food goes through them that fast.
You're right.
It takes more than 10 hours to digest, but
when we pitched Digestion the Miniseries,
The network didn't bite.
And where did all the light come from?
Except for in the mouth, digestion
takes place in complete darkness.
Believe me, it would have been a lot
cheaper to do "The Magic School Bus Radio Show."
And another thing.
You only showed the small
intestine absorbing stuff.
Um, so we left out something?
Something important.
The stomach doesn't break down everything.
The small intestine breaks things down too.
And all that stuff about the
system not working in reverse.
Sometimes it does, like when you throw up.
Right again.
But normally, it doesn't work that way.
And talking about normal,
they didn't complete the ride.
Waste products that
accumulate in the large intestine.
I know, I know.
They are eliminated out through the anus,
The end of the digestive system.
It's natural. It's normal.
But did you really expect us
to show that on daytime TV?
Well... maybe not.
And another thing.
Wanda using gum to go bungee
jumping in the large intestine?
I mean, come on.
[Chuckles] Cute, huh?
You could never use gum for bungee jumping.
Not in a million years.
I wish you guys would stick to the facts.
[Boinging]
What was that?
Um, that?
Oh, that was just the sound
of Liz stretching the truth.
[Boinging Continues, Music]
[Laughs]
♪ Surfing on a sound wave, ♪
♪ Swinging through the stars, ♪
♪ Take a left at your intestine, ♪
♪ Take your second right past Mars! ♪
♪ On the Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Navigate a nostril! ♪
Achoo!
♪ Climb on the Magic School Bus ♪
♪ Spank a planton too. ♪
Take that!
♪ On our Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Raft a river of lava! ♪
♪ on the Magic School Bus ♪
♪ Such a fine thing to do ♪
Woah!
♪ So strap your bones right to the seat!♪
♪ Come on in and don't be shy, ♪
♪ Just to make your day complete, ♪
♪ You might get baked into a pie! ♪
♪ On The Magic School Bus! ♪
♪ Step inside, it's a wilder ride! ♪
Come on!
♪  Ride on The Magic School Bus! ♪