At the far end of town
Where the Grickle-grass grows
And the wind smells slow and sour
When it blows
And no birds ever sing
Excepting old crows
Is the Street of the Lifted Lorax
Grickle-grass, Grickle-grass
Street of the Lifted Lorax
Somebody lifted the Lorax away
What was the Lorax?
And why was it there?
And why was it lifted
and taken somewhere...
from the far end of town
where the Grickle-grass grows?
The old Once-ler still lives here.
Ask him. He knows.
You won't see the Once-ler.
Don't knock at his door.
He lurks in his Lerkim
on top of his store.
And on Grickle-y midnights in August,
he peeks out of the shutters...
and sometimes he speaks
and tells how the Lorax was lifted away.
It all started way back.
Such a long, long time back.
Way back in the days
when the grass was still green...
and the pond was still wet
and the clouds were still clean...
and the song of the Swomee-Swans
rang out in space.
One morning,
I came to this glorious place.
Then I saw the trees, the Truffula Trees.
The bright-colored tufts
of the Truffula Trees.
Mile after mile
in the fresh morning breeze.
And under the trees,
I saw Brown Bar-ba-loots...
frisking about in their Bar-ba-loot suits.
Under the trees
Happy, dappy Bar-ba-loots
Under the trees in our Bar-ba-loot suits
Under the trees eating Truffula Fruits
- Oh, these succulent
- Mellifluous
- Deliciously
- Delifluous
Sweetly succulifluous
Truffula fruits
Summertime's a-comin', comin'
Under the trees
Humming-Fish are hummin', hummin'
- Oh, these glorious
- Splendembulous
Splendorious
- Splendimulous
- Namby-flamby, flimbulous
Truffula Trees
Those trees. Those trees.
Those Truffula Trees.
All my life I've been searching
for trees such as these.
The touch of their tufts
was much softer than silk.
And they had the sweet smell
of fresh butterfly milk.
I felt a great leaping of love
in my heart.
I knew just what I'd do.
I unloaded my cart.
In no time at all,
I had built a small shop.
Then I chopped down a Truffula Tree
with one chop.
What you doing in my tree stump, buddy?
Your tree stump?
Mister, I am the Lorax.
- I speak for the...
- Forget it. Hmp.
I don't really need the stump.
You can have it, little fellow.
Aha. Just enough to finish the cuffs.
A thing of beauty is a joy forever.
Now, uh, uh, oh, oh, who do you
say you were, little fella?
Mister, I am the Lorax.
I speak for the trees.
I speak for the trees
for the trees have no tongues.
And I'm asking you, sir,
at the top of my lungs.
That thing,
that horrible thing that I see...
what's that thing you've made
out of my Truffula Tree?
Look, Lorax, calm down.
There's no cause for alarm.
I chopped down just one tree.
I'm doing no harm.
Hah. This thing is most useful.
This thing is a Thneed.
A Thneed,
a fine something that all people need.
It's a shirt.
It's a sock.
It's a glove.
It's a hat.
But it has other uses.
Yes, far beyond that.
You can use it for carpets,
for pillows, for sheets or curtains...
or covers for bicycle seats.
Sir, you're crazy.
You're crazy with greed.
Why, there's no one on earth
who would buy that fool Thneed.
The birth of an industry,
you poor, stupid guy.
You telling me what the public will buy?
Please, I object,
in the name of the trees.
All complaints will be filed in this box,
if you please.
Now I had reached the stage
where the potential was known.
This business was too big
for one Once-ler alone.
Promptly I built me a radio phone.
I called my brothers, uncles
and aunts. I said, "Listen here.
Here's a wonderful chance for
the whole Once-ler family to get rich."
Get over here fast. Take the road to
North Nitch. Turn left at Weehawken.
Sharp right at South Stitch.
Don't stand around gawkin'
Turn left at Weehawken
To the Once-ler's house we go
Don't waste your time talkin'
Turn left at Weehawken
To the house of the glorious Once-ler we go
Opportunity's knockin'
There'll be no more squawkin'
We're gonna get rich
Filthy rich
No more holes in our stockin'
Turn left at Weehawken
To the house of the glorious Once-ler we go
Gentlemen, I wish to speak for the trees.
Here are some facts to cogitate
and ruminate.
It takes 10 months for a Truffula seed
to germinate.
It takes 10 long years
before the seed grows into a sapling.
It takes 10 more years...
And, in no time at all,
in the factory I built...
the whole Once-ler family
was working full tilt.
We were all knitting Thneeds
just as busy as bees...
to the sound of the chopping
of Truffula Trees.
Then, oh, baby, oh,
how my business did grow.
Now chopping trees one at a time
was too slow.
So I promptly invented
my Super-Axe-Hacker...
which whacked off
four Truffula Trees in one smacker.
We were making Thneeds
four times as fast as before...
and my profits, incidentally,
were soaring galore.
Hmm, inadequate roadways.
I want a four-lane highway over there.
Instant Roadway Company,
at your service, sir.
I speak for the trees.
Let them grow. Let them grow.
But nobody listens too much,
don't you know?
I speak for the trees.
And I'll yell and I'll shout...
for the fine things on Earth
that are on the way out.
They say I'm old-fashioned
and live in the past.
But sometimes I think progress
progresses too fast.
They say I'm a fool
to oppose things like these...
but I'm going to continue to speak
for the trees.
I'm going to continue to speak
It's always fair weather
When good Once-lers get together
I'm going to continue
to speak for the trees.
Off the old assembly line
Comes another Thneed
Answering humanity's
Each and every need
Everybody do, do, do
Do, do need a Thneed
It isn't just a tanning vest
Use it for a hammock when you need rest
A toothbrush holder for your weekend guest
Your canary will love it
It's a lovely nest
Try it in soup, it adds great zest
It will cure those backache pains
In your chest
Everybody do, do, do
Do, do need a Thneed
You'll be amazed, you'll be nonplussed
It tastes like bread without the crust
Grooms your hair when it gets mussed
Rids your home of dismal dust
It's a natural, it's a must
Eliminates carburetor rust
Everybody do, do, do
Do, do need a Thneed
It's super-duper, hooper-hyper
Makes a perfect windshield wiper
Foolproof trap to catch a viper
We've no complaints from any griper
Papa smokes 'em in his piper
- Baby says
- Boy, what a diaper
Everybody do, do, do
Do need a Thneed
Today we're here to celebrate
Perpetuate and demonstrate
Our love for the good ol' Once-ler
Founding father of the Thneed
Three cheers for the good ol' Once-ler
Georgie Washington of the Thneed
Very heartwarming.
Oh, place your hand upon your heart
And recollect his humble start
He came here in a horse-drawn cart
Upon his sacred mission
Today the Once-ler's fame has grown
Today the name of Thneed is known
It's carved in everlasting stone
Everlasting stone
And seen on television
For he's a jolly good Once-ler
Aren't we all?
Nine hundred and ninety-nine thousand...
nine hundred and ninety-five.
Ninety-six, 97, 98, 99, 1 million.
Stop it! Stop it!
There's something I've got to tell you.
Huh? Oh, it's Nature Boy,
the garden club member.
Now, listen all of you. I am the Lorax.
I speak for the trees.
Whoops.
That was the Lorax.
He spoke for the trees.
Miss Funtzler, Miss Funtzler?
Yes, Mr. Once-ler?
Miss Funtzler, send in Miss O'Schmunsler.
Miss O'Schmunsler for Mr. Once-ler.
Take a letter, Mr. Once-ler?
Take a letter, Miss O'Schmunsler
To my cousin Yenna Yuntzler
General manager, Thneeds Incorporated
Stockholm, Sweden
Dear Yonni
I'm overjoyed to hear how our business
in the Scandinavian market is...
by leaps and bounds speeding.
The entire international picture
is most exuberantly rosy and...
Mr. Once-ler, he's back.
That Lorax nut is back again.
Yes, I am the Lorax
who speaks for the trees...
which you seem to be chopping
as fast as you please.
But I'm also in charge
of the Brown Bar-ba-loots...
who played in the shade
in their Bar-ba-loot suits...
and happily lived, eating Truffula Fruits.
Now thanks to your hacking my trees
to the ground...
there's not enough Truffula Fruit
to go around.
I see your point, yes,
I do see your point.
They loved living here,
but I can't let them stay.
They'll have to find food.
And I hope that they may.
Good luck, boys. Good luck.
Bar-ba-loot suits
Hikin' off to somewhere
In our Bar-ba-loot suits
Please think about it, would you?
Every once in a while
I sit down with myself asking
"Once-ler, why are you a Once-ler?"
And I cringe, I don't smile
As I sit there on trial asking
"Aren't you ashamed, you old Once-ler?
You ought to be locked in a hoosegow,
you should.
The things that you do
are completely ungood."
Yeah. Ha, ha.
But if I didn't do them
Then someone else would
"That's a very good point, Mr. Once-ler."
Progress is progress,
and progress must roll.
Things were going just fine
all the way down the line.
Thneeds were selling like hotcakes
from Timbuktu to Texas.
I was feeling quite relaxed
in my good old solar plexus...
when he snuck out of a pipe.
He was back with another gripe.
Once-ler, you're making
such smogulous smoke.
My poor Swomee-Swans,
why, they can't sing a note.
No one can sing
who has smog in his throat.
And so...
Please pardon my cough.
They cannot live here.
I am sending them off.
Where will they go?
I don't hopefully know.
Will there be another dawn?
A sunrise for the Swomee-Swan
Exit, exit Swomee-Swan
Going, going, going, gone
What do you want,
I should shut down my factory?
Fire a hundred thousand workers?
Is that good economics?
Is that sound for the country?
I see your point,
but I wouldn't know the answer.
Tell you what I'll do. I'll think it over.
No!
You've run out of time
for thinking things over!
I'm sorry to yell, but my dander is up.
Let me say a few words
about gluppity-glupp.
Your machinery chugs on
day and night without stop...
making gluppity-glupp
and also schloppity-schlopp.
You're glumping the pond
where the Humming-Fish hummed.
No more can they hum,
for their gills are all gummed.
So I'm sending them off.
Oh, their future is dreary.
I hear things are just as bad
up in Lake Erie.
Just fish out of water on hard, dry land
People ain't fish
So they can't understand
What happens when simple things
Get out of hand
And the fish and his family's
On hard, dry land
Well, Mr. Once-ler?
Hmp.
First the poor Bar-ba-loots,
then the poor Swomee-Swans.
Now the poor Humming-Fish.
Oh, Mr. Lorax.
Mr. Lorax, this cursed factory of mine,
now at last I understand.
Mr. Once-ler, Mr. Once-ler!
Huh?
Oh, uh, yes, Miss Funtzler.
Stock market has just closed,
and Thneeds Incorporated stock is up.
Up 27 and five-eighth points.
Wow. Wow.
Rowdy-dow!
Now, you listen to me, pop,
while I blow my top.
Trees.
You speak for the trees.
Well, I speak for men
and human opportunities.
For your information, you Lorax...
I'm figgering on biggering
and biggering...
and biggering and biggering.
Turning more Truffula Trees
into Thneeds...
which everyone, everyone, everyone needs!
And at that very moment,
we heard a loud whack...
from outside in the fields
came the sickening smack...
of an axe on a tree.
Then we saw the tree fall.
The very last Truffula Tree of them all.
No more trees.
No more Thneeds. No more work to be done.
And in no time my uncles and aunts,
everyone all waved me goodbye.
They jumped into their cars and drove
away under smoke-smuggered stars.
For he's a jolly good Once-ler
Aren't we all?
Now all that was left
beneath the bad-smelling sky...
was my big, empty factory,
the Lorax, and I.
The Lorax said nothing.
Just gave me a glance.
Just gave me a very sad,
sad backward glance.
As he lifted himself
by the seat of his pants, and I...
I'll never forget the grim look
on his face when he heisted himself...
and took leave of this place
through a hole in the smog...
without leaving a trace.
And all that the Lorax left here
in this mess...
was a small pile of rocks with one word.
"Unless"?
Yes, unless.
What's an unless?
Just a faraway word
Just a faraway thought
A thought? About what?
About something I ought?
Well...
A thought about something
That somebody ought
Unless someone like you
cares a whole awful lot...
nothing is going to get better.
It's not.
Hold on a minute. Where is it now?
Uh, don't go, don't go.
I've got something for you.
Ah, here it is. It's a Truffula seed.
It's the last one of all.
Catch, don't muff.
You're in charge
of the last of the Truffula seeds.
And Truffula Trees
are what everyone needs.
Plant a new Truffula.
Treat it with care.
Give it clean water and feed it fresh air.
Grow a forest.
Protect it from axes that hack.
Then the Lorax and all of his friends
may come back.