♪♪
Hello, everybody.
Thanks for coming.
I am The Lorax.
I speak for the trees.
And I'd like to say
a few words, if you please.
Regarding the story
that you're about to see,
it actually happened--
just take it from me.
But there's more to this story
than what's on the page,
so please pay attention
while I set the stage.
We open in Thneedville,
a city, they say,
that was plastic and fake,
and they liked it that way.
A town without nature,
not one living tree,
So what happened to them?
Cue the music. Let's see.
Buzz. Buzz. Buzz.
♪♪
♪ In Thneedville ♪
♪ It's a brand-new dawn ♪
♪ With brand-new cars
and houses and lawns ♪
♪ Here in
Got-all-that-we-need-ville ♪
♪ In Thneedville,
we manufacture our trees ♪
♪ Each one is made
in factories ♪
♪ And uses 96
batteries ♪
♪ In Thneedville,
the air is not so clean ♪
♪ So we buy it fresh ♪
♪ It comes out
this machine ♪
♪ In Satisfaction's-
guaranteed-ville ♪
♪ In Thneedville,
we don't want to know ♪
♪ Where the smog and trash
and chemicals go ♪
♪ I just went swimming,
and now I glow ♪
♪ In Thneedville,
we have fun year-round ♪
♪ We surf and snowboard
right in town ♪
♪ We thank the Lord
for all we've got ♪
♪ Including this brand-new
parking lot ♪
♪ Parking lot ♪
♪ Pa-a-a-arking lot ♪
♪ Oh, look, it's
Aloysius O'Hare ♪
♪ Aloysius O'Hare ♪
♪ The man who found
a way to sell air ♪
And became a zillionaire!
Hip-hooray. Hip-hooray.
Hip-hip-hooray.
♪ In Thneedville,
we love living this way ♪
♪ It's like living
in paradise ♪
♪ It's perfect ♪
♪ And that's how it will stay ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ Here in Love-the-
life-we-lead-ville ♪
♪ Destined-to-succeed-ville ♪
♪ We-are-all-agreed-ville ♪
♪♪
♪ We love it here in ♪
♪ Thneedville ♪♪
-
- Yes.
♪♪
Oh, hi, Ted.
Oh, hey. Audrey. Hi.
Did your ball land
in my backyard again?
What? No.
A model airplane,
this time.
Hey, do you wanna see
something cool?
Come on.
Whoa.
Did you p--
Did you paint this?
Do you like it?
What?
Are you kidding?
This is amazing.
What are those?
Those are trees.
Real ones.
They used to grow
all around here.
And-- And people said
that the touch
of their tufts...
was softer than anything,
even silk.
And they smelled
like butterfly milk.
Wow. What does that even mean?
I know, right?
Oh, yeah.
What I want more
than anything
in the whole world...
is to see
a real living tree,
growing in my backyard.
So if, say-- I'm just
thinkin' out loud here--
if a guy somehow
got you one--
Well, I'd probably marry him
on the spot.
I bet that sounds crazy.
Does that sound crazy?
No. Not crazy.
Not crazy at all.
Ted, honey,
don't play with your food.
You either, Mom.
So, Mom,
do you happen to know...
if there's,
like, anyplace...
where I could get
a real tree?
Ted, we already have a tree.
It's the latest model.
Yeah, but I mean
like a real one...
that-- that grows
out of the ground
or whatever.
You know, a real tree.
Really? You'd rather have
some dirty, messy
lump of wood...
that just sticks
out of the ground
and it does what?
I don't even know what it does.
What's its purpose?
Look at what we've got.
It's the Oak-a-matic,
the only tree
with its own remote.
Summer, autumn, winter...
and disco.
♪♪ Do the Hustle ♪
♪ Do the Hustle ♪
Mom--
Come on, Ted.
Get into it.
- Dance with the tree.
- Oh, it hurts, Mom.
Please stop.
♪♪
So, anyway, let's just say
I need a tree.
Where would I go?
What do I do?
Then you know what?
You'd need to find
the Once-ler.
The-- The what?
Mom, it's not really
the time for one of your,
uh, you know,
magical fables, okay?
That's right. I forgot.
I'm old
and can't even remember
to put my teeth in.
Stand down.
That's not what I meant.
No, really.
I forgot my teeth.
Would you be a dear
and go get them for me?
Sure, Mom.
Okay, here's the deal.
The Once-ler is the man
who knows what happened
to the trees.
You want one,
you need to find him.
The Once-ler?
Mm-hmm. Okay.
Grammy, is this a real thing
that we're talking about now?
Oh, he's real,
all right.
Well, where can I find him?
Oh.
Far outside of town
where the grass never grows...
and the wind smells
slow-and-sour when it blows.
- Whoo!
-
And no birds ever sing,
excepting old crows.
-
- Whoa!
Quit doing that.
That's the place
where the Once-ler lives.
Wait. Outside of town?
Hey!
People used to say
if you brought him
15 cents, a nail...
and the shell of a great-
great-great-grandfather snail--
he'd tell you everything.
Hmm?
Whoa!
Mr. O'Hare, what we've got
for you...
is something that is
going to take O'Hare Air...
to the next level.
Now, Mr. O'Hare,
I know what you're thinking.
One-- "I've gotten rich
selling people air
that's fresher...
than the stinky stuff
outside."
Two-- and here's
the important one--
"How can I possibly make
even more money?"
We can tell ya, sir.
We can tell ya.
Check out
this commercial. Huh?
Well, here goes
another lame Saturday.
Dude, I don't think so.
Huh?
- ♪♪
- Hey--
Dude. Right here.
- Man.
- Yeah!
What?
Yeah.
O'Hare Purified Air.
Freshness to go.
Please breathe responsibly.
Huh? Love it.
Oh, my goodness.
Yeah.
You gotta be kidding me.
You really think people are
stupid enough to buy this?
Our research shows
that if you put something
in a plastic bottle...
people will buy it.
Exactly.
And--
And what's more,
when we build a new factory
to make the plastic bottles,
the air quality's
just going to get worse.
Which will make people want
our air even more,
and drive sales-- where?
Through the roof!
So in other words,
the more smog in the sky--
the more people will buy.
See, that's why
he's a genius.
- It even rhymes.
- I'm aware it rhymes.
Coats. Big.
What do you two
knuckleheads want?
I'm in the middle of a meeting!
What? Why is he leaving town?
No one ever leaves town!
See what he's up to.
Whoa.
Huh?
Whoa!
Whoa! Whoa.
Oh, man.
Whoa.
All right.
Mm-mmm.
Okay.
What the--
Whoa!
Who are you?
Who are you and what
are you doing here?
I'm Ted! I'm Ted.
I can't breathe.
Are you--
Are you the Once-ler?
Oh, man.
Didn't you read the signs?
No one is supposed
to come here.
Get out of here
and leave me alone!
And don't let the boot
hit you on the way out.
The boot?
Whoa! Hello. Ow.
Listen! People say
that if someone
brings you this stuff...
that you'll tell them
about trees.
Oh, no, no, no, no. Whoa.
Trees?
Yeah.
Real ones. You know,
that grow out of the ground.
Hello?
Sorry. It's just--
Well, I didn't think anyone
still cared about trees.
Well, that's me.
The guy who still cares.
I'm here.
Hey. What-- What--
Whoa.
You wanna know about trees?
About what happened to them?
Why they're all gone?
It's because of me.
Wait. What?
It's because of me!
And my invention,
the Thneed.
It was an amazing product
that could do the job
of a thousand.
All right. Sounds ridiculous
but, I mean, that's cool.
You're darn right it was cool.
It all started a long time ago.
Can we start
not so long ago maybe?
- Do you want a tree?
- Yes. Yes.
Then it all started a long,
long time ago.
I was a young man,
leaving home.
Well, here I go, Mom.
Off to change
the world
with my Thneed.
I'm-- I'm actually doing it.
Yes. But just remember, Oncey--
If somehow your invention
ends up a failure...
instead of a success,
oh, it wouldn't
surprise me at all.
Nice wheels.
Burn.
Ow!
Yeah. "Burn!"
But you'll see, okay?
I'm gonna prove you all wrong.
Come on, Melvin.
So there I was
at the very bottom.
♪♪
With nothing but
a wagon, a mule...
and a completely irrational
sense of optimism.
♪♪
I was searching the globe,
obsessed with finding
the perfect material
for my Thneed.
♪♪
But I'd had
absolutely no success.
Until one day,
I found--
-- paradise.
Oh! We're gonna be there soon.
I'm sure. It's like-- Whoa.
This is
the most beautiful place--
okay-- I have ever seen.
Oh!
♪ Ta-da ♪
- ♪ Ta-da ♪
- Whoa.
♪♪
Whee.
♪ Yeah ♪♪
♪ This is it ♪
♪♪
♪ This is the place ♪
♪ These Truffula trees
are just what I need ♪
♪ Gonna chop one down
and make my Thneed ♪
♪ But first ♪
♪ Na, na, na-na-na-na ♪
♪ Na-na, na-na
na-na-na ♪
- Now you!
- ♪ Na, na, na-na-na-na ♪
Ha, ha. That's great.
♪ Na-na, na-na,
na-na-na-na-na ♪
♪ Na, na, na-na-na-na ♪
♪ La, la, la-la-la-la ♪
♪ La, la, la, la-la-la-
la-la-la-la-la-la-la ♪
- ♪ Na, na, na-na-na-na ♪
- ♪ Ho ah-ha-ha ♪
♪♪
♪ So now our friendship
can begin ♪
♪♪
♪ Hand in hand
and wing and fin ♪
♪ There's nothing
you and I can't do ♪
♪ So let's all make
my dreams come true ♪
♪♪
Huh?
♪ Na, na,
na-na-na-na ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na-- ♪
Hey, guys.
Come on.
Where's my backup chorus?
-
- What?
Aha! Oh.
Ooh.
Whoo.
Hey, hey, hey.
Wait. Wait a minute.
Excuse me?
Yeah. That's awesome.
You know, feeding junk food
to forest animals? That's great.
But, uh, is there
a musical number...
where you show me
how to get a tree?
Because I'd love
to hear that one.
Oh, yes. Right after
the musical number...
about the kid who kept
interrupting the story...
and was never
heard from again.
- Mm-hmm.
- Right. Got it. Proceed.
All right. Here we go.
About to make a Thneed.
About to change the world.
-
Check it out, guys.
What? Uh, oh.
Where'd everybody go?
Little did I know...
that by chopping down
that tree,
I had just summoned
a mystical creature
as old as time itself.
A legendary,
slightly annoying,
guardian of the forest.
The Lorax.
♪♪
Hey.
Did you chop down
this tree?
Uh, no.
Who did it?
What's that?
I think
he did it.
Leave. Vacate the premises.
Take your ax and get out.
And who are you?
What? What?
I'm-- I'm The Lorax.
Guardian of the forest.
I speak for the trees.
So you're telling me
you just didn't see me...
magically appear
out of that stump.
With all the lightning
and thunder and stuff.
You didn't see any of that?
No, but that
sounds amazing.
- Can I see some of that?
- Uh, yeah.
I could show you.
But that's not how it works.
Okay. Um,
didn't really happen.
Oh, I know
what you want.
I've got one of these...
for the cutest little guy
I ever saw.
Yummy, yummy, yummy,
yummy, yummy.
How dare you!
Gimme that.
Mmm.
I'm gonna eat this,
but I am highly offended by it.
Whoa! What are you--
Wait. Hey, Mustache.
Will you stop that?
What's your deal, man?
Time for you
to go, beanpole.
Pull 'em right out.
Just gonna put 'em
right back in.
We can do this all day.
Ho!
Stop right there!
Stop it.
Whoo.
So you'd hammer one
of nature's innocent creatures.
What? No!
I would never hit
this little guy.
You, on the other hand,
I would gladly pound you
and your mustache
into the ground.
Behold!
The intruder
and his violent ways.
Shame on you.
For shame.
All right.
You know what? That's it.
You listen to me,
you furry meat loaf.
I'm gonna chop down
as many trees as I need.
Okay? News flash.
Not going anywhere.
End of story.
Then you leave me
no choice.
If you're not gone
by the time the sun sets
on this valley,
all the forces of nature
will be unleashed upon you...
and curse you
until the end of your days.
You have been warned.
Thanks.
Yeah. Okay.
You have
been warned.
But I didn't listen
to his warning.
And you won't believe
what happened that night.
- What?
- If you wanna hear more,
then come back tomorrow.
Hey, wait. Wait. Tomorrow?
Whoa! Whoa. Whoa-ho-hoa!
Are you serious right now?
You live in the middle
of nowhere.
It stinks out here.
Don't make me come back.
I guess you don't really
wanna hear the rest
of the story.
No, no, no, no.
No, I do.
I really do.
I wanna hear the story.
I just--
Nah. You don't have
what it takes. Good-bye.
Hey, wait, wait, wait.
I have what it takes.
It's all right. It's okay.
I'll come back.
It's no problem.
See? Here I am. Leaving.
Walking away now.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Hmm. Maybe.
Just maybe.
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪♪
What'd you wish for,
Audrey?
Well, I'd love to tell you,
but, sadly, according
to the universal wish laws,
I cannot.
I know what
she wished for.
Was it, perhaps--
-- uh, this?
Ted, you-- you didn't.
Oh, no.
I totally did.
Happy birthday,
Audrey.
Oh.
Kiss him. Kiss him. Kiss him.
Ted. Ted.
Huh?
Tedster, you're kissing
the cereal again, hon.
What? I-I just--
I li-- I like this cereal.
What one is this?
Yeah.
Okay. Well, I'll make sure
to buy extra next time for you.
All right. Cool.
Hey, I gotta run.
I gotta go do a thing.
- So I'll see you guys.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
You're not going
anywhere, young man.
It's Sunday.
You know what that means.
Family time, and we're all
playing board games.
But--
Hmm.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, man.
Mom, seriously.
Every turn?
Hey, back off.
Hmm.
Ooh. Uh, no.
Okay! Family time is over.
It is now personal time.
I'll be in my room.
Oh. Okay, dear.
Have fun.
I knew I could break her.
Go.
Huh?
Go see him.
Oh, yeah!
You rule.
Thank you, Grammy.
Whoa.
Hey. Ted, right?
Um, Mr. O'Hare?
So, I hear you've become
interested in trees.
What's that all about?
Uh-- Oh, um--
Where did you
hear that?
Oh.
Teddy, there's not much
that goes on in Thneedville
that I don't know about.
Here's the deal.
I make a living
selling fresh air to people.
Trees? Oh.
They make it for free.
So when I hear people
talking about them,
I consider it kind of...
a threat to my business.
Come on, I don't even know
what you're talking about.
You listen to me, boy.
Don't go poking around
in things you don't understand,
or I'll be
your worst nightmare.
I'm Frankenstein's head
on a spider's body!
Yeah. Um.
Okay, my mom's
expecting me,
so I'm just gonna--
Of course. Of course.
Now go back
to your family game time.
Grandma just finished her turn.
H-H-How did you know?
Please. I have eyes everywhere.
- Huh?
- You got a beautiful
town here, Ted.
Lots of fun stuff to occupy
your short attention span.
Why, I can't think
of any reason...
you'd ever wanna go
outside of town again.
Ever.
Okay. Good talk.
Really good talk.
-
- Oh, no.
Look out.
Hey, man. Hey, you know
you need to change
that doorbell.
- Aw, you missed me.
- What?
Well, you're already back.
Clearly you missed me.
A little. Right?
No. I didn't. I just--
I'm here to hear
the end of the story.
Why are you so interested
in trees anyway?
Why aren't you
like other kids,
break dancing
and wearing bell-bottoms...
and playing the Donkey Kongs?
Yeah. Right. Right.
Yeah. I don't know.
Uh, I just--
I just, you know,
thought it'd be kinda cool
to have one, you know.
Uh-huh.
It's a girl, isn't it?
What? No.
Really? 'Cause when a guy
does something stupid once,
well, that's because
he's a guy.
But if he does the same
stupid thing twice,
that's usually
to impress some girl.
Hey, she's not some girl.
She's a woman.
In high school.
And she loves trees.
And I'm gonna get her one.
Aw. How nice to see
someone so undeterred...
by things like reality.
- Thank you.
- All right.
Where did we leave off?
Now that's a Thneed.
Nothing unmanly
about knitting.
No, sir.
Look at that--
Oh. Who taught you guys
how to steal a bed?
Shh.
♪♪
♪ Fa-la-la, fa-la-la ♪
♪ Fa-la-la, la, la ♪
Okay, nice and easy.
Nice work, you guys.
Couldn't have done it
without ya.
You gotta be kidding me.
Can he swim?
Of course he can't swim.
Hang on, Pipsqueak.
I'm coming to get you.
Hey, you fishies.
Stop that bed.
Oh!
Huh?
Jump! Jump!
Come on.
Get up there.
Go. Go.
A bit more.
A little bit more.
Ugh. Now what?
Mm-mmm.
Get up there.
Whoa.
Oh.
Okay. Pipsqueak,
give me your hand.
Come on.
Reach out for The Lorax.
Where'd you go?
Oh.
Bar-ba-loots.
Oh, that's bad.
♪♪  ♪♪
Hey, beanpole,
wake up!
Whoa!
-
Uh, what's happening?
Where is-- Where am I?
Hey! You got trouble.
And it's coming up fast.
We're in a river.
Ah. Oh, no.
Just do something!
Help is on the way!
Just a minute!
Huh.
Ooh!
Oh, no.
Egad.
Wake up. Wake up.
Yuck.
Clear!
Whew!
Oh.
I was heading into the light
and you pulled me right back,
and here I am.
You saved my life.
Yeah. I know.
Well, no. It's not
that big a deal.
It is a big deal.
Look. I almost went
over that waterfall.
Wait. My bed.
How did my bed
get in the river?
Uh, about that, uh,
actually, um,
I put your bed
in the water.
I didn't mean ya
any harm.
I just wanted to calmly
float you away.
Look. Everyone here
needs the trees,
and you're chopping 'em down.
So, we've got a big problem.
All right. Look.
I hereby swear that I will
never chop down another tree.
I promise.
Thank you, but I'm gonna
keep my eye on you.
Good. Now I've got
a big day tomorrow,
so I'm going
to get some sleep.
Right after I find my bed.
-
Ow. Okay.
Uh, what are you--
Question-- What are
they doing here?
And, uh,
follow up, if I may--
What are you doing here?
Well, after the incident
last night,
we found one of your socks,
and came here to return it.
But when
we got here--
What?
-- you were asleep.
- Ew.
Exactly. And sleeping
is the body's way...
of telling other people
to go away.
I know, but you looked so cozy.
And it was cold outside,
and we just fell asleep.
No harm done.
No harm done?
No harm done? Okay.
Okay, I put my lips on the--
Well, I used to anyway.
Ew.
Did you just--
In my bowl?
That's why you have
one of these.
You don't even have
a mustache.
Okay. That's it.
What? I thought we made
a deal last night.
Yes. We did. And I said
I wouldn't chop down
any more trees.
And I said I was gonna
keep an eye on you.
I'm starving.
What's for breakfast?
Eh, breakfast is overrated.
You know what?
I got work to do.
Yep. I gotta go into town
and sell my Thneed.
You chopped down
one of my trees...
to make that piece
of garbage?
Garbage? Oh, no.
Oh, no!
You do not get it.
This is
a revolutionary product...
that will change the world
as we know it.
It has a million uses.
Look at this.
It's a swimsuit.
Po! Mud tracked
all over your floor...
by uninvited guests?
Well, the Thneed sure
comes in handy for that.
Whoop-it-up-bup-oh.
But wait. There's more.
Thanks to its all-natural
microfibers, the Thneed
is super absorbent.
It also works as a hat.
You probably wanna
wring it out first.
Go ahead. Go ahead.
Knock yourself out.
But nobody's
gonna buy that thing.
Good to know.
Well, fortunately,
you're not
the target market, weirdo.
You're bringing a guitar?
Oh, yeah.
Oh, I got a little jingle.
Gonna blow some minds.
Gonna sell some Thneeds.
Yeah.
♪♪
♪ Everybody needs a Thneed ♪
♪ A fine thing
that all people-- ♪♪
Sit down! Go on!
Unfortunately, I didn't
sell it the first day.
♪ The Thneed is good
The Thneed is great ♪
Hey! Hey!
Or the second day.
Yeah. Oh. Aw, hey.
Or the third
or fourth or fifth day.
Ow.
Okay, that one
hit the tender spot.
Until finally--
That's it!
You know what?
I'm done with this thing.
My family was right.
I quit.
♪♪
Hey, cool hat.
Oh, my gosh.
I totally want one.
That thing makes me
like you more.
Oh.
Hmm.
What? Aw...
Hey. Where's your Thneed?
You sell it?
Hey. Yeah. Uh, no. No.
Didn't sell it.
Turns out it's ahead
of its time, I guess.
Hey, you gave it
your best shot. Right?
What more can you do?
Come on. Take a seat.
We'll deal you in.
Uh, what are we playing?
I'm playing poker.
He's playing Go Fish.
And I think he's hungry.
Aw.
♪♪
Pancake-a-da-pancake.
Whew, up.
Oh, oh, oh.
Hmm.
Who is up for ninths?
Ooh! Ooh! Ooh!
All right.
Pass 'em over.
Yeah, see?
Wh-- What's going on?
Oh, no.
That's a lot of people.
♪♪
♪ Everybody needs a Thneed ♪
♪ A fine thing
that all people need ♪
♪ The Thneed is good
The Thneed is great ♪
♪ Let's hope
we're not too late ♪
♪ It's a super trendy hat ♪
♪ It's a tightrope ♪
♪ for
an acrobat ♪
♪ A net for catching
butterflies ♪
♪ A thing we use for exercise ♪
♪ Everybody needs a Thneed ♪
♪ A fine thing
that all people need ♪
♪ Everybody needs a Thneed ♪♪
Oh, yeah.
We're in business, baby.
Mom? Hey, it's me.
I told you
I was gonna be a success.
You need to bring
the whole family here
right now.
We're gonna be rich!
What?
I'm gonna need
all the help I can get.
Don't worry.
So, has he told you
how to get a tree yet?
Actually, no.
But I think he's gonna get
to that part really soon.
Here we are.
What?
Oh. I'll just be a minute.
Oh, wow.
Hey, Audrey!
Oh. Hi, Ted.
What's up?
Aw, you know me.
Just cruisin',
puttin' out the vibe.
Just me and my thoughts.
Oh, is this the girl
you're always
talking about--
Grandma!
Stop making things up.
She's even prettier than--
Okay. Gotta run. Bye.
Okay, Grammy,
let's get you home.
Whoa! I'm so sorry.
So sorry.
Did not wanna see that.
Whoa!
Whoa-ho-ho!
Hey.
Hey, I'm back.
What have you got there?
Ha-ha, yes.
Whoa.
Mmm.
Thank you, Ted.
Now, picture this.
Sun shining, a blue sky,
a perfect day.
It was all downhill
from there.
♪♪
Whoa.
What a dump.
Hey, hey.
Aunt Grizelda.
Hey, Chet, check this out.
Go long.
No. Uh, Brett,
that's actually not a--
Um, okay.
I got it!
I got--
Got it.
He totally ran
into that tree.
Ow.
Oncey, is that you?
Mom!
There he is. There's my big,
suddenly successful son.
We always knew
you'd make it, Oncey. Right?
Hey. I love this guy.
But you always said
I wouldn't amount
to anything, remember?
Oh, hush your mouth. I was just
trying to motivate you.
I'm really glad
that you clarified that...
because it actually
hurt my feelings
for a really long time.
Anyway, uh,
you're all here.
You all work for me,
and that's cool,
so let's get to work.
Brett! Chet!
Set up the R.V.
Would you stop throwing
that bear?
Oof.
No, no, no, no.
Whoa. Whoa.
Time out. Back up.
Stop. Don't move an inch.
Nobody's moving in here.
You gotta go. Good-bye.
So who invited
the giant furry peanut?
You calling me a peanut, huh?
I'll go right up your nose.
-
-  Whoa, whoa, whoa!
You wouldn't
hit a woman.
That's a woman?
Okay.
Everyone cool it.
Let's not get off
on the wrong foot here.
Um, family,
this is my friend--
Acquaintance.
Acquaintance,
very good acquaintance,
The Lorax.
He speaks for the trees.
That's right. And on behalf
of the trees, get out!
Will you just--
Be nice.
This is my family.
And I'm gonna need their help
if my company's
gonna get bigger. Okay?
Bigger?
Yeah. This isn't some
rinky-dink operation anymore.
I got plans. Big plans.
A vision of a world
filled with Thneeds.
It's gonna be huge.
Which way
does a tree fall?
Uh, down?
A tree falls the way it leans.
Be careful
which way you lean.
I mean, look at this.
It's amazing.
I am so proud of me.
Oncey, we've got us
a little problem.
- Problem?
- Mm-hmm.
See, we're not
making Thneeds fast enough.
Harvesting the tufts
takes too long.
Well, what else
can we do?
Well, and this
just came to me,
we could always start
choppin' down the trees.
What?
Whoo! Now you're thinkin'.
That would speed things up.
- But--
- No buts, Oncey.
You're runnin' a business now.
You have to do what's best
for the company and your mama.
Well, I guess it couldn't hurt
to chop down a few trees.
You've made me
so proud, Oncey.
Come here.
Hey. I love
this guy.
No, no, no, no!
Stop it. Please stop.
Take that, you stupid tree.
Boom!
Where do you think
you're going?
Excuse me, sir.
I need to talk
with your boss.
Oh, I'm sorry,
but Mr. Once-ler
is not seeing anyone right now.
Yeah, well,
he'll see me, so--
Hey, keep your paws
off me.
Give me a reason, shorty.
Hey, you broke
your promise.
You're better
than this.
You gotta stop.
This is bad!
Have a nice day!
Bad? I'm not bad.
I'm the good guy here.
He just doesn't get it.
Do you think I'm bad?
Thank you.
I mean, something good
finally happens to me,
and he just has to come along
and rain on my parade.
What's his problem?
See?
♪♪
Yeah. Bad. Right.
♪ How ba-a-a-ad can I be? ♪
♪ I'm just doin'
what comes naturally ♪
♪ How ba-a-a-ad can I be? ♪
♪ I'm just following
my destiny ♪
♪ How ba-a-a-ad can I be? ♪
♪ I'm just doin'
what comes naturally ♪
♪ How ba-a-a-ad can I be? ♪
♪ How bad can I possibly be? ♪
♪ Well, there's
a principle of nature ♪
♪ Principle of nature ♪
♪ That almost
every creature knows ♪
♪ Called survival
of the fittest ♪
♪ Survival of the fittest ♪
♪ And check it,
This is how it goes ♪
♪ The animal that wins
gotta scratch and fight ♪
♪ And claw and bite and punch ♪
♪ And the animal that doesn't ♪
♪ Well, the animal
that doesn't winds up ♪
♪ Someone else's
lu-lu-lu-lu-lunch ♪
♪ Lunch, lunch, lunch, lunch ♪
♪ I'm just sayin' ♪
♪ How ba-a-a-ad can I be? ♪
♪ I'm just doin'
what comes naturally ♪
♪ How ba-a-a-ad can I be? ♪
♪ I'm just following
my destiny ♪
♪ How ba-a-a-ad can I be? ♪
♪ I'm just doin'
what comes naturally ♪
♪ How ba-a-a-ad can I be? ♪
♪ How bad can I possibly be? ♪
♪ There's a principle
in business ♪
♪ Principle in business ♪
♪ That everybody knows
is sound ♪
♪ It says
the people with the money ♪
♪ People with the money ♪
♪ Make this ever-lovin' world
go round ♪
♪ So I'm biggering my company
I'm biggering my factory ♪
♪ I'm biggering
my corporate sign ♪
♪ Everybody out there,
you take care of yours ♪
♪ I'll take care of
mine-mine-mine-mine-mine ♪
♪ Shake that bottom line ♪
♪ Let me hear you say
Smogulous Smoke ♪
♪ Smogulous Smoke ♪
♪ Schloppity-schlop ♪
♪ Complain all you want
It's never ever, ever,
ever gonna stop ♪
♪ No ♪
♪ Come on, how bad
can it possibly be? ♪
♪ How ba-a-a-ad can I be? ♪
♪ I'm just building
the economy ♪
♪ How ba-a-a-ad can I be? ♪
♪ Just look at me
petting this puppy ♪
♪ How ba-a-a-ad can I be? ♪
♪ A portion of proceeds
goes to charity ♪
♪ How ba-a-a-ad can I be? ♪
♪ How bad could I possibly be?
Let's see ♪
♪ All the customers are paying ♪
♪ And the money's multiplying ♪
♪ And the P.R. people
are lying ♪
♪ And the lawyers are denying ♪
♪ Who cares
if a few trees are dying? ♪
♪ This is all so gratifying ♪
♪ How bad? ♪
♪ How bad can this
possibly be? ♪♪
So how are things?
What are you doing here?
Happy yet?
You fill that hole
deep down inside you,
or do you still need more?
Look. If you've got a problem
with what I'm doing,
why haven't you used
your "powers" to stop me?
I told you.
That's not how it works.
Right. I forgot.
You're a fraud.
I need you to get out. Now.
Why? Do I make you
uncomfortable?
Remind you of
the promises you made?
The man you used to be?
You know what?
You can just shut
your mustache.
My conscience is clear.
I have done nothing illegal.
I have my rights.
And I intend to keep on
biggering and biggering...
and turning more Truffula trees
into Thneeds.
And nothing
is going to stop me.
Well, that's it.
The very last one.
That may stop you.
Somebody sure made a bundle
on that thing.
Wonder what the next
million-dollar invention's
gonna be.
Yeah. I wonder.
Son, you have
let me down.
Brett, you are now
my favorite child.
Hey, look.
I don't want
any trouble.
And you won't get any.
Not from them.
Thanks to you and your hackin'
and smoggin' and gluppin',
they can't live here anymore.
So I'm sending 'em off.
Hopefully, they'll be able
to find a better place
out there somewhere.
- Melvin?
-
Melvin.
Hey, Pipsqueak.
Hey.
So this is really
all your fault.
You destroyed everything.
Yes.
And each day
since The Lorax left,
I've sat here regretting
everything I've done.
Staring at that word.
"Unless."
And-- And wondering
what it meant.
But now I'm thinking.
Well, maybe you're the reason
The Lorax left that word there.
Me? Why would he
leave that for me?
Because unless someone like you
cares a whole awful lot,
nothing is going to get better.
It's not.
The last Truffula seed.
You need to plant it, Ted.
Yeah, but nobody cares
about trees anymore.
Then make them care.
Plant the seed in the middle
of town where everyone can see.
Change the way
things are.
I know it may seem small
and insignificant,
but it's not about
what it is.
It's about what it can become.
That's not just a seed
any more than you're just a boy.
I won't let you down.
I know.
Meow. Meow.
Me-e-o-w.
Hey, Audrey! Audrey!
Ted? What are you doing?
Meet me at my house.
Uh, wait. But--
My house, okay?
Gotta plant the seed.
Okay, we're gonna need,
uh, water, and, uh,
something to dig with.
Um, what-- what do I have--
Ted?
Ugh. Mom, I'm busy, Mom!
Theodore Wiggins,
get down here right now,
and I am not
kidding with you.
Ted, I'd like you
to meet Mr. O'Hare,
the most powerful man
in town.
There he is.
Hello, Ted.
Uh, hi.
Isn't he clever,
Mr. O'Hare?
He knows his own name
and everything.
You know what I would love
right now, Mrs. Wiggins?
A delicious cookie.
Uh--
Wonderful.
Teddy and I'll stay here
and talk.
Sure. Why don't you
go ahead and adopt him?
I'm just kidding.
That was a joke,
and I just was joking.
I'll get your cookie.
I know you have it, Ted.
So let's put an end
to this nonsense, shall we?
Hand it over.
I'm sorry. I-I don't know
what you're talking about.
Really? Well, then,
I guess you wouldn't mind us
checking your room.
- No, no, no, no!
- Morty! McGurk!
Find the seed!
No. You can't go up there.
No, guys, this is ridiculous.
Stop.
Up. Up.
Hey!
No. You can't come in my room.
Find it!
What-- What is going on here?
This doesn't involve you.
Get back downstairs.
Excuse me, down there.
I don't care who you are,
you little crazy baby man.
Get out of my house now.
This is outrageous.
Fine. Sorry.
Must've been
a misunderstanding.
We'll be leaving now.
And my apologies, Ted.
You be safe.
Wha--
Mind telling me
what's going on here?
The seed.
Where is it?
- Seed?
-
Where's Grammy?
It's alive.
I remember you.
Ted, what--
Uh--
Audrey.
Hey, did you wanna--
Well, okay.
Ted, what is this about?
It's about this.
Wait, wait, wait.
Is that--
Yes. The last Truffula seed.
And you're gonna help me
plant it...
right in the middle of town
where everyone can see it.
I could just kiss you
right now.
Hup! We don't
have time for that.
I don't know.
We have a little time.
But you know what?
Let's just go.
Let's go.
Forget about it.
- Huh?
-
Here it comes.
I'm going for it.
Oh, hello.
- Huh?
-
Ted. Ted.
Big, scary blimp coming.
Ugh.
Whoa!
You won't get away
with this, boy!
Bang.
Go faster, you idiot!
What?
Yeah!
Step on it, Ted.
Hmm?
- Ooh.
-
You're fired.
- Whoa. Ted, look out.
-
- Nobody beats--
- Ted!
--Aloysius O'Hare!
♪♪
Whoa. This is not good.
How's it doing?
Loser!
Oh, ho, ho, ho, ho, really?
Oh, no.
The seed!
Get that seed!
Hey!
Hang on.
Here we go!
Grammy!
Ha!
Seriously, how cool
is your grandma?
Oh. Mwah.
Huh? Whoa!
No.
Come on!
Yeah. That's right.
There it is.
Hey, hey, hey!
Watch the road,
you meathead!
Hey. Ow. Ow.
Oh, come on!
What the--
Get it unstuck!
Bring it on, Teddy.
You don't have the guts.
Ted!
Grammy.
Yes!
Hey. Hey, hey, hey!
- Hey, it's Mr. O'Ha--
-
Take that, shorty.
So we hike up to the falls,
and we're standing--
Okay, we have to get this
in the ground.
But where? There's--
There's no dirt anywhere.
Ooh.
- No. Uh, Grammy--
-
Whoa.
Whoopsie.
Hey,
get out of there.
Hey.
What? What?
See, what'd I tell you?
Easy, huh?
Hey, they broke
O'Hare's head.
What do you think
you're doing, kid?
Uh, I'm looking for a place
to plant a tree.
A real one.
Why would we need
a tree?
- Exactly.
-
Oh, man.
Folks--
the last thing you want
around here is trees.
They're filthy.
Spewing that sticky,
nasty sap...
all over the place.
They bring poisonous ants...
and stinging bees.
Hey.
Ouch. Think about
the kids.
And I just thought of, you know,
they-- they make leaves!
You know that, right?
Then these leaves,
they just fall.
They just fall
wherever they want.
Come on. We know why
you're really against trees.
Because they produce
fresh air.
For free.
I am wounded.
You have lied.
It is not a lie.
It's called photosynthesis.
Come on.
She's making that up.
That's a made-up word, people.
Thneedville is perfect
just the way it is.
We don't need trees.
That boy has a seed.
We need to stop him!
Who's with me?
Come on.
O'Hare's right!
Seeds will ruin us all!
Stop it!
I'm afraid of seeds!
Last chance, kid.
Hand it over.
Where do you think you're going?
Come on. Let's go.
Get in. Get in!
Stop that maniac!
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Watch out!
Ted, you're gonna
hit the wall.
Yeah. I know.
Wow. Did you see that?
Who does this kid
think he is, huh?
I am Ted Wiggins,
and I speak for the trees.
And the fact is...
things aren't perfect
here in Thneedville.
And they're only gonna get worse
unless we do something about it.
Unless we change our ways.
And we can start
by planting this.
Okay. Come on now.
Everything's fine.
Right?
I say we tell this kid
what we think about that seed.
People. Come on!
You. Get out there right now
and get these people on my side.
Or else you're fired.
Go on.
Tell 'em what you think.
♪ You don't know me,
but my name's Cy ♪
♪ I'm just the O'Hare
delivery guy ♪
♪ But it seems like trees
might be worth a try ♪
♪ So I say let it grow ♪
♪ My name is Dan ♪
♪ And my name's Rose ♪
♪ Our son Wesley kinda glows ♪
♪ And that's not good,
so we suppose ♪
♪ We should let it grow ♪
♪ Let it grow, let it grow ♪
♪ You can't reap
what you don't sow ♪
♪ Plant a seed
inside the earth ♪
♪ Just one way
to know its worth ♪
♪ Let's celebrate
the world's rebirth ♪
♪ We say let it grow ♪
♪ My name's Marie,
and I am three ♪
♪ I would really like
to see a tree ♪
Aw.
♪ La, la, la,
la, la-la, la lee ♪
♪ I say let it grow ♪
♪ I'm Grammy Norma, I'm old
and I've got gray hair ♪
♪ But I remember when trees
were everywhere ♪
♪ And no one had
to pay for air ♪
♪ So I say let it grow ♪
♪ Let it grow, Let it grow ♪
♪ Like it did so long ago ♪
♪ It's just one tiny seed
But it's all we really need ♪
♪ It's time to change
the life we lead ♪
♪ Time to let it grow ♪
♪ My name's O'Hare,
I'm one of you ♪
♪ I live here
in Thneedville too ♪
♪ The things you say
just might be true ♪
♪ It could be time
to start anew ♪
♪ And maybe change
my point of view ♪
Nah.
I say let it die.
♪ Let it die, let it die ♪
♪ Let it shrivel up and-- ♪♪
Come on. Who's with me, huh?
Nobody.
♪ You greedy dirtbag ♪
♪♪ Let it grow, let it grow ♪
♪ Let the love inside you show ♪
♪ Plant a seed
inside the earth ♪
♪ Just one way
to know its worth ♪
♪ Let's celebrate
the world's rebirth ♪
♪ We say let it grow ♪
♪ Let it grow, let it grow ♪
♪ You can't reap
what you don't sow ♪
♪ It's just one tiny seed ♪
♪ But it's all we really need ♪
♪ It's time to banish
all your greed ♪
♪ Imagine Thneedville
flowered and treed ♪
♪ Let this be our solemn creed ♪
Thank you, Ted.
♪ We say let it grow ♪
♪ In Thneedville ♪
♪ It's a brand-new dawn ♪
♪ We say let it grow ♪
♪ In Thneedville ♪
♪ We say ♪
♪ Let it grow ♪
♪ It's a brand-new dawn ♪♪
Hmm.
You done good, beanpole.
You done good.
By the way,
nice mustache.
♪ Plant a seed
inside the earth ♪
♪ Just one way
to know its worth ♪
♪ When we celebrate the world ♪
♪ Celebrate the world ♪
♪ Come on and celebrate
the world ♪
♪ Grow ♪
♪ It don't matter
how you got it ♪
♪ It's yours now.
Don't you hide it ♪
♪ Let it grow ♪
♪ Let the love inside you
show it ♪
♪ Just one way
to know you're
worth it ♪
♪ Let it grow ♪
♪ Just believe
and you're almost there ♪
♪ Use your heart
to show you care ♪
♪ Come on and celebrate
the world ♪
♪ Celebrate the world ♪
♪ Come on and celebrate
the world, yeah ♪
♪ All you gotta do
All you gotta do ♪
♪ Is live your life, be true
Live your life, be true ♪
♪ And never be afraid
Never be afraid ♪
♪ To grow ♪
♪ Grow ♪
♪ It don't matter
how you got it ♪
♪ It's yours now
Don't you hide it ♪
♪ Let it grow ♪
♪ Let the love inside you
show it ♪
♪ Just one way to know
you're worth it ♪
♪ Let it grow ♪
♪ It's your turn now ♪
♪ To show your world now ♪
♪ Open up your heart
and let it grow ♪
♪ It's your turn now ♪
♪ To show your world now ♪
♪ Open up your heart
and let it grow ♪
♪ It don't matter
how you got it ♪
♪ It don't matter ♪
♪ It's yours now
Don't you hide it ♪
♪ Should not ♪
♪ Let it grow ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Let the love inside you
show it ♪
♪ Just one way to know
you're worth it ♪
♪ Let it grow ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Let it grow ♪♪
♪♪
♪ Ta-da ♪
♪ Yeah ♪♪